There was me.
That is, Alex,
and my three droogs.
That is, Pete, Georgie and Dim.
And we sat in the Korova Milk Bar,
trying to make up our rassoodocks...
... what to do with the evening.
The Korova Milk Bar sold milk plus.
Milk plus vellocet or
synthemesc or drencrom...
... which is what we were drinking.
This would sharpen you up...
... and make you ready for a bit
of the old ultra-violence.
In Dublin 's fair city
Where the girls are so pretty
I first set my eyes
On sweet Molly Malone
As she wheeled her wheelbarrow
Through streets broad and narrow
Crying, "Cockles and mussels..."
One thing I could never stand...
... was to see a filthy,
dirty old drunkie...
... howling away at the
filthy songs of his fathers...
... and going "blerp blerp"
in between...
... as it might be a filthy old
orchestra in his stinking guts.
I could never stand to see anyone
like that, whatever his age.
But more especially when he
was real old, like this one was.
Can you spare some cutter,
me brothers?
Go on! Do me in, you bastard cowards!
I don't want to live anyway.
Not in a stinking world
like this.
And what's so stinking about it?
It's a stinking world because
there's no law and order anymore!
It stinks because it lets
the young get onto the old...
...like you done!
It's no world
for an old man any longer.
What kind of a world is it
at all?
Men on the moon.
Men spinning around the earth.
And there's not no
attention paid...
...to earthly
law and order no more.
Oh, dear land
I fought for thee
It was at the derelict casino
that we came across Billy-boy...
... and his four droogs.
They were about to perform
a little of the old...
... in-out, in-out on a weepy
young devotchka they had there.
Well, if it isn't fat, stinking...
...billy goat
Billy-boy in poison.
How are thou...
...thou globby bottle of cheap,
stinking chip-oil?
Come and get one in the yarbles...
...if you have any yarbles...
...you eunuch jelly, thou.
Let's get them, boys!
The police!
Come on. Let's go!
The Durango 95 purred away
real horrorshow.
A nice, warm vibratey feeling
all through your guttiwuts.
Soon it was trees and dark,
my brothers...
... with real country dark.
We fillied around with other
travelers of the night...
... playing Hogs of the Road.
Then we headed west.
What we were after now
was the old surprise visit.
That was a real kick...
... and good for laughs and
lashing of the old ultra-violent.
Who on earth could that be?
I'll go and see.
Yes, who is it?
Excuse me, can you please help?
There's been a terrible accident!
My friend's bleeding to death!
Can I please use your telephone?
We don't have a telephone.
You'll have to go somewhere else.
But, missus, it's a matter
of life and death!
Who is it, dear?
A young man.
He says there's been an accident.
He wants to use the telephone.
I suppose you better let him in.
Wait a minute, will you?
I'm sorry, but we don't usually
let strangers in...
What do you want from me?
Pete, check the rest
of the house. Dim...
I'm singing in the rain
Just singing in the rain
What a glorious feeling
I'm happy again
I'm laughing at clouds
So dark up above
The sun 's in my heart
And I'm ready for love
Let the stormy clouds chase
Everyone from the place
Come on with the rain
I've a smile on my face
I'll walk down the lane
With a happy refrain
And I'm singing
Just singing...
... in the rain
Viddy well, little brother.
Viddy well.
We were all feeling a bit
shagged and fagged and fashed...
... it having been an evening
of some small energy expenditure.
So we got rid of the auto and
stopped at the Korova for a nightcap.
Hello, Lucy.
Had a busy night?
We've been working hard too.
Pardon me, Luce.
There was some sophistos from
the TV studios around the corner...
... laughing and govoreeting.
The devotchka smeched away, not
caring about the wicked world one bit.
Then the disk on the stereo
twanged off and out.
And in the short silence
before the next one came on...
... she suddenly came
with a burst of singing.
And it was like, for a moment,
O my brothers...
... some great bird
had flown into the milk bar.
And I felt all the malenky
little hairs on my plott...
... standing endwise.
And the shivers crawling up
like slow, malenky lizards...
... and then down again.
Because I knew what she sang.
It was a bit from
the glorious Ninth, by Ludwig van.
What did you do that for?
For being a bastard
with no manners.
Without a dook of an idea about how
to comport yourself public-wise.
I don't like you should
do what you done.
And I'm not your brother no more
and wouldn't want to be.
Watch that.
Do watch that, if to continue
to be on live thou dost wish.
Yarbles!
Great, bouncy yarblockos to you!
I'll meet you with chain
or nozh or britva anytime.
I'm not having you aiming
tolchocks at me reasonless.
It stands to reason,
I won't have it.
A nozh scrap anytime you say.
Doobidoob.
A bit tired maybe.
Best not to say more.
Bedways is rightways now.
So best we go homeways
and get a bit of spatchka.
Right, right?
Where I lived was with
my dada and mum...
... in municipal flat block
1 8- A, Linear North.
It had been a wonderful evening.
And what I needed now
to give it the perfect ending...
... was a bit
of the old Ludwig van.
Oh, bliss!
Bliss and heaven!
It was gorgeousness and
gorgeosity made flesh.
It was like a bird
of rarest spun heaven metal.
Or like silvery wine
flowing in a spaceship...
... gravity all nonsense now.
As I slooshied...
... I knew such lovely pictures.
Alex. Alex!
What do you want?
It's past eight, Alex.
You don't want to be
late for school, son.
Bit of a pain in the gulliver, Mum.
Leave us be,
and I'll try and sleep it off.
And then I'll be as right
as dodgers for this after.
But you've not been
to school all week, son.
Got to rest, Mum.
Got to get fit.
Otherwise, I'm liable
to miss a lot more school.
I'll put your breakfast in the oven.
I've got to be off meself now.
All right, Mum.
Have a nice day at the factory.
He's not feeling too good
again this morning, Dad.
Yes. Yes, I heard.
You know what time he got in?
No, I don't.
I'd taken me sleepers.
I wonder...
...where exactly is it
he goes to work of evenings.
Like he says...
...it's mostly odd things he does.
Helping-like...
...here and there, as it might be.
Hi, hi, hi, Mr. Deltoid.
Funny surprise, seeing you here.
Alex-boy!
Awake at last, yes?
I met your mother
on the way to work, yes?
She gave me the key.
She said something about
a pain somewhere.
Hence, not at school, yes?
A rather intolerable pain
in the head, brother sir.
It should be clear
by this afterlunch.
Or certainly by this evening, yes.
The evening's the great time,
isn't it, Alex-boy?
- Cup of the old chai, sir?
- No time, no time.
Sit, sit, sit!
To what do I owe
this extreme pleasure, sir?
Anything wrong, sir?
Wrong? Why should you
think of anything being wrong?
Have you been doing
something you shouldn't?
Just a manner of speech.
Yes, well, it's just a manner
of speech from your...
...post-corrective advisor to you
that you watch out, little Alex.
Because next time it's not
going to be the corrective school.
Next time it'll be the Barley place,
and all my work ruined.
If you've no respect
for yourself...
...you at least might have some
for me, who sweated over you.
A big, black mark, I tell you,
for every one we don't reclaim.
A confession of failure
for every one of you...
...who ends up in the stripy hole.
I've been doing nothing I shouldn't.
The millicents have nothing
on me, brother.
Sir, I mean.
Cut out this clever talk
about millicents.
Just because the police
haven't picked you up...
...doesn't mean that you've not
been up to some nastiness.
There was a bit of nastiness last night.
Some very extreme nastiness, yes?
A few of a certain Billy-boy's
friends were ambulanced off late.
Your name was mentioned.
The words got to me
by the usual channels.
Certain friends of yours
were named also.
Nobody can prove anything
about anybody, as usual.
I'm warning you, little Alex...
...being a good friend
to you as always...
...the one man in this
sore and sick community...
...who wants to save you
from yourself!
What gets into you all?
We've been studying the problem
for damn well near a century.
But we get no farther
with our studies.
You got a good home here.
Good, loving parents.
You've got not too bad of a brain.
Is it some devil
that crawls inside of you?
Nobody's got anything on me.
I been out of the millicents'
rookers for a long time.
That's just what worries me.
A bit too long to be safe.
You're about due, by my reckoning.
That's why I'm warning you...
...to keep your handsome
young proboscis out of the dirt.
Do I make myself clear?
As an unmuddied lake, sir.
As clear as an azure sky
of deepest summer.
You can rely on me, sir.
Excuse me, brother.
I ordered this two weeks ago.
Can you see if it's arrived?
Just a minute.
Pardon me, ladies.
Enjoying that, are you, my darling?
A bit cold and pointless,
isn't it, my lovely?
What's happened to yours,
my little sister?
Who you getting, bratty?
Goggly Gogol?
Johnny Zhivago?
The Heaven 17?
What you got back home
to play your fuzzy warbles on?
I bet you've got little
pitiful, portable picnic players.
Come with Uncle
and hear all proper.
Hear angel trumpets
and devil trombones.
You are invited.
Hi, hi, hi, there.
Well, hello.
He are here!
He have arrived!
Hooray!
Welly, welly, welly,
welly, welly, welly, well!
To what do I owe the extreme pleasure
of this surprising visit?
We got worried.
There we were, waiting and drinking
away at the old knifey moloko...
...and you had not turned up.
And we thought
you might have been, like...
...offended by something
or other.
So around we come to your abode.
Appy polly loggies.
I had something of a pain
in the gulliver, so I had to sleep.
I was not awakened
when I gave orders for wakening.
Sorry about the pain.
Using the gulliver
too much-like, maybe.
Giving orders and
discipline and such, perhaps.
You sure the pain is gone?
You sure you'd not
be happier back in bed?
Let's get things nice
and sparkling clear.
This sarcasm,
if I may call it such...
...does not become you,
my little brothers.
As I am your droog and leader
I'm entitled to know what goes on.
Now then, Dim.
What does that great big
horsey gape of a grin portend?
All right, no more
picking on Dim, brother.
That's part of the new way.
New way?
What's this about a new way?
There's been some very large talk
behind my sleeping back, I know it.
If you must have it,
have it, then.
We go around shop crasting
and the like...
...coming out with a pitiful
rookerfull of money each.
And Will the English
in the coffee mesto...
...saying he can fence anything
any malchick tries to crast.
The shiny stuff. The ice!
The big, big money's available,
is what Will the English says.
And what will you do
with the big, big, big money?
Have you not everything you need?
If you need a motorcar,
you pluck it from the trees.
If you need pretty polly,
you take it.
Brother, you think and talk
sometimes like a little child.
Tonight we pull a man-size crast.
Good! Real horrorshow!
Initiative comes
to thems that wait.
I've taught you much,
my little droogies.
Now tell me what you had in mind,
Georgie-boy.
The old moloko plus first.
Would you not say?
- Something to sharpen us up.
- Some moloko plus.
You got to go there first.
We got a start on you. Moloko Plus!
As we walked along
the flatblock marina...
... I was calm on the outside,
but thinking all the time.
So now it was to be
Georgie the General...
... saying what we should do
and what not to do.
And Dim as his mindless,
grinning bulldog.
But suddenly I viddied that
thinking was for the gloopy ones...
... and that the oomny ones used, like,
inspiration and what Bog sends.
For now it was lovely music
that came to my aid.
There was a window open
with a stereo on...
... and I viddied right at once
what to do.
I had not cut into any
of Dim's main cables.
And so with the help
of a clean tashtook...
... the red, red kroovy
soon stopped.
And it did not take long to
quieten the two wounded soldiers...
... down in the snug
of the Duke of New York.
Now they knew who was
master and leader.
Sheep, thought I.
But a real leader knows
always when, like...
... to give and show generous
to his unders.
Now we're back to where we were.
Yes?
Just like before,
and all forgotten?
Right, right, right?
Right.
Well, Georgie-boy...
...this idea of yours for tonight.
Tell us all about it, then.
Not tonight.
Not this nochy.
Come, come, come, Georgie-boy.
You're a big, strong chelloveck,
like us all.
We're not little children,
are we, Georgie-boy?
What, then, didst thou
in thy mind have?
It's this health farm.
A bit out of the town.
Isolated.
It's owned by this rich ptitsa
who lives there with her cats.
The place is shut down for a week
and she's completely on her own.
It's full up with, like,
gold and silver...
... and, like, jewels.
Tell me more, Georgie-boy.
Tell me more.
Oh, shit!
Who's there?
Excuse me, can you please help?
There's been a terrible accident!
Can I please use your telephone
for an ambulance?
I'm frightfully sorry.
There's a telephone in the
public house a mile down the road.
I suggest you use that.
But missus, this is an emergency!
It's a matter of life and death!
Me friend's lying in the middle
of the road, bleeding to death!
I'm very sorry, but I never open
the door to strangers after dark.
Very well, madam.
You can't be blamed
for being suspicious...
...with so many scoundrels
and rogues of the night about.
I'll try and get help
at the pub, then.
I'm sorry if I disturbed you.
Thank you very much.
Good night.
Dim, bend down.
I'll get in that window
and open the front door.
Radlett Police Station?
Good evening. It's Miss Weathers
at Woodmere Health Farm.
I'm sorry to bother you, but
something rather odd just happened.
It's probably nothing at all,
but you never know.
A young man rang the bell,
asking to use the telephone.
He said there's been
some kind of accident.
The thing that caught my
attention was what he said.
His words sounded like those quoted
in the papers this morning...
...in connection with the writer
and his wife who were assaulted.
Just a few minutes ago.
If you think that's necessary.
But I'm quite sure
he's gone away now.
All right, fine.
Thank you very much.
Hi, hi, hi, there.
At last we meet.
Our brief govorett through the
letter-hole was not satisfactory.
Who are you?
How the hell did you get in here?
What the bloody hell
do you think you're doing?
Naughty, naughty, naughty!
You filthy old soomaka.
Now listen here,
you little bastard!
Just turn round and walk out
of here the same way you came in.
Leave that alone!
Don't touch it!
It's a very important work of art.
What the bloody hell do you want?
To be perfectly honest, madam...
...I'm taking part in an
international students' contest...
...to see who can get the most
points for selling magazines.
Cut the shit, sonny...
...and get out of here before you
get yourself into serious trouble.
I told you to leave that alone!
Now get out of here...
...before I throw you out!
Wretched, slummy bedbug!
I'll teach you to break
into real people's houses.
Fucking...
...little...
...bastard!
- Let's go. The police are coming!
- One minoota, droogie.
You bastards! I'm blind!
I'm blind, you bastards!
I can't see!
It's no good sitting there in hope,
my little brothers.
I won't say a single solitary
slovo unless I have my lawyer here.
I know the law, you bastards.
Righty-right, Tom.
We'll have to show our friend Alex
here that we know the law too.
But that knowing the law
isn't everything.
Nasty cut you've got there,
little Alex.
Shame, isn't it?
Spoils all your beauty.
Who gave you that, then?
How'd you do that, then?
What's your point, you bastard?
That is for your lady victim.
You ghastly...
...wretched scoundrel.
Get him off me!
You rotten little bastard!
Good evening, Mr. Deltoid.
Good evening, Sergeant.
They're in room B, sir.
Thank you very much.
Sergeant...
Good evening.
Good evening, Inspector.
- Would you like your tea now, sir?
- No, thank you, Sergeant.
May I have some
paper towels, please?
We're interrogating
the prisoner now.
- Perhaps you'd care to come inside.
- Thank you very much.
Good evening, Sergeant.
Good evening, all.
Oh, dear! This boy
does look a mess, doesn't he?
Just look at the state of him.
Love's young nightmare-like.
Violence makes violence.
He resisted his lawful arrestors.
This is the end of the line for me.
The end of the line, yes.
And what of me, brother sir?
Speak up for me.
I'm not so bad.
I was led on by
the treachery of others.
Sings the roof off lovely,
he does, sir.
Where are my treacherous droogs?
Get them before they get away!
It was all their idea, brothers.
They forced me to do it.
I'm innocent!
You are now a murderer,
little Alex.
A murderer.
Not true, sir.
It was only a slight tolchok.
She were breathing, I swear it.
I've just come from the hospital.
Your victim has died.
You try to frighten me.
Admit so, sir.
This is some new form of torture.
- Say it, brother sir.
- It'll be your own torture.
I hope to God
it'll torture you to madness.
If you'd care to give him a bash
in the chops, don't mind us.
We'll hold him down.
He must be a great
disappointment to you, sir.
This is the real weepy and tragic
part of the story beginning...
... O my brothers and only friends.
After a trial,
with judges and a jury...
... and hard words spoken against
your friend and humble narrator...
... he was sentenced to 14 years
in Staja Number 84- F...
... among smelly perverts
and hardened prestoopniks.
The shock sending my dada beating
his bruised and krovvy rookers...
... against unfair Bog
in His Heaven.
And my mum boo-hoo-hooing
in her mother's grief...
... at her only child
and son of her bosom...
... like, letting everybody down
real horrorshow.
Morning.
One up from Thames, mister.
Right! Open up the cell!
Yes, sir.
Here are the prisoner's
committal forms.
Thank you, mister.
- Name?
- Alexander DeLarge.
You are now in
H.M. Prison Parkmoor.
From this moment, you will address
all prison officers as "sir."
Name?
Alexander DeLarge, sir.
Sentence?
14 years, sir.
Crime?
Murder, sir.
Right.
Take the cuffs off him, mister.
You are now 655321.
It is your duty
to memorize that number.
Thank you, mister. Well done.
- Thank you.
- Let the officer out.
All right, empty your pockets.
Are you able to see the white line
painted on the floor...
...directly behind you...
...655321?
Then your toes belong...
...on the other side of it!
- Yes, sir.
- Right.
Carry on.
Pick that up...
...and put it down properly.
One half-bar of chocolate.
One bunch of keys
on white metal ring.
One packet of cigarettes.
Two plastic ball pens.
One black, one red.
One pocket comb, black plastic.
One address book,
imitation red leather.
One ten-penny piece.
One white metal wristlet watch...
...Timawrist, on a white metal
expanding bracelet.
Anything else in your pockets?
- No, sir.
- Right.
Sign here for your
valuable property.
The tobacco and chocolate
you brought in...
...you lose that...
...as you are now convicted.
Now over to the table
and get undressed.
Were you in police custody
this morning?
One jacket, blue pinstriped.
Prison custody?
Yes, sir, on remand.
- One necktie, blue.
- Religion?
C. Of E., sir.
Do you mean the Church of England?
Yes, sir.
The Church of England.
Brown hair, isn't it?
Fair hair, sir.
Blue eyes?
Blue, sir.
Do you wear eyeglasses
or contact lenses?
No, sir.
One shirt, blue.
Collar attached.
Have you been receiving medical
treatment for any serious illness?
One pair of boots, black leather.
Zippered. Worn.
Have you ever had
any mental illness?
Do you wear any false teeth
or any false limbs?
One pair of trousers,
blue pinstriped.
Have you ever had any attacks
of fainting or dizziness?
One pair of socks, black.
Are you an epileptic?
One pair of underpants,
white with blue waistband.
Are you now, or have you ever been,
a homosexual?
Right.
- The mothballs, mister.
- Mothballs, sir.
Now then, face the wall...
...bend over and touch your toes.
Any venereal disease?
Crabs? Lice?
- Through there for the bath.
- One for a bath.
What's it going to be, eh?
Is it going to be in and out
of institutions like this...
...though more in than out
for most of you?
Or are you going to attend
to the divine word...
...and realize the punishments
that await unrepentant sinners...
...in the next world
as well as this?
A lot of idiots you are...
...selling your birthright
for a saucer of cold porridge.
The thrill of theft.
Of violence.
The urge to live easy.
Well, I ask you what is it worth...
...when we have undeniable proof...
...yes, incontrovertible
evidence...
...that hell exists?
I know!
I know, my friends.
I have been informed...
...in visions...
...that there is a place...
...darker than any prison...
...hotter than any flame
of human fire...
...where souls...
...of unrepentant criminal sinners
like yourselves...
Don't you laugh, damn you!
Don't you laugh.
I say, like yourselves...
...scream...
...in endless and
unendurable agony.
Their skin...
...rotting and peeling.
A fireball...
...spinning in their
screaming guts!
I know. Yes, I know!
All right, you lot!
We'll end by singing hymn 258...
...in the prisoner's hymnal.
And let's have a little reverence,
you bastards!
I was a wandering sheep
- Sing up, damn you!
- I did not love the fold
Louder!
I did not love my shepherd's voice
I would not be controlled
Louder!
It had not been edifying.
Indeed not.
Being in this hellhole
and human zoo for two years now.
Being kicked and tolchoked
by brutal warders...
... and meeting leering criminals
and perverts...
... ready to dribble all over...
... a luscious young malchick
like your storyteller.
It was my rabbit...
... to help the prison charlie
with the Sunday service.
He was a bolshy,
great burly bastard.
But he was very fond of myself,
me being very young...
... and also now very interested
in the Big Book.
I read all about the scourging
and the crowning with thorns.
And I could viddy myself
helping in...
... and even taking charge of
the tolchoking and the nailing in.
Being dressed in the height
of Roman fashion.
I didn 't so much like
the latter part of the Book...
... which is more like
all preachy talking...
... than fighting
and the old in-out.
I like the parts where these old
yahoodies tolchok each other...
... and then drink
their Hebrew vino...
... and getting onto the bed
with their wives ' handmaidens.
That kept me going.
"Seek not to be like evil men.
Neither desire to be with them...
...because their minds
studieth robberies...
...and their lips speak deceits."
If thou lose hope, being weary
in the days of distress...
...thy strength
shall be diminished.
Fine, my son. Fine.
Father?
I have tried, have I not?
You have, my son.
- I've done my best, have I not?
- Indeed.
I've never been guilty of any
institutional infraction, have I?
You certainly have not, 655321.
You've been very helpful.
And you've shown
a genuine desire to reform.
Father...
...can I ask you
a question in private?
Certainly, my son. Certainly.
Is there something
troubling you, my son?
Don't be shy to speak up.
Remember...
...I know of the...
...urges that can
trouble young men...
...deprived...
...of the society of women.
It's nothing like that, Father.
It's about this new thing
they're all talking about.
About this new treatment.
It gets you out of prison
in no time.
And makes sure you
never get back in again.
Where did you hear about this?
Who's been talking
about these things?
These things get around.
Two warders talk, as it might be.
And somebody can't help
overhearing what they say.
Then somebody picks up a scrap
of newspaper in the workshops...
...and the newspaper
tells all about it.
How about putting me in
for this new treatment?
I take it you are referring...
...to the Ludovico technique.
I don't know what it's called.
I just know it
gets you out quickly...
...and makes sure you
never get back in again.
That is not proven, 655321.
In fact, it is only in the
experimental stage at this moment.
It has been used, hasn't it?
It has not been used
in this prison yet.
The governor has grave
doubts about it.
And I've heard there are
very serious dangers involved.
I don't care about the dangers.
I just want to be good.
I want for the rest
of my life to be...
...one act of goodness.
The question is...
...whether or not this technique
really makes a man good.
Goodness comes from within.
Goodness...
...is chosen.
When a man cannot choose...
...he ceases to be a man.
I don't understand about
the whys and wherefores, Father.
I only know I want to be good.
Be patient, my son.
Put your trust in the Lord.
Instruct Thy Son
and He shall refresh thee...
...and shall give delight
to thy soul.
Amen.
- Mister!
- All present and correct, sir!
Right!
All present and correct, sir!
Prisoners, halt!
Now pay attention!
I want you in two lines...
...up against that wall,
facing this way.
Go on, move!
Hurry up!
Stop talking!
Prisoners ready
for inspection, sir!
How many to a cell?
Four in this block, sir.
Cram criminals together
and what do you get?
Concentrated criminality.
Crime in the midst of punishment.
I agree, sir. We need
larger prisons, more money.
Not a chance, my dear fellow.
The government can't be
concerned any longer...
...with outmoded
penalogical theories.
Soon we may need all prison
space for political offenders.
Common criminals are best dealt
with on a purely curative basis.
Kill the criminal reflex,
that's all.
Full implementation
in a year's time.
Punishment means nothing to them.
They enjoy their
so-called punishment.
You're absolutely right, sir.
Shut your bleeding hole!
Who said that?
I did, sir.