I'm requesting--
Captain, I'd like to request
that it be me who's the attorney--
That it be myself who’s assigned.
No, I'd like to request
that it be I who am assigned--
'That it be I who am assigned'?
That's good.
That's confidence-inspiring.
Good grammar there.
Captain, I'd like to request...
that I be the attorney assigned.
I'm Lieutenant Commander Galloway
here to see Captain West.
Go right in, Commander.
They're expecting you.
Thank you.
-Jo, come on in.
- Thank you, sir.
Captain West,
this is Lieutenant Commander Galloway.
-Jo, you know Commander Lawrence.
- Yes, sir.
Captain, I appreciate
you seeing me on such short notice.
- Would you like to sit down?
- I'm fine, sir.
- Have a seat.
- Okay.
I understand we had some trouble
over the weekend down in Cuba?
Yes, sir.
This past Friday, two Marines--
a Lance Corporal Harold Dawson
and a Private Louden Downey--
entered the barracks room of a P.F.C.
William Santiago and assaulted him.
Santiago died at the base hospital
approximately an hour later.
The N.I.S. Agent who took
Dawson and Downey's statements...
maintains they were trying
to prevent Santiago...
from naming Dawson
in a fence line shooting incident.
They're scheduled to have a hearing
down in Cuba this afternoon at 1600.
- What's the problem?
- Dawson and Downey...
are both recruiting poster Marines,
and Santiago was known to be a screw-up.
I was thinking it sounded an awful lot
like a Code Red.
Christ.
Sir, I'd like to have them moved
up to Washington and assigned counsel--
someone who can really
look into this--
someone who possesses
not only the legal skill...
but a familiarity
with the inner workings of the military.
In short, Captain,
I'd like to suggest that...
I be the one who that--
that it be me who is assigned
to represent them...
myself.
Commander Galloway, why don’t you
get yourself a cup of coffee?
Thank you, sir. I'm fine.
I'd like you to leave the room so
we can talk about you behind your back.
Certainly, sir.
I thought this Code Red shit
wasn't going on anymore.
With the Marines at Gitmo, who knows
what the hell goes on down there?
We better find out
before the rest of the world does.
Damn thing could get messy.
All right,
what about this Commander Galloway?
She's been working a desk
in Internal Affairs...
for a little over a year now.
- Before that?
- Disposed of three cases in two years.
Three cases in two years?
Who's she handling, the Rosenberg’s?
- She's not cut out for litigation.
- She's a hell of a investigator.
In Internal Affairs she can crawl up
a lawyer's ass with the best of them.
- But when it comes to trial work--
- I know. All passion, no street smarts.
Bring her back in.
Commander, we're gonna have the
defendants moved up here in the morning.
- Thank you, sir.
- Division will assign them counsel.
-But not me.
-From what I get from your colleagues...
you're much too valuable in your
present assignment to be wasted...
in what I'm sure will boil down
to a five-minute plea bargain...
and a week's worth of paperwork.
Sir, I think there might be
more involved than that.
Don't worry about it.
I promise you Division will assign
the right man for the job.
All right. Let's go.
Let's get two.
- Sorry.
- Nothing to be sorry about, Sherby.
You just look the ball
into your glove.
Shooting two.
- Sorry.
- You gotta trust me, Sherby.
Keep your eyes open, your chances of
catching it increase by a factor often.
- Kaffee.
- Let's try it again.
Dave, you seem distraught.
We were supposed to meet 15 minutes ago
about the McDermott case.
You're stalling on this thing.
Now we either do it now...
or, no kidding, Kaffee, I'm gonna
hang your boy from a fucking yardarm!
Yardarm? Sherby, does the Navy
still hang people from yardarms?
I don't think so.
Dave, Sherby doesn't think the Navy
hangs people from yardarms anymore.
I'm gonna charge him with possession
and being under the influence on duty.
You plead guilty, I'll recommend 30 days
in the brig with loss frank and pay.
It was oregano, Dave.
It was $10 worth of oregano.
Yeah, well, your client thought
it was marijuana.
My client's a moron.
That's not against the law.
Kaffee, I got people to answer to
just like you do. I'm gonna charge him.
With what,
possession of a condiment?
- Kaffee.
- I tried to help you out of this...
but if you ask for jail time,
I'm gonna file a motion to dismiss.
- You won't get it.
- I will get it.
And if the M.T.D. is denied,
I'll file a motion...
seeking to obtain
an evidentiary ruling in advance.
And after that, I'm gonna file
against pretrial confinement.
And you're gonna spend the next three
months going blind on paperwork...
because a signalman second-class bought
and smoked a dime bag of oregano.
Let's go! Let's get two!
B misdemeanor,
20 days in the brig.
C misdemeanor,
15 days restricted duty.
I don't know why
I'm agreeing to this.
'Cause you have wisdom
beyond your years.
Morning.
Morning, Captain.
How's the baby, Sam?
I think she's getting ready
to say her first word any day now.
How can you tell?
She just looks
like she has something to say.
Excuse me.
I'm sorry I'm late.
It's all right, Danny.
I know you don't have a good excuse...
so I won't force you
to come up with a bad one.
- Thank you, sir.
- This first one's for you.
Seems you're moving up
in the world.
Been requested by Division.
Requested to do what?
Guantanamo Bay, Cuba.
A Marine corporal named Dawson illegally
fires a round from his weapon...
over the fence line
and into Cuban territory.
- What's a fence line?
- Sam.
A big wall separating the good guys
from the bad guys.
- Teacher's pet.
- P.F.C. William Santiago...
threatens to rat on Dawson
to Naval Investigative Service.
Dawson and another member
of his squad...
P.F.C. Louden Downey,
go into Santiago's room...
tie him up,
stuff a rag down his throat...
and an hour later, Santiago's dead.
Attending physician says the rag
was treated with some kind of toxin.
They poisoned it?
- Not according to them.
- What did they say?
Not much.
They're being flown up here tomorrow...
and on Wednesday at 0600, you'll catch
a transport down to Cuba for the day...
to find out what you can.
Meantime, go and see
Lieutenant Commander Joanne Galloway...
with Internal Affairs.
Any questions?
Uh, the flight to Cuba--
Was that 0600 in the morning, sir?
Seems important to Division
that this one be handled by the book.
So I'm assigning co-counsel.
Any volunteers?
I got a stack of papers on my desk
about a mile high.
- Work with Kaffee on this.
- Doing what?
Kaffee will have this done
in about four days.
Doing various administrative things.
Backup, whatever.
In other words, I have
no responsibilities here whatsoever.
Right.
My kind of case.
Okay, but I've got to have
that report by Wednesday.
- Hi.
- Hold on. Hi.
Daniel Kaffee.
I was told to me with, uh--
Lieutenant Commander Galloway.
About a briefing?
I'll call you back.
You're the attorney Division assigned?
I'm lead counsel.
This is Sam Weinberg.
I have no responsibilities here
whatsoever.
Come in, please. Have a seat.
Lieutenant, how long
have you been in the Navy?
Going on nine months now.
And how long have you been
out of law school?
A little over a year.
I see.
Have I done something wrong?
It’s just that when I petition Division
to have counsel assigned...
I was hoping I'd be taken seriously.
No offense taken,
in case you were wondering.
Commander,
Lieutenant Kaffee is generally...
considered the best litigator
in our office.
He's successfully plea-bargained
44 cases in nine months.
One more,
I get a set of steak knives.
Have you ever been in a courtroom?
I once had
my driver's license suspended.
Commander, from what I understand,
if this thing goes to court...
they won’t need a lawyer,
they'll need a priest.
No, they'll need a lawyer.
Dawson's family's been contacted.
Downey's closest living relative
is Ginny Miller, his aunt.
She hasn't been contacted yet.
Would you like me to take care of that?
If you feel like it.
One of the people
you'll be seeing down there...
is the barracks C.O.,
Colonel Nathan Jessup.
I assume you’ve heard of him.
Who hasn't?
He's been in the papers lately.
He's expected to be appointed...
director of operations
of National Security Council.
- Really?
- These are the letters...
that Santiago wrote
in his eight months at Gitmo.
- That's Guantanamo Bay.
- I knew that one.
He wrote to the fleet commander
to the commandant of the Marine Corps.
Even his senator. He wanted
to be transferred off the base.
No one was listening.
Are you with me?
Yeah.
Finally, he wrote
to the Naval Investigative Service...
where he offered information about
Corporal Dawson's fence line shooting...
in exchange for a transfer.
Right. Is that all?
Lieutenant,
this letter makes it look like...
your client had a motive
to kill Santiago.
Got you.
And Santiago is who?
The victim.
Write that down.
Am I correct to assume these letters...
don't paint a flattering picture
of Marine Corps life at Guantanamo Bay?
- Yes, among--
- Am I further right in assuming...
investigation of this incident might
embarrass the Security Council guy?
- Colonel Jessup.
- Twelve years.
Sorry?
I'll get them to drop the conspiracy
and conduct unbecoming.
Twelve years.
You haven't talked to a witness
or looked at a piece of paper.
Pretty impressive, huh?
You're gonna have
to go deeper than that.
Do you have some sort of jurisdiction
here that I should know about?
My job is to make sure
that you do your job.
I'm special counsel
for Internal Affairs...
so my jurisdiction’s pretty much
in your face.
Read the letters. I'll expect
your report when you return from Cuba.
- Sure.
- You're dismissed.
I always forget that part.
He's a little preoccupied.
Team's playing Bethesda Medical
next week.
Tell your friend
not to get cute down there.
The Marines in Guantanamo
are fanatical.
About what?
About being Marines.
Dear sir...
my name is P.F. C. William T. Santiago.
I'm a Marine stationed
at Marine barracks...
Rifle Security Company Windward,
Second Platoon Bravo.
I'm writing to inform you of my problems
with my unit here in Cuba...
and to ask for your help.
I've fallen out on runs before
for several reasons...
such as feeling dizzy or nauseated.
Buton May 18, I'd fallen back
about20 or30yards...
going down a rocky unstable hill.
My sergeant grabbed me
and pushed me down the hill.
Then Isawall black, and the last thing
I remembered was hitting the deck.
I was brought to the hospital where
I was told I just had heat exhaustion.
I ask you to help me.
Please, sir. I just need
to be transferred out of R.S. C.
Sincerely,
P.F. C. William T. Santiago...
U.S. Marine Corps.
P.S. In exchange for my transfer
off the base...
I'm willing to provide you
with information about--
'The illegal fence line shooting
that occurred the night of August 2.'
Who the fuck
is P.F.C. William T. Santiago?
Private Santiago is a member
of Second Platoon Bravo, sir.
Yeah. Well, apparently he's not
very happy down here in Shangri-la...
because he's written letters
to everybody but Santa Claus...
asking for a transfer.
And now he's telling tales
about a fence line shooting.
Matthew?
I'm appalled, sir.
You're appalled.
This kid broke the chain of command
and ratted on a member of his unit...
to say nothing of the fact
that he is a U.S. Marine...
and it would appear he can't run
from here to there...
without collapsing
from heat exhaustion.
What the fuck is going on
in Bravo Company, Matthew?
Colonel, I think it would be better
to hold this discussion in private.
That won't be necessary, Colonel.
I can handle the situation, sir.
The same way you handled Curtis Bell?
Don't interrupt me, Lieutenant!
- I'm still your superior officer.
- And I'm yours, Matthew.
I want to know
what we're going to do about this.
I think Santiago should be transferred
off the base immediately.
He's that bad, huh?
Not only that. But word
of this letter is bound to get out.
He's gonna get his ass whipped.
Hmm. Transfer Santiago.
Yes. I'm sure you’re right.
I'm sure that's the thing to do.
Wait. I've got a better idea.
Let's transfer the whole squad
off the base.
Let's-- On second thought, Windward--
Let's transfer the whole
Windward Division off the base.
John, go on out there
and get those boys down off the fence.
They're packing their bags. Tom.
- Sir.
- Get me the president on the phone.
We're surrendering
our position in Cuba.
- Yes, sir.
- Wait a minute, Tom.
Don't get the president just yet.
Maybe we should
consider this for a second.
- Dismissed, Tom.
- Yes, sir.
Maybe-- and I'm just
spit-balling here--
Maybe we have a responsibility
as officers to train Santiago.
Maybe we as officers
have a responsibility to this country...
to see that the men and women
charged with its security...
are trained professionals.
Yes, I'm certain
that I read that somewhere once.
And now I'm thinking,
Colonel Markinson...
that your suggestion
of transferring Santiago...
while expeditious
and certainly painless...
might not be,
in a manner of speaking...
the American way.
Santiago stays where he is.
We're gonna train the lad.
John, you're in charge.
Santiago doesn't make 4-6-4-6...
on his next proficiency
and conduct report...
I'm going to blame you.
- Then I'm going to kill you.
- Yes, sir.
I think that's a mistake, Colonel.
Matthew, I think I will
have that word in private with you now.
John, that's all. Why don't we meet
at the 'O' club and have lunch...
and we'll talk about the training
of young William?
I'd be delighted to hear any
suggestions that you might have, sir.
- Dismissed.
- Yes, sir.
Matthew, sit down. Please.
What do you think of Kendrick?
My opinion of him has nothing to do--
I think he's pretty much
of a weasel myself...
but he's an awfully good officer.
And in the end, we see eye-to-eye on
the best way to run a Marine Corps unit.
We're in the business
of saving lives, Matthew.
That is a responsibility
that we have to take pretty seriously.
And I believe that taking a Marine
who is not quite up to the job...
and shipping him off
to another assignment...
puts lives in danger.
Sit down, Matthew.
We go back a while.
We went to the Academy together.
We were commissioned together.
We did our tours in Vietnam together.
But I've been promoted
up through the chain...
with greater speed and success
than you have.
Now, if that’s a source of tension...
or embarrassment for you...
I don't give a shit.
We're in the business of saving lives,
Lieutenant Colonel Markinson.
Don't ever question my orders
in front of another officer.
All the paperwork's in order.
- Step over there.
- Yes, sir.
Hal, is this Washington, D.C.?
All right. Let's move.
Yes, sir.
- Got all of that one.
- Excuse me.
I wanted to talk to you about
Corporal Dawson and Private Downey.
- Say again?
- Dawson and Downey.
Those names sound like
they should mean something to me--
Dawson, Downey--your clients.
The Cuba thing. Yes!
Dawson and Downey. Right.
I've done something wrong again,
haven't I?
I was just wondering
why two guys have been locked up...
since this morning while their lawyer's
outside hitting a ball.
We need the practice.
That wasn't funny.
It was a little funny.
Would you be very insulted
if I recommended to your supervisor...
that he assign different counsel?
- Why?
- I don't think you’re fit to handle it.
You don't even know me.
Ordinarily, it takes someone hours...
to discover I'm not fit
to handle a defense.
Oh, come on.
That was damn funny.
You're wrong.
I do know you.
Daniel Alistair Kaffee,
born June 8, 1964...
at Boston Mercy Hospital.
Your father's Lionel Kaffee...
former Navy judge advocate and
attorney general of the United States.
Died 1985.
You went to Harvard law.
Then you joined the Navy...
probably because that's
what your father wanted you to do.
And now you're just treading water
for three years in the JAG Corps.
Just laying low till
you can get out and get a real job.
If that’s the situation, that's fine.
I won't tell anyone.
But it's my feeling that
if this case is handled in the same...
fast-food, slick-ass,
Persian bazaar manner...
with which you seem
to handle everything else...
then something's gonna get missed.
And I wouldn't be doing my job
if allowed Dawson and Downey...
to spend any more time in prison
than absolutely necessary...
because their attorney had predetermined
the path of least resistance.
Wow.
I'm sexually aroused, Commander.
I don't think
your clients murdered anyone.
What are you basing this on?
There was no intent.
The doctor's report says
Santiago died of asphyxiation...
brought on by acute lactic acidosis...
and that the nature of the acidosis
strongly suggests poison.
I don't know what any of that means,
but it sounds pretty bad.
Santiago died at 1:00 a.m.
At 3:00, the doctor wasn’t able
to determine the cause of death.
Two hours later,
he said it was poison.
Oh, now I see what you’re saying.
It had to be Professor Plum
in the library with a candlestick.
- I'm gonna talk to your supervisor.
- Okay.
Go straight up Pennsylvania Avenue.
It's the big white house
with the pillars in front.
- Thank you.
- I don't think you’ll have much luck.
I was assigned by Division.
Somebody over there thinks
I'm a pretty good lawyer.
So while I appreciate your interest
and admire your enthusiasm...
I think I can handle things myself.
You know what a Code Red is?
What a pity.
- Morning, sir.
- Morning.
Officer on deck!
Sir, Lance Corporal
Harold W. Dawson, sir!
Rifle Security Company Windward,
Second Platoon Bravo.
Someone hasn't been working
and playing well with others, Harold.
Sir, yes, sir!
Sir, P.F.C. Louden Downey, sir!
I'm Daniel Kaffee.
This is Sam Weinberg.
Sit down.
- This your signature?
- Yes, sir.
You don't have to call me 'sir.'
Is this your signature?
Sir, yes, sir.
You certainly don't need
to do it twice in one sentence.
- What's a Code Red?
- It is a disciplinary engagement.
What's that mean?
A Marine falls out of line, it's up to
the men in his unit to get him on track.
- What's a garden variety Code Red?
- Sir?
Harold, you say, 'sir,' and
I turn around and look for my father.
Danny, Daniel, Kaffee.
Garden variety. Typical.
What's basic Code Red?
Sir, a Marine refuses to bathe
on a regular basis...
the men in his squad
will give him a G.I. shower.
What's that?
Scrub brushes,
Brillo pads, steel wool.
Beautiful.
Was the attack on Santiago
a Code Red?
Yes, sir.
Does he ever talk?
Sir, P.F.C. Downey will answer
any direct questions you ask him.
Swell.
Private Downey, the rag
you stuffed in Santiago's mouth--
- Was there poison on it?
- No, sir.
Silver polish,
turpentine, antifreeze?
No, sir. We were just
gonna shave his head, sir.
When all of the sudden--
We saw blood dripping
down his mouth...
and we pulled the tape off and
there was blood all down his face, sir.
That's when Lance Corporal Dawson
called the ambulance.
Did anyone see you call
the ambulance?
No, sir.
Were you there
when the ambulance got there?
Yes, sir. That's when
we were taken under arrest.
The night of August 2, did you fire
a shot across the fence line into Cuba?
- Yes, sir.
- Why?
- My mirror engaged, sir.
- His mirror?
Every American sentry post has
a Cuban counterpart, called 'mirrors.'
Lance Corporal's claiming that
his mirror was about to fire at him.
Santiago's letter to the N.I.S....
said you fired illegally.
He's saying that the guy, the mirror--
He never made a move.
You see what I'm getting at?
If Santiago didn't have anything on you,
then why did you give him a Code Red?
'Cause he broke
the chain of command, sir.
- He what?
- He went outside of his unit, sir.
If he had a problem,
he should have spoken to me, sir.
- Then his sergeant, then commander--
- Yeah. All right.
Did you assault Santiago
with the intent of killing him?
- No, sir.
- What was your intent?
- To train him, sir.
- Train him to do what?
Train him to think of his unit
before himself-- to respect the code.
What's the code?
Unit, Corps, God, Country.
I beg your pardon?
Unit, Corps, God, Country, sir.
The government
of the United States...
wants to charge you two
with murder...
and you want me
to go to the prosecutor...
with ' Unit, Corps, God, Country'?
That's our code, sir.
It's your code.
We'll be back.
You guys need anything-- books,
papers, cigarettes, ham sandwich?
Sir, no, thank you, sir.
Harold, I think there's a concept
you better start warming up to.
Sir?
I'm the only friend you've got.
Smiling Jack Ross.
- Welcome to the big time.
- You think so?
Let's hope, for Dawson and Downey, you
practice law better than play softball.
Unfortunately for those two, I don't
do anything better than play softball.
- I'm out of here, Janelle.
- Bye.
- See you when I get back from Cuba.
- Say hi to Castro for me.
Will do.
What are we looking at?
They plead guilty, we drop
the conspiracy and conduct unbecoming.
- Twenty years. They're home in half.
- I want 12.
- Can't do it.
- They called the ambulance.
I don't care if they called
the Avon lady. They killed a Marine.
The rag was tested for poison.
The autopsy, lab reports.
They say the same thing:
maybe, maybe not.
Chief of Internal Medicine
at the Guantanamo Bay Naval Hospital...
says he's sure.
What do you know about Code Reds?
Oh, man.
- We off the record?
- Tell me.
I'm gonna give you the 12 years.
Before you go getting yourself into
trouble tomorrow, you should know...
the platoon commander,
Lieutenant Jonathan Kendrick...
held a meeting with the men
and specifically...
told them not to touch Santiago.
- We still playing hoops tomorrow night?
- Do we have a deal?
I'll talk to you when I get back.
- Hi there.
- Any luck getting me replaced?
Is there anyone in this command you
don't either drink or play ball with?
- Commander--
- Listen. I came to make peace.
Got off on the wrong foot.
What do you say? Friends?
I brought Downey some comic books
he was asking for.
The kid, Kaffee,
I swear he doesn't know where he is.
- Doesn't even know why he's arrested.
- Commander.
- You can call me Joanne.
-Joanne.
- OrJo.
- Yes.
Jo, if you ever speak to a client
of mine again without my permission...
I'll have you disbarred.
- Friends?
- I had authorization.
- From where?
- Downey's closest living relative.
Ginny Miller.
His aunt on his mother's side.
You got authorization
from Aunt Ginny?
I gave her a call
like you asked.
Very nice woman.
We spoke for about an hour.
You got authorization
from Aunt Ginny.
Perfectly within my province.
Does Aunt Ginny have a barn?
We could hold the trial there.
I can sew the costumes.
Maybe his Uncle Goober can be the judge.
I'm going to Cuba with you tomorrow.
And the hits just keep on coming.
- How's it going, Luther?
- Another day, another dollar, captain.
- You gotta play them as they lay.
- What goes around comes around.
- Can't beat 'em, join 'em.
- At least I got my health.
Well, then you got everything.
See you tomorrow, Luther.
Not if see you first.
Now don't forget.
When Sally gets back, you're my witness.
The baby spoke.
My daughter said a word.
Your daughter made a sound, Sam.
I'm not sure it was a word.
Come on, now.
It was definitely a word.
You heard her. The girl sat here,
pointed and said, ' Pa.'
She did. She said, ' Pa.'
She was pointing at a mailbox, Sam.
That's right, pointing as into say,
' Pa, look. A mailbox.'
Jack Ross came to see me today.
He offered me the 12 years.
- Oh, that's what you wanted, right?
- I know, I know.
I mean, I guess I'll take it.
I'll take it.
- So--
- It took about 45 seconds.
He barely put up a fight.
Danny, take the 12 years.
It's a gift.
You don't believe their story,
do you?
You think they ought to go to jail
for the rest of their lives.
I believe every word of their story...
and I think they ought to go to jail
for the rest of their lives.
- See you tomorrow.
- Okay.
Don't forget to wear the whites.
Very hot down there.
I don't like the whites.
Nobody likes the whites,
but we're going to Cuba.
- You got Dramamine?
- Dramamine keeps you cool?
No, Dramamine keeps you from
throwing up. You get sick when you fly.
I get sick when I fly because I'm afraid
of crashing into a large mountain.
I don't think Dramamine will help.
I got some oregano.
I hear that works pretty good.
You know, Ross said the strangest thing
to me right before I left.
He said the platoon commander
Lieutenant Jonathan Kendrick...
had a meeting with the men
and told them not to touch Santiago.
So?
I never mentioned Kendrick.
I don't even know who he is.
Ah, what the hell.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Lieutenants Kaffee and Weinberg,
Commander Galloway.
I'm Corporal Barnes. I'm to escort you
to the windward side of the base.
- Thank you.
- I got some camouflage jackets here.
- I suggest you both put them on.
- Camouflage jackets?
Yes, sir. We'll be riding
pretty close to the fence line.
The Cubans see
an officer wearing white...
they think it might be someone
they want to take a shot at.
Good call, Sam.
We'll just hop on the ferry.
We'll be there in no time.
- Wait. We gotta take a boat?
- Yes, sir.
- To get to the other side of the bay.
- Nobody said anything about a boat.
- Is there a problem, sir?
- No, no problem.
Just not crazy about boats.
Jesus Christ, Kaffee,
you're in the Navy, for crying out loud.
- Nobody likes her very much.
- Yes, sir!
Nathan Jessup. Come on in.
Thank you, sir. Daniel Kaffee.
I'm the attorney for Dawson and Downey.
This is
Lieutenant Commander Joanne Galloway.
- Pleasure meeting you, Commander.
- Observing and evaluating, sir.
Lieutenant Sam Weinberg.
He'll be assisting.
- Sir.
- This is my X.O., Colonel Markinson...
and platoon leader Lieutenant Kendrick.
I've asked them to join us.
Sit down, please.
- Lieutenant Kaffee.
- Colonel Markinson.
I had the pleasure
of meeting your father once.
I was a teenager.
He spoke at my high school.
Lionel Kaffee?
- Yes, sir.
- Well, what do you know?
John, this man's dad once made a lot of
enemies down in your neck of the woods.
Jefferson v. Madison County
School District.
Folks down there said a black girl
couldn't go to an all-white school.
Lionel Kaffee said,
'Well, we'll just see about that.'
How the hell is your dad, Danny?
He passed away seven years ago, sir.
Don't I feel like the fuckin' asshole.
Not at all.
Well, what can we do for you, Danny?
Uh, not much, sir.
This is really a formality
more than anything else.
JAG Corps insists that we interview
all the relevant witnesses.
The JAG Corps can be demanding
that way.
John will take you out
and show you what you want to see.
After that we can all
hook up for lunch.
- How does that sound? Good.
- Fine, sir.
I understand you had a meeting
with your men that afternoon.
- Yes, I did.
- What did you guys talk about?
I told the men
that we had an informer among us...
and that despite any desire
they might have to seek retribution...
Private Santiago
was not to be harmed in anyway.
- What time was that meeting?
- 1600.
That's 4:00.
Sam, we should make sure
somebody gets this to his parents.
- We don't need it anymore.
- Right.
Lieutenant Kendrick,
may I call you John?
No, you may not.
Have I done something to offend you?
No, I like all you Navy boys.
Every time we gotta go someplace to
fight, you fellas always give us a ride.
Lieutenant Kendrick,
do you think Santiago was murdered?
Commander, I believe in God
and His Son Jesus Christ.
And because I do, I can say this:
Private Santiago is dead,
and that is a tragedy.
But he is dead
because he had no code.
He is dead because he had no honor,
and God was watching.
How do you feel about that theory?
Sounds good. Let's move on.
Are you planning
on doing any investigating...
or are you just gonna take
the guided tour?
I'm pacing myself.
They were running around
for three hours...
looking for anything white
they could wave in the air.
Some of these people surrendered
to a crew from CNN.
Well, walk softly and carry
an armored tank division, I always say.
- That was delicious. Thank you.
- My pleasure, sir.
Colonel, I do have to ask you a couple
of questions about September 6.
Shoot.
On the morning of the sixth,
you were contacted by an N.I.S. agent...
who said that Santiago tipped him off
to an illegal fence line shooting.
- Yes.
- Santiago would reveal the person...
- in exchange for a transfer.
- Yes.
If you feel there are any details
that I'm missing...
you should feel free to speak up.
Thank you.
Now, at this point you called
Lieutenant Colonel Markinson...
and Lieutenant Kendrick
into your office.
- Is that right?
- Yes.
What happened?
We agreed that, for his own safety,
Santiago should be transferred off base.
Santiago was set to be transferred.
On the first available flight
to the States...
0600 the next morning.
Five hours too late,
as it turned out.
Yeah.
All right. That's all I have.
Thanks very much for your time.
Corporal's waiting with the Jeep.
He'll take you back to the flight line.
- Thank you, sir.
- Wait. I've got some questions.
- No, you don't.
- Yes, I do.
- On the morning that Santiago died...
did you meet with Dr. Stone
between 3:00 and 5:00?
Of course I met with the doctor.
One of my men was dead.
See? The man was dead. Let's go.
I'm just wondering if you’ve ever heard
the term 'Code Red.'
I've heard the term, yes.
This past February,
you received a cautionary memo...
from the commander-in-chief
of the Atlantic fleet...
warning that the practice
of enlisted men...
disciplining their own
wasn't to be condoned by officers.
Well, I submit to you
that whoever wrote that memo...
has never faced the working end...
of a Soviet-made
Cuban AK-47 assault rifle.
However, the directive
having come from the commander...
I gave it its due attention.
- What is your point, Jo?
- She has no point.
She often has no point.
It's part of her charm.
- We're out of here. Thank you.
- I think Code Reds still go on here.
- Do Code Reds still happen here?
-Jo, he doesn't need to answer that.
- Yes, he does.
- No, he really doesn't.
Yeah, he really does.
You know, it just hit me.
She outranks you, Danny.
- Yes, sir.
- I want to tell you something.
And listen up,
'cause I really mean this.
You're the luckiest man
in the world.
There is nothing on this earth sexier--
believe me, gentlemen--
than a woman that
you have to salute in the morning.
Promote 'em all, I say,
'cause this is true:
If you haven't gotten a blowjob
from a superior officer...
well, you’re just letting
the best in life pass you by.
Colonel, the practice of Code Reds
is still condoned by officers--
My problem is that I'm a colonel,
so I'll go on taking cold showers...
until they elect some gal president.
I need an answer to my question, sir.
Take caution in your tone, Commander.
I'm a fair guy, but this fucking heat
is making me absolutely crazy.
You want to ask me about Code Reds?
On the record...
I tell you I discourage
the practice...
in accordance
with the commander's directive.
Off the record,
I tell you it is an invaluable part...
of close-infantry training.
And if it happens to go on
without my knowledge, so be it.
I run my unit how I run my unit.
You want to investigate me,
roll the dice and take your chances.
I eat breakfast 300 yards from
4,000 Cubans who are trained to kill me.
So don't think for one second that
you can come down here...
flash a badge...
and make me nervous.
Let's go.
Colonel, I'll just need a copy
of Santiago’s transfer order.
What's that?
Santiago's transfer order. You guys
have paperwork on that kind of thing.
I just need it for the file.
- For the file.
- Yeah.
Of course you can have a copy
of the transfer order for the file.
- I'm here to help in anyway I can.
- Thank you.
You believe that, don’t you, Danny, that
I'm here to help you in anyway I can?
Of course.
Corporal will take you by personnel
on your way out to the flight line...
and you can have
all the transfer orders that you want.
- Let's go.
- But you have to ask me nicely.
I beg your pardon?
You have to ask me nicely.
You see, Danny, I can deal with
the bullets and the bombs and the blood.
I don't want money,
and I don't want medals.
What I do want is for you to stand there
in that faggoty white uniform...
and with your Harvard mouth
extend me some fucking courtesy.
You gotta ask me nicely.
Colonel Jessup,
if it’s not too much trouble...
I'd like a copy
of the transfer order, sir.
No problem.
In the seventh. San Diego leads.
Braves try to comeback.
Runners don’t go.
Hard drive, right field.
We're gonna have a tied ballgame.
It's on its way,
and it is now 10 to 10.
And I don't believe it.
- Who is it?
- It's me.
I really missed you. I was just saying
to myself it’s been almost three hours.
- Markinson's disappeared.
- What?
Colonel Markinson's gone U.A. --
unauthorized absence.
I know what it means.
When?
This afternoon.
Sometime after we left.
- I'll try to find him in the morning.
- I've already tried.
You tried?
Joanne, you're coming dangerously close
to the textbook definition...
of interfering
with a government investigation.
I'm Louden Downey's attorney.
Aunt Ginny. She says she feels
like she's known me for years.
So I suggested that she might feel
more comfortable...
if were directly involved
with the case.
She had Louden sign the papers
about an hour ago.
I suppose
it's way too much to hope...
that you’re making this up
just to bother me.
Don't worry. I'm not gonna
make a motion for separation.
- You're still lead counsel.
- Splendid.
I think Kendrick ordered the Code Red,
and so do you.
Let's go.
Officer on deck!
- Did Kendrick order the Code Red?
- Sir?
Don't say 'Sir' like I just asked you
if you cleaned the latrine.
You heard what I said. Did
Lieutenant Kendrick order you guys...
to give Santiago a Code Red?
Yes, sir.
- Did he?
- Yes, sir.
You mind telling me
why you never mentioned this before?
-You didn't ask.
-That won't win you a place in my heart.
I get paid no matter
how much time you spend in jail.
Yes, sir. I know you do, sir.
- Fuck you, Harold!
- All right.
At ease.
- Let's sort this thing out.
- Shit!
There was a platoon meeting
on September 6 at 4:00 in the afternoon.
Lieutenant Kendrick says
that he gave strict instructions...
that nothing was to happen
to Santiago.
Now, is this true?
I want you to speak freely.
Ma'am, that's correct...
but then he dismissed the platoon
and we all went to our rooms.
And what happened then?
Lieutenant Kendrick came
to our room, ma'am.
When?
About five minutes after the meeting
broke, sir. About 1620.
And what happened then?
Lieutenant Kendrick ordered us
to give Santiago a Code Red.
Jack!
Hang on.
They were given an order.
-Jack, come on.
- Be right back.
- What are you doin', Jack?
- How long did you know about the order?
- I didn't. Who's this?
That's Jo Galloway, Downey's lawyer.
She's very pleased to meet you.
- What exactly are you accusing me of?
- How long did you know about the order?
He didn't, 'cause if he did
and hadn't told us...
he'd be violating about 14 articles
of the Code of Ethics.
He has enough to worry about...
God forbid our clients
decide to plead not guilty...
and testify for the record
that they were given an order.
Kendrick specifically told those men
not to touch Santiago.
That's right. And then he went
into Dawson and Downey's room...
and specifically told them
to give him a Code Red.
- Kendrick said different. Have proof?
- He's lying. I have the defendants.
And I have 23 Marines
who aren't accused of murder...
and a lieutenant
with four letters of commendation.
- Why did Markinson go U.A.?
- We'll never know.
- You don't think I could subpoena him?
- You can try, but you won't find him.
You know what he did for the first 17
of his 26 years in the Corps?
Counterintelligence. Markinson's gone.
There is no Markinson.
Look, Danny.
Jessup's star is on the rise.
Division will give me
a lot of room on this one...
to spare Jessup
and the Corps any embarrassment.
How much?
Involuntary manslaughter,
two years, they're home in six months.
No deal. We're going to court.
- No, you're not.
- Why not?
'Cause you’ll lose,
and Danny knows it.
If we do go to court,
I'm gonna have to go all the way.
They're gonna be charged
with a whole truckload--
murder, conspiracy,
conduct unbecoming.
Even though he's got me by the balls
out here, Danny knows...
that in a courtroom,
he loses this case.
Danny is an awfully talented lawyer.
He's not about to see
his clients go to jail for life...
when he knows
they can be home in six months.
That's the end of this negotiation.
I'll see you tomorrow morning
at the arraignment.
All right. Here's the story.
The government's offering
involuntary manslaughter, two years.
Be home in six months.
Wow, Kaffee!
You're the greatest lawyer in the world!
Ooh, how can we ever thank you?
Fellas, you hear what I just said?
You're going home in six months.
I'm afraid we can't do that, sir.
- Do what?
- Make a deal, sir.
What are you talking about?
We did nothing wrong, sir.
We did our job...
and if that has consequences,
then I'll accept them.
But I won't say that I'm guilty, sir.
Did you--
Did she put you up to this?
- We have a code, sir.
- Oh, well, zip-a-dee-doo-dah!
You and your code plead not guilty.
You'll be in jail the rest of your life.
Do what I'm telling you,
you'll be home in six months.
Do it, Harold.
Six months.
It's nothing.
It's a hockey season.
- Permission to--
- Speak!
Jesus!
- What do we do then, sir?
- When?
After six months, we'll be
dishonorably discharged, right, sir?
Probably.
Well, what do we do then, sir?
We joined the Marines because we wanted
to live our lives by a certain code.
And we found it in the Corps.
Now you’re asking us to sign a piece
of paper that says we have no honor.
You're asking us
to say we’re not Marines.
If a court decides
that what we did was wrong...
then I'll accept
whatever punishment they give.
But I believe I was right, sir.
I believe I did my job...
and I will not dishonor myself,
my unit or the Corps...
so that I can go home
in six months...
sir.
Commander, I'd like to talk to Lance
Corporal Dawson alone for a minute.
Sergeant.
We're gonna go to another room.
- We'd like another holding room.
- All right, ma'am.
- It's gonna be okay.
- Sit down.
You don't like me very much, do you?
Forget it. Don't answer that.
It doesn't matter.
You know...
Downey worships you.
He's gonna do whatever you do.
Are you really gonna let this happen
to him because of a code, Harold?
- Do you think we were right?
- It doesn't matter--
- I think you’d lose.
You're such a coward.
I can't believe
they let you wear a uniform.
I'm not gonna feel responsible for this.
I did everything I could.
You're going to Leavenworth
for the better part of your life.
And you know what?
I don't give a shit.
What happened to saluting an officer
when he leaves the room?
Open it up.
I don't believe it.
Dawson's gonna go to jail
just to spite me.
Fine. If he wants to jump
off a cliff, that's his business.
I'm not gonna hold his hand on the way.
I want to get him a new lawyer. How?
Just make a motion tomorrow morning
at the arraignment.
The judge will ask you
if you want to enter a plea...
and you tell him that you want
to have new counsel assigned.
That's that.
One thing, though. When you ask
the judge for new counsel...
Danny, be sure and ask nicely.
- What do you want from me?
- I want you to let them be judged.
I want you to stand up
and make an argument.
An argument that didn't work
for Calley at My Lai.
for the Nazis at Nuremburg.
Oh, for Christ's sake, Sam.
Do you really think that's the same
as two teenage Marines...
executing a routine order they never
believed would result in harm?
These guys aren't the Nazis.
Don't look now, Danny,
but you’re making an argument.
Yeah, yeah. Tomorrow morning
I get them a new attorney.
Why are you so afraid
to be a lawyer?
Were Daddy's expectations
really that high?
Oh, please. Spare me
the psycho-babble father bullshit!
Dawson and Downeywill have their day
in court, but with another lawyer.
Another lawyer won’t be good enough.
They need you.
You know how to win. You know they have
a case, and you know how to win.
If you walk away from this now,
you've sealed their fate.
Their fate was sealed
the moment Santiago died.
- Do you believe they have a case?
- You and Dawson.
You both live
in the same dream world.
It doesn't matter what I believe.
It only matters what I can prove.
So, please, don't tell me
what I know and don't know!
I know the law!
You know nothing about the law.
You're a used car salesman, Daniel.
You're an ambulance chaser
with a rank.
You're nothing. Live with that.
So I told Duncan...
'If you want to take this to court
I'm gonna file nine discovery motions...
and you're gonna spend a year
going blind on paperwork...
because a 90-year-old man
misread the Delaware insurance code.'
- So what happened?
- He calls back 15 minutes later.
He says, ' Let's make a deal.'
All rise.
Where are we?
Docket number 411275VR-5.
The United States v.
Lance Corporal Harold W. Dawson...
and Private First Class Louden Downey.
The accused are charged with murder,
conspiracy to commit murder...
and conduct unbecoming
a United States Marine.
Does the defense wish to enter a plea?
Yeah.
They're not guilty.
Enter a plea of not guilty
for the accused.
We'll adjourn until 1000,
three weeks from today...
at which time this general
court-martial will reconvene.
Why does a lieutenant junior grade
with ninth months' experience...
and a track record for plea bargaining
get assigned a murder case?
Would it be so that it never sees
the inside of a courtroom?
We'll work out of my apartment
every night, 7:00.
Jo, pick up a carton of legal pads, half
a dozen boxes of red and black pens.
Sam, get a couple of desk lamps.
I need a preliminary medical profile.
Jo, we need all proficiency and conduct
reports on Dawson, Downey and Santiago.
The only thing I have to eat
is Yoo-hoo and Cocoa Puffs...
so if you want anything else,
bring it with you.
- Okay?
- Yeah.
So this is what
a courtroom looks like.
Were you able to speak
to your friend at the N.I.S.?
Yeah. She said if Markinson
doesn't want to be found...
we're not gonna find him.
She said I could be Markinson,
and you wouldn't know it.
Are you Markinson?
I'm not Markinson.
That's two down.
What?
I'm just wondering,
now that Joanne’s on this--
I'm just wondering
if you still need me.
- They were following orders.
- An illegal order.
Do you think they knew
it was an illegal order?
It doesn't matter what they knew.
Any decent person would have refused--
They're not permitted
to question orders.
Then what's the secret? Huh?
What are the magic words?
I give orders every day--
We have softball games
and marching bands.
They work at a place where you have to
wear camouflage or you might get shot!
I need you.
You're better at research than I am,
and you know how to prepare a witness.
I've got medical reports
and Chinese food. I say we eat first.
What?
You got any kung pao chicken?
This is our defense-- intent. No one
can prove there was poison on the rag.
Code Red-- they're common
and accepted in Guantanamo Bay.
The order-- A: Kendrick gave it,
B: They had to follow it.
- That's it.
- What about motive?
We're a little weak on motive.
They had one.
- That doesn't mean they're guilty.
- Relax.
We'll deal with the fence line shooting
when it comes up.
Let's start with intent. I don't
want to know what made Santiago die.
I just want to show it could've been
something other than poison.
Jo, talk to doctors. Find out everything
there is to know about lactic acidosis.
This is Lieutenant Commander Galloway
with the JAG Corps in Washington.
I've been trying to track down
a Lieutenant Colonel Matthew Markinson.
Doctor, was there any sign
of external damage?
No scrapes? No cuts?
Bruises? Broken bones?
- Was there any sign of violence?
- You mean, other than the dead body?
Shit, I walk into that
every goddamn time.
He ordered me and Lance Corporal Dawson
to give Willie a Code Red.
Answers still have to come
much faster.
This Iowa farm boy thing
will play for a while...
but in the end, it sounds
like he's searching for the truth.
He's right. From now on,
Willie is Private Santiago.
You start calling him Willie,
and all of a sudden he's a person...
who's got a mother
who's gonna miss him, okay?
They drew the court members
this afternoon.
Seven men, two women,
five Navy, four Marines.
All officers with line experience.
Neither of the women have children.
That's a bad break.
There’s nothing we can do.
My father always said a jury trial
is not just about the law.
It's about assigning blame.
Santiago's dead, and he shouldn't be.
These nine people are gonna insist
that someone be blamed for that.
Ross is handing them our clients.
We're gonna hand them Kendrick.
This is about a sales pitch.
It's gonna be won by the lawyers.
So remember, poker faces. Don’t flinch
in front of the court members.
Something doesn't go our way, don't hang
your head or shift in your seat.
Whatever happens, you have to look like
it's exactly what you knew would happen.
- If you pass me documents--
- Do it swiftly and don't look eager.
Don't wear that perfume in court.
Wrecks my concentration.
Really?
I was talking to Sam.
What time is it?
It's time to go home.
Try to get some sleep.
- Yeah.
- Give me a ride?
Sure.
You're a good man, Charlie Brown.
I'll see you in court, counselor.
- Danny, I--
- You don't have to say it.
We've had our differences.
I said some things I didn't mean.
You said some things you didn't mean,
but you’re happy I stuck with the case.
And if you’ve gained a certain respect
for me over the last three weeks...
of course, I'm happy about that.
But we don't have to make
a whole big deal out of it.
If you like me,
I won't make you say it.
I was just gonna tell you
to wear matching socks tomorrow.
Okay. Good tip.
We're ready.
Better believe it.
We're gonna get creamed.
- Lieutenant Kaffee?
- Yes?
You are gonna save our son,
aren’t you?
I'll do my best.
Danny, I'd like you to meet
Ginny Miller, Louden's aunt.
- You're Aunt Ginny?
- Uh-huh.
I'm sorry. I was expecting
someone older.
So was I.
Last chance.
I'll flip you for it.
- All rise.
- Too late.
All those having business
with this general court-martial...
stand forward
and you shall be heard.
Colonel Julius Alexander Randolph
is presiding.
Is the government prepared
to make an opening statement?
Yes, sir.
The facts of the case are these:
On midnight of September 6,
the accused entered the barracks room...
of their platoon mate,
P.F.C. William Santiago.
They woke him up,
tied his arms and legs with tape...
and forced a rag into his throat.
A few minutes later, a chemical reaction
called lactic acidosis...
caused his lungs to begin bleeding.
He drowned in his own blood...
and was pronounced dead
at 37 minutes past midnight.
These are the facts of the case,
and they are undisputed.
That's right.
The story I’ve just told you...
is the exact same story you’re gonna
hear from Lance Corporal Dawson...
and it's the exact same story
you're gonna hear from Private Downey.
Furthermore, the government
will also demonstrate...
that the accused
soaked the rag in poison...
and entered Santiago's room
with motive and intent to kill.
Now, Lieutenant Kaffee...
is gonna try and pull off
a little magic act here.
He's gonna try a little misdirection.
He's gonna astonish you
with stories of rituals...
and dazzle you
with official-sounding terms...
like 'Code Red.'
He might even try to cut into
a few officers for you.
He'll have no evidence, mind you, none,
but it's gonna be entertaining.
And when we get to the end,
all the magic in the world...
will not have been able to divert
your attention from the fact...
that Willie Santiago is dead
and Dawson and Downey killed him.
These are the facts of the case,
and they are undisputed.
Lieutenant Kaffee.
There was no poison on the rag,
and there was no intent to kill.
Any attempt to prove otherwise is futile
'cause it just ain't true.
When Dawson and Downey went
into Santiago's room that night...
it wasn't because of vengeance
or hatred.
It wasn't to kill or harm, and it wasn't
because they were looking for kicks.
It's because it was
what they were ordered to do.
Let me say that again.
It's because it was
what they were ordered to do.
Out in the real world
that means nothing...
and here at the Washington Navy Yard
it doesn't mean a whole lot more.
But if you’re a Marine assigned
to Rifle Security Company Windward...
Guantanamo Bay, Cuba,
and you're given an order...
you follow it
or you pack your bags.
Make no mistake about it.
Harold Dawson and Louden Downey
are sitting before you today...
because they did their job.
Is the government ready
to call its first witness?
If it please the court,
the government calls Mr. R.C. McGuire.
Mr. McGuire, would you
raise your right hand, please?
Do you solemnly swear that the testimony
you give this general court-martial...
will be the truth, the whole truth
and nothing but the truth?
- I do.
- Have a seat, please, sir.
Would you state your full name
and occupation, for the record?
Robert C. McGuire, Special Agent,
Naval Investigative Service.
Mr. McGuire, did your office receive
a letter from P.F.C. William Santiago...
on 3 September of this year?
- We did.
- What did that letter say?
That a member of Santiago’s unit
had fired his weapon over the fence line.
Was that Marine
identified in the letter?
No. I notified the barracks C.O.
Colonel Jessup...
that I would be coming down
to investigate.
And what did you find?
The shift reported only one sentry
returned his weapon to the switch...
with a round of ammunition missing.
- Who was that?
- Lance Corporal Harold Dawson.
Your witness.
Mr. McGuire, have you questioned Dawson
about the fence line shooting?
Yes. He claims to have been engaged
in some manner by the enemy.
- You don' believe him?
- It's not my place--
Lance Corporal Dawson's been charged
with a number of crimes.
Why wasn’t he charged with firing
at the enemy without cause?
There wasn't enough evidence
to support such a charge.
Thank you.
Mr. McGuire, I don't understand
what you mean when you say...
'There wasn't enough evidence
to support such a charge.'
You had William Santiago's letter.
Santiago was the only eyewitness.
I never had the chance to interview him,
so I don't know what he saw.
And now we'll never know,
will we, Mr. McGuire?
- No more questions.
- The witness is excused.
Corporal Carl Edward Hammaker,
Marine Barracks...
Rifle Security Company Windward,
Second Platoon Bravo.
Corporal, were you present at a meeting
that Lieutenant Kendrick held...
on the afternoon of September 6
with the members of the Second Platoon?
Yes, sir.
Would you tell the court
the substance of that meeting?
Lieutenant Kendrick told us
we had an informer in our group--
that Private Santiago had gone
outside the chain of command...
and reported to the N.I.S.
on a member of our platoon.
Did that make you mad?
You can tell the truth, Corporal.
- Did it make you mad?
- Yes, sir.
How mad?
Private Santiago betrayed a code
we believe in very deeply, sir.
- Were the other squad members angry?
- Object. Speculation.
- Were Dawson and Downey?
- Is the government counsel...
honestly asking the witness to testify
as to how my clients felt?
Sustained.
Corporal, did Lieutenant Kendrick
leave a standing order at that meeting?
- Yes, sir.
- What was it?
Well, it was clear that he didn't want
us taking matters into our own hands.
What was the order?
Sir, he said Santiago
wasn't to be touched.
Your witness.
Corporal Hammaker, were you
in Dawson and Downey's barracks...
five minutes after this meeting?
No, sir.
Thanks.
I have no more questions.
The witness is excused.
The government calls
Corporal Raymond Thomas.
I understand Captain Ross is planning
on calling all the other members...
of Rifle Security Company Windward
to testify.
In light of the defense Lieutenant
Kaffee is planning to mount...
the explicit instructions of a platoon
leader seems particularly relevant.
The defense is willing to concede
that all 22 witnesses...
will testify substantially
as Corporal Hammaker did...
if the government is willing to concede
that none of them...
were in Dawson and Downey's room
at 16:20 on September 6.
Captain?
The government will stipulate.
Then we'll adjourn for the day.
You can call your next witness tomorrow.
All rise.
I want to go over the doctor again.
- We're taking the right approach.
- We've been over this already.
Listen to me. 3:00-- Stone says
he doesn't know what killed Santiago.
Then he meets with Jessup,
and at 5:00 he says it was poison?
- The doctor's not telling the truth.
- Oh, that's a relief!.
I was afraid I wouldn't be able to use
the 'liar, liar, pants on fire' defense.
We can't prove coercion.
Let's go over what we have, okay?
Private Santiago was admitted
to the E.R. at0012...
and he was pronounced dead
at 0037.
Dr. Stone, what is lactic acidosis?
If the muscles and other cells
of the body burn sugar...
instead of oxygen,
lactic acid is produced.
That lactic acid is what caused
Santiago's lungs to bleed.
Normally, how long does it take
for the muscles and other cells...
to begin burning sugar
instead of oxygen?
Twenty to thirty minutes.
And what caused this process
to be sped up in Santiago's muscles?
An ingested poison of some kind.
Your Honor, we object at this point.
The witness is speculating.
Commander Stone is an expert
medical witness.
In this courtroom, his opinion
is not considered speculation.
Commander Stone is an internist,
not a criminologist.
The medical facts here
are ultimately inconclusive.
A point I'm confident you’ll illustrate
to the court under cross-examination.
So I'm sure you won't mind
if his opinion is admitted now.
Not at all, sir.
Dr. Stone, did Willie Santiago
die of poisoning?
Absolutely.
You're aware that the lab and coroner's
report show no traces of poison?
- Yes, I am.
- Then how do you justify--
There are literally dozens of toxins
which are virtually undetectable...
both in the human body
and on a fabric.
The nature of the acidosis
is the compelling factor on this issue.
Thank you, sir.
Commander, is it possible for a person
to have an affliction--
some sort of condition-- which might
speed up the process of acidosis?
Commander, is it possible?
It's possible.
What might some of those
conditions be?
If a person had a coronary disorder...
or a cerebral disorder,
the process would be more rapid.
If had a coronary condition and
a clean rag was placed in my mouth...
and the rag was pushed too far down,
is it possible that my cells...
would continue burning sugar
after the rag was taken out?
It would have to be
a very serious condition.
Is it possible to have
a serious coronary condition...
where the warning signals were so mild
as to escape a physician...
during a routine medical exam?
Possibly. There would still
be symptoms, though.
- What kind of symptoms?
- There are hundreds--
- Chest pains?
- Yes.
- Shortness of breath?
- Fatigue?
- Of course.
Doctor, is this your signature?
Yes, it is.
This is an order for Private Santiago
to be put on restrictive duty.
Would you read your handwritten remarks
at the bottom of the page, please?
'Initial testing, negative.
Patient complains of chest pains...
shortness of breath and fatigue.
Restricted from running distances
over five miles for one week.'
Commander, isn't it possible
that Santiago had a serious condition...
and it was that condition that caused
the accelerated chemical reaction?
It's not possible?
I personally give each man
a thorough physical examination.
Private Santiago was given
a clean bill of health.
That's why it had to be poison,
right, Commander?
'Cause if you put a man with a serious
coronary condition on duty...
and that man died
from a heart-related incident...
you'd have a lot to answer for,
wouldn’t you, Doctor?
- Object! Move to strike.
- Sustained.
I have no more questions,
Your Honor.
Dr. Stone, you've held
a medical license for 17 years.
You're Board-certified
in internal medicine.
You are chief of internal medicine
at a hospital which serves 5,426 people.
In your professional medical opinion,
was Willie Santiago poisoned?
We renew our objection
to Commander Stone's testimony...
and ask that it be stricken
from the record.
We further ask the court members to lend
no weight to this witness's testimony.
The objection is overruled.
The defense strenuously objects
and requests an 802 conference...
so that His Honor might have a chance
to hear discussion before ruling.
The objection of the defense
has been heard and overruled.
- Move to reconsider.
- Your objection is noted.
The witness is an expert,
and the court will hear his opinion!
Dr. Stone, in your expert,
professional opinion...
was Willie Santiago poisoned?
Yes.
Thank you, sir.
I have no more questions.
Commander, you may step down.
Please the court, while we reserve
the right to call rebuttal witnesses...
the government rests.
We'll stand in recess until 1000,
Monday the 19th...
at which time, the defense
will call its first witness.
All rise.
'I strenuously object'?
Is that how it works?
'Objection overruled.'
' No, no. I strenuously object.'
'Oh, well, if you strenuously object,
then I should take time to reconsider.'
I got it on the record.
You also got the court members
thinking we're afraid of the doctor.
You object once, so they can hear us say
he's not a criminologist.
You keep after it, and suddenly it looks
like a bunch of fancy lawyer tricks.
It's the difference between paper law
and trial law.
You even had the judge saying
Stone was an expert!
She made a mistake.
Let's not relive it.
I'm gonna go call my wife.
I'll see you tonight.
Why do you hate them so much?
They beat up on a weakling.
That's all they did.
The rest of this is just
smoke-filled coffeehouse crap.
They tortured and tormented
a weaker kid!
They didn't like him,
so they killed him.
And why? Because
he couldn't run very fast!
All right.
Everybody take the night off.
- I'm sorry.
- I know.
We've been working 20 hours a day
for three and half weeks straight.
Just take the night off.
Go see your wife, your daughter.
Jo, go do...
whatever it is you do
when you're not here.
- What day is tomorrow?
- Saturday.
We start at 10:00.
Why do you like them so much?
'Cause they stand on a wall....
and they say, ' Nothing's gonna hurt you
tonight, not on my watch.'
Don't worry about the doctor.
This trial starts Monday.
1 and 2 with two out.
And a line drive to left center.
Kirby racing.
He won’t get there.
And rounding third is Cal Ripken...
and the Twins' streak is over.
One strike away, and Andy Milligan
feels right now like Hulk Hogan.
I'm sorry to bother you.
I should've called first.
No, I was just watching
a ball game. Come on in.
I was wondering if-- How you’d feel
about my taking you to dinner tonight?
- Are you asking me out on a date?
- No.
Sounded like you
were asking me on a date.
I've been asked out on dates before,
and that's what it sounded like.
Do you like seafood?
I know a good seafood place.
My third case was
a drunk and disorderly.
It lasted nine weeks. I rounded up
31 people from the bar that night.
Nine weeks on a D and D?
What was the prosecutor offering?
Fifteen days.
You sure hustled
the shit out of him.
Well, after that
they moved me to Internal Affairs.
- Tough to blame them.
- Where I have earned...
two meritorious service medals
and two letters of commendation.
Why are you always giving me
your resume?
Because I want you to think
I'm a good lawyer.
I do.
No, you don't.
I think you’re an exceptional lawyer.
I watch the court members.
They respond to you. They like you.
I see you convincing them,
and I think Dawson and Downey...
are gonna end up
owing their lives to you.
Jo, I think--
I think you should prepare yourself
for the fact that we're gonna lose.
Ross's opening statement--
it was all true.
Let's pretend for a minute
that it would actually matter...
that the guys
were given an order.
I can't prove it ever happened.
We'll keep doing what we're doing
and we'll put on a show...
but all we have is the testimony
of two people accused of murder.
We'll find Markinson.
Jo, we're gonna lose,
and we're gonna lose huge.
Corporal Jeffrey Owen Barnes,
Marine Barracks Windward...
Guantanamo Bay, Cuba.
Corporal Barnes, name some reasons
why a Marine would receive a Code Red.
Being late for platoon
or company meetings.
Keeping his barracks in disorder.
Falling back on a run.
- Have you ever received a Code Red?
- Yes, sir.
We were doing seven-man assault drills,
and my weapon slipped.
It was 'cause it was over 100 degrees,
and my palms were sweaty...
and I'd forgotten to use the resin
like we were taught.
What happened?
That night, the guys in my squad
threw a blanket over me...
took turns punching me in the arm
for five minutes...
then they poured glue on my hands.
And it worked too, 'cause
I ain't never dropped my weapon since.
Was Private Santiago ever late
for platoon meetings?
Yes, sir.
- Was his barracks ever in disorder?
- Yes, sir.
- Did he ever fall back on a run?
- All the time, sir.
Did he ever, prior to the night
of September 6, receive a Code Red?
No, sir.
- Never?
- No, sir.
You got a Code Red
'cause your palms were sweaty.
Why didn't Santiago,
this burden to his unit, ever get one?
Dawson wouldn't allow it, sir.
Dawson wouldn't allow it.
The guys talked tough about Santiago,
but they wouldn’t go near him.
They were too afraid of Dawson.
Object.
The witness is speculating.
I'll rephrase. Jeffrey, did you ever
want to give Santiago a Code Red?
- Yes, sir.
- Why didn’t you?
'Cause Dawson
would kick my butt, sir.
Good enough. Captain Ross
is gonna ask you some questions now.
Corporal Barnes...
I hold here the Marine Outline
for Recruit Training.
- Are you familiar with this book?
- Yes, sir.
- Have you read it?
Would you turn to the chapter
that deals with Code Reds, please?
Just flip to the page of the book
that discusses Code Reds.
Well, you see, sir, Code Red
is a term that we use.
Just down in Gitmo--
Oh, we're in luck, then.
Standard Operating Procedure, Rifle
Security Company, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba.
I assume we'll find the term Code Red
and its definition in that book.
No, sir.
Corporal Barnes, I'm a Marine.
Is there no book, no manual or pamphlet,
no set of orders or regulations...
that lets me know that as a Marine one
of my duties is to perform Code Reds?
No, sir.
No book, sir.
No further questions.
Corporal, would you turn
to the page in this book....
that says where
the mess hall is, please?
Lieutenant Kaffee,
that's not in the book, sir.
You mean to say in all your time
at Gitmo you've never had a meal?
No, sir.
Three squares a day, sir.
I don't understand.
How did you know where the mess hall was
if it’s not in this book?
Well, I guess I just followed the crowd
at chow time, sir.
No more questions.
- Corporal Barnes, you may step down.
- Thank you, sir.
7:00 tonight we'll do
a final Kendrick review.
I want to slam-dunk this guy.
Hey, Luther.
Admiral, how's
the big case going?
Nose to the grindstone.
- No flies on you.
- A rolling stone gathers no moss.
Well, it ain't over
till the fat lady sings.
You can say that again.
- It ain't over till the fat lady sings.
- Till the fat lady sings.
Walked into that one.
Oh, Jesus Christ!
You left the door unlocked.
- You scared the shit out of me.
-Just keep driving.
Are you aware
you're under subpoena?
Yes. I'm also aware that the lives
of two Marines are in your hands.
If there was something
I could do about that, I would.
But since I can't,
all I can do is help you.
- What do you know?
- I know everything.
- Was it a Code Red?
- Yes.
- Did Kendrick give the order?
- Did you witness it?
- I didn't need to.
Then how do you know?
You know shit.
He was never gonna be transferred
off that base.
Jessup was gonna keep him on the base.
He said he wanted him trained.
- The transfer order has your signature.
- Yeah, I know.
I signed it the morning you arrived
in Cuba, five days after Santiago died.
I'm gonna get you a deal, some kind
of immunity with the prosecutor.
In about four days, you'll appear
as a witness and tell what you know.
I'm gonna check you into a motel.
We are gonna start from the beginning.
I don't want a deal,
and I don't want immunity.
I want you to know that I'm proud
neither of what I've done or am doing.
- Where is he?
- The Downtown Lodge in Northeast.
- I want him guarded.
- That's a good idea.
- My clearance code is 411527273.
- Clearance code?
- Thank you.
- Do you have a clearance code?
This is Jo Galloway.
I need to secure a witness.
Anyway, he also said that Jessup’s lying
about the transportation off the base.
Jessup said that 6:00 the next morning
was the first flight leaving.
Markinson says there was a plane
that left seven hours earlier.
That was impressive. Did you hear
what I said about the flight?
Sam, when a flight takes off,
there's a record kept, right?
Yeah, you need the tower chief’s log
from Gitmo.
- Get it.
- We're gonna win.
We don't know who Markinson is.
We don't know what the logbook will say.
You just concentrate on Downey.
I'm gonna tell Ross where we are.
Nice work today.
Redirect on Barnes.
- I have Markinson.
- Where is he?
Motel room in Northeast with
six Federal Marshalls outside his door.
The transfer that Markinson
signed is phony.
Jessup's statement that the 6:00 a.m.
flight was the first available is a lie.
We're checking the tower chief’s log.
I'd like a beer, please.
In the meantime, I'm gonna put Kendrick
on the stand and have some fun.
All right, I have
an obligation to tell you...
that if you accuse Kendrick or Jessup
of any crime without proper evidence...
you'll be subject to a court-martial
for professional misconduct.
That's something that'll be stapled to
every job application you ever fill out.
Markinson's not gonna hold up, Danny.
He's a crazy man.
I'm not saying this to intimidate you.
I'm being your lawyer here.
Thanks, Jack. And I think the fucking
bunch of you are certifiably insane.
Your code of honor makes me
want to beat the shit out of somebody.
Don't lump me in with them
just because we wear the same uniform.
I'm your friend, and I don't think
your clients belong in jail...
but I don't get
to make that decision.
I represent the United States government
without passion or prejudice.
- My client has a case.
- Here you go.
I want you to acknowledge that
the judge advocate has made you aware...
of the possible consequences involved
in accusing a Marine officer...
of a felony
without proper evidence.
I've been so advised.
You got bullied
into that courtroom, Danny.
By everyone.
By Dawson, by Galloway.
Shit, I practically dared you.
You got bullied into that courtroom
by the memory of a dead lawyer.
You're a lousy fucking
softball player, Jack!
Your boys are going down, Danny.
I can't stop it anymore.
Lieutenant Kendrick, in your opinion,
was Private Santiago a good Marine?
I'd say he was about average.
You signed three proficiency
and conduct reports on Santiago.
On all three reports, you indicate
a rating of below average.
Yes, Private Santiago
was below average.
I did not see the need
to trample on a man's grave.
We appreciate that,
but you’re under oath now.
Unpleasant as it may be,
we'd all just as soon hear the truth.
I'm aware of my oath.
These are the last three pro-con reports
you signed for Lance Corporal Dawson.
Dawson received
two marks of exceptional...
but on this most recent report of June 9
he received a rating of below average.
- I'd like to discuss this last report.
- That would be fine.
Lance Corporal Dawson's ranking after
the school of infantry was perfect.
Over half that class has since
been promoted to full corporal...
while Dawson has remained
a lance corporal.
Was Dawson's promotion held up
because of this last report?
I'm sure it was.
Do you recall why Dawson was given
such a poor grade on this report?
I'm sure I don't.
I have many men in my charge.
I write many reports.
Lieutenant, do you recall an incident
involving a P.F.C. Curtis Bell...
who'd been found stealing liquor
from the Officers' Club?
Yes, I do.
Did you report Private Bell
to proper authorities?
I have two books at my bedside--
The Marine Corps Code of Conduct
and The King James Bible.
The only proper authorities I'm aware of
are my commanding officer...
Colonel Nathan R. Jessup
and the Lord our God.
At your request, Lieutenant Kendrick,
I can have the record reflect...
your lack of acknowledgement
of this court as a proper authority.
- Objection. Argumentative.
- Sustained.
Watch yourself, counselor.
Did you report Private Bell
to your superiors?
I remember thinking very highly
of Private Bell--
not wanting to see his record tarnished
by a formal charge.
You preferred it be handled
within the unit?
Yes, I most certainly did.
- Do you know what a Code Red is?
- Yes, I do.
- Have you ever ordered a Code Red?
- No, I have not.
Did you order Dawson and two other men
to make sure that Private Bell...
received no food or drink, except water,
for a period of seven days?
That is a distortion
of the truth, Lieutenant.
Private Bell was placed
on barracks restriction.
He was given water and vitamin
supplements, and I can assure you...
at no time
was his health in danger.
I'm sure it was lovely
for Private Bell.
But you did order
the barracks restriction, didn’t you?
- You did order the denial of food?
- Yes, I did.
Wouldn't this form of discipline
be considered a Code Red?
If called the other 478 Marines
at Guantanamo Bay to testify...
would they consider it
a Code Red?
The witness can't possibly testify
as to what 478 other men would say.
We object to this entire line
of questioning. It's argumentative...
and irrelevant badgering
of the witness.
The government's objection
is sustained, Lieutenant Kaffee...
and I would remind you that you’re now
questioning a Marine officer...
with an impeccable service record.
Thank you, Your Honor.
Lieutenant, was Dawson given a rating
of below average on this last report...
because you learned he'd been sneaking
food to Private Bell?
- Object!
- Not so fast. Lieutenant?
Lance Corporal Dawson
was given a below average rating...
because he had committed a crime.
A crime?
What crime did he commit?
Dawson brought a hungry guy some food.
He disobeyed an order.
And because he exercised
his own set of values...
because he made a decision
about the welfare of a Marine...
that was in conflict with your order,
he was punished, is that right?
Lance Corporal Dawson
disobeyed an order.
Yeah, but it wasn't
a real order, was it?
After all, it's peacetime.
He wasn't being asked to secure a hill
or advance on a beachhead.
I mean, surely a Marine
of Dawson's intelligence...
can be trusted to determine on his own
which are the important orders...
and which orders might, say,
be morally questionable?
Can he?
Can Dawson determine on his own
which orders he's going to follow?
No, he cannot.
A lesson he learned
after the Curtis Bell incident, right?
- I would think so.
- You know so, don’t you?
- Object!
- Sustained.
Lieutenant Kendrick,
one final question.
If you had ordered Dawson
to give Santiago a Code Red--
- I specifically ordered those men--
- Would he disobey you again?
- Lieutenant, don't answer that!
- You don't have to. I'm through.
Lieutenant Kendrick, did you order
Lance Corporal Dawson...
and Private Downey
to give Willie Santiago a Code Red?
- No, I did not.
- Thank you.
What's the word?
I got the tower chief’s log from that
night. Jessup’s telling the truth.
- 6:00 a.m. flight was the first plane.
- Let me see this.
- Working late tonight?
- Oh, yeah.
There wasn't a flight at00.
What the fuck are you trying to pull?
The first flight stateside
left Guantanamo Bay at 2300.
It arrived at Andrews Air Force Base
at a few minutes past 2:00.
Really? Then why isn't it
listed in the tower chief’s log?
Jessup.
What are you telling me?
He fixed the logbook?
Maybe he can make it so a plane didn't
take off, but I can prove one landed.
I'll get the logbook from Andrews.
You're not gonna find anything
in the Andrews logbook, either.
He can make
an entire flight disappear?
Jessup is about to be appointed director
of operations for the Security Council.
You don't get to that position without
knowing how to sidestep some land mines.
He's not gonna be able
to sidestep you.
You don't still intend
to put me on the stand?
Thursday morning, 10:00.
There's gotta be someone
who can testify to the flight.
This isn't TWA.
There isn't a regular flight schedule.
Do you have any idea how many planes
take off and land every day?
A ground crew kid won't remember
a flight that landed four weeks ago.
- How do you know if you don't check?
- Forget the flight!
Markinson will testify that Jessup
refused to transfer Santiago.
He'll testify to the forged transfer,
and that'll be enough.
That and Downey's testimony
really ought to be enough.
Why did you go into Santiago's room
on the night of the 6th?
To give Private Santiago
a Code Red, ma'am.
Why did you give him a Code Red?
I was ordered to give him a Code Red
by the platoon commander...
of Rifle Security Company Windward,
Lieutenant Jonathan James Kendrick.
You're gonna do fine.
You think they'll let us go back
to our platoon soon, ma'am?
Absolutely.
Do you remember the order of questions?
Are you sure?
And we'll use small words, 'cause he
gets rattled if he doesn't understand.
- I'm just saying go slow.
- I'm gonna go slow.
And get him off
as fast as you can.
What?
It's gonna be fine.
Dear Mr. and Mrs. Santiago...
I was William's executive officer.
I knew your son vaguely,
which is to say I knew his name.
In a matter of time,
the trial of the two men...
charged with your son's death
will be concluded...
and seven men and two women
whom you've never met...
will try to offer you an explanation
as to why William is dead.
For my part, I've done as much as I can
to bring the truth to light.
And the truth is this--
Your son is dead for only one reason--
I wasn't strong enough to stop it.
Always, Lieutenant Colonel
Matthew Andrew Markinson...
United States Marine Corps.
Private, I want you
to tell us one last time.
Why did you go to Private Santiago's
room on the night of September 6?
A Code Red was ordered
by my platoon commander...
Lieutenant Jonathan James Kendrick.
Thank you.
Your witness.
Private, the week of2 September...
the switch log has you down
at Post 39 until 1600.
Is that correct?
I'm sure it is, sir.
They keep that log pretty good.
How far is it from Post 39
to the Windward Barracks?
Well, it's a ways, sir.
It's a hike.
About how far by Jeep?
About ten or fifteen minutes, sir.
You ever had to walk it?
Yes, sir. That day, Friday.
The pickup private--
That's what we call the guy
who drops us off and picks us up...
also 'cause he can get girls
in New York City.
The pickup private got a flat,
sir, right at 39.
He pulled up and, bam,
blowout with no spare.
So we had to double-time it
back to the barracks.
And if it’s about ten or fifteen
minutes by Jeep, I'm guessing...
it must be a good hour by foot,
am I right?
Pickup and me did it
in 45 flat, sir.
Not bad.
You've said that your assault
on Private Santiago...
was a result of a order
that Lieutenant Kendrick gave you...
in your barracks room
at 1620, am I right?
Yes, sir.
But you just said that you didn't
make it back to the barracks until 1645.
Well, if you didn't make it back
to the barracks until 1645...
how could you be
in your room at 1620?
Well, you see, sir,
there was a blowout--
Did you ever actually hear
Lieutenant Kendrick order a Code Red?
Well, Hal said that--
Private, did you ever
actually hear...
Lieutenant Kendrick
order a Code Red?
I'd like to request a recess
in order to confer with my client.
- Why did you go into Santiago's room?
- The witness has rights!
- The witness has been read his rights.
- The question will be repeated.
Why did you go
into Santiago's room?
Did Lance Corporal Dawson tell you
to give Santiago a Code Red?
- Don't look at him!
- Hal!
Answer the captain's question!
Yes, Captain, I was given an order
by my squad leader...
Lance Corporal Harold W. Dawson,
United States Marine Corps...
and I followed it.
Where do you think he is?
As far as Downey was concerned,
it was an order from Kendrick.
It doesn't matter that
he didn't hear it firsthand.
He doesn't distinguish
between the two.
Danny, I'm sorry.
Don't worry about it.
Sam and I were just talking about
how all we really have to do...
is call some witnesses
who will talk about implied orders.
Maybe we can put Downey back
on the stand before we get to Dawson.
If we work at it, we can get Dawson
charged with the Kennedy assassination.
Are you drunk?
Pretty much.
Yeah.
I'll put on a pot of coffee.
We've got a long night's work ahead.
She's gonna make coffee.
That's nice.
Downey wasn’t in his room.
Wasn't even there.
That was an important piece
of information, don’t you think?
Danny, it was a setback,
and I'm sorry.
But we fix it,
and move on to Markinson.
Markinson's dead.
You really gotta hand it
to those Federal Marshals, boy.
It's not like he hanged himself
by his shoelaces...
or slashed his wrists
with a concealed butter knife.
This guy...
got into full dress uniform,
stood in the middle of that room...
drew a nickel-plated pistol
from his holster...
and fired a bullet into his mouth.
Anyway, since we seem to be out of
witnesses, I thought I'd drink a little.
I still think we can win.
Maybe you should drink a little.
We'll go to Randolph in the morning and
make a motion for a 24-hour continuance.
- Why would we want to do that?
- To subpoena Colonel Jessup.
- What?
- Listen for a second. Hear me out.
I won't listen,
and I won't hear you out.
Your passion is compelling, Jo.
It's also useless.
Louden Downey
needed a trial lawyer today.
You're chicken shit.
You're gonna use what happened today
as an excuse to give up.
It's over.
Why did you ask Jessup
for the transfer order?
- In Cuba. Why?
- What does it matter?
- I wanted the damn transfer order!
- Bullshit.
You could've gotten it by calling
any department at the Pentagon.
You didn't want the transfer order.
You wanted to see Jessup’s reaction.
You had an instinct,
and it was confirmed by Markinson.
Let's put Jessup on the stand
and end this thing!
What possible good could come
from putting Jessup on the stand?
He told Kendrick
to order the Code Red.
He did? That's great!
Why didn’t you say so?
And of course
you have proof of that!
Oh, I'm sorry. I forgot. You were sick
the day they taught law at law school.
You put him on the stand,
and you get it from him.
Oh, we get it from him!
Yes! No problem!
Colonel Jessup, isn't it true that
you ordered the Code Red on Santiago?
- Listen, we're all a little--
- I'm sorry. Your time's run out.
What do we have for the losers?
Well, for our defendants...
it's a lifetime
at exotic Fort Leavenworth.
And for Defense Counsel Kaffee...
it's a court-martial!
Yes, Johnny,
after falsely accusing...
a highly decorated Marine officer...
of conspiracy and perjury...
Lieutenant Kaffee will have
a long and prosperous career...
teaching typewriter maintenance
at the Rocco Clubo School for Women.
Thank you for playing
'Should we or should we not...
follow the advice
of the galactic ally stupid?'
I'm sorry I lost
your set of steak knives.
Stop cleaning up.
- Want a drink?
- Yeah.
- Is your father proud of you?
- Don't do this to yourself.
I'll bet he is.
I'll bet he bores the shit
out of the neighbors and relatives.
'Sam's made Law Review.
He's got a big case he's making.
He's arguing.
He's making an argument.'
I think my father would’ve enjoyed
seeing me graduate from law school.
I think he would've liked that
an awful lot.
Did I ever tell you I wrote a paper
about your father in college?
Yeah?
One of the best
trial lawyers ever.
Yes, he was.
If were Dawson and Downey
and I had a choice...
between you or your father
to represent me in this case...
I'd choose you any day of the week
and twice on Sunday.
You should've seen yourself
thunder away at Kendrick.
Would you put Jessup on the stand?
- Do you think my father would have?
- With the evidence we got?
Not in a million years.
But here's the thing-- and there's
really know way of getting around this--
Neither Lyle Kaffee nor Sam Weinberg
are lead counsel for the defense...
in the matter of
U.S. v. Dawson and Downey.
So there's really only one question--
What would you do?
Jo, get in the car.
Joanne, please get in the car.
Look--
I apologize. I was angry.
I'm sorry about what I said.
I'm gonna put Jessup on the stand.
What do you suggest we do?
I say we hit Jessup
with the phony transfer order.
What's a transfer order
without a witness?
- We have a witness.
- A dead witness.
In the hands of a lesser attorney,
that would be a problem.
Look at this. Last night
he's swimming in Jack Daniels...
and now he can leap tall buildings
in a single bound.
I'm getting my second wind.
Sit down, both of you.
Good. Jessup told Kendrick
to order the Code Red. Kendrick did.
Our clients followed the order.
The cover-up isn't our case.
To win, Jessup needs to tell the court
members that he ordered the Code Red.
- You think you can get him to say it?
- I think he wants to say it.
I think he's pissed off
that he's got to hide from us.
I think he wants to say that he made
a command decision, and that's the end.
He eats breakfast 300 yards away...
from 4,000 Cubans
that are trained to kill him.
No one's gonna tell him
how to run his unit.
Least of all the Harvard mouth
in his faggoty white uniform.
I need to shake him,
put him on the defensive...
and lead him right
where he's dying to go.
- That's it? That's the plan?
- That's the plan.
- How are you gonna do it?
- I have no idea.
- I need my bat.
- Your what?
I think better with my bat.
Where's my bat?
- I put it in the closet.
- You put it in the closet?
- I was tripping on it.
- Don't ever put that bat in the closet.
- He thinks better with his bat?
- I can understand that.
Stay here.
I'm going to the office for a while.
He does think better with that bat.
Sam, I need you
to do something for me.
- What's going on?
- Gotta go out to Andrews.
- Where's Sam?
- He's on his way.
- Did he get the guys?
- Yeah.
Listen, can I talk to you
for a second?
Oh, yeah, sure.
How you feeling?
Well, I think Jessup’s
gonna have his hands full today.
Listen, Danny...
when you're out there today...
if you feel like
it's not gonna happen...
he's not gonna say it...
don't go for it.
You could get in trouble.
I'm special counsel
for Internal Affairs...
and I'm telling you
you could get in a lot of trouble.
Wait, Lieutenant Commander Galloway...
you're not suggesting
that I back off a material witness?
If you think you can't get him, yeah.
All rise.
- Where's Sam?
- He's on his way.
- Call your first witness.
- Where is he?
- He'll be here.
- Lieutenant.
Call your witness.
Defense calls Colonel Nathan Jessup.
Colonel Jessup, would you raise
your right hand please, sir?
Do you solemnly swear that the testimony
you will give in this court-martial...
will be the truth, the whole truth
and nothing but the truth?
Yes, I do.
Have a seat please, sir.
Would you state your name, rank
and current billet for the record, sir?
Colonel Nathan R. Jessup,
commanding officer...
Marine Ground Forces,
Guantanamo Bay, Cuba.
- Thank you, sir.
- He's not here.
Colonel, when you learned
of Santiago’s letter to the N.I.S....
you had a meeting
with your two senior officers.
- Is that right?
- Yes.
The platoon commander,
Lieutenant Jonathan Kendrick...
and the executive officer,
Lieutenant Colonel Matthew Markinson.
Yes.
And at present Colonel Markinson
is dead. Is that right?
Objection. I'd like to know just what
the defense counsel is implying.
I'm implying simply that at present
Colonel Markinson is not alive.
Colonel Jessup doesn't need to appear
in court to confirm that information.
I just wasn't sure the witness was aware
that two days ago...
the colonel took his own life
with a .45-caliber pistol.
The witness is aware,
the court is aware...
and now the court members
are aware.
We thank you for bringing this
to our attention.
Move on, Lieutenant..
Yes, sir.
Colonel, you gave Lieutenant Kendrick
an order at this meeting, right?
I told Kendrick to tell his men
that Santiago wasn't to be touched.
And did you give an order
to Colonel Markinson as well?
I ordered Markinson to have Santiago
transferred off the base immediately.
Why?
I felt his life might be in danger
once word of the letter got out.
Grave danger?
Is there another kind?
Colonel, we have the transfer order
that you and Markinson co-signed...
ordering that Santiago be on a flight
leaving Guantanamo at 6:00 the next day.
- Was that the first flight?
- The 0600 was the first flight.
You flew up to Washington this morning.
Is that right?
I notice you’re wearing your
class 'A' dress uniform in court today.
- As are you, Lieutenant.
- Did you wear that on the plane?
Please the court, is this dialogue
relevant to anything--
Defense didn't have the opportunity
to depose this witness.
- I'd ask for a little latitude.
- A very little latitude.
I wore utilities on the plane.
- You brought your dress uniform?
- Yes.
- Toothbrush, shaving kit, underwear?
- Your Honor!
Is the colonel's underwear
a matter of national security?
Gentlemen! You better get somewhere
fast with this, Lieutenant.
Yes, sir. Colonel?
I brought a change of clothes
and some personal items.
Thank you.
After Dawson and Downey's arrest
on the night of the sixth...
Santiago's barracks were sealed off
and its contents inventoried.
' Four pairs camouflage pants,
three long-sleeve khaki shirts...
three pairs of boots, four pairs
green socks, three green T-shirts--'
Please the court, is there a question
anywhere in our future?
Lieutenant Kaffee, I have to ask you
to state your question.
I'm wondering why Santiago
wasn't packed.
I'll tell you what.
We'll get back to that one in a minute.
This is a record of all phone calls made
from your base in the past 24 hours.
After being subpoenaed to Washington,
you made three calls.
Do you recognize
those number, sir?
I called Colonel Fitzhughes
in Quantico, Virginia.
I wanted to let him know
that I would be in town.
The second call was to arrange a meeting
with Congressman Richmond...
of the House Armed Services Committee.
And the third call
was to my sister Elizabeth.
Why did you make that call, sir?
I thought she might like
to have dinner tonight.
- I'm gonna stop this.
- These are phone records from Gitmo...
for September 6,
and these are 14 letters...
that Santiago wrote in nine months...
requesting-- in fact, begging--
for a transfer.
Upon hearing the news that
he was finally getting his transfer...
Santiago was so excited that
do you know how many people he called?
Zero. Nobody.
Not one call to his parents
saying he was coming home.
Not one call to a friend, saying,
'Can you pick me up at the airport?'
He was asleep in his bed at midnight,
and according to you...
he was getting on a plane
in six hours.
Yet everything he owned
was hanging neatly in his closet...
and folded neatly in his footlocker.
You were leaving for one day.
You packed a bag and made three calls.
Santiago was leaving
for the rest of his life...
and he hadn't called a soul...
and he hadn't packed a thing.
Can you explain that?
The fact is,
there was no transfer order.
Santiago wasn't going anywhere.
Isn't that right, Colonel?
Objection. Your Honor, it's obvious
that Lieutenant Kaffee's intention...
is the smear
a high-ranking Marine officer...
in the hope that the mere appearance
of impropriety will win him points.
It's my recommendation, sir,
that Lieutenant Kaffee be reprimanded...
and the witness be excused
with the court's deepest apologies.
Overruled.
Your objection is noted.
Is this funny, sir?
No, it's not.
It's tragic.
- Do you have an answer?
- Absolutely.
My answer is,
I don't have the first damn clue.
Maybe he was an early riser
and liked to pack in the morning.
And maybe he didn't have any friends.
I'm an educated man, but I'm afraid
I can't speak intelligently...
about the travel habits
of William Santiago.
What I do know is that he was set
to leave the base at 0600.
Now, are these really the questions
that I was called here to answer?
Phone calls and footlockers?
Please tell me that you have
something more, Lieutenant.
These two Marines
are on trial for their lives.
Please tell me that their lawyer hasn't
pinned their hopes to a phone bill.
Do you have any other questions
for me, counselor?
Lieutenant, do you have anything
further for this witness?
Thanks, Danny.
I love Washington.
Excuse me.
I didn't dismiss you.
I beg your pardon?
I'm not through with my examination.
Sit down.
- Colonel.
- What's that?
I'd appreciate it if you’d address me
as 'colonel' or 'sir.'
I believe I've earned it.
Defense counsel will address
the witness as 'colonel' or 'sir.'
I don't know what the hell
kind of unit you're running here.
The witness will address this court
as 'judge' or 'your honor.'
I'm quite certain I've earned it.
Take your seat, Colonel.
What do you want to discuss now?
My favorite color?
Colonel, the 6:00 a.m. flight
was the first one off the base?
Yes.
There wasn't a flight
that left seven hours earlier...
and landed at Andrews Air Force Base
at 2:00 a.m.?
Lieutenant, I think
we've covered this, haven't we?
Your Honor, these are
the tower chief’s logs...
for both Guantanamo Bay
and Andrews Air Force Base.
The Guantanamo log lists no flight
that left at 11:00 p.m.
The Andrews log lists no flight
that landed at 2:00 a.m.
I'd like to admit them
as defense exhibits Alpha and Bravo.
I don't understand. You're admitting
evidence of a flight that never existed.
We believe it did, sir.
Defense will be calling Airmen
Cecil O'Malley and Anthony Rodriguez.
They were working the ground crew
at Andrews at 2:00 a.m. on the 7th.
- These men weren't on the list.
- Rebuttal witnesses, Your Honor...
called specifically to refute testimony
offered under direct examination.
- I'll allow the witnesses.
- This is ridiculous.
- Colonel, a moment ago--
- Check the tower logs, for God's sake!
We'll get to the airmen
in just a minute, sir.
A moment ago you said that
you ordered Lieutenant Kendrick...
to tell his men
that Santiago wasn't to be touched.
That's right.
And Lieutenant Kendrick was clear
on what you wanted?
Crystal.
Any chance Lieutenant Kendrick
ignored the order?
Ignored the order?
Any chance he forgot about it?
Any chance Lieutenant Kendrick left your
office and said, 'The old man is wrong'?
When Lieutenant Kendrick
spoke to the platoon...
and ordered them not to touch Santiago,
any chance they ignored him?
You ever served
in an infantry unit, son?
- No, sir.
- Ever served in a forward area?
Ever put your life
in another man's hands?
Asked him to put his life in yours?
We follow orders, son.
We follow orders, or people die.
It's that simple.
Are we clear?
Yes, sir.
Crystal.
I have just one more question before
I call Airmen O'Malley and Rodriguez.
If you gave an order
that Santiago wasn't to be touched...
and your orders
are always followed...
then why would Santiago
be in danger?
Why would it be necessary
to transfer him off the base?
Santiago was a substandard Marine.
- He was being transferred--
- That's not what you said!
You said he was being transferred
because he was in grave danger.
I said, 'Grave danger?'
You said, 'Is there any other kind?'
- I recall what I said.
- I can have it read back to you.
I know what I said!
I don't have to have it read back to me.
Then why the two orders?
Colonel?
Sometimes men take matters
into their own hands.
You've made it clear that your men
never take matters into their own hands.
Your men follow orders,
or people die.
So Santiago should have been
in danger, should he?
- You snotty little bastard.
- I'd like to ask for a recess.
- I'd like an answer to the question.
- The court will wait for an answer.
If Lieutenant Kendrick
gave an order...
that Santiago
wasn't to be touched...
then why did he
have to be transferred?
Lieutenant Kendrick ordered the Code Red
because that's what you told him to do!
- Object!
- And then you cut these guys loose!
- I'll hold you in contempt.
- You doctored the logbook!
- Damn it, Kaffee!
- Consider yourself in contempt.
Colonel Jessup,
did you order the Code Red?
- You don't have to answer that.
- I'll answer the question.
- You want answers?
- I think I'm entitled!
- I want the truth!
You can't handle the truth!
Son, we live in a world
that has walls...
and those walls have to be guarded
by men with guns.
Who's gonna do it? You?
You, Lieutenant Weinberg?
I have a greater responsibility
than you can possibly fathom.
You weep for Santiago,
and you curse the Marines.
You have the luxury
of not knowing what I know--
that Santiago's death,
while tragic, probably saved lives.
And my existence, while grotesque and
incomprehensible to you, saves lives!
You don't want the truth because
deep down you don't talk about...
you want me on that wall.
You need me on that wall!
We use words
like honor, code, loyalty.
We use these words as the backbone
of a life spent defending something.
You use them as a punch line.
I have neither the time
nor the inclination to explain myself...
to a man who rises and sleeps under
the blanket of the freedom I provide...
and then questions the manner
in which I provide it!
I would rather you just said thank you
and went on your way.
Otherwise, I suggest you
pick up a weapon and stand a post.
Either way, I don't give a damn
what you think you are entitled to!
Did you order the Code Red?
- I did the job--
- Did you order the Code Red?
You're goddamned right I did!
Please the court,
I suggest the members be dismissed...
so that we can move to an immediate
Article 39-A session.
The witness has rights.
Captain Ross?
The members of the court will retire
to an anteroom until further instructed.
All rise.
What the hell is this?
Colonel, what's going on?
I did my job.
I'd do it again.
I'm gonna get on a plane
and go on back to my base.
You're not going anywhere, Colonel.
M.P. s, guard the colonel.
Yes, sir.
- Captain Ross.
- What the hell is this?
Colonel Jessup, you have
the right to remain silent.
I'm being charged with a crime?
Is that what this is?
- I'm being charged with a crime?
- You have a right to consult a lawyer.
- This is funny. That's what this is.
- This lawyer may be appointed by you.
I'm gonna rip the eyes out of your head
and piss in your dead skull!
You fucked with the wrong Marine!
Colonel Jessup, do you understand
these rights as I have just read them?
You fucking people.
You have no idea
how to defend a nation.
All you did was weaken
a country today, Kaffee.
That's all you did.
You put people's lives in danger.
Sweet dreams, son.
Don't call me son.
I'm a lawyer and an officer
in the United States Navy...
and you're under arrest,
you son of a bitch.
The witness is excused.
All rise.
Have the members reached a verdict?
We have, sir.
Lance Corporal Dawson
and Private First Class Downey.
On the charge of murder,
the members find the accused...
not guilty.
On the charge
of conspiracy to commit murder...
the members find the accused
not guilty.
On the charge of conduct
unbecoming a United States Marine...
the members find the accused
guilty as charged.
The accused are hereby sentenced
to time already served...
and you are ordered to be dishonorably
discharged from the Marine Corps.
This court-martial is adjourned.
All rise.
What does that mean?
What did that mean?
I don't understand. Colonel Jessup
said he ordered the Code Red.
- I know.
- What did we do wrong?
- It's not that simple.
- We did nothing wrong!
Yeah, we did.
We were supposed to fight for people
who couldn't fight for themselves.
We were supposed
to fight for Willie.
I have to take these men
over to personnel for some paperwork.
You don't need to wear a patch
on your arm to have honor.
There's an officer on deck.
Airmen Cecil O'Malley
and Anthony Rodriguez--
What exactly were these guys
gonna testify to?
Unless I'm mistaken, they were both
gonna testify under oath...
that they had absolutely
no recollection of anything.
- Strong witnesses.
- And handsome too, don’t you think?
I'll see you around campus.
I gotta go arrest Kendrick.
Tell him I say hi.
Will do.