Here. You
starting all over again?
What about it if I am?
Supposing the police come along?
Let 'em come.
The windows are steamed up.
The doors are locked.
It's like a Turkish bath
in here.
Don't it make you thirsty?
Here.
Watch my stockings.
Move over a bit, then.
Get your knee off
the steering wheel!
I can't. I'm stuck.
Here. I'll do it.
Oh, that hurt!
I've told you before
to be careful where
you put your legs.
I was only trying to be helpful.
I can help meself.
Hello.
They never make these cars
big enough, do they?
Well, are you all settled in?
Right. We can begin.
My name is...
Alfie.
I suppose you think
you're going to see
the bleedin' titles now.
Well, you're not, so relax.
Alfie.
What time did your old man say
he'd be waiting at the station?
Never mind about him.
That's just who I am gonna mind.
Never spoil a good thing.
That's a thing
you women can't get
into your heads.
Enough's as good as a feast.
Ohh, you've changed your tune.
That horn put me off.
I hate noise
at a time like that.
Eh, mate?
Don't forget your napkin.
When I first saw you
put your handkerchief
over your shoulder,
I thought you were
going to play fiddle.
I'm from a musical family.
Here.
What?
Mind you don't catch cold.
I've had a lovely time, Alfie.
A married woman, see?
They're all in need
of a good laugh.
It don't never strike
their husbands.
Make a married woman laugh,
and you're halfway
there with her.
Course it don't work
with a single bird.
Starts you off
on the wrong foot.
Get one of them laughing,
you won't get nothing else.
♪ Ia-Di,
la-dum... ♪♪
Just listen.
It was dead glum
when I met it tonight.
I listened to its problems,
then I got it laughing.
It'll go home happy.
Where did you tell your husband
you were going?
Pictures with olive.
What pictures?
Just the pictures.
Never be vague like that.
It plants suspicion.
No wonder there's
all this broken marriage
and divorce about.
It would never occur to him
another man would
want to take me out.
I see.
Suck these sweets, siddie,
so he don't smell the gin.
I don't care if he does.
Now be human.
We're having fun.
Why hurt him?
You like to see everybody happy.
I don't believe in
making anybody unhappy
or in making an enemy.
You could be crossing
the Sahara desert,
and he'd be just
the bloke you'd meet.
What about next week?
Same time, same place?
Maybe.
I'll go and get me ticket.
What she don't know is,
we won't be seeing
much more of her.
She's on her way out.
When a married woman
gets too hot,
it's time to cool off.
Next she'll want to introduce me
to the husband.
I can see it coming.
Well, good night, dear girl.
This is a ticket
for the firm's dance
on Saturday.
Won't your old man be there?
Yeah, I'd like you
to meet. Good night.
Don't forget your napkin.
Yeah. Well, I'm like
the boy scouts--
always prepared.
Once I met the husband,
it puts me off the wife.
He could be dying on his bed,
but if I ain't met him,
I won't think about him.
It's once you meet.
Likely as not, he'll be
a real good sport.
His sort usually are.
As I'm having it off with her,
I'll think about him
hanging his drip-dry shirts
or arguing in the pub
about football or cricket.
A lot of his sort are
Chelsea supporters.
Hello.
Had a nice time, dear?
Not bad at all.
Good film?
Well, there was a queue,
so we went to
a restaurant instead.
Did you enjoy yourself?
That's the main thing.
I did me best.
What about you?
I've been going through
that garden catalog.
It's very interesting.
You should go out more often.
You come back ever so cheerful.
Made over again, you might say.
Now I'm off to visit
a little bird called Gilda.
While she ain't exactly stupid,
she is a bit on the simple side.
She'd never make a number one.
You couldn't show her off.
She ain't an exciting dresser,
but she's a cracking
little stand-by,
and she ain't
a Liberty-taker.
Most birds go mad
to get a bloke,
and the first thing they do
is go about changing him.
Now, I told Gilda
I ain't the marrying sort,
and she don't mind.
She's a stand-by,
and she knows it.
Any bird that knows
its place in this world
can be quite content.
Alfie? Did you
forget your key?
Oh.
Humphrey, it's you.
Yeah, I'm sorry for
coming round so late,
but, well, you know,
I was just passing by.
Yes, I see.
Only I just finished work
and was feeling a bit lonely
so thought I'd, like,
you know, pop in.
Yes, I see.
Uh, have I come
at an awkward time?
I am expecting Alfie any minute.
Cor, there ain't half
a pong in here.
It's phul Nana, scent of Araby.
Don't you like it?
No. I like everything
to smell natural.
I got your meal ready.
Never push things
at me right away.
I like to get me bearings.
Just as you like it.
That's enough of that.
I saw that geezer
Humphrey going off.
Here, here.
You're not having it
off with him, are you?
Alfie, I can't bear another man
to come near me
since I met you.
Well, I just wondered.
Did he just call to give
you these chocolates?
No. He called to
tell me he loved me.
Love ya? Blimey,
some men are funny.
Alfie, do you love me?
Well, shall we say,
I like you a lot.
Now, well, I will have
that grub after all.
Hot water bottle?
She's getting a bit previous.
Hello.
Uh...
Is today the 22nd?
Yeah, I think so.
Shouldn't our little friend
have arrived on the 19th?
Don't worry.
He'll turn up.
He always has.
He's usually so punctual.
I had a good day.
Took over £50 on the till.
Isn't that wonderful?
It's not as if
it was your money.
Well, I like to think
of them doing well.
Besides, it keeps me busy.
Ain't it time you started
that fiddle on the till?
I couldn't.
Must be the only till in London
that ain't bent.
Luigi and his wife,
they treat me like family.
There's all the more
reason to do 'em.
Alfie, I'm happy as I am.
You could still be happy
with a few hundred quid
in the bank
instead of tuppence halfpenny.
Now, look...
The one thing you got
to get into your head is
that nobody don't
help you in this life.
You got to help yourself.
If you'd only fiddled
5 Bob a day,
you'd have 200 nicker by now.
Money isn't everything, Alfie.
Only people ain't
got none talk like that.
I've had a fiddle
on every job I've done.
A fiddle gives you an
interest in your work.
And everybody should
take an interest
in their work.
There's another little job done.
Yeah.
You sound cheerful, elkins.
Yes, some mornings
I feel quite chirpy.
Not all that chirpy
on what I'm paying you.
You must have a fiddle.
That's defamation of character.
I'll report you to the union.
How do you think
I got where I am?
I'm satisfied as long
as you do the job well,
but don't get greedy.
Otherwise you'll kill the goose.
I tumbled at once.
I shouldn't have whistled.
Never be cheerful on a job
if you're doing a fiddle.
You're getting careless, alf.
You can say that again.
Little Gilda, she's pregnant.
How long?
A couple of months.
You ain't getting
married to her, are you?
What, me in my state of health?
Sorry. Full up.
Room for just one more inside.
Humphrey, I'm glad
it's your bus.
Are you?
I haven't seen you for so long.
You don't need
flinging downstairs
to know you're not welcome.
I'm sorry.
That's all right.
I've missed our little chats.
Have you? Oh.
2 sixpennies, when
you've got the time.
Ta.
I've never seen you
looking lovelier.
I still can't get
you out of my mind.
How's, um, how's
Alfie these days?
He's fine. Fine.
Mind you, it doesn't
hurt like it used to.
What doesn't?
Well, you know,
the old heartache.
Still, I wouldn't be without it.
You haven't got engaged
or anything like that, have you?
No, nothing like that.
He doesn't rush
into things, Alfie.
I don't expect you'll
ever be needing me,
but if you do, I'll--
I'll always be there.
Bye, Gilda.
God bless.
Hello, Alfie.
You're late, girl.
I ran all the way.
Any news? Any reports
from the front?
No.
It doesn't look like it.
We've definitely
got to do something
about this little lot.
I-I've tried
everything, Alfie.
You've been taking
stuff on the quiet?
You don't want to make
yourself ill, you know.
Alfie...
You're not getting cooey lately.
I'm sorry.
You're not only cooey,
you're more bossified.
It's as though I've got
to take notice of you,
instead of you of me.
I can't describe it,
but I can feel it.
Do you love me?
And what can I say when you ask?
You shouldn't ask.
I'll tell you...
When I feel like it.
I'll make the coffee.
Yeah. Make it strong.
Alfie, I was thinking...
Why can't we...
Go through with it?
Blimey, I've never been
through with anything.
If I was to marry you,
you'd gain a husband,
but you'd lose a friend.
You don't have to marry me.
I've got it worked out.
You've got to think twice
before turning
an innocent creature
out into this world.
I wouldn't turn him out.
I'll have him adopted.
Adopted? What are
you talking about?
By a rich woman, see?
A rich woman?
I'd like to do
that much for him.
He'd have a good life then.
Steady on, girl.
I mean, you can't be sure
there's something there yet.
This morning, I thought
I felt him kick.
How can he kick?
It's not the size
of my thumbnail.
I'll tell you next time.
You'll do nothing of the sort.
Don't give way to your
impulses like that.
Something a woman
might think natural,
like as not, a bloke
would find sickening.
Mrs. Artoni at the cafe
used to call her husband
every time their baby moved.
What you don't realize
is that men are more
sensitive than women.
Remember that big bird
I used to dance with?
One Sunday night,
she showed me her operation scar
what she had made
when she was a kid--
a long scar with
white skin around it.
I got straight out of bed
and put me clobber on.
"What's up with you?"
She says.
"I'd sooner go see
a bleeding horror film"
I said, "than
a thing like that."
Alfie, please.
Please...
Can I... You know,
go through with it
and have the baby?
What are you asking me for?
It's yours, isn't it?
Nobody in this world
has any right to stop you doing
what you want to do.
Oh, steady on, girl.
Now then, now then...
Don't break your bleeding heart.
If you want to do something,
and you think it's right,
you do it.
To hell with them.
Mind me shirt.
Now...
You know what?
She was quite happy
them months she was carrying,
which to my mind
was a bit out of place,
her not being married, see?
Mind you, she came over
quite beautified for a time,
especially in the early months.
And I told her,
"blimey, girl, you ain't
as ugly as I thought."
Anyway, her time comes,
and into the hospital
she goes to have it.
I wasn't there. I didn't
know till they told me.
Then, from all accounts,
the kid comes out at 3:00.
Right bang on the minute,
you might say.
Alfie?
I didn't see you there.
You look all different.
What do you mean?
Oh, sort of mumsie.
Um, I--I put my name
down as Mrs. elkins.
Was that all right?
Of course.
Put your name down
as who you like.
It's a free country, isn't it?
I brought you some flowers.
Well, I didn't want to
be seen carrying them.
Oh, that's nice.
Oh, freesias.
How delightful.
I'll put them into
a vase, Mrs. elkins.
What do you think of your
little son, Mr. elkins?
My what?
He hasn't seen him yet.
Here he is.
He's the image of his father.
Yes...
I can see more of me
in him than you.
What are you going to call him?
I thought Malcolm Alfred.
Malcolm bleedin' Alfred?
He'll never forgive you,
you give him a name like that.
Here. He's moving.
Quick, you better take him.
Nah, the mistake
I made with Gilda
was getting involved.
I was having
a beautiful little life,
and I couldn't see it.
There was this manageress
of a dry cleaners.
And I was getting a suit
cleaned in the bargain.
Well, you can't turn
something like that down.
Then there was
this chiropodist woman
from a foot-comfort
service
I was having it off with.
I never had me feet
in such lovely condition.
I was hopping about
like a little fairy.
She's got a little
ginger mustache.
But I find I'm quite
willing to overlook
the odd blemish in a woman,
provided she's
got something else
to make up for it.
Well, that's what we're
all here for, isn't it?
To help one another out
in this life.
Then there was Dora,
this little bird
I was having it off with
every Monday and Wednesday
when her young man was at
his body-building classes.
And there was always
the odd bird
that came my way by chance.
Oh, what a lovely baby.
Yeah.
Is it yours?
No, no.
It's my sister's.
So why I had to be involved
with Gilda, I do not know.
What's that brown
round his mouth?
That chocolate bar I gave him.
Oh, Alfie.
You shouldn't.
You smell a bit milkified.
Oh, I'm sorry, Alfie.
I'll have a wash.
No, I don't mind.
It smells mumsie.
How long are you going
to keep him
breast-feeding?
As long as I can.
It's best for him.
Don't let yourself
get too attached to him.
But I'm his mother.
And I'm his father,
but you've got to be fair.
You've got to think of him.
What about this rich woman?
What rich woman?
The one you was
getting him adopted to.
I got to think about it.
I can't rush into it.
You better make up
your mind quick.
Why?
Because he might
get so drawn to you,
he'll fret his heart out
when they take him away.
Who says they're going
to take him away?
That's what you said,
that a rich woman
was going to adopt him
so he wouldn't want for nothing.
That was a long time ago.
You know what you've had?
You've had a change of heart.
I can see it in your face.
Well, haven't you ever had one?
Yes, but I've
always resisted it.
Lying there in the hospital
feeding him
must have brought it on.
I saw your face changing
every time I went in.
I'm not ashamed of it.
But think of him.
You couldn't raise him
like this rich woman could,
give him the things she could.
We'll see.
I'm going back
to work next week.
She could really
take care of him--
dress him handsome,
feed him beautiful.
Who says I can't
dress him proper?
Look.
Look at that lovely
shawl and cot cover
and all the things
in that drawer.
You can't learn him
to talk nice,
not like this rich woman could.
I can if I try hard.
Before he can talk proper,
he'll be "bleedin' this"
and "bleedin' that."
I won't let him.
These are dry.
Who'll look after him when
you go back to the cafe?
I'm going to the brewery.
It's better paid.
Lugging bleedin'
beer crates about?
When will you learn some sense?
Who'll watch him while
you're at the brewery?
A woman called
Mrs. tippet.
She's got four children
of her own, Alfie.
She'll watch him
from Monday morning
till Friday teatime.
I'll have him all weekend.
I think that's best for him.
And what about--
and what about me?
Do you think I'm going
to spend my weekends
dodging about under wet nappies?
You won't leave us,
Alfie, not now?
I'll have to think about it.
I won't ever ask you
for anything,
not a farthing.
But don't leave us now.
If you do,
I'll--I--
now, don't talk like that.
I haven't said I'll leave you.
I just don't think
you'll do right by him.
But I will.
I'll look after him,
straight up.
I'll never neglect him.
I'm only telling you
the truth, as I see it.
You won't leave us, will you?
Oh, promise me, Alfie.
Let go.
Don't ruckle me sleeve.
I ain't a savage, you know.
I ain't going to scarper.
But don't you start off crying.
Otherwise I'll belt you one.
I don't feel up to it.
Don't. Don't jump up
to him at once.
You'll grow so attached
to one another
he won't even go
to this Mrs. tippet.
Here, mate. That's
enough of that now.
I'll give you
something to cry for.
Come on now.
There, you see?
All you need
is a father's voice.
He's got a hard life
in front of him,
so don't give him
any wrong impression
from the start.
Now, about this
little kid of mine,
he turns out to be
a real quick 'un.
He don't half love it
when I play games with him.
Never wants his mother,
always asking for his father.
Very soon,
I find I'm getting
quite attached to him.
Know what I mean?
Now, that's something
I always guard against
because sooner or later,
that's going to
bring you some pain.
So if a bird
ain't got you one way,
she's got you another.
That's the trouble, isn't it?
Once you get a kid in your life,
it ain't your bleedin' own.
Look at the things
you have to do.
Next, please.
Well, you can't be too careful,
not with hereditary.
No smoking, please.
Queer job
for a bird, isn't it--
photographing people's insides.
Chin on the top, please.
Hands on hips.
Shoulders forward.
What does she think I am,
a bleedin' contortionist?
Nice hands, though.
Firm but gentle.
Know what I mean?
I wouldn't mind her
giving me a--
hold it.
Next thing,
they'll be taking pictures
of what you're thinking.
There'll be some
"x" certificates
knocking around then, eh?
Sorry I'm late.
There was a traffic jam
at Piccadilly.
It's all right.
You're here now.
I brought you some cherries.
Oh, you shouldn't have done.
Well, we never got that rain
they promised us.
It doesn't look like it.
You had a hard morning?
The usual.
I don't like you working
on that brewery bay.
That's no job for a woman.
You get used to it.
What's that?
That's that ring
I was talking about.
Oh, it's heavy.
22-karat.
Solid gold.
Same as I say,
that was my mother's.
They don't make rings
like that today.
They made them to last
in the old days.
Can I try it on?
Yeah, go on.
Eh, no. No, sorry,
but it's--it's bad luck.
They say that once you
put a wedding ring on,
you should never
take it off again.
I don't know if there's
anything in it.
Humphrey...
How would you feel...
Bringing up another man's child?
Um...
Have a cherry?
You mean little Malcolm.
I mean, once we were married,
I could only look on him
as my own child.
I'd try to be
a good father to him,
if he'd have me.
Here.
Can I have this?
Here. Come on, darling.
Have a bit of
the lady's sandwich.
Just a little bit
of the lady's sandwich.
Come on, darling.
Won't hurt you.
Just a little bit.
Come on. Good boy.
I--I must go.
I shall be late for work.
Will you think over
what I said to you
last Wednesday?
I've been thinking it over.
Now I'll tell it to you
for the very last time, Malcolm.
Then you got
to go to bye-byes.
Abou Ben adhem,
may his tribe increase,
awoke one night
from a dream of peace
and saw within the
moonlight in his room,
makin' it rich,
and like a Lily in bloom,
an angel writin'
in a book of gold.
What's an angel?
You know what
an angel is. I told you.
They're up in heaven,
all around god.
Exceeding peace had
made Ben adhem bold.
Who's Ben adhem, eh?
He's the man that
it's all happening to.
Now shut your eyes
and listen, Malcolm.
Lie down...
And don't ask questions.
And to the presence
in the room he said,
"what writest thou?"
The vision raised its head,
and with a look made
of all sweet accord,
answered,
"the names of those
who love the lord."
What a lad he is--
could hardly keep his eyes open,
but he wouldn't give in.
You know what?
He went off just like that.
He'll be a real handful
in a few months' time.
We'll have to be careful
what we say in front of him.
He's as sharp as a needle.
Wait till he sees
that great Teddy bear
I bought for his birthday.
It's about that size,
ever so soft.
The bloke who sold it
said it was
a real rich kid's Teddy.
Here, do you fancy
an hour's kip, girl,
while he's asleep?
Cloth ears, I'm talking to you.
Humphrey's been to see me
twice this week at lunchtime.
What's he after--
a bit on the side?
No. Nothing like that.
We just talked a bit.
Then don't tell me
what you talk about
because I don't want to know.
I can't bear to hear
about a bird and a bloke
having their innocent
talks together.
I think it's more
intimate than the other.
What is he after?
He wants to marry me.
What did you tell him?
That I'd talk it over
with you first.
Why talk it over with me?
You're a free agent.
Malcolm needs a father.
What do you think I am?
I don't mean a weekend father.
I mean a proper father.
Well, we all need
proper fathers.
And proper mothers, too.
There's just not enough
to go around these days.
I don't love him.
I don't know what love is,
the way you birds talk about it.
But I--I respect him.
Well...
You'd better marry him
then, hadn't you?
You got young buster
in there to think about.
I'll be seeing you.
Maybe.
Daddy.
Daddy!
Nice, isn't it?
Goes like a bomb, too.
This car-hire firm
I'm working for,
they have all the best stuff.
Know where I'm off to now?
Pick up a party of publicans,
take them to Brighton
for the races.
Well, you've got
to enjoy yourself.
Once a bloke thinks about
a bird he's finished with--
there's a waste of time.
I'm not picking them up
till half past 11:00,
so I'm just popping in here.
It's about that x ray.
Didn't come out right
or something.
Load of red tape.
Tilt forward, please.
Thank you.
You've done this
before, haven't ya?
Thank you.
Have you been worrying
about anything lately?
Who, me?
No. I'm not
the worrying sort.
Here. You know what?
Gilda's only decided to marry
this Humphrey geezer--
do you get tired easily?
No. I'm full of energy.
Always have been.
I got a letter from her, see?
"I don't love him," she says,
"but I do respect him."
I don't want no bird's respect.
I wouldn't know
what to do with it.
Step on the scales, please.
I haven't got
much time, you know.
She's told me time and again
she loves me.
Loves me for meself,
whatever that may mean.
Have you lost any weight lately?
No. I always
weigh 12 stone 6.
Have done for years.
I've never told her I love her,
except when you
got to say something
for appearances' sake.
11 stone 9 pounds.
Get out of it.
You sure these scales are right?
This suit don't weigh nothing.
9 ounces. Lightweight.
It's a new terylene and mohair.
You don't feel
as though you
got nothing on at all.
The one thing I never
do with a woman,
I never--
take your shirt off, please.
Eh?
Would you take
your shirt off, please?
I never crawled to one.
They either take me
as I am or not at all.
Do you perspire?
I mean, do you sweat much?
Sweat? No.
Tell a lie.
I did sweat last Sunday
at the locarno.
I was dancing then, see,
and I'd had a few beers.
Of course, I use a deodorant
under me armpits.
Just rub it on.
Quite good, they are.
I see.
Do you ever sweat at night?
At nights?
You mean in bed?
Yes. In bed.
Come to think of it,
I did sweat a lot last night,
and I couldn't understand why.
Sit there with your
back to me, please.
Now take a deep breath.
Now breathe out slowly.
She said in her letter,
"Malcolm and me
will be all right
'cause I'll be home
to look after him."
Again. A good deep one.
Hold it.
Oh. Let it out.
"What about you,
Alfie?" She says.
"What will you do?"
Say 99.
99.
I came over quite choked
at that bit.
Again. Whisper it
this time.
99.
Whisper it again.
Of course,
I managed before--
I managed before I met her,
and I'll manage now she's gone.
Do you have a pain in your back?
Pain? No.
Last week, I'm missing her,
so I calls her up.
Funny, I do feel
some pain there now.
A bit to the left.
There?
Higher up.
Yeah. There.
Is it tender?
It is when you prod it.
Turn around, please.
Yeah, so I calls round, see?
And you know what?
She kept me at the door.
Take a deep breath.
But Malcolm must have heard me
'cause he kept
yelling "daddy."
Breathe out.
She wouldn't let me touch her.
She drew back, first time ever.
99.
100.
Oh. 99.
"I'm sorry, Alfie," she says,
"but I'm playing fair
by Humphrey,
as I did by you."
Do you cough much?
Cough? Nah.
Well, only in the mornings,
but so does everyone.
You know, after the first smoke.
She never wanted no other geezer
when she was with me.
What playing fair
was there in that?
Do you bring anything up
when you cough?
Nah. I just
clear me chest.
That's the point
of coughing, isn't it?
Bring something up,
clear the tubes.
The pair of them are taking
my little son from me.
Sometimes, I can hear him
calling "daddy" after me.
Do you find
you get quickly
irritable of late?
Funny you should ask that,
because I find I do me nut
very easily these days.
Do you sleep well?
Like a top.
The moment my head touches
the pillow, I'm off.
I never wake up till...
I never used to wake up
till it was time to get up.
That's elkins
with an "s."
Know what I mean?
I think so.
And now?
I always wake up dead on
the same time--4 A.M.
No matter how much
I've had to drink or...
Can I be perfectly
frank with you?
Certainly.
No matter who's beside me.
You know what I mean?
Yes. I understand.
I never have been partial
to these all-night sessions
because, for one thing,
I've rarely
found a woman--
you don't mind if I
come out with it straight?
You can tell me everything.
Very few birds can get
into my rhythm of sleeping.
I see.
I find myself
lying there in the dark,
staring at the ceiling.
I keep thinking about this kid.
I was very friendly
with his mother.
Nothing special.
Just an ordinary girl,
but I knew him well, the child.
There's something
I must tell you--
all I wanted was for her
to come back with Malcolm
so we could spend
our Sundays together.
But she never come.
Understand me?
Oh, yes. Perfectly.
Now, if you lose a bird,
you can always replace her.
But with a child,
it's different.
They're each one themselves.
Each one's got
his different nature.
Now, I may not be
the best daddy in the world,
but I'm his real dad.
There's something
I simply must tell you.
He's come out of these loins.
What do you want to tell me?
Look at this.
They can't get away from it.
He's my son.
This is your x ray,
Mr. elkins.
Blimey! Is that me?
Yes, it is.
I'm just a load of ribs.
There are two shadows
on your lungs.
Shadows on me lungs?
What are you talking about?
Look at this patch.
You've got an infection here,
and one here.
Infection?
I can't have.
I ain't been with nobody.
It's not a question--
you got to do
something about this.
We can deal with it.
I want the best
attention there is.
I'll even pay for it.
It's just a question of rest.
I can't rest.
I'm off to Brighton
with a party of
licentious victualers
for a real good blowout.
It's all been booked.
You need rest
in the quiet of the country.
I hate the country.
How can you rest
with all that bleedin'
dawn chorus?
Oh.
What's the matter?
My--my feet
feel like lead.
The sweat is pouring off me.
Now, Mr. elkins,
do keep calm.
These are only shadows.
Shadows?
On me lungs?
I'm bein' eaten away.
This is the end of me.
Oh, god in heaven, help me.
Good afternoon,
Mr. elkins.
Good afternoon.
Here. Once you know
you ain't going to die,
funny how soon
you pull back to normal.
Know what? I used to think
money was everything.
If you've got money,
I used to say,
you can have beautiful birds,
handsome suits, a car.
But those things
ain't a bit of use
without your good health.
Hello, Harry.
Not come yet?
She's run off with the milkman.
Here...
See this chap here?
His name's Harry clamacraft.
He's 35 years old,
married, with three kids.
He's sitting in bed
waiting for his wife
Lily to visit him.
He's had nothing
else on his mind
since last Sunday.
I know for sure she'll be late.
Watch it.
In a minute, he'll
pick up that book
and pretend he's not worried
and he's reading.
There.
What did I tell ya?
He's no more reading than I am.
He's listening
for her footsteps.
I ain't had a single visitor
since I been in here.
I told them all
I'm on silence--
not allowed to talk.
Oy, Harry,
your old woman's here.
Mrs. clamacraft,
come through here.
Do you think I should?
I'm not supposed to.
Course you can.
Come on.
There she is, Harry.
Hello, love.
Oh, Harry, I'm ever
so sorry I'm late.
That's all right.
Now you've come.
She's 20 minutes late.
Now she wastes another
20 telling him why.
I left home in time,
but everything went wrong
at the station.
You look worried.
I was only worried
in case something might
have happened to you.
Here's your
new-laid eggs.
And here's your marmalade.
Bleedin' great chunks
of peel in it.
No wonder he don't get well.
Did that chap come about
the smell in the garden?
He thinks it might be trouble
with the main drain.
Look at him.
Now he's worried about
the bleedin' drains.
How were your last x rays?
I think they're improving.
Next time have him look
at that loose gutter.
It might fall
on you and the kids.
Yeah. Kill
the bleedin' lot.
I will.
How was your sputum test?
Now there's a morale raiser.
They're waiting for the results.
Are you managing all right?
I mean, about money.
Yes. Everything's
going fine.
You sure?
Yes, certain.
They're trying to get through
to one another.
It ain't easy
with their sort of mentality.
Here. See this?
Carla her name is.
Hear how her skirt rustles?
There's something
about that rustling.
I think I'll get on me bed,
just in case.
Don't let me disturb you.
You can take that later.
I know what it must be like
seeing each other
only once a week.
She seems quite nice.
Yes. She's very nice.
I'll just get you ready
for your injection,
Mr. elkins.
Oh, thank you, nurse.
Hmm...
Would you like a banana?
Oh...
Thanks.
Ta.
Did--did
my mother come round?
What?
Oh! Yes.
Was everything all right?
She seemed put out
because I hadn't made the kids
a cooked dinner.
Ah, she's mad
about Sunday dinners.
Young Phil's
missing you ever so.
Is he?
He must have woken up
early this morning.
I could hear him
talking away to himself.
He kept scolding you
for not coming home.
Ah, bless him.
Oh, I seem to have
only just got here.
Don't hurry.
Dirty beast.
I'll get the sister
to give you your
injection after tea.
Tell her to send the blonde.
Don't forget to write.
First thing,
as soon as they've
gone to school.
Give my love
to Phil and Shirley.
I will.
Bye-bye, love.
Eat your eggs.
I will.
Don't worry, love.
I'll be all right in a minute.
I'll look after him.
He hates me going.
I'll soon cheer him up.
Oh, thank you.
You get dependent
on them coming, see?
And it don't do to get
dependent on nobody.
They bring
their fruit and flowers
and tell you
how well you're looking.
After about five minutes,
they're dying for the bell
to go so they can leave.
I know.
I've watched them.
They're no sooner out the door
than they say,
"did you see old Ned?
"Didn't he look rough?
"Keep them insurance
policies dusted.
Don't throw
that black hat away."
I've heard 'em.
Mr. elkins?
Oh, hello, nurse.
You should be in bed.
I couldn't sleep.
I come down
and made meself a cup of tea.
You're not supposed to.
I've been doing
things all my life
I'm not supposed to.
You know what?
I had a horrible nightmare.
You must have had
too much supper.
No, serious.
I dreamt the hydrogen
bomb had fallen
and I didn't get killed.
But I got some of that dust
on me shoulder, see?
So I rushes in this house,
shuts the door,
and who should be there
but little Malcolm.
Who?
Hey? Oh, yeah.
It's this kid I used to know.
And then I realized
that this--
this dust on me,
this poison I picked up,
will kill him.
And I was taking it to him.
I was taking death to him.
But what could I do?
I had to save me bleeding self,
didn't I?
Didn't half make me
feel rough, though.
I suppose it would make sense
to a psychiatrist.
I wish just for once
I could do something
good in me dreams.
It wouldn't cost me anything,
and I'd get a great deal
of satisfaction out of it.
Just goes to show you,
they got you when you're
awake and asleep.
You'll be leaving
here next month.
Yeah. I'll be glad
to get back to London.
It won't be the same
without you around here.
I ain't gone yet, girl.
Would you like me
to give you something
to make you sleep?
There's a good idea.
All right.
Come with me.
Marvelous what you can get
on the national health,
isn't it?
Goodbye, Mr. elkins.
Goodbye,
Mrs. clamacraft.
Bye-bye, love.
You know something, Harry?
What?
These visiting days
ain't doing you any good.
How do you mean?
It takes you a week
to get over one.
If you're not careful,
you'll leave here
in your wooden suit.
That's all I live for,
to see her.
You got to live for
yourself, not for others.
You'd have to do without her
if she got killed.
Don't talk like that.
All I'm saying is,
it don't do
to get attached to nobody
like that in this life.
What you don't
understand--
yeah?
What you
don't understand--
what?
What?
Is the bond between
husband and wife.
What I do understand
is human bleedin' nature.
Here. How do you know
your missus ain't
got a geezer outside?
Say another word
about my wife--
Harry! Harry! Harry!
Harry, don't get aeriated.
Harry. Here, sit quiet.
Here, have a fag.
The doc says
I'm not to smoke
more than five a day.
Take no notice of him.
No, all I meant was,
with a bird,
you can never tell
where it's been
or what it's done.
Would you mind saying "she"?
You're talking about my wife.
She or it, they're all birds.
What you got to do, Harry,
is start living for yourself,
like I do.
They won't keep me here long.
But, Alfie, I miss the kids,
especially the youngest.
Now, just listen to me, Harry.
Listen to me for a minute.
Supposing tonight
you was to snuff it,
know what I mean?
You're rotten--
no, just supposing.
That's it, have a giggle.
That's all life is, a giggle.
Say your old woman
picks up with a bloke
and brings him home.
Not Lily. She wouldn't.
Why not?
She ain't bad.
She got
a fair little figure--
not my type, but still...
Anyway, she introduces
this bloke
as uncle bill.
Your kids would get
a big kick out of it.
Not young Phil.
He wouldn't.
He'd be the first,
specially if
uncle bill brought toys.
He wouldn't buy Phil with toys.
Next thing, your missus
tells the neighbors
the kids need a dad.
She'll blame it on the kids.
What are you getting at?
I only want you to see the truth
and start getting better.
For the first month
after you're gone,
your wife and kids
might take flowers
to the cemetery.
But once she's married
and the kids
call uncle bill "dad,"
your grave will become
a mass of weeds.
If you came home
six months later,
your kids would ask uncle bill,
"dad, who is it?"
If you don't stop,
I'll knock your bloody head in!
Harry, all I want is
for you to see life,
see what it is
and what it does to you.
I--I never wanted
to hurt you, Harry.
I never want to hurt anybody.
No. I suppose not.
But you do, Alfie.
But you do.
Want a game of draughts?
Yeah, all right.
Come on.
Alfie!
Great.
Alfie, just like old times.
How are you doing?
I'm all right, all right.
I feel all right.
I've got a gaff
lined up for you.
I'm not used to all this noise.
Come on.
I've had six months
of peace and quiet.
I'd be dead scared
to take a car
through the streets.
I got just the job
for you, then--
all the fresh air you want.
Street photography.
Doing it meself now.
Where?
Up at tower hill.
Tons of tourists.
Chat the birds up easy.
They're asking for it
half the time.
Nothing to it--
"hold it, lady.
More to the left."
Three for 12 and a Tanner.
He's a nice gentleman.
You can have it on your own
if you don't like him, love.
You got film in that camera?
Are you loaded?
Yeah.
Oh, good morning.
Come on, lady.
Give us a great big smile.
Here you are, sir.
Not today.
I don't want
my photograph taken.
I can't blame you.
What about the young lady?
Nor does she.
What about it?
One on your own?
All right.
I think I will.
Vacationing?
No.
Immigrant?
In a way.
Married?
Sometimes.
Now?
No. Not now.
How do you want me?
I got two positions--
straight up or sideways,
depending on your nationality.
I'll have you against the ships.
All right.
I've always been partial
to the Navy.
Now, you look
a real treat there.
We've no time to waste here.
We got a fast film in today.
Allow me, madam.
He's getting a bit
choked up, isn't he?
Don't let it worry you.
It doesn't.
It doesn't seem
to worry you either.
I never let any man worry me.
I see what you mean.
Now, that's lovely.
Can you hold it?
I'll do my best, young man.
Put a jerk in it.
I'll put a jerk in you.
Hold it.
Lovely. That's
a real beauty.
Now the close-up.
Lick your lips.
Strewth.
Now watch the Dickie bird.
Now what's your address?
And your telephone number?
That's three of each.
Be 15 shillings, sir.
Haven't you got any change?
No, I haven't.
I'll have to go look for some.
Keep the bloody change.
'Ello! How about
a little souvenir?
You can have an enlargement
for 4 and 6, sir.
I got just the job
for you, Nat says.
Plenty of fresh air.
Know what?
I got the flu twice
in six weeks.
I went back to
the hire-car lark...
With the, uh, rolls here.
It's very nice
of you to come, Alfie.
Wasn't it, lil?
Yes, it was.
If I'd known you'd be here,
I wouldn't have come.
I didn't mean that.
Of course not.
She looks real tired,
don't you think so, Alfie?
I'm all right.
You got to think about yourself.
Otherwise, you'll never
get out of here.
Yeah, but...
Can you give her
a lift in your car?
Oh, Harry, please, no.
It's a long way
for her by train.
Yeah. I'll
take her back.
It's a pleasure.
He'll take you back.
She didn't want to come,
and I didn't want to take her.
We both agreed,
to please Harry, see?
Looks real ribby though,
don't she?
To brighten her up,
I'm taking her a roundabout way,
to show her
a bit of the scenery.
Well, you can only try,
can't you?
How would you like
a nice cup of tea?
I don't want to be any trouble.
That's all right.
One thing about driving a rolls,
they're pleased
to see you anywhere.
Know what?
When she smiles
that little smile of hers,
I'm quite touched by it.
Yeah, now I look at her,
she ain't so ugly after all.
It must be hard
on you, girl--
old Harry being away so long.
Still, I'll say this for him,
he could hardly wait
for those visiting
days to come round.
Don't worry about him, Lily.
He'll be home soon.
Of course he will.
Cheer up.
Well, what I'm going to do,
old Harry will never know.
And even if he did,
he shouldn't begrudge me--
nor her, come to that.
And it will round off
the tea nicely.
I don't know what
you must think of me.
I bet you ain't been
with many blokes
besides Harry.
I haven't been with anyone.
Where you going, love?
London.
It's a big place
for a little girl.
Hop in.
Hello, frank.
What do you want to eat?
I'm not hungry.
Just a cup of tea, please.
You must eat something.
No, thank you.
Just tea with sugar.
Hello!
Hey!
How you doing?
Watch your loading ropes, frank.
They look a bit dodgey.
Ta.
What's the fancy dress for?
Got a rolls outside, don't I?
You're almost a stranger, Alfie.
Why didn't you turn up?
Sorry, darlin'.
I couldn't make it.
Uh, a small tea
and a slice of
buttered toast, please.
You won't get far
on cups of tea.
I'll be all right.
Who's the mystery?
That one, frank brought in.
You want to watch it, Alfie.
That's frank's bird.
It's not my type, anyway.
I'll just go check those ropes,
see they're all right.
You O.K.?
A bit dead in here
though, isn't it?
I think I'll have a tune.
They ain't half
got some old ones,
ain't they?
Yes.
Did you come in with frank?
Yes. Why?
He's a good bloke,
frank. Good mate.
Yes, he seems nice.
Yeah. He'd share his
last cigarette with ya.
Very good-hearted
is frank.
You know what?
He'll even share his birds
with his mates.
One bloke told me
he'll even lend you his wife...
Like the Eskimos do.
I wouldn't fancy that.
Well, I mean, she's
so bad-tempered.
I didn't think he was married.
He's got at least one wife.
Being a long-distance
lorry driver,
he's away from home
every other night.
Funny, some blokes, aren't they?
I wouldn't like
anything like that--
sharing a girl--
would you?
No.
Where are you making for?
Well, London.
Any particular place?
Not really.
I'd like to get a room
and a job, if I could.
Here. I might be
able to help you.
I know the personnel officer
of a big toffee factory.
Could I see you in London, then?
See me in London?
I could take you there.
But I'm--
I've got a rolls
Royce out there,
radio, heater--
the lot.
But I shall have to tell
that man frank first.
Can't risk that.
He'll knock your block off.
Mine, too.
See that door there?
Well, 50 yards down the road
is a telephone kiosk.
You wait for me there.
I don't like doing that.
You don't want to be
frightened of me.
I ain't a wolf, you know.
Go on, before he comes back.
You don't want sharing, do ya?
No.
No, course you don't.
Go on, there you go.
Would you please tell
that driver I came in with
that I'm sorry,
but I've had to go.
I'll tell him.
How much do I owe you, Flo?
1 and a penny.
You ain't going yet, Alfie?
I'm in a hurry all of a sudden.
What about your toast, then?
Give it to frank.
He could do with a slice.
See ya.
See ya, Alfie.
Did you see the way
he lapped it up?
Can't see what they all
see in him.
Frank will go raving mad
when he comes back.
Good.
Sit back and enjoy
yourself, girl.
Do your folks at home
know where you're going?
I haven't got any.
Oh, there must be somebody.
I want to make a new
start in London.
Well, I reckon you've
landed on your feet.
You'll have a great
little life with me.
♪ baby, I'm sorry...
It ain't come up too bad,
has it?
All it needed was a good wash
and a bit of care and attention.
It's quite dainty.
You know what I mean?
Here. I no sooner
take a pair of socks off
than it washes them.
And it can cook, too.
A bit limited on the menu.
Mostly Lancashire hot-pot
and steak-and-kidney pie.
They blow you out a bit.
But it does do
a marvelous egg custard.
I ain't never tasted
nothing like it.
And it's pretty fair
on the other and all.
A bit on the shy side,
but I find it makes
quite a change these days.
Oy, turn it down a bit, Annie.
♪ Baby, I'm sorry
♪ oh, baby,
I'm sorry... ♪
It's in love, see?
Now, when it listens
to that stuff,
it daydreams that the bloke
who threw it over
will one day want it back.
What a bleedin' hope.
Just watch how it works.
Scrub, scrub, scrub.
It takes some birds like that.
Not all of them.
Can I get you
a cup of tea, Alfie?
Take it easy.
You always want to
be doing something.
Here, I had
a bird once--
a big, fat thing
it was--
got crossed in love
or something.
The bigger they are,
the harder they fall.
She used to sit in front
of the fire all day long,
smoking cigarettes
and drinking tea,
till her shins
were burned red raw.
"Get us a cup of tea,
bracken-shins,"
I said to it one time.
"What?" It said.
"You paralyzed?"
I soon got rid of it.
Are you visiting your friend
at the sanatorium?
Old Harry? Yeah.
You fancy a ride
in the car, girl?
I've some washing to do.
You're always bleedin' washing.
Why don't you take a rest?
I feel better if
I'm doing something.
If it makes ya feel better,
I won't stop ya.
Punishes itself, you see.
That way, life can't
get at it the same.
What time will you
be back, Alfie?
When I go out that door,
I don't know what day
I'll be back,
let alone what time.
I'm what is called a free agent.
Sorry.
I just thought
I'd have your meal ready.
Make a meal
that's always ready--
hash or stew or something.
I thought I'd do
something special.
Get those boots for
me, will you, girl?
See? Even she's
started asking me
when I'll be back.
Know what?
That little remark
could be the writing
on the wall.
Annie, when are you
going to start using
those gloves I bought you?
You'll ruin your hands,
what with all that
scrubbing and whatnot.
They don't matter.
They may not matter to you,
but they matter to me.
Nothing puts me off more
than a woman getting hold of me
with hard, horny mitts.
You got pretty little fingers.
They're like a child's.
Look after them for me.
Sometimes, it gets
a dead, ghostified look
come over its little face,
as though it were
all sick inside
with love or something
and its poor bleedin' mind
was stumbling about,
looking for a corner to rest in.
Take the other night,
for instance.
After what we'd just
been through together,
it made me really mad.
After all, there's a time
and a place for everything.
Even your thoughts
have a proper place.
Sorry, Alfie.
Forget him, girl.
I'm here and in the flesh.
Blimey, she looked dead guilty.
Know what?
I was sorry I spoke.
"Alfie," I says to meself,
"she's as human
as you are."
Well, I'll be off now, girl.
Like to give me
a brush-down?
Shall I say you'll be
back about 7:00, Alfie?
Say what you like.
Whether I'll be or not
is another matter.
You have something ready.
If I'm here, I'll eat it.
If I'm not, I won't.
You know what, Annie?
You're a nice-looking girl,
only you want to
brighten yourself up.
Don't mope about depressed.
You got to think of others.
So long.
Take care of yourself, Alfie.
I didn't like leaving it
there on a Sunday,
scrubbing away.
But what could I do?
You know what I mean?
I couldn't take it with me.
Going up in the world, ain't I?
Do you know
what the rents are here?
15 quid a week.
That's including
central heating, of course.
You'll never guess
who I'm calling on.
Well, I wouldn't have
believed it meself
three months ago.
I'm here, girl.
That's life, ain't it?
You can never tell
what's round the corner.
Know what I mean?
Down one minute, up the next.
You drop a Tanner, look
around, what do you find?
Ruby!
Hello, baby.
Hold it! Gotcha.
She's in lovely condition.
Ooh...
Ooh! What are you
so impatient about?
What do you think?
Don't kiss my ear.
You know what it does to me.
Come on, what about it?
Let's at least
have a drink first.
Whiskey?
You haven't got a beer,
light ale, or something?
Yes, I've probably got
a beer on the ice.
She gets all this lot
off income tax.
Business expenses, see?
She owns three hairdressers.
The thing I like about Ruby,
she's a mature woman.
When she gets hold of you,
you can feel a lifetime
of experience
in her fingers.
I find I'm going in more
for that sort of woman
these days.
Here! Don't you dig
your nails in again,
like you did
last Thursday night.
I got scratches
all down me back.
I may do more than
that to you today.
Great long wheals they are.
She dug her nails right in.
She's had two husbands.
Both dead.
And I've a good idea
what they died of.
She don't keep asking
do you love her,
like young birds do.
She don't never mention love.
She knows what she wants,
and she's going to get it...
If there's any going.
Cheers.
Alfie...
Don't you ever think about
bringing your girlfriends
flowers or candy?
Yeah, I often think about it,
but I never do it,
not unless they're in hospital.
Don't put your wet glass
on my polished table.
You know, you're
getting bleedin' fussy.
I'm not getting bleeding fussy.
Yes, you are.
I am not fussy!
Hello.
Ah!
She's in beautiful condition.
You're a little sexpot,
ain't ya?
Am I?
You're a little
lust-box, ain't ya?
My little lust-box.
I might settle down with her.
With a wife like Ruby,
you wouldn't want
nothing on the side.
You know what I mean?
Ha ha ha!
Bedroom.
Here. Come and have
a look at this a minute.
Great, ain't it?
Have you caught the ceilings?
Look at the size of that bath.
King-size.
It's a bit of a tight squeeze
with the two of us in it,
but you can have a lot of fun
splashing about and whatnot.
Do you know
there have been times
I felt lucky to get
out of that bath alive?
♪ He found himself another gal ♪
♪ The dirty rotten hound
♪ he found himself
another creole miss ♪
♪ So now you've met
another guy ♪
♪ Slowly take your time
♪ give away too much,
and you are lost ♪
♪ Now he's telling you a lie ♪
♪ Smiles as sweet as lime
♪ baby, Sally, baby,
you've been crossed ♪
♪ Well, don't waste
your time, Sally ♪
♪ Find another guy...
Hello, lace.
Hello, Alfie.
♪ Don't waste your time, Sally ♪
♪ Comin' through the rye
♪ get up and go, Sally
♪ don't sing too low, Sally ♪
♪ At least he didn't
take your dough, Sally ♪
♪ Go, Sally, go ♪
Have you got the car
outside, Alfie?
Know what? I got this bird
Annie from up north
staying at my pad.
She can't half cook.
What's bleedin' cooking
got to do with it?
She don't like it
if he don't come
home for meals, eh?
No. She does some
handsome nosh-ups--
steak-and-kidney pie,
Lancashire hot-pot.
I love her cooking, I do.
I thought you was
looking a bit blown out.
What do you mean, blown out?
It's just the appearance,
you see, Alfie.
What appearance?
Well, you look all puffed up,
blown out,
sort of ponsified.
Ponsified?
I've never felt fitter
in all my life.
He wasn't saying you wasn't fit,
was you, Lacey?
No, you just look
different, that's all,
don't he?
What's bleedin'
different about me?
That bird Annie of yours,
she's putting a block on you,
and you can't see it.
Looks that way to me, mate.
She's only looking after me.
Looking after you?
In 12 months, you won't
recognize yourself.
You'll be stuffed to
the ears with that hot-pot.
♪ Far away to fight the foe ♪
♪ Now I hear
the bugles callin' ♪
♪ And I can
no longer stay... ♪
♪ Well, goodbye, Dolly,
I must leave you ♪
♪ Well, goodbye,
Dolly gray... ♪
Oh, how you going, mate?
I thought it was you.
Remember that day you
come in the busy bee?
What day was that?
You was in chauffeur's uniform.
Oh, yeah.
What about it?
You didn't, by any chance,
slope off with a little
girl called Annie
when my back was turned?
Me? I don't know what
you're talking about.
You're a bloody liar!
Watch the suit.
It just come back
from the cleaners.
♪ Well, goodbye, Dolly
♪ I'm gonna
leave you... ♪
♪ Somethin' tells me
I am needed ♪
♪ Far away to fight the foe ♪
♪ Now I hear
the bugles callin'... ♪
♪ Goodbye, Dolly
♪ I'm gonna leave you
♪ goodbye, Dolly gray
♪ well, goodbye, Dolly
♪ I've got to leave you
♪ though it grieves
my heart so ♪
♪ Somethin' tells me
I'm needed ♪
♪ Far away to fight the foe ♪
♪ I hear the bugles callin' ♪
♪ I can no longer stay
♪ but, Dolly
♪ I'm gonna leave you
♪ goodbye, Dolly
♪ gray ♪
Is that you, Alfie?
Yeah, it's me.
I'm late, ain't I?
Start ruckin' me.
What happened?
You've got an awful black eye.
Blimey! He's injured
me for life!
Where's that steak you bought?
I've made you steak-
and-kidney pie with it.
I'm fed up
with hot-pots
and steak-and-kidney
pies.
Can't we have something
out of a can for a change?
Corned beef or spam?
Handsome grub, that was.
You said you liked my
steak-and-kidney pies.
If I get that lot on top
of a skinful of beer,
I'll hardly be able to
draw me bleedin' breath.
I'll feel full up,
blown out, ponsified.
You always said you
loved that feeling
of being really full.
What I loved once
and what I love now
are two different things.
And where's
my button-down shirt?
Your blue one?
In the drawer.
No, the pink one.
I washed it.
It'll soon be dry.
I only wore it a couple hours.
I thought it would feel fresher.
You only wash to fill in
your bleedin' time.
Why should I?
To get him out of your mind.
To get who out of me mind?
That bleedin' Tony you
write about in your diary.
Alfie, have you been in my bag
and read my diary?
Why shouldn't I?
You shouldn't
because them's
me secret thoughts.
You ain't entitled
to secret thoughts,
not living with me.
Everyone's entitled
to secret thoughts.
Then you shouldn't
write them down
and let me see them.
I only wrote them
to get them out of me.
Here's what I think of you,
your secret thoughts,
and your bleedin'
steak-and-kidney pie!
And don't take nothing
that don't belong to you either.
Don't let your custard spoil.
It's in the oven.
Annie?
Annie!
Come back!
I didn't mean it!
Annie!
Come in.
You're a bit early, girl.
I didn't want to be late.
Is he coming?
Yeah, about 2:00 he
said he'd be here.
Here, give us your bag.
Blimey, your hands
ain't half cold.
You ain't worrying, are you?
A bit.
Yeah. You're all
dark under the eyes.
I couldn't sleep last night.
Ah...
Well...
And, uh, you can
get ready for him
when you want to.
Thanks.
I've let meself in for
something this time,
all right.
It was that day I took her
out to the river, see?
Right about three months
ago, it was.
That was something I thought
I got for nothing.
It don't never work out
that way, does it?
So I agrees to help her
and lay it all on.
It was the least
I could do--
Knowing old Harry and all.
See what I mean?
Come in, mate.
Well, here we are.
What do you mean, here we are?
I mean you've come
to the right place.
This is the young lady
I talked to you about
on the phone.
Pleased to meet you.
Ain't you got
your gear with you?
Don't ask questions.
Oh, sorry. Right,
well, this is the room
where you can examine
this young lady.
And why should I examine
this young lady?
Well, you've got to, ain't you,
before you do it?
Before I do what?
Do what you come to do.
Be quiet, Alfie.
There must be some mistake.
You are the bloke--
the gentleman I talked to
last Thursday, ain't you?
Alfie, please be quiet.
Don't worry, my dear.
Now I must have a serious talk
with you both.
Are you two married?
Us two married?
Blimey!
Do we look it?
No. I mean,
she's a married woman,
but I'm a single man.
Is there any chance
of you getting married
in the near future?
I doubt that.
What do you say, Lily?
But you are the putative father.
The what?
Me?
I'm nothing. I'm just obliging
a friend.
Well, that's unusual.
It's very unusual.
You are the man who...
Is going to help me?
Her old man's
in a sanatorium, see?
She's had a moral lapse.
See what I mean?
I'm not quite sure that I do.
It will never happen again.
The only reason
she needs helping
is that her marriage
would look very dodgey
if her husband come out
at this stage of the game.
She got three other
kids as well.
Where do you fit in?
She had no place to go.
That's most altruistic.
I, uh, hope you both...
Appreciate the seriousness
of this case.
To terminate a pregnancy
after more than 28 days
is a criminal offense
punishable in a court of law
with seven years' jail.
Do you understand this?
Yeah.
Not only that,
but it's a crime
against the unborn child.
It's a course never to be
embarked upon... Lightly.
Therefore I must ask you
to consider all
the circumstances thoroughly
before you go through
with your decision,
since afterwards it will be too
late to change your mind.
Have you given the matter
your fullest consideration?
What do you say, Lily?
I've no way out.
And you've decided
to go through with it?
Yes, I must.
Then I might be able
to help you.
Thank you.
Um... Yes. Oh, yes--
have you got the money?
Eh? Oh, yeah,
the money.
The young lady got it.
It will be 30 pounds.
25. That was the
figure we discussed.
Very well then, 25.
Right. Very well.
Um, right, young lady.
If you'd care to follow me.
I'll need some boiling water.
Oh, yeah, the kettle's
on the stove in there.
Good.
I hate anything like this.
My understanding of women
only goes as far
as the pleasure.
When it comes to the pain,
I'm like every other bloke.
I don't want to know.
Have you done?
Almost everything I can do.
Can she go home now, then?
Good lord, no.
Don't you understand?
It's only been induced.
It hasn't happened yet.
That comes later.
If her temperature
rises rapidly,
give her two of these.
I'll leave you six.
How will I know?
Well, uh, if she
starts to sweat,
give her two.
Here, mate, don't you think
you ought to stay
and see the job through,
considering how much
you've been paid?
Two if she sweats.
How you feeling, girl?
He gave me these tablets
to give to you.
Take two if your
temperature goes up.
You do look old, girl.
He got his money
easy... Eh?
Ohh!
Not too loud.
My landlady will hear.
I can't help it!
The pain!
Lily.
God, this pain!
I'm sorry, Lily.
I'm--I'm sorry.
I had to do it.
If my landlady heard,
she'd have the ambulance here,
doctors, police, the lot.
Then all this
would have been for nothing.
You see what I mean?
That's why I had to do it.
Shh, shh, shh, shh.
Lily, Lily.
Shh, shh, Lily, Lily, Lily.
Lily, Lily, Lily,
shh... Shh.
Shh... Shh... Shh.
Shh... Shh, shh.
Lily, Lily.
Is there something
I can get you, Lily?
Eh?
Would you like a cup of tea?
No. You go.
I'm better on my own.
There's nothing you can do.
You'll be all right, will you?
Eh?
Sure you'll be all right?
I know it don't look nice,
going off and leaving her.
But what do look nice
when you get close up to it, eh?
Here, come on.
Oh, you naughty boy.
You're keeping everyone waiting.
Suzanne Elizabeth,
I baptize thee
in the name of the father
and of the son
and of the holy ghost.
Amen.
And now we join together
in the family prayer
of Christians.
Our father, which art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name,
thy kingdom come,
thy will be done
on earth as it is in heaven.
Who's daddy's best boy, eh?
Who's daddy's best boy?
Who's the best boy in the world?
Lily...
Is it all over?
Yes.
I'll be ready to go in a minute.
There's no hurry,
girl. No hurry.
Don't.
Eh?
Don't go in there.
I could have dropped
on the spot with the shock.
All I was expecting
to see was...
Well, come to think of it,
I don't rightly know what
I was expecting to see.
Certainly not this
perfectly formed... Being.
I half expected it to cry out.
It didn't, of course.
It couldn't have done.
It could never have had
any life in it.
I mean, not a proper
life of its own.
No, I suppose not.
Still...
It must have had
some life, of course.
And as it lay there
so quiet, so still...
It quite touched me.
And I started praying
or something,
saying things like, uh,
"god help me"
and things like that,
and then I starts to cry.
Straight out.
The tears were running down
me face, all salty,
like I was a kid meself.
Crying for him, you mean, alf?
No, no, not for him.
He was past it.
For me bleedin' self.
It don't bring it home
to you what you are
when you see a helpless
little thing like that
lying in your own hands.
He'd have been quite perfect.
And I--I thought
to meself...
"You know what, Alfie?
"You know what you done?
You murdered him."
Well, there's nothing
you can do about it now, alf.
Will you lend me 25 quid, Nat?
Don't be bloody funny.
That's all I've got
in the world.
I'll give you this watch
as security.
If I haven't paid you
back in two weeks,
you can sell it.
I don't want no security.
Thanks very much, Nat.
Well... That's that.
You all ready?
Come on.
I'll run you home.
I'd sooner go on me own.
You say that again,
you will go home on your own.
I want to.
O.K. By me.
There's a bus to Waterloo
or a green line all the way.
This is for little Phil.
Who?
Phil, your youngest,
the one that writes
all them squiggly letters.
What is it?
You want to see it?
I bought it a long,
long time ago...
For a little kid I used to know.
Catch.
Tell him it's from
his uncle Alfie.
Come with me.
I'll take you home.
I'm definitely going
to settle down
with this Ruby.
I'm fed up
with being on the move.
You know, I find
I'm not stalking
these young birds anymore.
Hey, Ruby!
Where are you, girl?
Alfie?
Yeah, I thought
I'd give you a surprise.
I'll be right out.
Uh, make yourself a drink.
All right.
Uh, I was sleeping.
I've got a headache.
I took a pill.
Oh, sorry.
You said you were
on a job today.
Yeah, but it fell through.
Want a drink?
No, thanks.
Maybe you better go, darling.
I've got a splitting headache.
All right, then.
Better have these
now I've brought them.
Alfie, what a thing
for you to do.
I--I never thought
I'd live to see the day.
I like surprising a woman.
You certainly did that.
Look at the wrapper.
They're not off a barrow.
I can see that.
Well, they're lovely.
Really lovely.
Thank you.
I'll go. You take
an aspirin, girl.
I will.
That's new.
New, what?
That radio.
Where'd you get that?
I picked it up cheap.
You'll ring me tomorrow?
I'll--I'll be
all right then.
I'll come around lunchtime.
We might have a session.
Why not?
Right.
See you.
Alfie.
Yeah?
I'm sorry about the headache.
I'll make it up to you.
Sure.
What's that?
What?
That.
It's a guitar.
What, you doing it
with groups now?
Don't be so disgusting.
And the radio.
You got a bloke
in there, haven't you?
It's none of your damn business.
Pick him up cheap, too?
There's no one in there.
I honestly thought
you had a headache.
What a mug I've grown into.
Get out. I have
a splitting headache.
Why him?
Better than me?
What's he got that I haven't,
apart from long hair?
Well?
Come on, let's have it.
What's he bleedin' got?
He's younger than you are.
You got it?
"He's younger than you are,"
that's what she said.
Anybody would think
I was doddering about
on bleeding crutches.
Trouble is I still keep
thinking about her.
I can't get her out of me mind.
Who'd have thought a ruddy
great lust-box like her
would have found her way
into anybody's feelings?
She might have looked
a hard case,
but underneath
she was quite mumsie,
and she was
in beautiful condition.
Do you know, I'm beginning
to think she was beautiful.
After all,
it ain't through the eyes
that you feel beauty.
It's how the heart
hungers for something
that makes it beautiful.
Coo-ee.
Siddie.
Alfie, hello.
I ain't seen you in ages.
You didn't turn up.
Oh, look, I can explain that.
Ain't half missed you.
I like that gear.
Where you going?
I got the car around the corner.
What about it?
No, I can't. I'm going
to meet me husband.
It's nice material.
Still, you always was
a snappy dresser.
What about Sunday then?
I'm not sure.
Come on.
Same time?
Same place?
We'll see.
I'll wait for you
for about five minutes.
Don't forget your napkin.
I'm like the boy scouts,
I am--
always prepared.
See you then, eh?
Maybe.
You know what?
When I look back
on my little life
and the birds I've known,
I think of all the things
they've done for me
and the little
I've done for them.
You'd think
I've had the best of it
all along the line.
But what have I got out of it?
I got a Bob or two,
some decent clothes,
a car.
I got me health back,
and I ain't attached.
But I ain't got
me peace of mind,
and if you ain't got that,
you ain't got nothing.
It seems to me if they
ain't got you one way,
they got you another.
So what's the answer?
That's what
I keep asking meself.
What's it all about?
Know what I mean?
Come on, boy.
Come on.
♪ What's it all about,
Alfie? ♪
♪ Is it just
for the moment we live? ♪
♪ What's it all about
♪ when you
sort it out, Alfie? ♪
♪ Are we meant to take
more than we give ♪
♪ Or are we meant
to be kind? ♪
♪ And if only fools
are kind, Alfie ♪
♪ Then I guess
it is wise to be cruel ♪
♪ And if love belongs
only to the strong, Alfie ♪
♪ What will you lend
on an old golden rule? ♪
♪ As sure as I believe
♪ there's a heaven
above, Alfie ♪
♪ I know there's something
much more ♪
♪ Something even nonbelievers ♪
♪ Can believe in
♪ I believe in love, Alfie ♪
♪ Without true love we
just exist ♪
♪ Alfie
♪ until you find
love you've missed ♪
♪ You're nothing, Alfie
♪ when you walk
♪ let your heart lead the way ♪
♪ And you'll find love
any day, Alfie ♪
♪ Alfie