Sir, we got
the CPU on-line. No problem.
Good. Stand by in Operations.
OK, let's go.
Are you all right?
Yes.
Sir...
they sealed off this wing at
both ends, welded the doors...
and blocked off the stairs
with heavy equipment.
But it looks like
the barricade didn't hold.
-Any bodies?
-No, sir.
Last stand.
Must have been
a hell of a fight.
Looks that way.
All right, Drake, this way.
We should be able to cut through
the med lab to Operations.
Lieutenant.
Gorman.
Are those the same ones?
Careful, Burke.
Looks like
love at first sight to me.
Oh, he likes you, Burke.
Two are alive.
The rest are dead.
"Surgically removed
before embryo implantation.
"Subject Marachuk, John J.,
died during the procedure."
They killed him taking it off.
Yo, Hicks.
I think we got something here.
Behind us.
One of us?
Apone, where are your people?
Anybody in D-Block?
Negative.
We're all in Operations.
Talk to me, Frosty.
Let's keep moving, baby.
It's moving.
Which way?
It's coming straight for us.
Straight up.
Fuck!
Hold up.
Ripley.
Hey, shh, it's all right.
It's all right.
Grab her, Corporal.
Don't be afraid.
Come on. We won't hurt you.
Shh. It's all right. It's OK.
Come on out. Come on. Easy.
I got her. Ow! Damn!
Don't let her go.
She's under the grill!
Frost, get your light up here.
Where'd she go?
She's on the other side.
Shine the light!
Here. Here.
Keep back. Don't scare her.
Grab her. We're gonna lose her.
Damn it!
Wait.
It's OK. It's all right.
Don't be afraid.
See?
Wait. No, you don't.
It's OK.
You're gonna be all right now.
Shh.
Easy. Easy.
It's gonna be OK.
It's all right.
You're gonna be OK.
Shh, shh, shh.
Easy. Easy.
What's her name again?
Rebecca.
Now think, Rebecca.
Concentrate.
Just start at the beginning.
Where are your parents?
Look, Rebecca, you have to try-
Gorman, give it a rest,
why don't you?
Total brainlock.
Physically, she's OK.
Borderline malnutrition,
but no permanent damage.
Come on. We're wasting time.
Try this.
It's a little hot chocolate.
There you go.
Whoop.
That good, huh?
Uh-oh.
I made a clean spot here.
Now I've done it.
Guess I'll have to do
the whole thing.
Hard to believe there's
a little girl under all this.
And a pretty one, too.
You don't talk much, do you?
Smoking or non-smoking?
Tell me what
you're scanning for.
PDTs.
Personal data transmitters.
Every colonist had one
surgically implanted.
If they're within twenty klicks,
we'll read it out here.
So far, zippo.
I don't know how you
stayed alive...
but you're one brave kid,
Rebecca.
Newt.
What'd you say?
My name's Newt.
Nobody calls me Rebecca
except my brother.
Newt.
I like that.
I'm Ripley.
It's nice to meet you.
And who is this, hmm?
Casey.
Hello, Casey.
What about your brother?
What's his name?
Timmy.
Is Timmy around here, too?
Maybe hiding like you were?
Any sisters?
Mom and Dad?
Newt, look at me.
Where are they?
They're dead, all right?
Can I go now?
I'm sorry, Newt.
Don't you think you'd be safer
here with us?
These people are here
to protect you.
They're soldiers.
It won't make any difference.
Need anything else?
Hello, Bishop.
Do you need anything else?
No.
Nice pet you got there.
Magnificent, isn't it?
Yo! Stop your grinnin'
and drop your linen!
Found them.
They alive?
Unknown, but it looks
like all of them...
over at
the processing station...
sub-level three...
under the main cooling towers.
It looks like
a goddamn town meeting.
Let's saddle up, Apone.
Aye, sir.
Let's go. They ain't payin' us
by the hour. Head 'em out.
OK, Frost, you're driving.
It's OK. Don't worry.
It'll be OK.
I want
a straight "V" deployment...
second team on left flank.
Advance on axial six-six-four.
Tracker on-line. Set the V-gain
to filter R-F ambient.
Hudson, tracker on-line.
Left and right, little buddy.
Forty meters in,
bearing two-two-one...
there should be a stairwell.
Check. Got it.
You want sub-level three.
Let's go, people.
Hudson, you got the point.
Hicks, watch our tails.
Nice and easy.
Check those corners.
Watch your spacing.
You heard the man.
Don't bunch up. Stay loose.
Your transmission's
showing a lot of break-up.
Probably getting some
interference from the structure.
Use those lights.
Next one down,
and proceed on a two-one-six.
Roger.
That's a two-one-six.
I'm not
making that out too well.
What is it, Hudson?
You tell me. I only work here.
What is that?
I don't know.
Proceed inside.
Watch your fire
and check your targets.
Remember, we're looking
for civvies in here.
Easy.
Tighten it up, Frost.
We're getting a little thin.
Nice and easy.
Looks like
some sort of secreted resin.
Yeah, but secreted from what?
Nobody touch nothing.
Busy little creatures, huh?
Hot as hell in here.
But it's a dry heat.
Knock it off, Hudson.
Lieutenant,
what do those pulse-rifles fire?
Ten millimeter
explosive-tip caseless.
Standard light
armor-piercing round. Why?
Look where your team is.
They're right under
the primary heat exchangers.
So?
So if they fire their weapons
in there...
won't they rupture
the cooling system?
Oh, ho ho. Yeah.
She's absolutely right.
So what?
This whole station is basically
a big fusion reactor.
Right?
So she's talking about
a thermonuclear explosion...
and, "Adiós, muchachos."
Oh, great. Wonderful.
Shit!
Look.
Uh...Apone.
We can't have any firing
in there.
I want you to collect
magazines from everybody.
Is he fuckin' crazy?
What do we use, harsh language?
Flame units only.
I want rifles slung.
Sir, l-
Just do it, Sergeant.
And no grenades.
You heard the man.
Pull 'em out. Let's have 'em.
Come on, Vasquez.
Clear and lock.
Damn!
You, too. Give it up, Ski.
Crowe, I want it now.
Give it up.
Right on, Vas.
Let's go. Give it up.
Frost, you got the duty.
Open that bag.
Thanks a lot, Sarge.
Hicks, cover our ass.
Head 'em out, people.
I like to keep this handy
for close encounters.
I heard that.
Any movement?
Nothing.
Zip.
Holy shit.
Newt, go sit up front.
Go on!
Now!
Steady, people.
Let's finish our sweep.
We're still Marines,
and we got a job to do.
Keep it moving.
Easy.
-Top!
-What?
We got a live one!
You're gonna be all right.
Please...kill me.
Stay calm. We'll get you out.
It's gonna be all right.
We've got to get her
out of here.
What is it, Dietrich?
What's going on?
Convulsion!
Ohh!
Dietrich, get back!
Aah! Aah!
No!
Frost, flamethrower!
Get back! Flamethrower! Move!
-Movement!
What's the position?
I can't lock in!
Talk to me, Hudson!
Multiple signals.
They're closing.
Go to infrared, people.
Look sharp!
What's happening, Apone?
We can't see anything in here.
Pull your team out, Gorman.
I got readings
in front and behind.
Where, man?
I don't see shit.
He's right.
Nothing's back here.
Something's moving,
and it ain't us!
Oh, shit.
Tracker's off-scale, man.
They're all around us, man!
Jesus!
Maybe they don't
show up on infrared at all.
Aah!
Frost!
Come on!
Aah!
Jesus Christ, Apone!
What is going on?
Wierzbowski
and Crowe are down!
Dietrich, Crowe! Sound off!
Frost! Frost!
Aah!
Wierzbowski!
Let's rock!
Yeah!
Who's firing? God damn it!
I ordered a hold fire.
They're coming out of
the goddamn walls! Let's book!
Uh, Apone...
I want you to lay down
a suppressing fire with...
Vasquez, Drake,
hold your fire, God damn it!
Are you copying me?
Lay down a suppressing fire
with the incinerators...
and fall back by squads...
Say again?
All after "incinerator."
Lay down a suppressing fire
with the incinerators...
and fall back...
Aah!
Sarge!
Apone, talk to me.
Apone? Talk to me!
He's gone!
Get them out of there!
Shut up!
Hicks, whoever's left,
get the hell-
-Shut up!
-God damn it!
Where's Apone?!
The Sarge is gone!
Let's get the fuck out of here!
Let's go, Marines!
Hudson?
Vasquez?
Hudson, look out!
Get it!
Hudson!
Hicks! Hicks!
It's too much!
Fall back!
I told them to fall back.
They're cut off!
Do something!
Fuck!
Keep movin'!
Hold on, Newt.
Ripley,
what the hell are you doing?
Turn around!
That's an order!
Get off me, damn it!
God damn it, that's an order!
You had your chance, Gorman.
Come on!
Come on, Drake!
Yeah!
Let's move it!
Come on. Let's go! Let's go!
It's blocked, man.
We got to go around!
Open the door! Hicks!
Drake, we are leaving!
Run for it!
Shit!
Let's go!
Drake, come on, man!
Drake, come on!
Aah!
No!
Fire in the hold!
He's gone!
No! Drake's out there!
Put it out!
Drake's coming!
He's gone!
No, he's not!
Forget him ! He's gone!
Get on the goddamn door!
Eat this!
Aah!
Ripley! Go, go, go!
Whoa!
Oh.
It's all right! We're clear!
Ripley,
you've blown the transaxle!
You're just grinding metal!
Come on, ease down.
Ease down.
You OK?
I'm all right.
Get away from me, man!
Lieutenant.
What happened to Gorman?
I don't know...
maybe a concussion,
but he's alive.
No, man, he's dead!
Wake up, pendejo!
I'm going to kill you!
Back off.
Right now.
Somebody get me a first aid kit.
Hey. Hey, look.
The Sarge and Dietrich
aren't dead, man.
Their signs are real low,
but they ain't dead.
Then we get them.
-We don't leave people behind!
-I ain't going back!
You can't help them !
You can't.
Right now they're being cocooned
just like the others.
Oh, dear Lord Jesus,
this ain't happenin', man.
God damn it.
This can't be happenin', man.
This isn't happenin'!
We've got
seven canisters of CN-20.
I say we roll them in there
and nerve gas the whole nest.
It's worth a try, but we
don't know if it'll affect them.
Let's bug out and call
it even. Why even talk about it?
I say we take off and
nuke the entire site from orbit.
It's the only way to be sure.
Fuckin' "A"!
Hold on one second.
This installation
has a substantial dollar value.
They can bill me.
OK, look.
This is an emotional moment
for all of us, OK?
I know that.
But let's not make
snap judgments, please.
This is clearly an important
species we're dealing with...
and I don't think you or I
or anybody has the right...
to arbitrarily exterminate them.
Wrong.
Yeah. Watch us.
Maybe you haven't been
keeping up on current events...
but we just got
our asses kicked, pal!
I'm not blind
to what's going on...
but I cannot authorize that kind
of action. I'm sorry.
Well, I believe Corporal Hicks
has authority here.
Corporal Hicks is...
This operation
is under military jurisdiction.
Hicks is next in chain
of command, right, Corporal?
Yeah.
Yeah, that's right.
Yeah. Look, Ripley...
this is a multimillion dollar
installation, OK?
He can't make that decision.
He's just a grunt.
Uh, no offense.
None taken.
Ferro, do you copy?
Standing by.
Prep for dust-off.
We need immediate evac.
Roger. On our way.
I say we take off,
nuke the site from orbit.
It's the only way to be sure.
Let's do it.
Let's go.
Pick it up, Hudson.
Pick it up, baby.
All right. Set him down here.
Move it, Spunkmeyer.
We're rolling.
Hold on a second.
There's something-
Just get up here.
I'm in. Ramp closing.
Spunkmeyer.
God damn it.
Well, where the fuck-
Run!
Well, that's great.
That's just fuckin' great, man.
Now what the fuck
are we supposed to do?
We're in some real
pretty shit now, man!
Are you finished?
You all right?
I guess we're not
gonna be leaving now, right?
I'm sorry, Newt.
You don't have to be sorry.
It wasn't your fault.
That's it, man.
Game over, man! Game over!
What the fuck
are we gonna do now?
What are we gonna do?
Maybe we could build
a fire, sing a couple of songs.
Why don't we try that?
We'd better get back
'cause it'll be dark soon...
and they mostly come at night.
Mostly.
That's everything, right?
This is absolutely everything
we could salvage...
out of the APC wreckage.
We got four pulse-rifles
with about fifty rounds each.
That ain't so good.
We got fifteen
of these M-40 grenades.
Don't touch that.
Dangerous, honey.
Is that the only flamethrower?
Yeah. It's only
half-full, but it's functional.
And another one's damaged.
I don't know about that one.
But the good news...
we got four of these
robot sentries...
with display
and scanners intact.
They really kick ass.
They'll come in handy.
How long after we're declared
overdue can we expect a rescue?
Seventeen days.
Seventeen days?
Hey, man, I don't wanna
rain on your parade...
but we're not gonna last
seventeen hours.
Those things are gonna come here
like they did before, and-
Hudson! Hudson!
This little girl
survived longer than that...
with no weapons and no training.
Right?
Why don't you put her in charge?
You better just start
dealing with it, Hudson.
Deal with it,
because we need you...
and I'm sick of your bullshit.
Now get on a terminal
and call up a floor plan file.
Construction blueprints.
I don't care.
Anything that shows the layout.
-Are you listening?
-Yeah.
I need to see air ducts,
electrical access tunnels...
sub-basements...
every possible way
into this complex.
We don't have much time.
OK.
OK, I'm on it.
Hudson!
Just relax.
I'll be in med lab.
I'll check on Gorman,
continue my analysis.
Fine.
You do that.
This service tunnel...
must be how
they're moving back and forth.
That's right.
It moves from
the processing station...
right into the sub-level.
Come down on that.
OK, come over.
Hold it. Go back.
Punch that in there.
No. It's back here.
OK.
There's a pressure door
at this end.
Couldn't we put a remote
sentry unit in the tunnel...
then seal that door?
That'll work...
but we gotta figure on them
getting into the complex.
That's right, so...
we repair the barricades
at these two intersections...
Right.
...and weld plate steel over
these ducts here and here...
and here.
Then they can only come at us
from these two corridors.
Right. Then we put
the other sentry units here...
and here, right?
-Right.
-Outstanding.
Now all we need
is a deck of cards.
Let's move
like we've got a purpose.
Affirmative.
Do your thing, baby.
Come on, Vasquez,
let's get out of here.
"A" and "B" sentries
are in place and keyed.
Roger.
Stand by. Arming now.
Test it, Hudson.
-Do it.
-Fire in the hole!
Great.
Let's get the hell out of here.
We're sealing the tunnel.
Come on, baby.
For what it's worth.
I want you to put this on.
What's it for?
It's a locator.
Then I can find you anywhere
in the complex on this.
It's just a precaution.
Thanks.
Doesn't mean we're engaged
or anything.
All right, what's next?
Last stop.
Get in.
Scoot down.
That's good.
Now lie here and have a nap.
You're very tired.
I don't want to.
I have scary dreams.
Well, I bet Casey
doesn't have scary dreams.
Let's take a look.
Nope. Nothing bad in there.
See?
Maybe you could just
try to be like her.
Ripley, she doesn't
have bad dreams...
because she's just
a piece of plastic.
Right.
I'm sorry, Newt.
There.
My mommy always said
there were no monsters...
no real ones, but there are.
Yes, there are, aren't there?
Why do they tell
little kids that?
Most of the time it's true.
Did one of those things
grow inside her?
I don't know, Newt.
That's the truth.
Isn't that how babies come-
I mean, people babies?
They grow inside you.
No. That's very different.
Did you ever have a baby?
Yes, I did.
I had a little girl.
Where is she?
She's gone.
You mean dead.
Here.
Take this.
For luck.
How's that?
Don't go, please.
Newt, I'm gonna be
right in the next room.
And you see that camera?
I can see you
through that camera...
to see if you're safe.
I'm not gonna leave you, Newt.
I mean that.
That's a promise.
You promise?
I cross my heart.
And hope to die?
And hope to die.
Now go to sleep...
and don't dream.
Sneak.
The molecular acid oxidizes...
after the creature's death,
completely neutralizing it.
Bishop, that's interesting,
but it gets us nowhere.
I'm trying to figure out
what we're dealing with.
Let's go through it again.
They grab the colonists,
they move them over there...
and they immobilize them
to be hosts for more of these.
Which means there would have
to be a lot of these parasites.
One for each colonist.
That's over a hundred, at least.
Yes. That follows.
Each one of these things
comes from an egg, right?
So who's laying these eggs?
I'm not sure.
It must be something
we haven't seen yet.
Hey, maybe
it's like an ant hive.
-Bees have hives.
-You know what I mean.
There's, like, one female
that runs the whole show.
Yes. The queen.
Yeah. The mama.
And she's badass, man.
I mean big.
-These things ain't ants.
-I know that.
Bishop, I want
these specimens destroyed...
as soon as
you're finished with them.
Mr. Burke gave instructions...
they were to be kept alive
for return to the Company labs.
He was very specific about it.
Those two specimens
are worth millions...
to the bio-weapons division.
If you're smart, we can both
come out of this heroes...
and we will be set up for life.
You're crazy, Burke.
Do you know that?
Do you think you can get
a dangerous organism...
past ICC quarantine?
How can they impound it
if they don't know about it?
But they will know
about it, Burke. From me.
Just like they'll know
you were responsible...
for the deaths of one hundred
fifty-seven colonists.
Wait a second!
-You sent them to that ship.
-You're wrong.
I just checked
the colony log...
directive dated 6-12-79,
signed Burke, Carter J.
You sent them out there
and didn't even warn them.
Why didn't you warn them, Burke?
What if that ship
didn't even exist?
Did you think about that?
I didn't know.
So if I made a major
security situation out of it...
everybody steps in...
and there's no
exclusive rights for anybody.
Nobody wins. I made a decision,
and it was wrong.
It was a bad call, Ripley.
Bad call?
These people are dead, Burke!
Haven't you any idea
what you've done?
I'm gonna make sure
they nail you right to the wall.
You're not gonna sleaze your way
out of this one.
Right to the wall.
Ripley.
You know,
I expected more from you.
I thought
you'd be smarter than this.
I'm happy to disappoint you.
What's going on?
They're coming.
-Where?
-In the tunnel.
Here we go.
"A" and "B" gun
tracking and firing.
Multiple targets.
Look at those ammo counters go.
"B" gun's down 50 percent.
Man, it's a shooting gallery
down there.
Sixty rounds left on "B."
Forty...twenty...ten.
"B" gun's dry. Twenty on "A."
Ten...five...
That's it.
Jesus.
They're wall-to-wall in there.
They're at the pressure door.
Man, listen to that.
Bishop here.
I'm afraid I have some bad news.
Well, that's a switch.
It's very pretty,
but what are we looking for?
That's it.
Emergency venting.
That's beautiful, man.
That beats it all.
How long till it blows?
Four hours...
with a blast radius
of thirty kilometers...
equal to about forty megatons.
We got problems.
I don't fucking
believe this!
Vasquez,
close the shutters.
Why can't we
shut it down from here?
The crash
caused too much damage.
An overload was inevitable
at this point.
Oh, man, I was getting short.
Four more weeks and out.
Now I'm going to buy it
on this rock.
Give us a break!
Four more weeks.
Oh, man.
We need the other
drop-ship from the Sulaco.
Can't we bring it down
on remote?
The transmitter was on the APC.
It's wasted.
I don't care how.
We better think of a way.
Think of what?
We're fucked! We're doomed!
Shut up! What about
the colony transmitters?
The uplink tower
at the other end?
The hard-wiring between here
and there was damaged.
We can't align the dish.
Somebody's gonna
have to go out there...
take a portable terminal
and patch in manually.
Yeah, sure. With those things
running around?
You can count me out.
We can count you
out of everything.
I'll go.
You go, man.
What?
I'll go.
I'm the only one qualified
to remote-pilot the ship.
Yeah, right, man.
Bishop should go.
Good idea.
Believe me,
I'd prefer not to.
I may be synthetic,
but I'm not stupid.
How long?
This conduit runs
almost to the uplink assembly-
one hundred eighty meters.
Say forty minutes
crawling there...
an hour to patch in
and align the antenna...
thirty minutes
to prep the ship...
and about fifty minutes
flight time.
It's gonna be close.
Good luck.
See you soon.
Watch your fingers.
Oh.
Vaya con Dios, man.
This is unbelievable.
Twenty meters and closing.
Fifteen.
How many?
Can't tell. Lots.
"D" gun's down 50 percent.
"C" gun's right behind it.
It ain't stopping 'em.
Jesus, it ain't stopping 'em.
A hundred and fifty
rounds on "D."
Come on, baby. Come on.
One hundred rounds.
Come on, come on.
"D" gun's down to twenty.
Ten.
Damn it!
Wait! They're retreating.
The guns stopped them.
You're right.
Next time
they walk right up and knock.
Yeah, but they don't know that.
They're probably looking
for other ways to get in.
That'll take 'em a while.
-Maybe we got 'em demoralized.
-Shut up.
I want you two
walking perimeter.
Move!
Hey, listen.
We're all in strung-out shape...
but stay frosty and alert.
We can't afford to let
one of those bastards in here.
All right. Vámonos.
How long's it been
since you got any sleep?
Twenty-four hours?
Hicks, I'm not gonna end up
like those others.
You'll take care of it,
won't you?
If it comes to that,
I'll do us both.
Let's just make sure it doesn't
come to that, all right?
All right.
Hey, I want to introduce you
to a personal friend of mine.
This is an M-41A pulse-rifle,
ten millimeter...
with an over-and-under
30 millimeter grenade launcher.
Feel the weight.
OK, what do I do?
Pull it in tight here.
-Right.
-Lean into it.
All right, it will kick some.
When the counter
reads zero here, you...
-I press this up?
-That's right.
Get another one in quick.
Slap it in hard.
Now you're ready
to rock 'n' roll.
-What's this?
-The grenade launcher.
I don't think you want
to mess with that.
You started this.
Show me everything.
I can handle myself.
Yeah, I noticed.
How do you feel?
All right, I guess.
One hell of a hangover.
Look, Ripley, I just want-
Forget it. Excuse me.