Andrew! Andrew Hardy!
If you're not down to breakfast
in 1 minute, I'll come up and get you.
I've been taught
never to come to breakfast...
...before doing my morning ablutions.
You know, Mrs. Hardy,
cleanliness is close to godliness.
Milly! Milly, come down here,
will you? Hurry!
Coming, Emily.
- Why Emily, dear, what's the matter?
- Milly, I think I'm going insane.
Oh, nonsense.
Now what is it, what's wrong?
Well, there you are.
Recipe for a chocolate pudding.
Read that.
Remove the mixture from the icebox,
add four eggs and...
Continued on next page, column two.
Pour it down the sink.
- Pour it down the sink?
- Add four eggs and pour it down the sink.
Now, am I insane or not?
Oh, somebody's cut out
a picture or something.
And we've been reading
'How to clean clogged drain pipes.'
Well, I thought that was a silly way
to make a chocolate pudding.
There's something very funny
going on around this house.
Only this morning I found two pages
cut out of the Home Fashion Guide.
I'm trying to finish this dress
without the pattern.
Maybe some pictures of flowers
on the other side and Andy cut them out.
What's happened to that boy?
I've called him twice.
Andrew Hardy, for the third time.
I'm practically there, Mom.
Gee, where's the fire?
- Fire?
- The way you expected me to get dressed...
...and downstairs I figured
maybe you thought I was a fireman.
Good morning.
Good morning, Aunt Milly.
Good morning, dear. Oh, Andy,
the pins! Did you prick yourself?
I'll get it, Mother.
Andy, how many times
have I told you?
Now sit down and wait
till I'm ready.
Not this morning. I'm botanizing.
I've got to collect 20 specimens
of wild flowers.
On Saturday? Is Mother's little lamb
feeling all right?
My dear mother, I'm studying Botany.
It's apparent you've never known
what it is to commute with nature.
Commune with nature.
Andy, stop eating that donut.
Botanically speaking, this isn't eating.
This is osmosis.
As in plants, so in human beings.
Eating is just osmosis on a larger scale.
Now take Dianthus careophyllus
or Rubus idaeus...
What kind of language is that
for a nice boy to use?
It's all right, Mom,
it just means raspberries.
Polly Benedict's father on the phone.
He wants Dad to meet him at orphan's
home positively before 1 o'clock.
Oh, dear, and your father's
gone fishing.
Calm yourselves, ladies,
I'll get the message...
...to the good Judge Hardy
while doing my botanizing.
I know his favorite place to fish.
And if you hurry, maybe you can find him
before he catches anything.
Then we won't have to have
fish for dinner.
- All right, Mom.
- Let's see your Botany specimens...
...maybe I can help you classify them.
Marian, Marian,
would you have me cheat?
Why, do you know that it's dishonorable
for a student to accept help?
Andy! Andy!
Oh, that boy!
Now he's gone without his breakfast.
Don't worry, Mother.
Nature feeds its own.
Don't be silly.
Andy can't eat wild flowers.
Of course, Daphne, there's no chance
of me ever meeting you.
But oh, boy. They can't put you
in jail for dreaming.
Well...
what are you doing here?
I was looking for you, Dad.
In the back of a log?
No, sir.
I'm collecting Botany specimens.
What you want me for?
Oh, Mr. Benedict wanted you to meet him
at the orphanage at one o'clock.
Sounds like trouble.
I hardly got my line wet.
Why don't you fish a little longer and...
Andy, it's taken me
two thirds of a lifetime...
...to learn that when there's
trouble ahead...
...there's no use trying to find
entertainment in the meantime.
So, come on to the orphanage.
Dad, I've been wanting to talk to you
for quite some time now.
Well, I've been around.
Shoot.
You want me to be a success in life,
don't you?
I certainly do.
Well, is it true
that all successful men...
...marry sophisticated women,
you know...
...women of the world.
I hardly think so.
But it'd help, though, wouldn't it?
Have a wife that could handle
chauffeurs and footmen...
and be at home as in a nightclub
as well as in a kitchen?
I see your point.
You know, you're a swell guy, Dad,
but I've often wondered how far
you'd have gone in this world...
...if you'd have married a woman
like Cleopatra.
I don't dare think of it.
What about the nice old-fashioned girls
like Polly Benedict?
I've been going around too steadily
with Polly Benedict.
I'm gonna have a little talk
with her about it.
I see.
Take the first turn for the orphanage.
Now wait for me.
In the meantime you might
cogitate on the fact...
...that Cleopatra brought disgrace,
disaster and death...
...to every man who ever
fell in love with her.
Death, where is thy sting?
Well, hello there!
You're new here, aren't you?
Please, yes, sir.
My name's Francis, please.
I'm glad to know you, Francis.
- Hello, little girl.
- I'm a boy, please.
Hm, you talk like a little girl.
How do you ever expect to grow up
and be a big he-man?
Like you?
Yes, son.
Now look, my boy.
If you go through life
the way you're starting,
people are always going to be taking
your marbles away from you.
Let me give you a little
man-to-man advice.
Now...
The default of the bonds
in your trust fund...
...absolves the Cyrus Carvel estate
of any further financial responsibility.
Default of bonds?
Why, Cyrus Carvel left millions.
Yes, and he left a good half million of it
to maintain his old home for our orphans.
Sixteen homeless orphans
where the founder of Carvel...
...wouldn't want that to happen
any more than we do.
As my son Andrew would say,
'They can't do this to us!'
But that letter, Jim. Those big
New York lawyers can't be wrong.
No? I drew up the trust fund
legal papers myself.
They're absolutely foolproof,
I made sure of that.
Are you positive?
I'll stake my legal reputation on it.
I'm so positive I'll go
to New York myself...
...and personally handle Messrs...
uh, Dabney, Court and Underwood.
Now what's your name?
My name's Butch and what
do you want to make of it?
There, that's swell, that's swell.
Now don't forget anything
that I told you.
Andy!
Hello, Polly.
Just run along and play
with your little bicycle, my little man.
Your uncle Andrew has a very
painful duty to perform.
I'm waiting for my father.
Say, Polly, I'd like to have
a little talk with you.
I'd like to have a little talk
with you too, Andy.
I don't think we ought to go
together so steadily.
What?
Well, relationships like ours sometimes
grow into more serious things.
And a girl of seventeen is always older,
and more mature,
more sophisticated than a boy
of the same age.
Why, you're crazy...
you're crazy, Polly.
- The situation isn't fair to you.
- Fair to me?
Who was it that failed in Geometry
the year I got B+?
And who was it said only last Sunday...
...that the Epistles were the wives
of the apostles?
As Mark Anthony said,
'Et tu, Brute!'
It wasn't Mark Anthony,
it was Julius Caesar.
Wouldn't you be happier with somebody
who could look up to you?
Look up to me?
Oh, my gosh!
Miss Benedict,
there are some girls of 17
that make you seem like a mere child.
A backward child at that.
Good day, Miss Benedict.
Well, I suppose I'll have to see you
at the editors' meeting.
But kindly continue to address me
as Miss Benedict!
Choo-choo-choo-choo-choo.
Well, young fellow,
do you like it here?
You said a mouthful, toots!
The editor-in-Chief
of the Carvel High Olympian...
...requests the gentleman associate
editor to kindly pay attention!
Oh, I've got more important things
on my mind, Beezy.
Botany, for instance.
Say, Andy, can I borrow
your Botany book?
You cannot!
He probably has Botany confused
with Mother Goose...
...and he won't go to bed without it.
Okay, you rat!
The meeting will come to order
to approve the cover for the next issue.
Oh, here it is.
What?
Why, Beezy, you're not gonna put
Cynthia Potter's picture on the cover...
...and call it the most beautiful girl
in the world, are you?
Well, if she isn't, who is?
Maybe the most beautiful girl in the world
don't even live here in Carver.
Andy, please, I practically promised
Cynthia she'd be on the cover.
All in favor of Cynthia's picture.
- No!
Oh...
I vote for a cover with the most...
...interesting achievement
of the month by a student.
And I don't mean boyish pranks.
I hate to agree
with Miss Benedict, but...
- ...I vote for the same thing.
- Oh, I'm ruined.
Well, meeting's adjourned.
Thanks, Andy,
I'll give this back Monday.
Hey, you lay that down, Beezy,
that's my property!
Why, Andy, he doesn't mean
any harm.
Hey, look at this!
Daphne Fowler, Princess Royal
of the 400.
Look, Polly, the book's filled
with pictures of that dame.
Well, of all the ridiculous
little-boy exhibitions.
Andy's got a crush
on Daphne Fowler!
Collecting pictures of a perfectly
awful girl that he's never seen.
I have so seen her.
I... I met her about two years ago.
The first time I met her even,
she liked me more than she ought.
Why, Daphne Fowler goes around
with grown men.
She wouldn't even look twice
at a small-town schoolboy.
Oh, yeah?
Well, she was so crazy about me...
...she asked me to come back
and have the first dance with her...
...when she made her debut.
Then why don't you go?
Well, I have been begging my father
to let me go to New York.
- You could always run away from home.
- Sure, you can hop a freight.
Yeah, maybe you do things like that
and break your mother's heart.
But I've been brought up better.
Furthermore, I doubt if I could even
get away from New York...
...without having to marry her.
But of course he can't possibly
get to New York.
Of course it would be great
if I could get to New York.
But I suppose we all have our crosses
to bear in this unhappy world.
Well, good evening, everybody.
Here it comes.
Here what comes?
What you've been dying to tell us
ever since you got home.
Can't fool me, James Hardy.
I give up.
Well,
to make a long story short,
we're all going to New York City
for a visit.
- New York, all of us?
- How wonderful!
New York?
But we won't know how to act.
There's always Grandmother's book
on etiquette.
New York!
Yes, I've got to lick a big New York
law firm for the orphanage.
How's that sound, Andy?
Uh... why... I can't go to New York.
Well, miracles never cease.
- Why?
- Why, I can't go and I won't go.
Here, here, here, wait a minute.
Why do we have to go to New York?
Why did we have to pick that place?
Why, in New York vice and corruption
forage rampant!
They'll tell you so in the paper.
New York's a sink of...of..
well, it's a sink.
I don't want to go,
I wouldn't be safe there.
Well, I've got to go to New York.
If the mountain won't come
to Mohammed,
Mohammed has to go to the mountain.
What would he want
with a mountain anyway?
You may never have another chance
to see New York.
What has New York have
that Carvel hasn't?
Just a lot of tall buildings.
And what do people do
when they get in tall buildings?
They jump out of windows,
that's what they do.
I tell you New York is a den of evil.
Well, son, New York is evil
in some of its aspects.
But so is every village and city
in the world.
But the fact remains,
we're leaving for New York.
James, you don't really
want me to go.
Why, there's my school,
and the expense.
Milly, when I married your sister
I said whither thou goest I will go.
And I might also have added
'I'll take your sister too.'
As regards your school,
I've already spoken to your principal.
And what about my school, Dad?
I'll miss my classes,
I'll get behind, and I won't graduate.
I'll end up a homeless derelict
in the gutter
Aunt Milly is going to give you
your lessons...
...every day until we get back.
And I've wired Martha Booth
to find accommodations.
Then Andy can have Betsy Booth
for a playmate.
She must be 15 now,
a nice old-fashioned girl, too
I think it's wonderful.
Well, dinner's getting cold.
Come on, Andrew, eat your dinner.
A guy's world comes crashing down
around his shoulders...
...and you offer him corned beef
and cabbage.
Something tells me we have Mr. Andrew
Hardy right where we want him.
Hello!
This is Miss Polly Benedict speaking.
Oh... hello, Miss Benedict.
Yes, I've read the morning papers.
Well, it's not positive that I'm going
to New York with the family.
I don't feel so well.
Oh, you'll feel better just as soon
as you're on the train...
...speeding to the side
of your loved one.
You'll be glad to know
that we're printing the story...
...of your flaming romance with Daphne
Fowler in the high-school magazine.
You're gonna what?
But you mustn't print
anything about me and Daphne.
It's a secret.
Listen, Hardy, Cynthia Potter ain't ever
gonna speak to me again,
so you'd better make good
with that debutante.
Cause when you get home
you'll be the talk of the town.
Talk of the town, huh?
We just know you're going
to send us back a photograph...
...of darling Daphne and you
to illustrate the story.
You what?
You... and Beezy... agreed...
...you're gonna put it
on the cover too, huh?
Yeah... yeah...
Goodbye.
Andrew, we'll meet you
and your father at the station.
Be there early because the engineer
may be in a hurry to start.
And don't forget to turn the gas out
under the coffee pot...
...when your dad's had his last cup.
Well, did you tend to everything
on your mother's list?
Everything but the kitchen stove.
You better do that now.
I don't want any more coffee.
Now what was it Mother
wanted me to do?
Oh, yes, I know...
I'm sure that's what Mother
wanted me to do.
Andrew!
Ugh...
Uuugh...
For goodness' sake,
what's the matter with you?
Don't worry about me, Dad.
Just go on and catch your train.
- Oh, what's wrong?
- I've had a complete nervous breakdown.
One minute I had my health,
the next minute I collapsed.
- Collapsed?
- I saw purple spots in front of my eyes.
Then everything went black.
I think I've got heart trouble.
I've just read a new treatment
for heart trouble.
It consists of grabbing the patient
violently by the back of the neck...
Oh, no, no, no, Dad, please
just leave me alone...
...just let me lie here
and die peacefully.
Andrew Hardy, if you aren't
up on your feet in 3 seconds, I'll...
Ohh...
Oh, well, it was worth trying.
You... you come along.
Andrew, I don't want to pry
into your secrets,
but all this to-do about going
to New York has me worried.
Dad, I can't tell you about that.
But maybe if we sat down
and talked life over carefully...
...for, say, about half hour or so...
And carefully miss the train?
No, Andrew, we're leaving this minute.
- Come on.
- That's, uh... final?
That is final.
Well, we'd better get
a move on then, Dad, because I...
...set the clock back 10 minutes.
You did...
You what?
Come on!
It's stupendous!
- It's unbelievable.
- Even if I see it, I don't believe it.
- James.
- Hm?
- That building.
- What?
It's on fire!
Oh, Mother, that's steam escaping.
I guess I'm nervous about fire.
Andrew, are you sure you turned out
the gas underneath the coffee pot?
Mom, don't I always do
everything you tell me to?
James, Martha Booth's husband
is a rich man.
Suppose she reserves rooms
in some very expensive hotel.
Don't you worry, Mother, I got a telegram
on the train this morning from Betsy.
Her mother and father are out of town,
but everything's okay.
1057 East 49th.
This is what New York City
calls a maisonette.
An apartment remodeled
from one floor...
...of an old brownstone residence.
James, I smell coffee.
Of course you smell coffee.
There's a general housework girl here.
Why, it's Betsy Booth!
Sure, I'm Betsy.
I hope you didn't mind my answering...
...your telegram the way I did.
Oh, hello, Mrs. Hardy!
Do you like the apartment?
Isn't it cute? The servant girl
can't come until tomorrow...
...so I'm making some coffee.
Hello, Andy, gee it's wonderful
to see you!
Will somebody please help me
get out of this apron?
You know, I didn't think you'd get here
for half an hour yet.
Oh, Andy, it's so wonderful to see you.
I guess I said that before,
though, didn't I?
You know... well, welcome
to New York, everybody.
I'm all out of breath, ain't I...
aren't I?
Well, I'm a little out of breath
myself, Betsy.
Don't tell me you got this apartment
and hired a girl all by yourself.
Uh-huh, I sure did.
There, you see, Andy.
Even in New York a nice girl thinks more
about growing up to be a good housewife...
...than dancing the rumble.
Ma, rhumba!
I smell the coffee burning.
Oh, Andy...
I brought my own radio over
for you to listen to.
You see, Mrs. Hardy,
it's only common gratitude,
after all, back in Carvel Andy took me
to my first grown-up party.
Son, how do you do it?
Oh, Dad, she doesn't mean anything.
It's...
Well, it's hero worship, that's all.
Well, my little hero,
let's get unpacked.
Mother, I'll bet this will be one
of the most exciting times in our lives.
Why, I could lick my weight
in wildcats in this town.
Emily, don't tell me you actually
brought this book of etiquette.
Why, darling, that's the way people
conducted themselves...
...way back in the eighties.
Nice people never change.
James, do you think it's all right
for Andy to walk home with Betsy?
- Hm?
- Well, I mean, there are gangsters.
They might take Andy for a ride,
or put him on the spot.
Well, Betsy's a New Yorker,
so of course she carries a gat.
Oh, of course...
Oh, my goodness!
And what I don't know
about New York...
...I've been reading in the guide book
and I can show you everything.
Like the Statue of Liberty,
and Grant's Tomb...
- ...Rockefeller Center...
- Kid's stuff.
Yes, I... I suppose so.
Even if it is a little hard
around Rockefeller Center.
Oh, and here's Saint Patrick's Cathedral.
I was here at a wedding last week.
Aren't weddings wonderful?
I'll never know. I expect
to live and die a bachelor.
Here's where we live, see?
Way up on the top floor.
Sure, very interesting for tourists.
Yeah, I suppose so.
Well, gee, Andy, it was swell of you
to bring me home.
- Oh, nothing at all, Beth.
- Won't you come in?
No, thanks, I've got
to be going home, I...
I've got a desperate problem
on my hands...
It's me against the city of New York...
...and one of us is going to be ruined
in the struggle.
Say, maybe it would help you
if you used Mother's car...
...and chauffeur while the folks
are away.
Say, that would help a lot, thanks.
Only I think that...
...maybe she'd like me to stay
right with the car.
You know, to see that it'd be safe.
Well, sure, that's all right...
I don't mind you riding around with me,
providing you don't ask
any personal questions.
Oh, I won't. I'll just snuggle up
in the corner.
You won't even know I'm there.
What time shall I bring
the car tomorrow?
What time do New Yorkers
usually get up?
What do you care? If there's anybody
you want to see, we'll wake them up.
All right, then let's get an early start.
Say about 6:30?
Oh, well...
I think there might be just
a few people in New York...
...that even we couldn't get up
that early.
Why don't we start about nine?
All right, nine it is.
Goodbye, Beth.
Goodbye, Andy.
Good afternoon, Miss Booth.
Lovely day, isn't it?
Kid's stuff.
Good afternoon, Miss Booth.
And how are you today?
I'll never know.
Good afternoon. There's some mail
on the drawing-room table.
Very interesting...
...for tourists.
Good afternoon, Miss.
Will there be anyone for dinner,
Miss Booth?
I expect to live and die a bachelor.
Mom.
Yes, dear?
If I asked you something
very confidential,
you wouldn't betray me
to your husband, would you?
My husband?
Why, my husband's your father.
Yes...
Oh, I see what you mean.
No, dear, no.
Look, Ma, if you were a stranger
in a strange city,
and you wanted to meet someone
that you'd never met before...
how would you go
about meeting them?
- Them?
- Say one or two, or just one person.
Well, I'd write them
a nice little letter.
Let's look at Grandmother Hardy's
book of etiquette.
That's it, Mom.
Saturate me with etiquette.
Of course a letter like this
couldn't be sent through the mail.
It would have to be delivered
in person.
Gosh, Mom, you must have been
reading my mind.
A letter introducing a young man
still unknown to fame...
...to a lady of fashion
or of distinguished social position.
'Dear Madam, permit me
to present to you my friend...'
'Mr. John Smith,'
Who's John Smith?
It would be you, dear.
Where was I?
'...to present to you my friend,
Mr. Andrew Hardy,'
'a gentleman whose polished manners
and irreproachable character,'
Boy, Mom, that's me all over.
Now, you wait here, Betsy...
and don't follow me.
No, I'll even keep my eyes shut.
- Oh, and don't you look, Prentiss.
- No, Miss Betsy.
Is she in?
- She?
- I mean, is Miss Fowler in?
I have a letter for her.
I'll see that Miss Fowler gets it.
Not this letter. This has to be
delivered personally.
Come in, please.
I'll speak to Mrs. Hacket
as soon as she's free...
...and you can give your letter to her.
- Who's Mrs. Hacket?
- Miss Fowler's secretary.
I'm afraid you won't be able to see
Miss Fowler herself.
Oh...
Won't you sit down, please?
Thanks.
- Oh, Mrs. Hacket.
- Yes, Miss Fowler?
Telephone the fashion show,
say I'm sorry to be late
but I'm leaving here immediately.
I'll attend to it, Miss Fowler.
I know, you get paid by the picture,
that's why you take so many.
I get paid by the job, Miss Fowler,
but my boss wants 20 new poses.
Can we have the head a little more
to the left, please?
Thank you.
Mother.
What is it, young man?
Oh... I have a letter here
for Miss Fowler.
It's a very special letter
and it has to be delivered in person.
I'll take it, please.
No...
Well, there's nothing in it
that a girl's mother shouldn't read,
so I guess it's all right.
What is it, Mother?
Nothing, my dear.
Come with me, please.
- With you?
- This way.
You know, Mrs. Fowler,
it's going to be a real pleasure...
...to make your daughter's acquaintance.
Well, I'm afraid it won't be
as simple as that, you see...
my daughter has a great many demands
on her time and energy.
She can't accept
all the friendship offered.
And... well, friendships aren't
established by letters of introduction.
- They aren't?
- No. You see...
Friendships come as a result
of knowing the same people,
liking the same things,
having common bonds
of mutual interests.
You mean that I couldn't have
a mutual interest with your daughter?
I'm afraid not.
You mean I'm not her social equal?
Well, let us just say that your paths...
...seem to go in different directions.
Well, you know, me... that is,
my family and me...
we're very nice people.
- Honest we are.
- I'm sure of that.
But there are millions
of nice people in the world and...
Well, Daphne can't be friends
with all of you.
You see what I mean.
Yes... I see.
You mean there's no special reason...
...why I should be friends
with your daughter.
- That's it.
- And...
...an awfully good reason
why I shouldn't.
I'm sorry, but, you know,
back where I come from...
everybody has a mutual interest
in everybody else.
Of course.
Goodbye.
Oh... I...
- I hope I didn't cause you any trouble.
- Not at all.
- Goodbye.
Andy...
Andy, darling, what's the matter?
I just aged 50 years.
Wh...what happened just now?
Oh, that's right, I promised
I wouldn't ask any questions.
What happened to me
is a secret I'll carry to the grave.
Where to, Miss Booth?
Anywhere.
Anywhere where I can find some peace.
Grant's Tomb, Prentiss.
'Let us have peace.'
General Grant, you and me both.
Well, let's go on inside.
Maybe the coffins'll cheer you up.
It's a fine world.
Back in Carvel there are people
waiting to laugh at my funeral and...
...here in New York they got coffins
to cheer me up.
Oh, I'm sorry...
I only meant that maybe the coffins
would make you be glad just to be alive.
Hm... there's something in that.
There's something, but not much.
Isn't it impressive?
Now don't you feel glad
just to be alive?
I never before really appreciated
the advantage of being dead.
Oh, Andy, couldn't you tell me
your problem?
I'm a woman, and maybe I could help.
I can't tell anybody.
Tragedy is gnawing at my vitals...
...but I can't tell anybody.
But you mustn't give up.
Look at Ulysses S. Grant.
He didn't give up when things
looked the darkest.
He never had trouble like I got.
All he had on his hands was a Civil War.
Well, then you pretend
that all you have is a Civil War.
Andy, can't you tell me
what your trouble is?
Did General Grant talk
or did he act?
Then you won't surrender?
You'll plan a new campaign?
Betsy, I shall search out
the enemy's weakest point...
...and make use of strategy.
If I'm late for lunch, all the strategy
in the world won't help me with my dad.
Come on!
- James!
- Oh, hello, Milly.
Well, how's the big fur coat
deal coming along?
Emily fall for it?
I've got Emily fooled.
She thinks the coat's for me.
But so far she says they're all
too young or too expensive.
You keep at it. I've wanted her to have
a good fur coat all her life.
But don't let on it's for her
until we get home.
Oh, I won't. She'd pop
right back to the store...
...and exchange the coat
for a new kitchen stove.
- Oh, James.
- Hm?
How's your orphanage business
working out?
Wonder if the children are home.
Milly,
I've been twice to the plush-lined offices
of Dabney, Court and Underwood...
...but it appears that mighty
Mr. Underwood is away on a shooting trip.
No one else around the office
seems to know what it's all about...
...or even think it's important.
So I'm going to court
and force a little action.
- Good.
- But don't tell Emily. She'd only worry.
Hello.
Well, who do you think you are?
Ulysses S. Hardy.
In the matter
of the Cyrus Carvel Estate...
versus the Carvel County Orphanage, Inc.
- Ready for the Orphanage, Your Honor.
- Ready for the Estate.
I'm Underwood.
My office didn't tell me about this...
...until your letter arrived.
Sorry.
Your name is Handy, isn't it?
No apologies are needed, sir,
but the name is Hardy.
Will you explain your petition, sir?
To force the Cyrus Carvel Estate
to resume supporting our orphanage.
If it please the Court, I can save
the taxpayers a lot of money.
Obviously you are not aware of this
amendment to the original agreement.
1931. Signed by Harland W. Wyatt.
President of the Carvel County's
Orphanage, Inc.
At the worst of the Depression,
Wyatt demanded...
...that we switch
the United States Securities...
...in the Orphanage Trust Fund
to European bonds.
I see.
Recent European developments...
those bonds are worthless.
Those European bonds defaulted.
The Trust has no further obligation.
This is Mr. Wyatt's legal acceptance
of the exchange.
The Cyrus Carvel Estate requests
that you dismiss Judge Hardy's petition.
Your Honor, this is a shocking surprise.
May I ask that this matter
be continued until Monday?
Which will give me time
to consider my position.
It is so ordered.
And we are happy therefore
to bring you the voice...
... of the glamourous and glowing example
of young American girlhood.
She who has been called the number 1
debutante of New York society,
Miss Daphne Fowler.
Thank you, Mr. Franklin.
Ladies and gentlemen, as President
of the Dog Lovers Society,
I invite all dog lovers to a benefit
we are giving at the Club Sirocco.
The entire receipts of the Club Sirocco...
...will go to our fund for homeless dogs.
I especially want to meet all the people
who have with me...
...a mutual interest in the welfare
of our little four-footed friends.
Betsy!
- Mr. Andrew Hardy.
- Oh, show him in, please.
- Good evening, Betsy.
- Good evening, Andy.
- Did it come? Where is it?
- Yes. It's there in the guestroom.
- Don't move, don't look, just wait.
- All right.
Betsy, what you're about to behold...
...is something most children
are never privileged to see.
# Alone, alone with a sky of romance #
# Above, alone #
# Alone on a night that was meant #
# For love #
# There must be someone waiting #
# Who feels the way I do #
# Whoever you are #
# Are you, are you? #
# Alone #
# Alone on this night that we two #
# Could share #
# Alone #
# Alone with the kiss that could make #
# Me care #
# And when you come, my promise #
# To be your very own #
# Alone #
# Alone with a heart meant for you #
I'm ready, Betsy, here I come!
Oh...
Ain't I something?
Andy, you're beautiful!
But don't you think there might possibly
be something wrong with the hat?
Yeah, I kinda thought
it was small too, Betsy, but...
...I didn't know how they were wearing
them this season in New York.
But you got a 6 7.8 didn't you?
Oh, Andy, I got mixed up.
I got a 6 7.8 glove
and a 5 1/2 hat.
- Oh... what are we gonna do?
Uh... my Dad's!
Gee, that certainly was
a narrow escape.
- New York must be full of midgets.
- Here, try this one.
Oh!
Your father must have a noble head.
Paper!
We'll stuff it with paper.
We can do it.
Oh, that's my dad's too.
I almost forgot all about a stud.
It certainly does look
like the real thing.
Andy, I don't want to ask
any questions but...
I've heard that the Club Sirocco
is awfully expensive.
Think nothing of it, my child,
Even if it's the swellest joint
in New York...
...they couldn't charge
more than a buck for dinner.
Oh, but they charge much
more than that, Andy.
Oh, I've got money to burn!
However, Betsy, there is something
you could tell me.
- What?
- Well, most likely...
...the food in New York is different
than that of Carvel.
So maybe you could tell me
how to order a magnificent dinner, huh?
Oh, I'm afraid I couldn't.
But I heard my dad say once...
...that if you want to go
to a strange restaurant,
and get the best food...
...just ask the waiter
for the specialty of the house.
Specialty of the house, huh?
Thanks a lot, Betsy, thanks a million.
You've been simply grand.
It's nothing.
You couldn't have done more for me
had you been an adult my own age.
Oh, gosh, I don't want to be late.
Where's my coat?
Andy, are you sure
you've got enough money?
- You know, that Club Sirocco...
- Betsy, please don't worry.
Listen, suppose the dinners are $2,
suppose the dinners are $3...
Oh, but Andy...
Listen, I've got $8 in my bankroll.
With $8 I could buy the Club Sirocco.
- Good night.
# And when you come I promise #
# To be your very own #
# Alone #
# Alone with a heart meant for you #
Your check, sir.
Oh... thanks.
I beg your pardon, sir.
Have you a reservation?
The name, please.
Well... I haven't got a reservation
but my name is Hardy.
Which Hardy is that, sir,
if you please?
- My father's Judge Hardy.
- Oh, Judge, this way, sir.
Uh, I'm in the right place, ain't I?
This is the Club Sirocco...
...where Miss Daphne Fowler's
having her dog lovers party?
That's right, sir.
This is her table here.
Uh...
What time do you expect Miss Fowler?
Not until later.
Your shirt stud, sir.
Oh...
Will you order now, sir?
Some hors d'oeuvres, perhaps?
I'll just take the specialty
of the house.
That'll be caviar Romanoff aux tortoni.
I'll have a double order then.
And after this
what will monsieur have?
Just continue, my man,
the specialty of the house.
Shall I carve it, sir?
Yeah, yeah.
Say, waiter, isn't it pretty near time
for Miss Fowler to arrive?
Later, I believe.
For dessert, sir, may I suggest
another specialty?
Your judgement is beyond reproach.
We call this bombe  la Corsican.
Ice cream with a French accent.
You look like a man
who needs a dog very badly.
A dog?
A worthy charity.
I'll buy one.
Each one autographed
by Miss Fowler in person.
Miss Fowler! Is she here?
Not until later, I believe.
$20, please.
- $20?
- Yes, sir.
Oh, no, thank you, I mean...
That is, I just noticed
that the little dogs...
...they were made of fur and I'm
very allergic to fur, no thank you.
Imagine charging $20
for a little 10c dog like that.
At that rate they'd charge you...
Well...
Waiter.
Excuse me.
Something else, sir?
How much is it costing me
for this dinner?
Um...
$3.75, $4, $12...
in between $35 and $40, sir.
30 or 40?
Yes, sir.
Anything else, sir?
Yes...
You can take me to see the proprietor.
He said he was Judge Hardy's son.
And I don't want to offend
anyone connected with a judge.
I don't seem to recall
any Judge Hardy in this city.
My father is Judge Hardy of Carvel.
What's Carvel?
Some little hillbilly town?
We're not hillbillies.
We wear shoes every day
Oh, well that's a big help.
And dress suits every night too?
I...
I rented this.
Putting on a big front, eh?
You also told Fred here that you were
a friend of Daphne Fowler's.
I did not.
I just asked if she was coming.
I've never exactly met Miss Fowler.
Just an all-around-four-flusher.
You should have seen the way he ordered.
He didn't even glance at the menu.
You could've at least
looked at the prices, couldn't you?
Yes.
But you wanted everybody to think
you were a big shot.
Yes, I did.
Well, what are we going to do
about this $34.75?
Well...
I've got $8 and...
...maybe I could work out
the balance by...
...washing dishes, or I could...
...or I could send you $1 a week...
Please, don't send me
to jail, will you?
You don't want to bring
your poor father...
...down in gray hairs
to his grave, eh?
He's pretty gray-haired already.
Well, I know your type.
You're just a small-town sport,
not dry behind the years yet.
Because you were king of kids
in your own hometown...
...you've got delusions of grandeur.
When I was a boy we used to call
your kind 'too big for their britches'.
But I don't think you even rate jail.
I think you need a good spanking.
Fred, put bub in a taxi.
Be sure the driver
gets the right address.
Come on, son.
- Oh, come in, come in, Betsy.
- Good morning. May I see Andy, please?
He must have got in
pretty late last night.
- We were asleep.
- Oh, I won't wake him then.
Oh, boy, he must have had
a big night last night.
It's time for him to get up.
Andrew.
Andrew! Wake up!
It's Betsy Booth.
Good morning, Betsy.
Good morning, Dad.
Good morning, son.
Gee, you sure look
like a gorgeous wreck.
Come in, please.
Tell me all about it.
Andy, what's wrong?
I don't care to discuss it.
I'm sorry.
I brought back your clothes.
Yeah, I packed the dress suit there...
I was going to bring it back.
At the present time I don't care
to come in contact with my family.
You've been simply wonderful
to me, Betsy,
but I just don't care to talk about
anything now, you know what I mean?
All right.
Well, I... I hope I'll be seeing you
when you feel better.
Yeah, sure, I'll call you as...
...as soon as the world is normal again.
Whenever it is.
Oh, my father's shirt stud,
it's in here all right, isn't it?
The stud, yeah... well, Betsy,
it was a little loose...
...and I thought that maybe I'd have
it fixed before I brought it back.
Oh, fine. My father's very keen
about that stud.
He paid $400 for it.
Bye, Andy.
$400!
Bye, Judge Hardy. And don't be worried
about Andy and me being mysterious.
What I'm worried about isn't Andy.
Bye.
Or maybe it is.
Some mail for you.
It's from Polly Benedict
and F. Bacon Anderson.
F. Bacon Anderson, I presume,
is Beezy?
Bad news?
Andy, I have problems of my own but...
...but I can help you if I could.
- You can't help with this.
- Help with what?
Oh, it's not your fault, Dad,
more than it is mine,
you being born what you are and...
...and me what I am.
What are you?
Dad,
why couldn't I have had a family
who had money,
family trees and, you know,
that kind of stuff?
You have a family tree.
You have parents, and grandparents,
and great-grandparents
like every living soul in the world.
- That's not what I mean.
- Well, what do you mean?
Why couldn't we have had class,
money, and social position?
Why couldn't we have been
somebodies instead of nobodies?
Gee, for the first time
in my life I've realized...
... I'm not as good
as somebody else.
You do, eh?
You get your hat and coat...
and come with me.
What's this place?
This is the Hall of Fame
of New York University.
Dedicated in humble tribute...
to mighty men which were of old
men of renown.
I brought you here
to show you some nobodies...
...that turned out to be somebodies.
I never thought I'd hear you,
my own son,
...deny the very soil you walk on.
The soil that was earned for you...
...by the blood and tears of men
who said that all men in America...
...should be equal.
Equal.
That's funny.
Well, equal in that they shall all have
equal opportunity.
Alexander Hamilton.
Patrick Henry.
Andrew Jackson.
They left you a heritage
of freedom and equality.
A heritage you should fight to keep.
Instead of kicking it around,
sniveling about class,
money and social position.
What's all that talk got to do
with the fact...
...that I've got to go back to Carvel...
...and face the worse punishment
a guy ever had to take?
Punishment.
There's a man over there.
Born a poor boy.
He took quite a bit of punishment.
That was fine 100 years ago,
when a guy had a chance but...
Now there's millions
of people like us that...
Well, I don't want to talk about it.
You don't understand and you never will.
Oh...
- You've reached that age, eh?
- What's age got to do with it?
Back in a little tank-town like Carvel
I might be king of the kids...
...but here in New York I'm...
...just a small-town hick
with delusions of grandeur and...
...and you're just a country judge
that nobody ever heard of.
When a boy's stupid,
he's just stupid, that's all.
Come on home.
Reduced to these basic
chemical elements, therefore,
the human body has a commercial value
of about 90c.
I'll sell out cheaper.
Name me 5 of those elements, Andrew.
Calcium, sodium, phosphorus, iron...
and misery, I guess.
Andrew, have you had a row
with your father?
I thought so.
That's why I suggested your lessons...
... instead of your going with him
to see the Statue of Liberty.
Headache no better, dear?
- The orphanage case?
- Yes.
They got me licked.
And all because Harlan Wyatt
lost faith in his own country.
Oh, those poor children.
And I was so sure of coming to New York
and showing them a thing or two.
I guess this town's too big for me.
Oh don't, dear, please.
Come on, you two,
we can see it beautifully now.
In this city that doesn't appreciate
my husband, I don't think much of.
And I wouldn't hesitate to say it
to the mayor himself.
Well! I'd think that every man,
woman and child in America...
...would be grateful
to what that stands for.
The flame of liberty.
Flame?
James, even if our home is just
a little house in a little town,
there'd be something in the New York
papers if it burned down, wouldn't there?
Mother, is the gas
under your coffee pot...
...all that the Statue of Liberty
means to you?
No, James Hardy, it isn't.
It means that...
that people can't get together
behind somebody else's back...
...and conspire to take away
their privileges.
Not bad, Mother, not bad.
Take away their privileges, huh?
Take away their privileges?
Why, of course!
- Why didn't I think of that?
- Think of what?
Mother, you just said, 'Conspire behind
their back to take away their privileges.
I believe you've saved the orphanage.
Now listen. I'm going to hop a plane
and fly back to Carvel.
So, Marian, you have Andrew down
at the Courthouse Monday morning at 9:30
...with my briefcase and papers...
The Cyrus Carvel Estate versus
the Carvel County Orphanage Inc.
If it please the court,
I'm Judge Hardy's son.
He told me to meet him here
at 9:30 and it's past ten...
He's got to be here soon.
We'll give him every opportunity.
I ask the court to pardon
for being late.
There is one essential point of law.
An agreement entered into
by two parties...
...for the benefit of the third party.
...cannot be amended without
the consent of the third party
And the third party
specifically mentioned...
...in our original agreement...
...is,
I quote...
'The creation and maintenance
of the Carvel Orphan's Home...
for the benefit of all homeless
orphans of Carvel...
...under the age of 18 years.
I would like to amend my petition
to name a new petitioner.
And who is the new petitioner,
Judge Hardy?
Just a minute, just...
Your Honor, this is the new petitioner.
One of the homeless orphans of Carvel
under 18 years of age.
With the Court's permission I should like
to question the petitioner.
Francis, did you ever sign...
an amendment to the original
trust agreement...
...between the Carvel Orphan's Home...
...and the trustees of the estate
of Cyrus Carvel?
No, Your Honor.
It is our contention that Mr. Underwood...
...is therefore obligated to put back
the United States securities...
...eliminated by the amendment.
...and to continue payments
to the orphanage.
If Your Honor please...
...I don't think that I would care
to oppose this new petitioner...
...before a jury of 12 good Americans
and truth.
And if Your Honor will consent
to a further adjournment,
I am certain that we can work out...
...an arrangement satisfactory
to everybody.
- So ordered.
- How does that strike you, Francis?
You said a mouthful, toots.
Off the record, I should like to remark
that in my opinion...
...Judge Hardy has also
said a mouthful.
Certainly nobody in this country wants
to see helpless orphans left uncared for.
Most admirable, Judge Hardy.
- Thank you, sir.
- Next case!
What about my club for lunch,
Judge Hardy?
- I don't want a club.
- Well, what do you want, sonny?
My name's Butch and I want
to go back there.
- What for?
- I want to watch His Honor...
...in the black nightshirt.
Well, supposing I take Butch home
for the day?
My wife and I haven't had children
of ours for 30 years.
- Well, think you'd enjoy him for a day?
- I think I would.
And, speaking of children,
what's become of your son?
Forgot all about him.
Well, I think he went on home.
Well, I'll have the youngster
home by sundown.
- Goodbye, Butch.
- Goodbye, toots.
Dad!
Yes?
Dad,
I just wanted to tell you
how proud I am...
You showing up that Mr. Underwood.
That's not the real point.
But they say he makes over
a million dollars a year.
Did you notice that the court treated me
with equal consideration?
Millions or not.
They did, didn't they?
And the real point is
that I had an opportunity to win.
A small-town judge...
...with no social position
had an opportunity equal...
...with the big-city lawyer.
An opportunity guaranteed
by the law itself.
The mighty men of old made this
that kind of a country.
And that kind of a country,
God willing, it always will be.
Dad, you...
...probably won't forgive me.
You shouldn't ever.
I don't deserve to be your son.
What I'm wondering is, do you deserve
to be any decent American's son.
Gosh, I don't know what got into me.
I guess I was led astray when I put
all my faith into General Grant...
...and he stabbed me in the back.
Yes?
It all just goes to show you
what will happen to a man...
...when he lets love blind him
to the principles of democracy.
Love again, Andrew?
Yeah, love.
I know it doesn't sound very logical
starting out with love...
... and ending up losing
a $400... pearl stud.
A $400 pearl?
Well, I think during this subway ride...
...we'd better have a serious
man-to-man talk.
- Yes, sir.
- But this time...
...start at the beginning,
the very beginning.
The beginning was when debutantes
started to wear strapless evening gowns.
Well, that'll do as a beginning.
Go on.
- Hello, Andy.
- Hello, Betsy, come in.
Andy, you didn't call me
all day today.
- Are you mad at me?
- I'm mad at the world.
I've got more troubles than anybody
since Job in the Bible.
I wouldn't be a bit surprised
if by tomorrow I got boils too.
Oh, you and trouble just naturally
gravitate to each other, don't you?
If you're worried about losing
the pearl stud,
I'm not going to tell anybody
about your wearing it.
How did you know I lost it?
You weren't a very good
actor, Andy.
Now do you feel better?
I'm in more trouble than that.
Why, I don't dare go back to Carvel.
I'd be the joke of the town.
The little children would follow me
down the street laughing.
Won't you please tell me about it, Andy?
It can't do any harm.
And besides, sometimes
a woman's intuition...
...is better than a man's brains.
Betsy, back home I got a crush on a girl
that lives here in New York.
Oh, that's bad.
That's nothing. I kind of boasted
around to some people in Carvel that...
...she liked me.
Doesn't she?
I never even met her.
And then I got double-crossed.
I got double-crossed right in the bosom
of my own family.
My father makes me
come to New York.
I... I don't get it.
I've got to get a picture of her
and take it back home...
...to prove that she's crazy
about me or...
...maybe I can bury myself
on a South Sea island.
I suppose she's awful pretty.
Yeah, I guess so.
But, you know, Betsy, I don't think of her
as being a real person anymore.
She's... she's more like a goal.
Do you understand?
No, I don't, if you've got
a crush on her.
But I haven't... anymore.
Honest, Betsy, I haven't.
I've just got to get her blame picture
or I'll be ruined.
That's all she means to me now.
Yeah, but maybe if you really met her
you'd go crazy about her again.
No, what I've been through
has knocked all that out of me.
No...
- What's her name?
- Daphne Fowler.
Daphne Fowler?
Yes, the number one debutante.
Oh, wonderful!
Hey, are you nuts?
Why are some men so dumb?
- Why didn't you tell me this before?
- Tell you what?
Hello, Stevens? This is Miss Booth.
May I please speak to Miss Fowler?
Thank you.
- You know Daphne Fowler?
- Of course I do!
Hello, Daph?
Daph, it's Betsy.
Oh, that's swell, Daph.
Listen, I want to bring a friend of mine
to your debut Monday night.
Oh, he's a swell guy.
He's an old friend of mine.
Oh, thanks, darling.
Listen, are you gonna wear
that new black strapless...
...evening dress you tried on last week?
Of course, I would. It's stunning.
All right, darling. I'll tell you
all about my friend later.
Bye-bye.
Well, that's settled.
Out of the mouths of babes!
She's a real girl.
Without her makeup on she hasn't
anymore glamour than I have.
- She hasn't?
- Specially when she's not dressed up.
Like on Botany trips.
Daphne Fowler likes Botany?
Uh-huh. Only uh...
...she doesn't get much fun out of it
because flowers always give her hay fever.
Hay fever, huh?
See, she's kind of susceptible to it
because... she's anemic.
In fact, she's so anemic she has to wear
long woolen underwear.
Long woolen underwear?
Gosh, it makes me feel kind of funny.
I know...
Whenever I get disillusioned
I always get a pain in my stomach.
Is Miss Betsy Booth here?
They told me at her home she might...
- I'm Betsy Booth.
- I'm from the insurance company.
Your butler reported a valuable
pearl stud missing.
Oh, well... I loaned it to a friend...
I'll wire him right away in Chicago
and have him send it back.
Have your butler let us know
when the pearl is returned...
...then we won't have to notify
the police.
Police!
So, that's the whole story,
Judge Hardy.
Naturally, I didn't want
the kid's dollar a week.
I know you don't, Mr. Carrillo.
You'd be doing me a favor.
Oh, no.
The show was worth
the price of admission.
At two dollars a week
out of his allowance...
...my son will have reason
to remember...
...New York City for a long,
long time.
$37.25.
I get the idea.
Can I send some champagne
around to your wife?
Oh, no, thanks.
There is one thing.
Somewhere in his ventures...
...my son lost a very valuable
pearl stud.
This one?
Well.
There she is, Andy.
The Number One Glamour Girl.
Are you sure she doesn't make
your heart get jittery?
No. Not a jitter.
I'm kind of fed up on glamour.
I'm going back to the nice
old-fashioned girls.
You know, the girls who can
look up to a man.
Hello, Daph!
Hello, Betsy, how are you?
Oh, you're a knockout
on that strapless number.
I'm freezing in it, you know.
- This is Mr. Hardy.
- Yes...
May I present Mr. Andrew Hardy,
one of nature's noblemen.
I'm most happy to make
your acquaintance, Miss Fowler.
Please, Mr. Hardy,
from one dog lover to another.
Mother, do you remember
Mr. Andrew Hardy?
- How do you do? I'm glad you came.
- Yeah, me too.
Shall we go in, Andy?
See you later, Daph.
Andy, Betsy's told me
the amazing story of your life.
So restrain yourself
until the sixth dance,
lover boy.
There's my pet photographer.
Guaranteed not to let your eyes blink.
Here's where we annihilate
the unbelievers in Carvel.
Oh, gee, Daph, you're swell.
Remember, the party doesn't get good
until after the mob goes home.
Come on.
Come on, Betsy, we're going to get
that photograph. Lead on, Andy.
Betsy, I've been working on Andy,
and he's really crazy about you.
But he doesn't know it yet.
Now, when the party simmers down...
...I'll arrange it for you to sing
and you turn it on hot.
Oh, listen, I've got a song that
if it doesn't wake up Andy Hardy up,
he must be made out of concrete.
# I woke up this morning and the sun #
# was shining but I didn't see it. #
# Think I drank my orange juice #
# But I don't know #
# I wouldn't guarantee it #
# Wore my yellow dress, #
# or was it blue, oh, what's the use? #
# I don't remember #
# Is it Monday, is it Tuesday, #
# Is it June or is it still December? #
# Sat beside my window #
# watched the couples strolling by #
# Felt so sorry for myself #
# I couldn't even cry #
# Finally I pulled the shade #
# I couldn't stand the gaff #
# So I sat down #
# and wrote my epitaph #
# I'm nobody's baby #
# I wonder why #
# Each night and day I pray #
# The Lord up above #
# Please send me down somebody to love #
# But nobody wants me #
# I'm blue somehow #
# Won't someone hear my plea #
# And take a chance with me #
# Because I'm nobody's baby now #
# Believe me #
# No, nobody's baby #
# And I've got to know #
# the reason why #
# Last week I was walking #
# down the street #
# And met a boy and I said #
# Hey, maybe I was meant for you #
# But he only tipped his hat #
# and shook his head #
# Kept on walking down the avenue #
# Oh, nobody wants me #
# I'm mighty blue somehow #
# Won't someone hear my plea #
# And take a little chance with me? #
# Because I'm nobody's baby #
# I'm blue somehow #
# Won't someone hear my plea #
# And take a chance with me #
# There's no denying #
# I'm crying, I'm lonesome #
# On my ownsome #
# I don't mean maybe #
# I'm nobody's baby #
- One more song.
- No, please, it's so late.
One more song, just one more.
- Gee, Betsy, you were terrific.
- Oh, thanks.
- Let's get out of here, huh?
- Sure.
I want to show you something
right here in New York...
...that millions of people
never see in their whole lifetime.
What?
A horse.
Come on.
You don't suppose something
will happen...
...that'll keep you from going
home tomorrow?
No, we have our tickets.
Are you sure it's all right
for you to stay out this late?
You know, it's getting dawn.
I'd stay out even if it wasn't all right.
Well, I wouldn't let you. Your mother
expects me to take care of you.
It gives me the nicest feeling.
You know, I...
I wish I wasn't leaving New York.
Oh, we can write to each other.
Yeah.
And every time I get a letter I'll pretend
you're sending me gardenias.
Like these.
Oh... I'm getting too old
for pretending.
I will send you gardenias.
Only not right away on account of that
allowance trouble that I told you about.
- Are you cold?
- No, I'm not cold. It's...
...it's just like Indian summer.
You know...
You know, you've changed a lot since
the last time you were in Carvel.
- I have?
- Yeah, you're more grown up...
Gee, I completely almost forgot
how swell you were.
Maybe I wasn't as swell
when I was in Carvel...
Or maybe you just didn't notice.
One thing about me
hasn't changed though.
No boy has ever kissed me yet.
You know, I was sitting here
thinking that I...
I wanted to...
I wanted to kiss you...
Then when I think that I do,
then I'm afraid that I don't.
Don't want to?
Sometimes wanting to and not wanting to
is better than wanting to.
I know... I knew you were thinking
about kissing me.
And I was just as afraid you would
as much as I was afraid you wouldn't.
Gosh, this is much too important
to be monkeying around with.
I'll remember that too.
Till we can see each other again.
Betsy,
I'll come back someday.
If you mean that...
...maybe you'd better kiss me
even if we both don't want to.
Someday.
Betsy, hey...
Don't cry.
I know why you're crying.
You're crying because...
Because I kissed you.
It isn't that glamourous to cry.
It's funny. When a girl cries
because you like her...
why, even when her nose is shiny
she's glamourous.
Oh, boy, that's what I call glamour.
I'll bet you...
I'll bet your Polly Benedict
couldn't be glamourous with a shiny nose.
Polly Benedict? Just you wait
until I get back to Carvel.
New York is wonderful,
but it's always good to get home.
Excuse me, everybody.
I've got to fix my hair.
Excuse me, too, I've got a couple
of predatory insects to destroy.
Save me a trip, will you, son?
Drop Francis off at the orphanage.
Oh, Dad, I'm too big to be
carting around babies.
Too big for your britches?
I'm sorry.
Gosh, bub, what a lot of grief you're
gonna go through before you're my age.
James, I smell coffee.
Now, now, Mother, that's...
Wasn't I silly to worry?
I just remembered what I told Andy
was to cancel the milk.
Don't worry about the milk. I personally
told the milkman not to leave any.
Hello, Polly? Have you seen your
advanced copy of the Olympian?
No, I haven't yet.
But it's here. I'll look at it right away.
Hold the wire.
I saw it!
I... I...
But how could it ever have happened?
What are we going to do?
Listen, I'll meet you
at the school right away.
Of course Andy had the cover changed,
but how did he dare?
Oh, Beezy, he did know that girl.
What awful idiots we've been.
Cynthia Potter warned me.
Andy kissed her the first time
he took her out.
I should have known better
than to trifle with a man like Andy.
Beezy, maybe he's been secretly married
to that Daphne Fowler all the time.
Andy Hardy, whose baby is that?
I remember you, sister. You're the little
girl that failed in geometry.
It was to protect this innocent babe's
future that we went to New York.
What?
Oh, the orphanage.
Polly, look. I thought I was dreaming
but they're all the same.
Of course, you printed up the story and I
supplied you with an exclusive cover.
And it's not faked either.
I trust that the younger generation
of this town...
...has learned to respect its elders.
I'm sorry, Andy.
I take back everything I said.
I'll apologize in writing.
Not necessary at all, bub,
you're just too big for your britches.
Take Francis back
to the orphanage for me.
Yes, sir...
I mean, yes, Andy.
Come on. You and me we'll stop
at Cynthia Potter's.
She's just crazy about babies.
You said a mouthful, toots.
So Daphne Fowler was in love
with you all the time.
Well, there's our picture there.
Society's Number One Glamour Girl
trying to coax me for a smile.
Swell girl, Daph.
Sort of a.. adolescent Cleopatra.
- Perhaps you are too mature for me.
- No doubt, no doubt.
But you know, Polly, when I was
in New York I was thinking.
Sophisticated girls, they make you
appreciate old-fashioned girls.
You know, the type that starts to cry
when you kiss them.
Are... are you engaged
to Daphne Fowler?
Daphne? Oh, no.
Just another milestone in my career.
You know, Polly. You used to be
a sweet, unaffected little child.
And I always thought that you
kind of looked up to me.
I do, Andy.
I think...
I think I should cry right now
if you were to kiss me.
That's a good idea. But of course
you don't want to go to extremes.
When you kiss a girl,
as I was telling Betsy,
- Betsy!
- Uh, why, It slipped... it slipped out.
Can I help it
if I have irresistible charm?
That's not charm. That's polygamy.
But, oh, Andy,
how we women love it.
- James, it's lovely.
- You really like it?
It's beautiful.
And since you want us to end up
in the poor house, I'll keep it...
James, you're the best husband
that ever lived.
Gosh, how one's women
do mount up.
Subtitles: Lus Filipe Bernardes
Watch Movies, TV Series & Live Sports
www.admitme.app