Annie!
It's okay.
Everything's gonna be all right.
There, there.
It was only a dream, Molly.
It's all right.
How am I supposed to get any sleep?
It was only a dream.
Everything's all right.
Molly shouldn't be in this room.
She's a baby.
She cries all the time.
She wets the bed.
I do not!
You're the one who shouldn't
be in here!
Brat, stop!
We're gonna get in trouble.
Go, Duffy! Go!
Oh, my goodness! Oh, my goodness!
Cut it out!
I mean it! Do you want
Miss Hannigan to come in?
Go back to bed.
Now. Or you'll have me to deal with.
Blow it out of your old wazoo.
Close your eyes.
Think about your folks.
You're the only one who has folks.
Mine are dead.
Think about the folks who
want to adopt you...
...because they want a little girl with
brown hair and brown eyes.
Oh, my goodness.
Did I hear singing in here?
All right. Fine.
Since we're all so wide awake!
Get up! Get out of bed!
Clean up this mess!
Get dressed!
This room had better be regulation
before breakfast...
...my little pig droppings.
Or kill, kill, kill!
It's in the middle of the night.
"It's in the middle of the night."
If this floor don't shine like
the top of the Chrysler Building...
...your backsides will.
Understand?
Yes, Miss Hannigan.
- What do we say, Annie?
- I love you, Miss Hannigan.
Why any kid would want to be
an orphan is beyond me.
You'll stay up till
this dump...
...shines like the top of
the Chrysler Building.
Kill, kill.
Little pig droppings.
Rotten orphans.
Nobody loves you.
I love you, Miss Hannigan.
Get to work!
Strip that bed!
Scrub that floor!
Polish my shoes!
And I mean...
...start now!
We gotta get out of here
or we'll get killed.
- Cover me up good.
- All you ever do is run away.
Oh, my goodness! Oh, my goodness!
She'll put you in the cellar.
- You'll get whipped again.
- You're gonna get us in trouble.
Molly, shut up!
- I'm gonna tell.
- And I'm gonna rearrange your teeth!
Stomp on her foot!
What are you all
just standing around here for?
You're supposed to clean
the bathroom and the kitchen...
...before lunch, my little
pig droppings.
And if you skip the corners,
there will be no lunch.
And we're not having hot mush today.
We're having cold mush.
- What?
- We love you, Miss Hannigan.
Wonderful.
Where's Annie?
- She had to go bathroom.
- "She had to go bathroom."
Miss Hannigan.
Mr. Bundles.
It's time for a tumble
with a bundle.
Not today. I'm behind...
My schedule, I mean.
What are schedules in the storms
of passion, Mr. Bundles?
Just so much flotsam and jetsam.
Miss Hannigan, please!
- What are you doing out here?
- Helping you.
- It's heavy today.
- It's a lot heavier than usual.
- It shouldn't be. What's in there?
- Miss Hannigan...
You're my kind of woman.
Till next month, Miss Hannigan.
I'll be right here.
Mr. Bundles, I'm in here.
- Thank you, Mr. Bundles.
- Good luck.
Get his taiI!
Poor dog.
Leave him alone.
What's he ever done to you?
Amscray!
All right, who's next?
Anybody else?
- Scram, man!
- Let's go!
Then get lost.
Shake a leg! Come on!
Hey, you're all right.
I did nothing any decent person
wouldn't have done.
Dumb dog.
Mister, that's my dog.
Yeah? Where's his licence?
Where's his leash?
He's no more your dog
than I am your father.
I left his licence at home.
Please don't take him to the pound.
My father's blind.
This dog leads him to work.
If he doesn't work, we'll starve.
What's his name?
My father's name?
- The dog's name.
- Oh, the dog's name!
His name's Sandy.
That's it. Sandy.
Call him.
Call him?
Go over there and call him.
You mean by his name?
By his name. The dog's name.
Sandy! Come here, Sandy.
Sandy!
Come here, Rover. Come here, boy.
Rin Tin Tin! Come to Daddy.
- Sandy, come here.
- Rin Tin Tin, come here.
Sandy!
Come here, Sandy. Come here, Sandy.
Come here.
Good old Sandy!
You've got yourself a dog.
Get him a collar and a leash.
Yes, sir.
Miss Hannigan! Miss Hannigan!
What?!
Annie!
Look what I found
under a paving stone.
Annie, my little peach fuzz,
are you all right?
- I was worried sick.
- I knew you would be.
A big-hearted woman like you.
How can I ever thank you...
...enough?
I'm sure we can think of something
if we get our heads together.
Kissy, kissy, kissy.
Kill! Kill!
- We love you, Miss Hannigan.
- Sure.
Oh, my goodness! Oh, my goodness!
He smells.
- What's his name?
- Guess.
Fifi?
That ain't a name for this mutt.
Rover.
She's coming. She's coming.
Hide him.
I love you, Miss Hannigan.
And you will love the paddle closet.
And this...
...will love the sausage factory.
- No, Miss...
- What?
We love you, Miss Hannigan.
Shut up.
All right! All right!
Yeah?
Miss Hannigan, I'm Grace Farrell.
The New York Board of Orphans
sent me.
My goodness, won't you come in?
- Thank you.
- Right this way.
Welcome.
Welcome to our happy home.
- Thank you.
- Ladies.
- What did you say your name was?
- Grace Farrell.
Grace. Aptly named.
I'm here to enquire about an orphan.
Grace, I can explain the whole thing.
What happened was...
...the child bribed Mr. Bundles
to smuggle her out of here.
I should've called Mr. Donnatelli, but
the truth is...
...I called the cops instead.
Anyway she's back, everything's fine.
All's well that ends well.
No harm, no foul,
my little scissors legs?
What are you talking about?
Are you pedalling beauty products?
I don't need beauty products.
If that's what you're doing,
pedal yourself right out of here.
I am the private secretary
to Oliver Warbucks.
The Oliver Warbucks?
- Oliver Warbucks the millionaire?
- No, the billionaire.
Mary, mother of God.
Mr. Warbucks would like to invite
an orphan to spend a week with him.
I'm here to select one.
That's just wonderful.
What kind of orphan did he
have in mind?
Friendly.
Intelligent.
M-l-S-S-l-S-S-l-P-P-I.
And happy.
How old?
Age doesn't really matter.
Seven.
Eight. Nine.
Ten?
Yes, 10 is just fine.
I'm sorry, I almost forgot.
- Mr. Warbucks prefers red hair.
- A 10-year-old redhead?
Sorry, I ain't got it.
What about this child?
- Annie?
- Yes.
You don't want Annie.
Why not?
She's... She's a drunk.
Fiddle-faddle.
How would you like to spend
a week with Mr. Warbucks?
Oh, boy! I would love to.
I would really, really love to.
Wait! Slow down!
Hold on there!
You can have any orphan in the whole
orphanage except Annie.
Why?
She's got it coming to her,
and I don't mean a week of luxury.
- She's got to learn to know her place.
- Her place?
Annie is entirely too cheeky.
- Mr. Warbucks likes cheeky orphans.
- Tough!
I assume you work for Mr. Donnatelli
and the Board of New York Orphans.
Don't assume nothing, sweetheart.
Mr. Warbucks knows Mr. Donnatelli.
- Is that a fact?
- Yes it is.
It's also a fact that he said how many
people he had lined up for your job.
- Is that a fact?
- Yes.
It's awful to be out of work,
isn't it, Miss Hannigan?
Just terrible.
Leaping lizards!
- Leaping lizards!
- The limousine is waiting.
- My dog.
- What?
Here, Sandy. Come here.
He's really nice. Really good.
He never jumps up on people.
He's a very sweet dog, but really,
I don't think Mr. Warbucks...
Then I'm not coming.
She's going to send him to
the sausage factory.
- She said so herself.
- I'm not zoned for dogs.
- We'll take the dog.
- Oh, boy!
Bye, Annie!
I'll be back.
I'll bring everybody presents.
Bye, Molly. See you soon.
Bye, Pepper. Bye, Duffy.
Is this a train station?
Are we going on a train?
No, this is Mr. Warbucks' house.
Leaping lizards.
Wow!
This is Punjab. He and the Asp
are Mr. Warbucks' bodyguards.
Come along. Let's get you settled.
Been to the zoo, Miss Farrell?
Not recently, Drake.
Has the organ been tuned?
Pool heated? Tennis net up?
French doors fixed?
Elevator oiled?
Typewriter repaired?
Second teletype installed?
- Are you allergic to dogs, Drake?
- No, filth.
- Is dinner under way, Mrs. Pugh?
- Yes, miss.
I'm preparing his favourite.
Texas grapefruit, Virginia ham...
...ldaho potatoes, Wisconsin cheese,
Washington apples and baked Alaska.
I have an announcement to make.
This is Annie, and she'll
be staying with us for a week.
This is her dog, Sandy.
He'll be staying with me.
May I take your sweater, miss?
- Will I get it back?
- Of course, miss!
What would you like to do first?
The windows, then the floors,
that way if I drip...
You don't understand. You don't
have to do any cleaning here.
I won't?
How am I gonna earn my keep?
You're our guest, Annie.
Hey, Annie!
Got something for you.
Here you are, Annie.
It's Mr. Warbucks. Don't worry now.
- Welcome home, sir.
- Did the painting arrive?
They're just uncrating it, sir.
I don't like it. Send it back.
Any messages?
President Roosevelt called three
times. He said it was urgent.
Everything's urgent to a Democrat.
What else?
Mr. Rockefeller, Mr. Vanderbilt,
Mr. Du Pont, Mr. Carnegie.
Wait! There's something interesting
in that woman's smile.
I might learn to like her.
Hang her in my bathroom.
No time for dinner tonight. Send out
for an American cheese sandwich.
Come, let's get started.
What the deviI's going on here?
This is the press representative.
Your image.
Oh, yes.
Pick him up, Punjab.
Get him another camera.
Why do I smell wet dog?
Because we gave Sandy a bath.
What's this?
This is Annie, the orphan
that'll be staying with us.
What are you talking about?
The photo of you sharing your home
with an orphan? Only for a week.
This doesn't look like a boy!
Orphans are boys.
You didn't say you wanted a boy. You
just said an orphan, so I got a girl.
I want a boy!
I've got an interesting
smile too, sir.
Couldn't you learn to like me, sir?
Hang me in the bathroom?
- Take them back now.
- Sir, she just got here.
That's okay, Miss Farrell.
We'll be okay.
It was nice meeting you anyhow.
I sure do like your place.
- Thank you, Annette.
- Annie. I've had a swell time.
The Asp drove us here in
a car the size of a train.
And Punjab put a spell on Sandy.
We made Drake sneeze.
And I played your pipe organ.
Sandy got a bubble bath.
I've had enough fun
to last me for years.
It's a really swell idea
to have an orphan for a week.
A really terrific idea.
Even if it is only for your image,
I'm glad you're doing it.
I'm glad you approve.
Let's get to work!
Are you sure you need a boy?
Couldn't she stay?
Whatever, but just for the week.
- You know what?
- What?
- I love you.
- I know.
- Kiss me as only you can.
- You deviI.
Get away!
- Rooster!
- Sis.
You're supposed to be in jaiI.
- They let me out early.
- For good behaviour.
I want you to meet a friend of mine.
Lily St. Regis.
- Named from the hotel.
- Room service.
This afternoon I put 10 on the nose
of a beautiful horse at 8-1.
Sure enough, the scum-bum
took off and whipped the pack.
No kidding?
The thing is, I got delayed
and I didn't have time to cash in.
Sis, first thing in the morning,
guaranteed.
All I need is 5 to tide me over.
Not even a nickel for the subway.
Come on, Sis.
I bet Miss Sticky-fingers here
can loan you a lousy 5 bucks.
I beg your pardon, I'm sure.
But I don't stoop to what you're
incinerating.
Give me back my goods, toots.
Okay, Rooster.
If I loan you 5 bucks, will you
take this dumb hotel out of here?
I'm sorry, Sis. Lily.
Not even a nickel for the subway.
You and her have the same mother?
Rooster!
This room's bigger than Grant's tomb.
Me too.
Come on, Sandy. Come on!
In conclusion...
...because your country has raised its
voice loud and clear for democracy...
...I will extend to you, a credit line...
...for 35 of my new fighter-bombers.
That will come with a year's supply
of spare parts and ammunition...
What's this?
Sandy's not used to sleeping
by himself. He gets lonesome.
Where were we?
- "Ammunition," sir.
- Are you getting a lot done?
I'd get a lot more done
if certain people...
If Franklin Delano Roosevelt
would leave me alone.
Six calls since I got home.
- What's he want?
- My support for the New Deal.
He is our president, sir.
Punjab!
Remove this animal and its young
mistress along with it.
Dear Richie, this letter will serve
as confirmation of correspondence...
...concerning the details
of your extended deferment.
- On or before September first.
If you cannot meet that deadline,
you will be charged interest.
Six percent. Cordially, et cetera.
P.S. One of my companies
is developing bomb-proof glass.
This may be of interest to you
if the global situation deteriorates.
- What was that?
- Well done, Sandy.
- Was that man trying to kill you?
- That will be all.
Yes, sir. Come along, dear.
- Who'd want to kill Mr. Warbucks?
- The Bolsheviks.
He's proof that
the American system works...
...and the Bolsheviks don't
want anyone to know.
The Bolsheviks? Leaping lizards!
- Get your dog out of my pool!
- He thought you were drowning.
- Go on, you mutt. Get out of here.
- Come on.
Do you like my suit?
What? Oh, yes.
Miss Farrell picked it out.
- It's hard getting used to a girl.
- Girls are easy to get used to.
Like Miss Farrell,
she does all the work around here.
- You don't know her first name.
- I do. It's Grace.
She thinks you're the greatest thing
since sliced bread.
I beg your pardon.
I know it's none of my business,
but you never notice anything.
Sliced bread.
Wilhelm, please offer your son my
congratulations on his engagement.
Hold on. Buy copper.
Tell the crown prince
that my yacht in Monte Carlo...
...is entirely at his disposal.
Hold on. More copper.
- Don't encourage her, Punjab.
- Maybe I should take her out.
- Where do you want to go?
- To meet President Roosevelt.
- How about a movie?
- Pepper went to a movie once.
She said it was swell,
and Miss Hannigan goes all the time.
- Take her to the movies.
- Aren't you going to take me?
Me? Annie, you may think
that Miss Farrell does all the work...
...but I'm a very busy man.
I know. I didn't mean
to get in the way, Mr. Warbucks.
Nobody has to take me.
I'll go practice my backhand.
Pepper lies a lot. She probably
hasn't been to a movie either.
Actually, I think it's better when
you don't know what you're missing.
Punjab, buy out the 8:00
show. Let's all go to the movies.
- You should leave your hair down.
- No, I couldn't.
Miss Hannigan says
a man don't look at your brains.
Come on, let's go to the movies.
Let's go see the stars.
For the "lady of the camellias."
- They're twice as large as usual.
- I'll have twice as many as usual.
Twice as many?
I know what those things cost.
Don't listen to her.
They're an investment.
You won't be young forever.
It's time you settled your future.
I know the very man for you.
- Really?
- Yes, really.
- No one loves you as much as I.
- True, but what can I do about it?
You should go away
and not see me anymore.
Don't go in anger. Laugh at yourself
a little, as I laugh at myself.
Come and talk to me once in a while
in a friendly way.
That's too much and not enough.
Believe in love, Marguerite.
Then you do love him.
Dare to tell me that you love him,
and you're free of me forever.
I love him.
Come in here, all of you.
See this woman? You know her.
Listen to what I'm going to say.
I thought she loved me.
I let her make sacrifices for me,
but I owe her nothing.
Go on, take it.
Buy camellias. Buy diamonds.
Buy carriages. Buy a grave.
You know how to treat a woman
as she deserves.
Marguerite.
Oh, it's you.
I've been down in the street
half the night...
...wanting to come up,
but not daring to. I felt so guilty.
Even if we can't
go to the country today...
...think of how happy we were once
and how happy we'll be again.
Think of the day you found
the four-leaf clover.
Think of the vows that
we're going to make to each other.
This is for life, Marguerite.
Marguerite.
No, don't leave me.
Marguerite, come back.
Could you get her nightgown?
It's behind the bathroom door.
Certainly.
- Miss Farrell.
- It's all right.
- How did you learn that?
- Learn what?
- That.
- What?
- You put her to bed.
- You put her to bed too.
- I did?
- Yes, you did.
Good heavens.
- That was a wonderful evening.
- I have to close a factory.
- About Annie.
- What about Annie?
Could we keep her?
That horrible orphanage,
I can't bear to send her back there.
Get ahold of yourself.
What's come over you?
I'd take care of her.
You have plenty of room here.
- We could take her on as your ward.
- Absolutely not.
I love money, I love power.
I do not now,
nor ever will, love children.
Watching you with her last night
I thought maybe...
Yes?
- I've just noticed something.
- Yes?
You're awfully pretty
when you argue with me.
- Thank you, sir.
- Oliver.
Do you just love money and power
and capitalism?
They'll never love you back.
- Your teeth are crooked.
- I'll have them fixed.
- I like them crooked.
- I'll leave them.
Thank you.
I could have the papers signed
this morning.
- It means a great deal to you.
- Yes, a great deal.
I'll do it myself.
I could just kiss you!
Grace, get her a little gift.
That's a good idea.
Get her a new locket.
Be careful at that orphanage.
That woman's got claws and fangs.
- We got Annie?
- Yeah.
It's a hard-knock life for us.
No one cares for you a smidge...
...when you're in an orphanage.
What are you doing?
Why aren't you marching in line
with the rest of them?
Duffy, come here. Come on.
You're hiding something
from Miss Hannigan behind your back.
- No.
- Let me have it.
Get inside!
I've seen his picture in the paper
with President Roosevelt.
- Hannigan, I presume?
- Yes.
I want to talk to you about Annie.
You want to return her and trade up?
I want to adopt her.
Would you excuse me for a moment?
- Please step into my office.
- Thank you.
Hi, sweetie.
Little cutie.
This way.
- Welcome.
- Miss Hannigan...
Mr. Warbucks, for a Republican,
you are sinfully handsome.
I go absolutely weak in the knees
over men like you.
- My God, is that thing real?
- Just sign the papers.
Would you like to see the bedroom,
my billiard ball?
Sign.
- I make a very dry martini.
- Right here.
- I make a very wet soufflé.
- Just your name.
- Don't be such an old meanie.
- Come, my dear.
- I have an appointment at 1.
- This way.
Women! Does it take this long
to get to Tiffany's and back?
- I hear the car.
- It's probably not the right car.
- It's the Duesenberg.
- What took you so long?
What's happening here?
- Where's Annie?
- She's taking her karate lesson.
- Don't be nervous.
- I'm not. You give it to her.
- It was your idea.
- She likes you more than me.
Oliver, will you pull
yourself together!
Want to see
what the Asp taught me today?
To the couch, Punjab, if you please.
- I didn't think it would work.
- Now you know it does.
- Shall I call a doctor?
- It'll be fine.
Thank you.
We'll leave you two alone.
I want to talk to you
about something very serious.
- You don't want me anymore.
- On the contrary, I do.
Good Lord!
- Can we have a man-to-man talk?
- Sure.
What I'm proposing
would involve a long-term agreement.
Maybe you ought to know more about
me before you make up your mind.
- Okay.
- Let's go for a walk.
I was born in Liverpool.
My brother died of pneumonia because
we didn't have money for medicine.
I decided then and there
that one day I would be very rich.
- Good idea.
- America was a land of opportunity.
I signed on a ship as cabin boy.
By the time I was 21,
I'd made my first million.
In the next 10 years,
I turned that into 100 million.
In those days that was a lot
of money. I was ruthless.
Making money was all I ever
gave a damn about, up till now.
- Let's go inside.
- Okay.
It has occurred to me that no matter
how much money I have...
...unless I have someone to share it
with, I might as well be broke.
- You know what I'm trying to say?
- Sure.
Kind of.
- Kind of?
- I guess not.
- You've given me so much already.
- I have the papers. It's official.
What is?
- Let me put it on you.
- No.
It's a swell locket, but if it's
all the same, I'll keep my old one.
It isn't all the same.
I've had this one engraved.
"To Annie,
With love from Daddy Warbucks."
When my folks left me
at the orphanage 10 years ago...
...they left a note saying
they'd come back to get me.
They kept the other half
of this old locket so I'd know them.
I'm going to find them someday and
have a regular mother and father...
...like a regular kid. I am.
I don't mean to hurt your feelings.
You've been nicer to me than anyone.
But I've been dreaming of my folks
for as long as I can remember.
I've just got to find them.
And I'll help you.
Grace, get me J. Edgar on the phone!
Drake, get me the chief of police!
Asp, get me Walter Winchell!
Punjab, get me
William Randolph Hearst!
And, Saunders, get me a drink!
Six, seven, eight, you're on.
L-O-D-E-N-T
lodent
The lovely Boylan Sisters.
Tonight as a special treat
from yours truly, Bert Healy...
...l'd like to introduce
a little orphan named Annie.
Who's that who just walked into
our Red Network studios?
It's none other than the
Wall Street tycoon, Oliver Warbucks!
Thank you, Bert Healy.
It's swell... Do I say swell?
Swell to be on the lodent Hour.
You're searching
for Annie's parents.
I told you that
before we went on the air. Oh, yes!
"I am conducting
a coast-to-coast search...
...for Annie's parents. Drop page.
Warbucks continues."
I am offering a cash reward
to Annie's parents of $50, 000.
Mr. Warbucks!
Oh, boy! 50,000 smackers.
Annie's parents, if you're listening,
contact Oliver Warbucks...
"Warbucks interrupts.
At my house, 987, Fifth Avenue,
New York City.
Thank you, Bert Healy,
and thank you, all-new lodent.
The toothpaste with miracle K-64
to fight hali..."
- Halitosis.
- "Thank you for your time.
Good night, Bert Healy,
for the Red Network. Drop page."
Did I just do a commercial?
Let's get out of here.
I've never endorsed a product
in all of my career.
From all of you, our smiles family,
this is Bert Healy saying...
The lovely Boylan Sisters.
Do I hear happiness in here?
They never miss.
Everybody's
going to get their chance.
Annie, it's your mother.
- We've got to get her out of here.
- Get the autocopter ready.
Guess what? Mr. Warbucks is going
to take you to see the president.
Oh, boy!
Aren't Republicans ostentatious?
Franklin, behave.
It's astonishing he's here at all.
- What do you call this, Oliver?
- An autocopter.
You don't need an airport.
They say it can land on a dime.
- Whatever that may be.
- You being here means a great deal.
It means nothing. It means only
that Annie wanted to meet you.
- Nice to meet you, Mr. President.
- It's my pleasure, Annie.
Thank you for bringing the old goat.
We'll make a New Dealer of him yet.
- Inconceivable.
- Don't mind him, Oliver.
Come along, Annie.
My Uncle Theodore used to teach
his children to walk on stilts.
I can't teach you to do that, but
you can roll in a chair with wheels.
The New Deal is badly planned,
badly organized and administered.
You don't think your
programs through.
Think what you're going to do
to the economy in the long run!
- People don't eat in the long run.
- People can't feed their children.
The lucky ones are left in orphanages.
The older ones steal, starve.
This country is run on business...
Take them off the dole and put
them to work. That's what I'll do.
In the National Parks, clearing trails,
fighting fires, planting trees.
- Hold it.
- I want to feed them and pay them.
Not much, but enough so they can
be proud to be Americans.
- That's a swell idea.
- It's mistaken foolishness.
Big-hearted and empty-headed.
Which parks? Which children?
What will it cost?
Who's going to run it?
- I was hoping you would.
- Me?
- And Annie.
- Leaping lizards!
- Out of the question.
- How can I help?
Wait a minute!
You can help us
recruit the young people.
Hold everything!
They think their government
doesn't care.
With your help
we could convince them otherwise...
I want to say something.
There's a song I used to sing
in the orphanage when I was sad.
- It always cheered me up.
- Eleanor!
Oh, Franklin.
You'll help us too,
won't you, Oliver?
Think of the children.
Think of Annie.
Sing, Oliver, that's an order
from your commander in chief.
- Eleanor?
- I can't sing.
Sing.
Solo for the president.
Everybody!
Republicans too, Oliver.
All right, everybody, step up.
I've got fresh fish here.
- Do you run this establishment?
- Unfortunately.
Ten years ago we left our
little baby girl on the front steps.
There was a job managing a hotel,
but only if we had no children.
- Wrap it up quick.
- We never meant to leave Annie.
Now we have a hardware store in
New Jersey. We can take care of her.
We've always loved her.
- You're Annie's parents?
- We live over the store.
- There's a yard out back.
- With chickens.
And a rooster.
Rooster?
My God! I never would
have recognized you.
If we can fool you,
we can fool "Big Bucks."
- 50,000 smackers.
- You'll be the death of me.
Sis, this is going to be
the best bunco job ever.
- We need details.
- About Annie. Specifics.
- What's in it for me?
- A three-way-split of the $50,000.
- I want half.
- All right, half!
Twenty-five grand for me and LiI,
25 grand for you.
Why don't we wait
to see what she's got?
See if it's worth 25 grand.
You want details? I've got specifics
on every kid in this dump.
It's just finding the right box.
Annie wears a locket around her neck.
It's a broken locket.
She says her parents saved the other
half to come and claim her with.
Years ago,
her parents were killed in a fire.
This is all their junk.
So, baby brother...
...we can also claim her
with that locket.
- 50,000 smackers.
- The kid we'll drop in the river.
They're going to do
something bad to Annie!
- Have you cleaned the can?
- Listen to me. I mean it.
Clean the can!
- Duffy, Tessie, somebody!
- Do you want a knuckle sandwich?
- We've got to warn Annie!
- Scrub!
It's in a sealed envelope.
The little brat.
Look in those!
Make yourself useful!
Open it.
Hurry.
Hit it, Sis.
Now do the other one.
Duffy, Tessie, somebody! They're
going to do something to Annie!
- Who is?
- They are!
- Who's they?
- Miss Hannigan.
Oh, my goodness!
Beautiful.
- Where do you think you're going?
- Go tell Annie.
Stop them.
Get in that closet.
Stop it.
Whose rotten idea was this?
Are they here?
If a man counts his chickens before
they hatch, he gets a scrambled egg.
- Have my parents come for me?
- We haven't found them.
I interviewed 865 couples.
None of them knew about the locket.
I never realized how many dishonest
people there are in New York.
They're dead. I guess I've known
that deep down for a long time.
I'm not giving up, so don't you.
I didn't want to be just another
orphan. I wanted to be special.
You are special.
Never stop believing that.
We're trapped.
Oh, my goodness. Oh, my goodness.
- We'll never get out of here.
- I've got an idea.
Great idea.
- It's heavy.
- Don't drop it.
All right, lean it over.
I'm not sure I want to do this.
We'll be in so much trouble.
- Duffy, hand me something.
- Here.
There's space up here.
Oh, my goodness. Oh, my goodness.
Help me get up.
It's a long way down.
Are you sure you want to do this?
- Wish me luck.
- Good luck.
We were starving. We needed the job.
That's why we left our little girl.
- Wrapped in a newspaper.
- On the steps of the orphanage.
What's this?
This is Ralph and Shirley Mudge
from Hoboken, New Jersey.
Annie!
Ralph, look!
She still has the locket.
We finally found you.
You heard about the reward
on the radio.
- Reward?
- We don't have a radio.
- In the paper.
- Paper?
- What paper?
- How did you know Annie was here?
- The lady at the orphanage told us.
- I have her birth certificate here.
I've kept it close to my heart
all of these years.
"Ann Marie Mudge.
October 18th, 1922."
I'll go pack.
Do you want me to help, baby?
No, thanks, Mom.
Come on.
A certified cheque!
We're so glad to have found Annie.
We don't need this.
- I'll take it back.
- Of course, we are poor people.
It would help us a lot.
We could buy her milk, a warm blanket.
Put it in your pocket, Mrs. Mudge.
Come on, you guys.
- Oh, my goodness!
- We're never going to make it.
- We've found Fifth Avenue.
- Number one, Fifth Avenue.
We've got to go to 987.
- Molly, get on my back.
- Come on, you guys, help.
- Will the stores take this back?
- All your new clothes?
I guess so.
Don't you want to keep them?
My folks are poor. All these clothes
are going to make them feel bad.
- Take them to the orphanage.
- Certainly.
This will look so cute on Molly.
This'll look good on Duffy.
Did you get it? Let me see it.
- I'd better keep it.
- Over my dead body.
- That's a good idea.
- Give me that.
Help, Mr. Warbucks!
We'll never find the house.
When I get my half!
- I say we go back.
- We can't.
We've been walking for 100 years!
- We're never going to get there.
- But we have to.
- Let's take a vote.
- All in favour of calling it quits?
- I'll get a gold lamé number.
- In Atlantic City.
We aren't stopping
till we hit Atlantic City.
- Help, Mr. Warbucks.
- Shut up, kid.
Look, there's Sandy!
Come here.
Come on, let's go!
Hurry up.
I can't run anymore.
Quiet down, girls.
You want to see Mr. Warbucks?
All right, come on.
Oh, my goodness!
- What now?
- Sir.
- I think he's a highness.
- Your Highness.
- We're friends of Annie's.
- Annie's gone.
- Her parents took her away.
- But they weren't her parents.
- They were bad people.
- Leaping lizards!
You take the autocopter.
J. Edgar? Warbucks here.
Orphan Annie has been kidnapped.
I want every G-man on this
in the next 20 minutes.
Where's the fire, fellas?
The truck is on Canal Street,
heading east.
Well done, Punjab. Don't lose them.
Can we stop? I've got to go.
I've really got to, Miss Hannigan.
I mean it. When you've got to go,
you've got to go.
Make it fast.
Rooster, grab her.
She's got the cheque.
- Cut her off at the bridge.
- Goddamn it!
Come back here, you goddamn kid!
Mr. Warbucks will eat your livers.
- I'll kill you.
- He's really going to kill her.
Rooster, stop!
Rooster, she's a baby.
Come back here.
Rooster!
She may be a mean,
rotten, little orphan...
...but I'm not going
to let you kill her.
Let go of me, you boozer!
Stop it!
- They're at the bridge.
- Turn right.
I know.
Help, somebody!
Leave me alone.
Please, help.
Help!
Have we got two nets?
Please, Punjab, help me.
Punjab, help.
- You must hold on.
- I can't.
Buddha says a child without courage
is like a night without stars.
Rooster, you reprobate.
Annie!
"To Annie, with love."
I love you, Daddy Warbucks.