I dare say, you wish you'd
never left Versailles.
You had a very pleasant time at court...
...with those gallant young officers.
With one in particular, I recall.
Why have we come here?
For YOUR sake. my love!
In order that you may have a husband...
....who IS a husband...
...and not just an invalid!
I'll soon be well...
Three months at the baths should cure me.
Welcome to the Chateau de Résance
your Excellency.
At last!
Help me, help me, someone...
This coach is an infernal rack!
That's it... steady... easy...
Easy!
Easy! Dolts! Easy!
Easy... easy!
Your Excellency
need not bother with the stairs...
We will prepare a room on the ground floor.
How far is it to the baths?
About an hour's drive.
I'll go the first thing in the morning.
Thank you, your Excellency.
A fine way to spend a honeymoon!
You'll find the days rather long, I'm afraid.
The time will pass.
They've sent for a maid.
Not necessary... I'm quite capable.
My dear...
You may be capable...
as the daughter of a Scottish merchant...
in Leghorn...
But as Madame la Marquise de Vincitata...
...wife of a grandee of Spain...
...who is envoy to the King of France...
At all times!
Yes, your Excellency.
There!...
You must be tired.
Don't let ME keep you any longer.
Good night, your Excellency.
Good night, Maria.
At what hour
will we leave for the baths, your Excellency?
Eight!
Denis...
Dear Denis...
Oh, Merciful Mother... help me to forget him.
Madame...
Yes?
My name is Lucia, madame...
I am the new maid.
What time is it?
It's scarcely daybreak...
But I was told it was a matter of life and death.
- Who gave you this?  - The cook's sister.
- And she?   - Don't worry, madame...
She told me to tell you...
...that she can hold her tongue.
And the rest of the servants are asleep.
Madame...
If there is any way in which I can help...
"By the mill at the first bridge".
Denis!
Maria!
Oh, I never dreamt you'd come!
How could it be otherwise?
But here is so far...
Ten days from Paris!
Oh, darling, what's going to happen to us?
- I do love you... I do!    - Dearest!
These are for always.
Always!
And you WILL take me away from him?
- Yes, I swear it!   - When?
You must trust me, my dear...
It will take planning...
Your husb...
The Marquis has powerful friends...
It would never do to fail.
First, I must go back to Paris.
Back to Paris?!
We'll need money, if we're to get out of France.
Besides, I'm an officer...
I can't desert.
I'd have to resign my commission.
Denis, I'm frightened!
Let's not think of it now, dearest...
We've many days to talk it over.
Meanwhile...
We mustn't wait too long.
In 2 or 3 months, he'll be well, and...
Madame...
He's back from the baths.
Tomorrow?
Provide he isn't home...
I'll get a message to you somehow.
Au revoir, dearest.
You've made extraordinary progress
in 3 months, monsieur.
In few days...
you'll be able to continue your honeymoon.
That's a nice way to put it, doctor!
But the truth is...
My honeymoon has never quite started!
And to think you've been all the way to Paris!
- Did you miss me?   - Oh, darling!
What is it, Maria?... You're frightened!
You're trembling!
Can't you guess?
I'm yours now... All yours!
Oh, my dearest!
We must leave at once... Tonight!
What if Don Luis returns?
He's been staying at the baths lately...
But I know he's ever so much better...
I'll watch for your signal.
One candle if I can go...
Two, if I can't.
And if you're in trouble my dear...
If anything should happen...
Then, I'll light three!
Dearest!
Rejoice, my dear!
Your husband is complete again!
I shan't say good night...
Dismiss your maid, when you've retired.
Did you hear someone running about?
Yes, master!
What does this mean?
Come here!
No!
What name?!
His name?!
Denis!
You...
...a merchant's daughter!
To soil the honour of my name!
The world will never know...
Do you hear me?!  Never!
That I vow!
There was no message, monsieur.
They left early this morning...
...bag and baggage.
Madame too?
Madame, the maid, the marquis...
Which way did they go?
By the road to Issoire.
Thank you.
I'm looking for a coach...
A large coach...
with a bearded man and two women.
It's here... came a little while ago.
When her supper comes...
...serve it quickly...
We may leave very soon.
Did you know my dear that I have the reputation
of being one of the best swordsman in Europe.
However, it's too late to think of that,
I'm afraid.
And he's so tired, poor boy...
So tired!... So worried!
Not in the house, please...
You are quick, m'sieur!
Quick to betray... quick to dishonour!
He's clumsy...
He can't harm the young man.
Denis!
Order the coach Sancho...
We'll continue our journey at once.
Poor boy!
Open up!
Who are you?
Never mind who we are...
Give her money, and hold your tongue.
Oh, m'lord!
It's come, master!
It's come... It's a boy!
Alive?!
Drive on, Sancho!
I thought you were in Paris.
Where's Maria?
Didn't you bring her?
I want to speak to your master.
I see... I'm just a servant...
Well, I'm not Maria's maid any longer.
I'm her father's housekeeper.
And his heiress, too, perhaps!
Who knows?
If you'll keep his house... well!
Isn't he a darling?!
Poor little fellow!
I respect your feelings, sisters...
In fact, I share them!
But this is a girl's school...
The child must be disposed of.
Well...
I'll speak to Father Xavier in the morning.
He isn't an ordinary foundling...
A satin cloak... a purse of gold...
A male child cannot be reared
in a school for little girls.
Oh, Sister...
This is St Anthony's feast day, too.
Sister, we implore you!
You may rest assured...
Everything was done, that could be done.
Buried in the The Alps!
Maria... my only child!
And the baby was buried, too.
Maria, and the infant.
Both of them.
You understand?
Aye!
It's hard to be the bearer of such news.
For a husband, especially.
My little girl!
Her bonny soul's at peace.
If you'll pardon my mentioning it, at this time...
There's just one other matter
while I'm here in Leghorn...
Your lease on this property is about to expire.
If it suits you...
I'd be glad to renew it on the same terms...
...for as many years as you choose.
Thank you, seńor.
I shall want to keep it.
It's where my daughter grew up.
Au revoir, seńor.
Gone!
No trace of her!
Nothing!
Nothing left!
Nothing.
But you're a great merchant!
You still have your work, your ships!
Aye!
But for whom?
Anthony...
AN-thony!
Daydreaming?!
Father...
Could I go for a walk outside the walls?
When school is closed for summer, you may...
But not before.
I want to go now!
Oh...do you?!
And how do you think it would look...
...to see a great big boy like you...
...going in and out of a girls' convent.
Mother Marie-José would be very angry.
But she has REAL people to talk to.
I have no one.
No one?
Only YOU.
Pardon me, Father.
Have you read your lesson?
We shall see!
Quid proxima...
quid superiore...
nocte egeris...
ubi fueris, quos convo-cheris...
"quos conVOCAVEris"!
quid consili ceperis...
quid nostra...
quem nostrum ignorare arbitraris.
Arbitraris?
What we did last night...
what you did the night before...
where you were...
whom you called together...
what plans you made.
Whom of us do you think
is ignorant of these things?
Now continue.
O tempora, o mores!
"Alas for the times...alas for its..."
It's...?
Mores...morals.
An important word, Anthony...
You should never forget it.
Why not?
Because morals are the foundation
of a man's soul.
With bad morals...
..a man is dishonest, ungodly.
And his house soon decays to the ground.
But the man with good morals...
...lives in honour and truth...
...and builds for himself
a great and beautiful mansion...
...that lives for all eternity...
...through his children
and his children's children.
Someday I'm going to have
a great and beautiful mansion.
It'll have towers so high...
...that I can see the whole world.
And it'll have a...
Father Xavier...
Sister Marie-José wishes to see you.
Thank you, sister.
Quem nostrum ignorare arbitraris?
That's a question!
Be sure you make it one.
You'll meet plenty of others.
Sister Ursula...
Later, my dear...
Sister Ursula is very busy now.
You can have it!
Oh, how sweet...
I couldn't make out what it was.
I have pigeons, too.
And I. I have a rabbit.
A rabbit?
His name is Oliver Cromwell.
You see, we're English.
What are you?
Is everybody something?
Of course!
What are rabbits?
Silly! They don't count!
But they're alive, aren't they?
Certainly... Everybody knows that!
I don't. I've never seen one.
I can't keep Anthony much longer, Father.
We'll have to place him.
Look!
My tall hat.
The scoundrel! Who is the other child?
Florence Udney...
The daughter of the British consul at Leghorn.
Father...
We must find him a place immediately.
Why in a few years...
...we'll send him to Rome to study...
Can't we wait until then?
No... this is a girls' school...
I've no place for a boy of 10.
He's such a child!
It's no use arguing Father...
I've made up my mind.
I'm sure there's someone to take him...
...right here in Leghorn.
A merchant, for instance...
There are several in the British colony.
Isn't he rather young to be apprenticed?
It's never too young to learn a trade.
Particularly for an orphan.
Well... have you any suggestions?
Perhaps Martin and Forsyth may take him.
They're very prominent.
What about the Casa da Bonnyfeather?
Mr Bonnyfeather is a good churchman.
He's been very lonesome since his daughter died.
Well, then... let it be...
The Casa da Bonnyfeather.
Yes...Casa da Bonnyfeather.
Look!
Please tell Mr Bonnyfeather
that Father Xavier has arrived.
He's expecting us.
Yes, Father... please go sit down.
Dear me!
Here... there you are.
Alright, Father.
Wait here, Anthony.
Father!
You've brought him?
Bag and all!
He comes to you, exactly as he came to us!
Including the 10 gold pieces.
10 gold pieces!
That's a goodly fortune for a lad his age!
He hasn't any clothes, though.
Cut that, man... we'll soon fix that!
Here... give me the receipt.
I'll sign it now.
Thank you.
Buried in The Alps...
I'm sorry, father.
For a moment,
the child reminded me of my daughter.
Bring him into the study.
Anthony... come and meet your benefactor.
How do you do, young man?!
Do you think you'll like it here?
I can't tell yet, Signore.
That's alright!
Be frank, and we'll get along fine!
May God bless you for this deed, Mr Bonnyfeather.
Thank you Father...
We'll take good care of him...
Never fear!
Goodbye, Anthony.
I want to stay with YOU, Father!
This is where you commence your future, Anthony.
You must have courage.
Come... we'll look for some clothes for you.
Guessippi...
Ah...signora...
Oh, the kitchen's so big!
And there's the cook...Signora Guessippi
We built the kitchen around her!
Signora... this is Master Anthony...
...our new apprentice.
He's in need of clothes... temporarily.
Perhaps you could spare a shirt
from one of your children.
It'll be done, Signore.
Who's the little girl?
That's Angela, her daughter.
Angela...
Say hello to the little gentleman.
Hello!
May I play with Angela, Sr Bonnyfeather?
Young man, you're here to work...
You've lots to learn!
I beg your pardon, sir.
Of course you may play with Angela...
Whenever you like!
Oh, thank you, sir!
And now, master Anthony, we'll go upstairs...
...and find a room you can sleep in.
I'll search for the clothes right away, Signore!
Angela... Angela...
Yes, Mama?
Come on!
He's sleeping.
It's Maria's, beyond a doubt.
She might have given it to someone.
She had a child, 10 years ago.
The baby didn't live.
How do we know?
But Don Luis told us!
After all, he was her husband...
He was there at the time.
Don Luis lied.
Of course...
If the Marquis de Vincitata...
...saw fit to abandon his wife's baby...
...there can be only one explanation!
Oh, no!
I won't have it thought that he...
He's a foundling.
And he'll remain a foundling.
That's all very well to say...
But if he bears YOUR name...
He'll NOT bear it.
We'll give him one.
No father!
No mother!
No name!
A child of sorrow and adversity...
Adversity...
Yes... by all the saints, he's earned it!
We'll call him "Adverse"!
Now...
and forever.
Anthony Adverse.
Angela... good morning!
Anthony, get up!  It's late!
Are we market today?
If you hurry, it's after 7...
Mr Bonnyfeather's having his breakfast already.
Why didn't you call me?
We've been making enough noise
to wake everyone in Leghorn!
Angela... Angela!
Yes, Mama, I'm coming.
Good morning, Faith.
Good morning, sir.
Good morning, my boy.
Any news from Paris?
Louis XVI has been put to death, as I expected.
Marie-Antoinette will follow.
Tony... watch what you're doing!
You've become fairly impossible.
Well, who wouldn't, with 10 children!
Eh, Tony?
Si, si Signore!
Excuse please.
7 hens.
No... 8.
Fill up the teapot, someone!
Fill it up yourself, you idiot!
Woman!
Then she burst out crying...
and threw the dishrag in Poppa's face!
Poor Tony... What's happened to him?
It's the big state lottery...
He's used up all our savings, buying tickets.
You can imagine Mama,
if he doesn't win something.
I've been wasting all my pity
on the King of France.
Speaking of lottery tickets...
Look.
Is it yours?
What would you do if you won?
Well, first, I'd marry YOU!
Then I'd buy a real villa...
...with vineyards...
and a huge fountain in the courtyard.
And a goat?
The finest goat in Leghorn!
No you wouldn't...
You just say that.
Haven't I always said it?
It's different now...
We're not children any longer.
It's all the more reason to believe me.
I wish I were a great lady!
With beautiful clothes
and a carriage all my own.
Then you'd be proud of me...
...instead of being ashamed of me.
I'll never be ashamed of you, Angela.
Never in a thousand years!
You will... some day.
Look at me!
You mustn't.... not on a road like this!
Let's sing!
Oh the spring will not be there forever...
And this day will return to us never...
All the promises made...
You have all mislaid...
I will wait here for you, oh my love.
I'll wait for you my love.
Attention, please!
An American brig is docking...
with merchandise from London.
You'll report to McNab at once...
He's over thee now, with the invoices.
Anthony!
You've become quite a man!
I might even say, a handsome young man!
Handsome enough to turn the heads
of the finest young ladies in Leghorn.
Tell me...
Why don't you linger longer with younger people?
I have work to do!
You've plenty of time to spend
with the cook's daughter.
Oh, not that I object!
She's a charming girl, but...
But you've got to take your proper place
in the world.
What IS my proper place?
Does anyone know?
You're...
You're a man, Anthony...
You'll make your own place.
Just run over to the quay...
...and welcome Capt. Jorham for me, will you?
I'm told he's a diminutive old fellow...
But he's proud!
As all the Yankees are...
You'll need tact!
You can depend on me, sir.
I hope so.
I should like to find someone...
...with whom I could share my responsibilities.
Sometimes, the great house of Bonnyfeather...
becomes too heavy a burden
for one man's shoulders.
My shoulders are broad, sir!
They belong to you...
...to use as you see fit.
Run along.... and don't forget...
Be sure to invite Capt. Jorham to dinner.
Yes, sir!
What was that crowd, out in the square?
When?
They're picking the winning numbers
in the lottery tonight.
Gambling! Did you hear that?!
These foreigners 'd corrupt the devil himself!
Thar she spouts!
Pipe down, Mrs Jorham!
Elisha, you're drunk!
Belay your sheets, woman!
So would ye be, if you'd had as much as me!
Listen!
They've finished... They're celebrating.
It's Tony Guessippi!
He's won the lottery!
It's Papa!
Wait... what's this?!
Yes... look at me!
It is me... Tony Guessippi!
I have won the lottery!
Insult me now, if you dare!
Shut up, you fool!
Wait!
How much money did he win?
40,000 scudi...
But it will not last him long!
He has ordered 12 carriages!
One for each member of the family!
One moment, please!
Tony, where are you going?
Far away... to the home of my ancestors...
And I am not coming back!
Wait!
Very well... Go!
Take your family... Get out!
And never let me see you again!
Angela... you mustn't go!
You don't know Papa when he's like this...
I must take care of the little ones.
I'll go with you.
No... that would make things worse.
Anthony, if you love me, find me later...
But don't come now!
Stop it!
Angela, you can't go... you mustn't go!
Anthony, I must!
Let me go!
I give up!
Your name is Adverse, isn't it?
Why did you grab me?
Don't worry... I won't again!
I'm Vincent Nolte, in case you're interested.
My father's a banker...
He does a lot of business with Mr Bonnyfeather.
She's gone!
Forget it... She'll come back.
You couldn't catch her now, anyway.
Oh, good evening Mr Bonnyfeather.
I was just saying, my father's a friend of yours.
Herr Nolte... the banker.
Why, upon my soul... How big you've grown!
Scarcely recognised you!
Mr Adverse ought to get around more.
I can't understand why we've never met.
Anthony, why don't you and young Nolte
spend the evening together.
Thank you sir, but I'm not a man of leisure...
I've work to do.
I think you've worked too hard lately...
It's time you relaxed and had a little pleasure.
Later.
He's right, you know... What do you say?
Well... good night gentlemen!
Have a good time!
No thanks... I don't think I'll...
Oh, come on!
Does this mean you're closing down for good sir?
Yes... I'm afraid so.
Tell the men they're to have a month's salary...
...and their freedom.
And you might add...
I'm revising my will today.
Each one of you will be remembered.
Thank you, sir!
The remainder of my estate...
...I bequeath to my apprentice...
...Anthony Adverse....
...provided he is still living at the time
this will is executed.
If he is not living, at such a time...
...I desire that the residue of my estate...
...shall be divided equally...
...between the aforesaid Faith Peliolegus...
...and the Convent of the Holy Child.
That's all you hear...
Business is at a standstill.
We're shutting down completely at the bank.
So are we.
And Bonaparte calls himself a liberator!
He has to enslave people first...
...before he can liberate them!
That's the way with conquerors.
- What can we do?   - Fight him!
We'll fight him!
It's no use, Tommy...
He's in Florence already.
In a few days, he'll be here...
...and not a soul will lay a hand to stop him.
Instead, he'll be hailed...
Let's forget about Bonaparte...
Think of something else.
How about going to the opera tonight?
There's a new company from Milan.
Music before the battle, eh?!
It may be the last we hear, for a long time.
You're right... I'd like to go!
Come along... let's buy the tickets.
Look, Vincent... There's Angela!
- Angela!  - Where?
The shepherdess, there in the middle.
I'm going down to see her!
No, wait until the act is over...
You won't be able to see her till then,
in any case.
Good night!
Signora Bovino.
Si, signorina.
Signorina Guessippi.
Si Signore... is she expecting you?
I'm an old friend.
Come in!
Who is it?
A gentlemen here to see you.
Gentleman? What gentlemen?
Adolfo, Maria, Nicolo, Pietrica, Vittoria...
Anthony!
Let me see you... It's been so long!
That's right... So hard to find you!
I've searched everywhere!
Oh, Angela mia!
Signora... and ovation... magnificent!
Just as you predicted!
Oh, I'm glad.
Debrulle, they shouted... Debrulle!
As though I were the whole troupe!
The stars never lie...
From now on your troupe will prosper!
Bless you! Come... give us some wine!
- We must celebrate!   - No, not now.
Why not?!
She doesn't need wine... She's happy!
Let her be.
She's asleep?
Aren't you proud of me?
I adore you!
I mean... the singing.
I adore your singing, too!
Oh... silly!
You couldn't possibly hear me
with all those other girls pitching
at the top of their lungs!
Oh you're different!
You stood right out!
I'm awkward perhaps... Or do I sing off-pitch?
You've learned how to get compliments!
Not compliments, Anthony...
I want the truth.
Signore Debrulle...
He's been very kind to me.
He's a nice man... full of encouragement.
But unless I can be a great singer...
...I'd rather not go on.
Even if you could, I wouldn't let you.
But I must earn my living somehow!
Have you forgotten already?
Forgotten?
The finest goat in Leghorn!
Do you still love me, Angela?
Of course!
What is it?!
Your career?
Yes... that is...
Oh, Anthony, don't you understand?
It's Bonnyfeather.
He's never give his consent!
Oh, I can make him understand!
- I know I can!   - And if you can't?
Angela, these 2 years have changed me...
I've worked...
I've earned a real place for myself
in the house of Bonnyfeather.
I repaid, in a way...
a part of the kindness he's shown me.
Then, if he needs you, he'll never let you go.
The House of Bonnyfeather's closed its doors.
Once again, I'm Anthony Adverse, orphan.
I have nothing...
I mean no inheritance... no tradition.
But I have my self!
And the name that was invented for me.
With you, Angela...
I could make that name stand for something.
For a new generation...
A great new family tradition.
Are you willing to give up your career...
...and your name?
For a man who hasn't even a real name
of his own to give you?
Oh, Anthony, I love you!
Does he know you're leaving?
No.
Don't tell him then.
Just go.
Why?
Because he's so selfish!
He'll want to keep you.
Not when he knows Angela and I are married.
Anthony... take my advice.
Bonnyfeather's through!
From now on this house will be a mausoleum...
A place to rot in!
So will Leghorn, so will Europe, for that matter!
If I were you, I'd go as far away as possible.
Come in.
Mr Bonnyfeather would like to see you.
Put this in, too.
When are you meeting her?
At noon.
Outside the convent.
Goodbye, Maria.
And good riddance!
Come in, Anthony.
Sit down.
I want to talk to you.
Anthony...
How would you like to go to Havana?
Go to Havana?!
It's for you to decide, of course.
But first let me do a little explaining.
Now as you know...
I'm being forced into retirement...
...by circumstances over which I have no control.
And even if conditions should change...
...I feel I'm too old...
...ever to become active again.
The wealth that I have accumulated, therefore...
...is of the utmost importance to me.
But unfortunately...
that wealth is in the form of credit.
Money that is owing to us
in all parts of the world.
Now, among our debtors...
...is a firm known as Gallego and Son...
...which has its headquarters in Havana.
Now, their debt is a very large one.
It amounts to 75% of my entire estate.
And so far, I've been unable to collect it.
They refuse to pay it?
Precisely.
And with Europe in the throes of war...
...there's no possible way to force them...
...other than to send someone there.
Haven't we an agent in Havana?
We have... but he's failed repeatedly.
Gallego and Son are slippery customers.
One has to resort to all manner of tricks.
Unless I'm mistaken...
It will require months of constant effort.
The employment of tact, influence...
...and above all, determination.
Now, the reason I want YOU
to undertake this mission...
...is because you're nearer to me
than anyone I know.
It's the sort of thing
a man would entrust to a son...
...if he had a son.
This is...
...the first real service you ever asked of me.
When would you want me to go?
I've arranged with Capt. Jorham...
You can sail tomorrow.
As soon as that?!
Aye!
The French fleet's on its way to Gibraltar
to effect a blockade.
In that case, won't I have trouble getting back?
It might take a year... possibly 2!
Would you be so good as to tell Capt. Jorham...
...to make accommodation for 2.
Why?
I should like my wife to accompany me.
Your wife!
Yes.
I was married to Angela Guessippi...
...this morning.
What time is it now?
1 o'clock.
Well, I can't wait any longer...
...will you please fasten this note
to the bell-pull, over there.
Alright... drive on!
You'll be sure to locate Angela... and tell her.
Aye... that I will...
And remember my boy, whatever happens...
...your home is here.
Some day, God willing...
...the doors of Casa Bonnyfeather will open again...
...for you... if not for me.
Thank you sir.
I shan't forget.
And how is our thrifty merchant getting along?...
...The Honourable John Bonnyfeather.
That old fool?!
The bigger fool... the better for you!
Your inheritance.
You flatter me... Your Excellency!
Why do you always call me 'Your Excellency'?
Well, perhaps if i saw you oftener
than once every 2 or  years
when you happen to be passing through Leghorn...
If you think it's on my way...
...you're mistaken.
When I left Madrid I had orders from the king...
...to proceed direct to Paris.
So, you see?!
Then take me with you, please!
You promised!
My dear...
...an attractive woman doesn't go to Paris...
...she lets Paris come to HER!
Meaning YOU, I suppose?!
You are so wise!
So clever!
But I know something that would kill you...
...if you knew!
And when will I have the pleasure of knowing?
When Paris no longer comes to Faith.
Well, goodbye Capt. Jorham...
It was a splendid voyage and I enjoyed it.
Pretty smart navigating, too...
The last time I hit Cuba...
...I was aiming for Charleston, South Carolina!
Welcome!
Welcome for the good Capt. Jorham!
And this, I'm certain, must be Seńor Adverse!
Delighted to meet you!
I'm Carlo Cibo.
Mr Bonnyfeather's representative.
And how's the enchanting Mrs Jorham?
She's waiting for me on board.
- Well, God bless you.  - Thank you sir.
Now, Mr Bonnyfeather...
Oh, yes, his letter about you arrived last week.
Unfortunate. Quite futile!
You might have saved yourself a journey.
Oh... you shall see!
My servant... devoted to me...
He'll bring your luggage to my house.
- But what...?    -We still have plenty of time!
Bring Seńor Adverse's luggage to my home.
Don't sleep on your way...
...or you'll get a beating!
My house is yours.
We shall drink to the past...
...forget the future...
...and pleasantly live the present.
I have a million questions about Europe...
...to ask you.   - Yes, but time is...
Please...time is unlimited in Havana.
I'm a gentleman of leisure...
With a house full of servants...
...and charming disposition.
And an overwhelming power of persuasion.
You'll be glad I persuaded you, my friend!
But wait till you see Havana!
Seńor, let me make myself clear...
I've come to Cuba for one reason...
...and one only...
...to collect the just debt to Mr Bonnyfeather.
And to return to my home and my wife,
as speedily as possible.
An admirable ambition, but quite futile.
- Why?   - Because Gallego has quit! Gone away...
There's nothing left of the firm
but an old trading post in Africa.
Well, I shall have to go there.
Take it over, if need be.
You can probably have it...
But who wants it?!
It's only good for slave trading.
Slave trading?!
Sure!... Gallego and Son were slave traders.
Didn't you know that?
My friend... the strongest men break
when they try to battle with fate.
Now, let me see...
You need a bit of tailoring, the first thing...
And then...
Tony... did you hear me?
Anthony!
I said you need completely new
and different clothes.
I shall arrange with my tailors to...
You remind me of Mr Bonnyfeather...
The first time I met him...
He thought I needed clothes too!
And did you?
As I recall, I was stark naked!
My boy... you haven't stopped to figure out yet
that life is just a series of sensations.
Some to be desired...
...others to be avoided. That's all that matters!
For instance...
...at this moment you and I
are riding comfortably in a carriage...
enjoying ourselves...
...while over there in that courtyard...
...a poor devil who is doubtless
a much better Christian than we are...
...is being beaten to death.
Hey... stop!
Enough! Stop it!
I'll start with you!
Wait! Tony...
To interfere with a master and slave
is punishable by death!
Come back to the carriage!
Stop it!
Back to the carriage!
Listen!
Bring the monk!
I know you, Carlo Cibo!
I know you!
You've seen what happens to slaves...
You've seen how a wicked system...
...has given one man the right of life and death...
...over his fellow men.
You've seen a man beaten, tortured, killed...
...because he was unfortunate enough
to have been born poor.
My son...
You'll meet a lot like her in Africa.
I want to speak to Seńor Cibo!
We're honoured by a visit from the police.
Be quiet... both of you!
Tell them to keep on playing.
Seńor, I'm sorry to disturb you...
...but we're looking for a monk.
A monk with Carlo Cibo?!
Upon my soul!
You know me better than that!
- He was seen in your company.  - Impossible!
Nevertheless, I must search your house!
Have you a warrant from the governor?
Not yet, seńor, but nevertheless...
Nevertheless you have to get one.
Goodnight!
- Has he gone?   - For the moment.
- What can we do?
There's no chance for François, I'm afraid...
Unless you can smuggle him out of Cuba.
You've both been very kind to me...
I thank you...
...and I'll pray for you.  - Where are you going?
To give myself up.
There's no need for you to become involved.
- Come with me.   - Where to?
- To Africa.  - Anthony, no!
In heaven's name, I implore you not to go...
You'll destroy yourself...
You'll live in eternal horror...
Unable to sleep... unable to think!
Followed always by the cries of those
you've sold into misery.
You cannot barter in human souls!
My debt is to Bonnyfeather.
It's a greater sin, not to repay it.
I think you're making a terrible mistake, Anthony.
Cuba is flourishing...
You can go into some business here...
...and eventually pay off Mr Bonnyfeather.
It may take longer...
But it mustn't take longer.
It must be done as quickly as possible.
I must get back to my wife.
My son... I will go with you to Africa.
Now you'll have to withstand salvation, Tony...
Morning, noon and night!
Perhaps I'll need salvation.
Receipts... 221 slaves at auction...
Ł14,229.25
Total proceeds today... Ł18,404.
Net profit on last shipment...
Ł12,878.67
A nice profit.
With luck, today's trading
should settle the Bonnyfeather debt.
Yes.
And you'll be free to go back to Europe.
I imagine you'll be glad to get away
from this infernal noise!
What do you want, Neleta?
You have not ordered the food
prepared for the feast after the trading.
There's plenty of time.
Please... you won't go away.
Isn't there work for you to do?
Ferdinando... welcome the chiefs for me.
But they expect YOU!
- They will be insulted!  - Do as I say!
Mr Adverse...
You ARE coming back with me, aren't you?
I'm sure that Mr Bonnyfeather...
Bonnyfeather! What does HE care?!
Has he ever once written me?
3 years in this hole, and not a word!
- Nothing!   - Well, perhaps...
The master of Futa Jaloon
must be welcomed by the master of Belagos...
Not a servant.
I give you my greetings...
And by the blessing of Allah...
trading will begin this day
at the firing of the gun.
I'll give Ł6.
I'll take Ł8.25.
Ł6.25
Look! The strength of a horse...
Teeth like pearls!
He is worth 8!
7!
8!
Ł7.25
7... and no more.
Done!
What's wrong here?
This one thinks he's been cheated.
- Only Ł7! He is worth...  - Quiet!
If there's any more trouble,
the trading will stop!
You can go back to your villages
as you came here...
Penniless!
Take him away!
Bring another one.
I see François is still helping the cripples.
The chiefs hate him.
They call him the White Devil-Doctor.
Have you no pity?
I told you I wanted no more trouble.
I've said that Brother François
may have the rejected slaves...
And I say it again!
He protects runaway slaves!
He only protects those slaves that you's kill...
because they've been rejected.
Take your cripple away from here!
Go on with the trading!
Bring another one!
Brother François!
There is one other you might save.
Who?
Mr Adverse... Today settles the debt.
I told you to go back to your huts!
The time has come when you said you'd leave.
My son, there can be no justification for sin.
But what little justification
you thought you had...
no longer exists.
You must go back.
To do what?
You have a wife.
How do I know?
Have I once heard from her?
Maybe she's dead.
In love with someone else.
Find out.
If she still loves me,
she can wait a little longer.
There's money here... money and power!
For the first time in my life
the name Adverse means something.
It's respected and feared.
By savages!
You yourself call them brothers.
Yet YOU would make slaves of them!
Well, what am I?
I'm slaving to pay a debt!
And a slave to conventions and gratitude.
Now, I pay a debt to myself.
I owe myself wealth and power.
I owe the name that was invented for me
the right to perpetuate itself.
It will not live, Anthony...
It will die of its own evil...
....unless you give it back to honour and truth.
I won't let it die.
I'll stay here.
When I can afford to leave, I will.
Afford?
Is it only the rich who can afford to be kind?
And live without sin?
I shan't come here to trouble you any more.
If you want to see me,
you'll have to come to my hut.
The ship's going.
With a big cargo, too.
The last until the rains are over.
Rains!
Neleta, you've had your wish...
The boat went away without me.
I am glad!
Master... Brother François refuses to come here.
Very well...
Why do you stare at me?
Go in the other room! Get out!
Get out of here!
It's your move, Mr Adverse.
Brother François!
My son, what is it? You have a fever!
Father Xavier!
Where have you been?
Anthony! Come... help me!
Quem nostrum ignorare arbitraris...
Father Xavier!
Could I go for a walk outside the walls?
What do you want?
I've come to see Anthony.
Get out!... We don't want you here!
Angela mia!
He hates you.  He said to go away!
Help me to save him!
If you don't go away from here...
I'll take your flock, and ship them to Havana!
Children, cripples and all!
Your master wouldn't let you!
How can he stop me?
He is sick.
I am master, now!
Please!
Remember what I said...
I'll give you until tomorrow to be gone!
Anthony, you must go back to bed!
No word from Brother François?
You told him I was still down with fever?
I told him, but he will not come.
Don't worry any more!
You are better... You are getting well!
In a few days the sun will shine!
There will be trading again.
Anthony will stay here...
For great power... Grow rich!
Power...
Money...
I must see Brother François!
It's nothing!
How do you know?
Where is Brother François?!
- In his hut, I tell you!   - You lie!
He's out in the jungle...
- They're after him to kill him!   - No!
- Tell me the truth!   - I am telling the truth!
You sent him away, that's what you did!
You hated him and wanted him to leave Africa...
You beast... You savage!
Brother François!
You're dying!
No, Anthony...
It is you who are dying... Not I.
Forgive me, I didn't know that...
They didn't tell me you'd been driven away.
Promise...
Promise me you'll leave Africa.
I promise!
Brother François!
Where do you go, Signore?
Casa da Bonnyfeather.
- On business?  - Why?
The Casa da Bonnyfeather has been closed
for the past 5 years,
I expected it would be.
Drive along.
Your Excellency has lived in Leghorn?
Yes... some years ago.
Do you remember a Vincent Nolte?
Yes... yes... I remember!
He's in Paris, now.
A great banker they say...
A friend of Napoleon.
He come here every now and then.
What brings him back?
Surely it can't be on business.
He's searching for a friend...
A young clerk, who went to sea and disappeared.
Disappeared?
Si, Signore, disappeared.
Too bad!
When the old Bonnyfeather died...
...left him a big fortune.
Bonnyfeather is dead?!
Yes... Over a year.
Mr Bonnyfeather's housekeeper?
Couldn't she locate this young clerk either?
No... Lucky for her too.
If this clerk will not come back...
...she will get all the money!
Adverse, yes... Anthony Adverse!
That was his name.
Ever hear of him?
There used to be an inn on the Strada Calypso...
- Si... Signora Bonino's place.   - That's right.
Drop my luggage there please.
You trust me, Signore?
Oh, I think so...
Just say it's for Mr Adverse. Mr Anthony Adverse.
Can you remember that?
- You!   - May I come in?
Did you think I'd died in Africa?
I didn't know what to think...
Your letters...
You knew where I was,
but you weren't going to tell, were you, Faith?
Mr Bonnyfeather didn't want it known
that you were engaged in slave-trading.
Anthony... why do you take this attitude?
We've always been friends.
On the contrary...
You've hated me from the first time I came here.
But why? That's what I want to know!
And why was Bonnyfeather so fond of me...
...to leave me his money?
Why... he was in his dotage!
That isn't true.
You know the real reason... Now tell me!
Tell me!
Oh... Don Luis!
This is Mr Adverse...
The heir to Bonnyfeather's estate.
Congratulations, Signore.
Your arrival is most opportune.
Would you join us?
We have much to talk over.
It's strange that I never heard
Mr Bonnyfeather speak of you.
I might say the same, Signore.
At one time,
Mr Bonnyfeather and I were very intimate.
But that was before you were born.
At least, before you were adopted.
Don Luis...
Do you know if Mr Bonnyfeather had any...
...unwelcome relatives?
Anyone, of whom he might have been ashamed?
What makes you ask?
I can't help feeling that I'm related to him.
The first time we met... I remember distinctly...
He was sitting at his desk in the other room...
..talking to a priest.
And when he looked in my direction,
he stopped suddenly...
...and just stared.
And tears came to his eyes.
Your parents might have been friends of his.
Perhaps.
Yet, why should he make me his heir?
You have no recollection?
Only that I was raised by a group of nuns...
...at the Convent of the Holy Child...
Anyone who could help prove Mr Adverse's identity
would be very welcome, I'm sure.
I know how eager he is.
You...enquired at the convent?
Records are meagre.
I was left there on the 17th January, 1773.
Abandoned?!
Yes... in a black bag...
...containing a Madonna and a few gold pieces.
Rather interesting...
Don't you think, Don Luis?
Young man... if I were you,
I wouldn't seek to know more.
You've been extraordinarily fortunate, as it is.
But isn't it only natural...
Considering the circumstances...
...it might also be dangerous.
Why?
For many reasons.
I advise you to forget it!
You are going to Paris?
At once... about the will.
I'll see Mr Nolte.
I trust you'll have no difficulty
in establishing your claim?
Thank you, Seńor.
I really came here to locate Angels... my wife.
I don't suppose you know what became of her?
Angela?!
Let's see...
The last I heard, she was touring the provinces
with an opera company.
How long ago was that?
3 years... no, 4 years.
And Mr Bonnyfeather
never tried to get in touch with her?
I couldn't say, I'm sure.
Wouldn't it be more truthful to admit that you
prevented him from getting in touch with her.
Pray that I'll find her, Faith...
...and ease your conscience.
If you have one.
Goodbye, Don Luis.
I'm indebted to you.
For the tea.
I told you I had a secret.
I told you, years ago.
You couldn't prove it.
Oh, couldn't I?!
There's an old picture of Maria...
...locked away in my drawer.
The resemblance is still remarkable...
Even a stranger would know.
I should have let him die.
I'd be a rich woman, if you had.
I'd be in Paris, claiming an estate.
Keep quiet! You'll have it yet!
No I won't... There's not a chance.
But I'll have SOMETHING for the life I've lived.
The disappointment. The years of boredom.
And you're the one who'll give it to me!
- I?!   - For the price of that picture.
For the honour of a grandee of Spain
whose pretty wife had a child...   - Silence!
Hurts, doesn't it?  Makes you cringe!
You detestable creature!
What is it you want?
Your name... in marriage!
- Are you sure?  - Yes!
Sancho... Don't let that coach get past!
What are you stopping for?
There is a coach ahead...
Pretty close, I should say...
...judging from the tracks.
Never mind... keep going.
Mr Adverse!
- Have you any enemies?   - Why?
Take a look at that coach down there...
See it?... hiding behind the boulder...
It looks to me as if they were waiting
to shove someone into the gorge.
Of course, they may not...
But on the other hand, there is that precipice.
How are the brakes?
Hold the coach maybe...
But the horses would drag us.
Could you hold the coach, without the horses?
Without the horses?!
Come down here... I'll show you what I mean.
If we could get that pin out, quickly enough...
He was the best servant I ever had.
The coach was rather handy, too!
Let's see your papers!
Come on... hurry up!
What's all the excitement around here?
None of your business!
Are we far from Paris?
2 or 3 hours.
Thank you.
Major... I have some information for you...
Yes, your Excellency?
Some way back, we met an Englishman...
...who I recognised as a spy...
He's travelling this way.
An Englishman?!
There isn't a doubt of it!
He's travelling under the name of Anthony Adverse.
Don't pay any attention to his passport!
Thank you, your Excellency!
We'll watch out for him!
- Pleasant journey!   - Thank you, major!
- What's the trouble?   - No trouble, monsieur...
If your papers are in order,
you'll be allowed to continue.
Anthony Adverse? From Leghorn?
Yes.
Are you a native of Leghorn?
- I was born there.   - Have you any proof?
My passport.
Step out, please.
Is that not sufficient?
You are perhaps unaware, Mr Adverse...
...that France and England are still at war.
I may be English, but I'm an Italian subject.
And your parents?
Your father... What was he?!
Don't you know?!
Arrest him!
The general will see you, Herr Nolte...
that you'll do him the honour
of remaining for dinner.
Thank you Mr Bourrienne.
It won't be much in the way of food, I'm afraid...
- Just a military mess...   - I'll be delighted.
What is it Doumet?
I've arrested this fellow on grounds of suspicion.
Also, for insulting an officer of the French army.
- An Englishman.  - That's good enough.
- Anthony!   - Hello, Vincent!
How did you get here?
Ask the major.
Do you know him?
Certainly I know him...
His name's Anthony Adverse.
We grew up together in Leghorn.
I was told the gentleman was a British spy.
By whom?
A traveller in the poste-chaise...
A Spanish nobleman.
A Spanish nobleman travelling in a public coach?
It does seem strange somehow...
Strange? It's incredible.
HE's the man you should have arrested.
Sorry, sir.
Release the guard.
My apologies, Mr Adverse...
I trust you won't mention this to the General?
I'm glad to be relieved of the necessity.
It's extremely regrettable, but unfortunately...
- De Bourrienne...   - Yes, I'm coming.
Excuse me, gentlemen.
Tell me some more of this business.
Well, the main thing is this...
We advanced a huge sum of money to Bonaparte...
...with the understanding he would pay us back...
...the moment he could lay his hands
on a lot of gold that is owing him in Mexico.
He learned recently
that the gold can't be shipped to France
without the payment of an exorbitant tax.
So he's refused to authorise its collection.
Until he does, we don't get our money.
Meanwhile, his failure to pay
has brought us to the verge of bankruptcy
And you too... personally!
As well as my clients.
Oh, it's frightful, Tony.
Why don't you let me lend you the money
that I've inherited from Mr Bonnyfeather.
That'll tide you over...
...at least until this gold affair is settled.
I wish there was some other means, Ouvrard.
Frankly... I'd rather lose everything...
than have Anthony run the risk
of impoverishing himself.
There isn't any risk...
I'm absolutely certain the gold will be delivered.
I too, monsieur.
I've even got Mademoiselle Georges
to use her influence with Napoleon.
Mademoiselle Georges? Who's she?
A new prima donna...
Bonaparte's infatuated with her.
An exquisite creature.
I'm to have the honour of escorting her
to the ball tomorrow night.
You don't say!
Would you like to go, Tony?
Perhaps we'd better.
It's entirely up to you.
Well, gentlemen...
I guess there's nothing more to discuss...
Is there?
Au revoir, monsieur...
and thank you for your generosity.
The money you're placing at our disposal...
...will just about save our skins.
You're quite welcome.
- Goodnight Vincent.   - Goodnight.
Tony... do you realise what you've done?
Yes.
You may lose your entire fortune.
Everything!
I know.
Don't you care for money?
Doesn't it mean anything to you?
Not very much, Vincent.
A man died so that I might learn
there was something besides money and power.
Tell me, what's happened to you?
If you don't want money and power...
...what DO you want?
Angela.
Good heavens, man...
You're not still looking for HER?
She's probably...
Probably dead... probably forgotten me...
Probably this, that, or 1000 other things.
I think about it till I'm ready to go mad.
Then I assure myself that one thing is possible...
SOMEWHERE... Angela is waiting for me.
Be reasonable Anthony...
Why should she wait for you?
Because she's my wife.
Because we pledged ourselves to the future...
...of the name that was invented for me.
With her, I can give it roots in the present...
..and have children to carry it to the future.
Love, a home, a tradition!
These are the very essence of a man's soul.
There are his wealth and his power.
Without them, he has nothing.
The general is early tonight.
Naturally... He's expecting Mademoiselle Georges.
According to Mr Nolte...
You had some very exciting adventures in Africa.
Please tell us about them!
I assure you I never had one
quite the equal of this.
Your friend's quite intriguing!
And I think very handsome.
Wait until you see him without his mask!
I can hardly wait till we unmask at midnight.
Mlle Georges has just arrived.
- Mademoiselle... your mask.  - Thank you.
Mademoiselle... May I have the honour?
Pleasure, monsieur.
This is once, Ouvrard...
...that I am willing to acknowledge
my indebtedness to a banker.
I've been told that Napoleon is a bad dancer.
You were told right, Mr Adverse... watch!
A friend of yours?
No!
I thought...
Mr Ouvrard must be hiding...
I can't see him anywhere.
- Allow me...   - No, please!
Can't seem to place him... Show him in.
I hope you'll pardon me...
The nature of my visit...
Debrulle! Why of course I remember!
It's been a long time since Leghorn.
Nevertheless, I should've remembered the name.
Where is Angela?
Surely you must know!
I do... that's why I'm here!
Oh my friend... My friend!
Tell me, Debrulle, is she still with the troupe?
No... no more.
Has she given up her singing?
Well... not entirely!
She still sings a little.
Where is she now?
She's taken a cottage out near Passy.
Passy? Then I can see her at once!
Why not!
Bless you! Come on... hurry!
Why does she live in such an out-of-the-way place?
Well, perhaps because she prefers it.
Go... Go, she's waiting for you!
Anthony!
Don't talk!
Just let me hold you close to me!
You've changed, but your eyes are still the same.
Oh darling, what happened?
What EVER happened?!
Bonnyfeather promised to tell you...
He didn't!
I went there once...
...but he sent word by Faith
that you didn't wish to see me.
- Faith lied!  - Is it true you went to Africa?
Faith would have told you that...
She knew that I was planning...
Let's not think of her now!
She doesn't matter.
All I want is to see you...
...feel your presence...
...and to know we're together.
Forever, this time.
Nothing must ever separate is again...
Nothing!
Why, Anthony?!
I've died a thousand times
since I saw you last.
I've been greedy and cruel...
I've wanted wealth and power.
Now I know there's nothing I want, but you.
Only you.
And the future that we'll make together...
- Anthony...  - Yes, mother?
You won't have to go to Havana
to find your father.  He's come back!
This is he!
My son!
And then what?
He took the child in his arms.
Was I right?
As usual.
That is all... you may go.
A child in his arms...
Do you want him arrested?
For being in love? Don't be a fool!
We can order him out of France.
No, that's wrong.
He must leave of his own accord.
Congratulations!
What for?
Bonaparte's agreed to our scheme.
- On the Mexican gold?  - Yes.
I've never seen him more amiable.
And whom do you think he's chosen
to go to America?
- How would I know?  - YOU, Tony!
None other than you, Anthony Adverse.
Provided you're willing, of course... sit down...
Let's talk it over.
The gold will be smuggled into New Orleans...
where you will receive it...
and arrange for its transfer to Philadelphia.
There it can be shipped on a neutral boat,
direct to France.
It's our only chance to get hold of it, Tony.
Failure means bankruptcy.
For you, as well as for us.
You don't seem to relish the idea.
Yesterday I should have welcomed it... now...
Decisions of this sort take time, naturally.
On the other hand we can't disguise the fact
that it's a matter of the gravest importance...
for all concerned.
I understand.
I'll give you my answer within 48 hours.
Don't worry, Vin.
It's your, now.
I want you to keep it always.
- Goodnight mummy.  - Goodnight, darling.
You've won him completely.
Angela...
Have I won you?... That's the question.
Anthony... you must go to America,
regardless of me.
I couldn't.
Not even to save Vincent.
But you're own money's at stake, as well as his.
Some day it should go to our son.
You wouldn't want him to be poor, as WE were.
You're my wife, Angela.
I can't understand
you're not wanting to come with me.
You're hiding something... What is it?
I have my career.
You told me once, you didn't want a career
unless you could be a great singer.
Truly great.
Yes... I remember.
After all, what does it mean to be great?
Look at Mlle Georges and Bonaparte...
Everyone knows how she managed to succeed.
Is that what they're saying?
You don't envy HER, do you?
No... I don't envy her.
Why won't you come with me... Why?
Oh, my darling!
My sweet!
You're all the world to me.
You're everything I ever wanted.
I only know that, now.
Don't say any more, Anthony!
Please don't say any more!
I didn't mean to make a scene.
I must be nervous...
I always am when I'm going to sing.
Sing? Where?
Tomorrow night.
- At the Opéra.   - Here?! In Paris?!
Yes.
That's wonderful!
Did you think I'd mind?!
I'll be there to hear you!
Oh, I'll be so proud!
Oh, Anthony!...
Oh, my husband... Hold me close!
Have you heard the rumour about the necklace?
The one Josephine has been begging for.
They say Bonaparte's given it to Mlle Georges!
No! He wouldn't dare!
Will she wear it, do you think?
No woman could resist a triumph like that!
Good evening, Ouvrard... Greetings!
How DO you do?!
This is quite a surprise, Don Luis!
I didn't expect to see you in Paris.
Nor I to see you, Monsieur.
Allow me to present my wife.
Life is strange, is it not, monsieur?
Incredibly.
I can't find Angela's name on the program.
Ssh! Mlle Georges is about to appear!
That's her voice!
That's Angela!
Quiet! That's Mlle Georges!
That girl used to wash my clothes.
I remember.
The necklace! You see it?
Goodbye, Anthony!
Goodbye.
Dearest Anthony...
You are far better fitted than I
to take care of...
...of our son.
I send him to you with all the love in my heart...
I know he will be happy.
Forgive me...
for not seeing you again.
Angela.
Mummy said that I'm to go away with you.
On a big ship.
Your mother said that?
She did... Honestly!
Are you sure you didn't ask her?
All I said was...
"Why don't you come, too?"
And she said...
Well, she would make it, some other time.
But that YOU had to go, and it seems a shame
not to have someone to go with you.
So I said... "Alright, I'll go!"
Did you mean it?
Do you really want to go?
Oh, Father!
Set tight all tacks and braces!
Well, here we are... off to America!
- Ever been there?    - No, never.
Lots of people going nowadays.
And they ain't coming back, either.
Looks as though
they'll have a big country over there!
Peace of mind.
That's all they're looking for.
A chance to lead lives of their own making.
Great place for youngsters, too...
They grow up big and strong!
You'll like it Master Adverse.
"Adverse"?  Is THAT my name?
Yes.
It's a new name, son.
Three people made it.
Father Xavier gave it a mind...
Father François, a soul...
And your mother, a heart.
We must never forget them Anthony.
- "Anthony Adverse"?   - Yes.
Anthony Adverse.
English subtitles by FatPlank for KG
Watch Movies, TV Series & Live Sports
www.admitme.app