He was the first.
We got a street
in the park named after him.
And Danny Topinka,
Billy Vorsovich,
Phil and Larry Powell,
Tommy Finnelli.
Six boys from Massapequa...
and they all knew
what honour, duty,
and sacrifice meant.
They paid
the highest price.
They died for it.
This town's
been hit hard.
It's always
Doc here, he was
in the First War.
A lot of us here
were in the Second.
That's why
we can't give up.
That's why we're going to
win in Vietnam.
Because Massapequa's
been there before,
because of those
six wonderful boys,
and because of him.
Ron...
come say a few words,
would you, please?
Ron Kovic,
ladies and gentlemen.
He was born
on the 4th of July, 1946.
Give him a big hand
on his great birthday.
I just want to say
for the guys in Vietnam
that we're doing our best.
It's not an easy situation,
but the boys' morale
over there is real high,
and you can feel
confident that we are...
we are going to
win that war.
I served my country,
and I don't want you
to feel sorry for me.
Do not shed a tear.
I have my hands,
my eyes, my ears...
I have my heart...
and I have...
what I feel...
I have what I feel is...
an unquen... quenchable...
O.K. It's O.K., Ronnie.
It's O.K., kid.
I'm sorry.
And we'll
continue to fight
because of guys
like Ron Kovic...
Dad, where's the car?
It's across
the street.
Like he said,
we're going to
win that war.
Ronnie.
Timmy?
Timmy, man?
Timmy!
I heard you were...
When did you get back?
When did you get out?
Wow, man.
Let's get the hell
out of here.
Mr Kovic?
Yeah. Sure.
Antiwar demonstrators have come
to Washington, D.C.
To shut the city down.
...and Martin's
Laugh In,
starring Dan Rowan
and Dick Martin,
with Sammy Davis, Jr.
And Judy Carne...
Honey.
Come on.
It's starting.
O.K. I'm coming.
It's the one
with Sammy Davis.
Oh, yeah?
Who else
used to play?
Come on, Ronnie.
No. Come on.
Tell me who.
Bobby Moore
at shortstop.
Grady Rogers
at third.
Grady got sick.
It was Finnelli at third.
Tommy Finnelli.
Yeah.
Got hit with one
of his own mortars.
That's crazy, man.
Shit, I heard
about that.
Remember the twins,
Phil and Larry Powell?
Oh, the twins. Oh.
They were great wrestlers.
Oh, man.
They were fucking great.
Tough.
Tough bastards.
When Phil got killed,
Larry... who wasn't much
for brains either...
went down the next day
and joined up.
Oh, God.
Then he got hit.
Oh, no.
It's true.
A land mine
or something.
He got hit in the head
with a tree.
Yeah. I'm telling you
the truth.
He goes over to Vietnam,
and he gets killed
by a flying fucking tree.
Oh.
That's really fucking funny.
I think the whole town
got devastated, Ronnie.
I don't think
we got a friend left.
It's really funny.
When did you
get hit, Timmy?
September the 18th.
Near Dong Ha.
A lot of bad shit
up there, Ronnie,
I'm telling you.
Things I don't
even want to talk about.
You know.
I mean, uh...
it was crazy.
Shooting
anything that...
anything that fucking moved,
you know?
When did you...
When did you get hit?
Me?
Well...
Uh, January 20th.
Yes.
Someplace off...
I don't even remember.
Up in the DMZ.
Walked into
a whole battalion of them.
Got shot
in the foot.
I got up
like I was...
back in the woods again,
like I was
John fucking Wayne,
emptying a mag, screaming,
"Come on, Charlie, motherfucker!
Come on out,
Charlie, motherfucker!"
Rat-tat-tat-tat.
I heard this crack
above my right ear,
and I just
felt my body...
drop out from under me.
Well, I thought
I was dead for sure.
Was the, uh...
How was
the hospital?
It sucked.
I know.
Really bad.
I'll tell you
something, Ronnie...
Sometimes
at night...
I get these headaches,
you know?
They're bad.
And, uh...
they just kind of
come over me,
and these doctors
don't know shit, you know.
They just come,
like I'm going crazy or something.
I don't feel... I don't feel
like me any more, you know?
I feel like...
when they come,
I feel like
somebody else.
What do you do?
Nothing.
Not a goddamned thing, you know?
Well... mostly I do
a lot of drugs.
Do anything
you can, you know?
Y-You get through it
any way you can.
When I was
in the hospital,
I thought, " Yeah.
Yeah, this makes sense."
What makes sense?
'Cause I failed, Timmy.
What are you
talking about?
'Cause I...
'Cause I killed someone...
some people. L...
I made some terrible...
mistakes.
Ronnie, we all made mistakes.
I mean, you...
you had no choice.
Those damn pansy
demonstrators
will never
understand.
Don't talk about it.
It was insane
over there.
Sometimes I wish...
I wish I'd...
When I got shot
in the foot,
I could have laid down.
Who gives a fuck now
if I was a hero or not?
I was paralysed,
castrated that day. Why?
'Cause I was so s...
stupid.
I have my dick and my balls now
and I think...
I think, Timmy,
I'd give everything I believe in,
everything I got...
all my values
just to have
my body again,
just to be whole again.
But I'm not whole.
I never will be,
and that's...
the way it is,
isn't it?
Ronnie...
it's your birthday.
You're alive.
You made it.
Smile.
Syracuse, New York,
our next stop.
Oh, where have you been
My blue-eyed son
My darling young one
I've walked
and I've crawled
On six crooked highways
I've been out in front
Of a dozen dead oceans
I've been 10,000 miles
In the mouth
of a graveyard
And it's a hard
It's a hard
It's a hard rain
That's gonna fall
Who did you meet
My blue-eyed son...
Those long letters
I wrote you
from over there?
Crazy stuff, huh?
That's all right.
I had to say everything
I couldn't say
when we were growing up.
They were
beautiful letters.
Yeah?
Yeah.
I wasn't too sure
about the spelling in them.
Who cares
if you can spell?
There was...
There was a lot of feeling
in the words.
I'm so sorry for what happened
to you, Ronnie.
My mom called me
at school and told me.
I was just
so shocked.
L... I wanted to...
reach out
and help you.
But...
it was just
so frustrating,
I just...
stood in the hallway
of my dorm room shaking.
I couldn't
say anything.
Donna...
uh, they need you
over at Locklin.
I can't right now,
Jeff. Later.
Well, don't forget
about the meeting.
Yeah, 9:00?
Yeah. Thanks.
I'm sorry.
You're real busy, huh?
We've got this Kent State
demonstration tomorrow.
I'm on the organizing
committee.
Kent State.
I heard about that.
It was... Jesus...
terrible.
It's terrible.
When I saw that girl
lying in that pool of blood
at Kent State,
I kept on thinking
of that poster
of the children
that were killed at My Lai.
And I kept on thinking
about you over there...
and all the boys
who've died,
who've sacrificed
their bodies and...
and their minds.
The war is
so wrong, Ronnie.
It's so wrong.
I just had to
do something.
We don't need arms
We need hands to hold
And we don't need bombs...
Strike now,
shut it down!
You know, Ronnie,
I'm not saying that you are,
but if you have any feelings
against the war,
you could really help.
I mean,
you've been there.
You know
what it's like.
You could tell people
what's happening,
and they'd really
listen to you.
Remember the prom?
Moon River
Wider than the sea
My huckleberry friend...
Remember that?
Yeah.
Moon River for me
Boy, was I crazy
that night.
I just had to dance with you
before I went in.
It was like I knew.
I made a promise to myself
that I would come back
and love you
forever.
Donna.
Hey, Donna.
Yeah?
The Reverend
can't make it tomorrow.
What?
He can't make it.
Oh.
What can we do?
Who can we get?
Just let me think.
I'll see you later.
Better hurry.
Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
Ronnie, I got to...
I got to go inside.
Do you want to come?
No, I don't
think so.
O.K.
Maybe I'll
hang around.
Maybe we'll
talk later.
All right.
I'll see you later.
1, 2, 3, 4!
We don't want
your fucking war!
1, 2, 3, 4! We don't want
1, 2, 3, 4!
We don't want your fucking war!
All right! Wow!
It's great to be at free
Syracuse University!
We're really getting
an education now, aren't we?
Right on, man!
Right on!
Right freaking on!
Yesterday I was at
Brooklyn College...
NYU... they were
both closed down!
Over 200 high schools
are closed down.
Over 400 universities
It'll be twice that number
by the time...
This is an unlawful
assembly.
If you do not
disperse...
The people that killed
the kids at Kent State
have names like
General Waste-more-land!
Spiro Agnew!
Tricky Dicky Nixon!
Wait for the command.
And then we go
to Washington,
confront the war makers
in their own house!
On to Washington!
On to the White House!
I loved
this country once.
And all this
I won over there.
Check it out...
Purple Heart,
Bronze Star,
all the commendation
medals,
all the rest
of that garbage.
It don't mean a thing.
Fuck this...
shit!
This is war!
I said this is war!
They just killed two brothers
at Jackson State!
Stand by to gas!
Take them down!
What's going on?
Get out!
Get out of here!
Get back! Get back!
Donna!
The whole world's
watching!
Donna!
Now, when I was just
a little boy
I stand up
to my daddy's knee
My papa said, son,
don't let the man get you
The way that
he done to me
'Cause he'll get you now...
He says...
No, he'll get you...
My machine breaks down,
and they're ready
to cut my leg off.
And that's what the guy...
Now, that's what the guy
in the hospital said.
He said, " You can
take your Vietnam,
and you can stuff it up your ass,"
he said.
That's what it's
about in Vietnam.
Hey, Mel!
Double shot of rye,
beer chaser,
sweetheart!
They ain't fighting
the war to win, anyway.
They should
just bomb Hanoi
and get the boys
the fuck out of there.
Four corner hard way.
Fuckin'-A.
Vietnam.
They ought
to write a song
about something
that gets under your skin.
Remember Del Shannon?
Runaway?
As I walk along
I wonder what went wrong
To our love
A love that was so strong
Oh, whoa, whoa, whoa
I'll tell you
what went wrong
It was fucking Vietnam
It was the wrong fucking war.
Timmy, it was
the wrong fucking war.
Take a shot, will you?
You can take
your Vietnam,
and you can shove it
up yo' fuckin' ass!
You shove it
up your ass, pal.
Is everybody
supposed to feel sorry
because you're in
a fucking wheelchair?
You ain't the only
fucking Marine here.
I was on Iwo Jima.
We lost 5,000 men
the first day.
Don't cry in your
fucking beer to me.
Now, you served
and you lost.
You got to live
with it.
You're a Marine, man.
Semper fi.
Picked them.
They didn't pick you.
Quit your fucking
pissing and moaning.
Timmy, Timmy,
who is this asshole?
I don't know.
Leave it alone.
I think guys...
like you...
are dumb fucking assholes.
That's what I think.
I bet you do, you sorry
son of a bitch.
'Cause you know
if they win,
if they win it,
you'll be the first
against the wall.
You know you can't trust
a fucking traitor.
Call me a fucking traitor?
If you weren't
in that chair...
I am in this chair!
Top of the ninth,
Charlie!
Shut the fuck up.
You shut the fuck up, man!
Come on, Phil,
forget it!
- Bullshit!
- He's a nutjob!
Come on, Ronnie,
he ain't fucking worth it.
Will you come on?
Hey, what's happening?
What's your name?
Jenny.
Penny?
How about going
to Mexico with me?
Mexico?
What do you mean, Mexico?
I mean, you're really beautiful.
That's what I mean.
Oh, yeah?
Oh, a really
beautiful place...
the ocean...
the sand, sun.
We could leave tonight.
We could take a plane.
Let's go tonight.
I think you're
really crazy.
Hey, hey, Billy!
Hey, Steve!
What's going on?
Same old same old.
Well, I can remember
the 4th of July
Running through
the backwoods bay
Whoo! Whoo! Whoo!
I bet you practised a lot.
I've got a lifetime
of practice, Jenny.
The way that he done to me
'Cause he'll get you now
Gonna getcha
Uhh
Well, I can remember...
You O. K?
You all right?
I don't mean
to laugh.
Shut up, Jenny.
Look at him.
He's fucking shitfaced!
Ronnie?
Ron?
Give him some room.
Get him out of here.
Give me my chair.
I just want to dance.
Jenny!
I got it.
Come on, come on.
Hey, Steve,
let's go. Come on.
Come on.
Steve, come on.
Let's go.
What's going on?
Are you drunk again?
Hey, Mom.
He's drunk again.
Eli, we have
a drunk for a son.
You leave that alone.
You can't stay
in this house.
This is what
you believe in,
but I don't.
I don't believe
in him any more.
I'll take care
of him.
I wish I were dead
like him.
You don't know
what you're saying.
That's the problem.
I'm not dead.
I got to live.
I got to roll around
and remind them
of Vietnam.
You don't want to see us.
You want to hide us
'cause it is
a can of shit!
And I am a fucking dummy!
He won't listen.
He won't change.
Take your mom seriously.
You can't drink
in this house.
I believed everything
they told us.
Go fight! Go kill!
Sergeant man,
Marine Corps!
Yo, squad!
Left, squad!
Right, squad, left!
And it's all a lie.
The whole thing
is a bunch of lies!
Stop it! Go to bed!
What did they do to you
in that war?
You need help, Ronnie.
No, you need help,
with all your God
and your bullshit dreams
about me!
You are ashamed of me!
Go to sleep.
You go to bed.
Fuck you!
What did you say
to me?
What...
Mom!
Fuck you!
You'll wake
the whole neighbourhood.
Wake them up!
Tell them!
Cusacks! Camelettis!
Walshes!
You tell them all
what they did to me,
what they did to this whole block,
this whole country.
They'll call the police.
We went to Vietnam
to stop communism.
We shot women
and children.
You didn't shoot
women and children.
The church
blessed the war.
Communism,
the insidious evil.
They...
They told us to go.
Yes, that's what
they told us.
Thou shall not kill, Mom.
Thou shall not kill
women and children.
Thou shall not kill,
remember?
Isn't that
what you taught us?
Stop it.
Stop it!
I don't want you
in this house.
You're out
of this house.
Ron, you made your point.
No! I haven't
made my point.
You tell her, Dad.
They're killing
everyone now!
I didn't force you
to go!
Yes, you did!
And it's all
falling apart!
King, Kennedy,
Kent State!
We all lost
the fucking war!
It's not my fault!
Communism won.
It's all for nothing.
That's not true,
Ronnie.
How do you know?
What do you know?
Ron.
Will you...
You tell her, Dad!
Tell her it's a lie!
It's a fucking lie!
There's no God!
God is as dead
as my legs!
There's no God!
There's no country!
It's nothing.
It's just me
and this fucking wheelchair
for the rest of my life
for nothing.
Me and this... this...
this dead penis, Mom.
Oh, God! Ronnie!
No, not with
the catheter.
- For God's sake...
- Penis!
Eli, I can't
stand it any more.
To hell with you.
In church
they say it's a sin
if you play
with your penis.
I just wish I could.
Don't say penis
in this house!
Penis!
Stop!
Big fucking erect penis, Mom!
- Stop!
- Penis! Penis!
He won't let go!
What can I do?
I never even got time
to learn how to use it.
It's gone in some
jungle in Asia.
Just gone for...
I'm sorry
it happened this way.
I'm sorry you're sad, Mom.
I'm so sorry
you're sa-sad.
I'm so fucked up.
Fucked up.
Ronnie...
maybe a little trip
is all you need.
That place
down in Mexico
you were
talking about.
I don't want
to go to Mexico.
to go no place.
I don't want
Ronnie...
I think
you should go.
What can I do,
Ronnie?
What do you want?
I want to be
a man again.
Who's going
to love me, Dad?
Who's ever
going to love me?
Who's going to love me?
Hey, you maggots,
ante up 5 American.
Let's go. Ante up.
Ed, you're light.
The game
is seven-card stud,
one up, two down.
One up, two down.
We got a 5, a jack.
That's a fucking joker, a king.
The price of poker
just went up, gentlemen.
Charlie buys a queen.
Charlie, puppy.
Two down, two down.
Hey, big blue eyes,
what's your name?
What's that?
What's your name?
Ron Kovic.
Just what we need.
Another limp dick.
Where from?
Massapequa,
Long Island.
Guys, say hello
to Ron Kovic.
Just in from the States.
Hi, Ron.
Laugh, motherfucker.
You'll get yours.
Fuck you.
Put your hand
right there, baby.
What's your name?
Charlie,
from Chicago.
How long has this game
been going on?
55 hours.
How long
have you been here?
A hundred fucking years.
'Cause I got a gun.
I ain't ever going back.
Fuck the States.
Nobody understood.
Nobody gave a shit.
The fucking women
didn't even want
to look at me.
Fucking States.
I ain't never
going back.
I want something simple.
Oh, baby,
you're so beautiful.
Ain't she beautiful?
Here we go.
She's beautiful.
Go into town.
Get yourself one.
Fuck the shit out of you,
even if you are paralysed.
Ain't that right, Martha?
You know what they say:
If you ain't got it in the hips,
you better have it in the lips.
Don't stay here,
man.
Get the fuck out.
You know, you're really drunk
on this Mescal shit...
when you swallow
the worm
and don't even know
you did it.
Last round of betting.
Let's go, maggots.
Are you from
Villa Dulce?
Yeah, yeah.
Yeah.
Bueno.
We go?
What's that?
Do you want
to go upstairs?
No. No, I'm just
looking around.
I just came in... Yeah!
I'd like to go upstairs.
I'd like to.
Good.
Then come.
Let's do it.
What's your name?
Maria Elena.
Maria Elena?
Hmm, si.
The money...
Sorry, I don't know how much...
This... This is good.
Why don't you
take them off?
No, I can't.
I can't
feel anything.
I was paralysed
in the war.
Vietnam?
Yes.
You let me see?
No.
Doesn't move.
I can't.
Oh, yes.
It's no good.
Yes, let me see.
No. Look, please...
the spine was severed.
I have no movement,
no feeling.
There's nothing
down here at all.
Nothing happens.
O.K.
We're going to have
a good time.
It's going to be O.K.
- You like?
- Yes.
Hey, man, Kovic.
How was it?
Ai yi yi yi
Did you get one?
Did you get two?
Look out!
Banzai, motherfucker!
She loves you,
right, tiger?
Thanks a lot.
It was great.
Just remember,
keep one hand on her tits
and the other hand
on your wallet.
Paradise!
Right, man?
Whoo!
Can I see this?
I'll rip your fucking eye out
and skull-fuck you, motherfucker.
You ever been skull-fucked?
Yeah, I'll do it, man.
I'll do it, motherfucker.
It don't mean a fucking thing.
I'll be here tomorrow.
You couldn't keep me away
with a baseball bat.
I'll be here for sure.
Vietnam.
So...
we get married
today, no?
Oh, yeah, yeah.
That would be great.
Yeah.
Hi.
Want to fuck me? Huh?
I'll give you
a blow job.
Hey, mister,
you want me?
60 pesos.
Let's go.
Aah!
"Dear Mr and Mrs Wilson...
"I don't... I don't know
how to tell you this.
"I knew your son
in Vietnam.
He was, uh..."
I'm going to kill that fucking guy.
I got him once.
I'll kill him now.
You'll see.
I'm serious.
Your body.
I'm just going
to fucking kill him.
ˇMás!
I'll fucking kill you!
I'll kill you,
bitch!
You can't talk to me
like that!
Hey! Charlie!
Get out! Get out!
The bitch thinks it's funny
I can't move my dick!
Fuck her.
I'll kill you, bitch!
Fuck all you
Mexican motherfuckers!
ˇMaricón!
You don't like it,
get out!
Fuck you!
Hey!
Don't touch my friend.
Don't you touch me!
Get the hell out!
Don't come back no more.
I wouldn't be here if
it weren't for that fucking war!
Fuck you!
Fuck all of you!
You sure you told him
the right place, man?
I told him fucking Villa Rosa!
Villa Rosa?
Villa Rosa!
Villa Rosa, seńor,
Villa Rosa.
Beautiful place.
Great whorehouse there,
man.
Wait until we get there.
Beautiful women with big tits,
small tits...
That goddamned slut.
That Mexican scumbag cunt.
I think I saw a sign,
Villa Rosa, Charlie,
10 minutes ago.
How far you going,
taco head?
żQué pasa?
Wasn't that turn back there...
that sign that said "Villa Rosa"?
Look at the meter!
It's rigged!
He's rigged the fucking meter!
Hey, asshole!
Hey, I told you
fucking Villa Rosa!
What are we
going to do now?
Fuck them.
Yeah, sure.
How we going to get out of here?
Fuck them all.
Fuck the whores.
Fuck the cab drivers.
Fuck Mexico.
Fuck Nixon, fuck Vietnam,
fuck them all.
But how we going
to get out of here?
They made me
kill babies, man.
Little gook babies.
You ever have
to kill a baby?
Yeah. O.K., come on.
We'll get a ride.
We got to get back
to the villa.
Fuck you!
What do you mean, O. K?
You ever have to kill
a little gook baby?
What the fuck do you know
what I did?
I didn't think so.
You're full of shit.
No, you are.
Leave me
the fuck alone!
You're nuts.
The sun
is going down.
We got to get
out of here.
Don't shit me, Kovic.
You never killed a baby.
You never had to.
You never put your soul
into that war,
never put your soul
on the line.
How the fuck
do you know?
Maybe I killed more babies
than you did, you fuck!
Maybe I did,
but I don't have
to talk about it!
Why not?
Why the fuck not?
What are you hiding?
What are you,
better than anybody else?
You a hero, maybe?
Got a bunch of fucking medals,
but deep down
you're full of shit!
You never fought.
You weren't even there.
What the fuck do you mean,
I wasn't there, man?
Come on, hero,
come clean.
Why should I?
What are you hiding?
You're the one that's hiding
here in Mexico.
What are you hiding from,
you whiny fuck?
Don't shit me!
You never killed anybody, anything,
did you, Kovic?
Did you?
Ever look at yourself
in the fucking mirror?
- Fuck you.
- You.
No... you!
Fuck you!
No, fuck you!
Get off me!
Hola, seńores.
żQué pasa aquí?
We need a ride.
O. K!
ˇVámonos!
You O.K., man?
Fuck you.
You're full of shit.
You don't get it.
You had a town once,
Charlie,
and a mother and father.
Things that made sense.
Do you remember
things that made sense,
things you could count on,
before we all
got so lost?
What are we going
to do, Charlie?
What am I going
to do, man?
What am I going to do?
Where you from, Wilson?
Venus, Georgia.
Georgia?
This is my second tour,
and I haven't seen
a Georgia boy get it yet.
Yeah?
Yeah,
I know about Wilson.
Sir, I think I might
have killed him, sir.
I think
I killed him.
I don't think so.
You don't have to worry
about them dogs.
They won't bite.
Y'all get away now.
Get on away!
It's all right.
They're probably just
afraid of that chair.
Mr Wilson, I'm Ron.
Thanks for, uh,
for seeing me.
Any friend of Billy's
is a friend of ours.
Well, uh, why don't you
come on in the house?
My wife fixed some chicken,
if'n you want some.
Yes, sir, it was
a real nice funeral.
Marine Honour Guard came
all the way down from Atlanta
in their fancy uniforms.
Fired their rifles
up in the sky.
Thank you.
The drums was beating.
'Course it was nothing
like the big war
100 years ago
down here.
But there was Billy
and Bruce... Bruce Crabtree...
Andy Henderson.
And the Rutledge boy,
Lance.
Yeah, Lance.
He was a nice boy.
For the life of me,
I still can't quite
figure that war out.
Why we had to go
all that dang way to fight it
and why's we had to lose
so many young men.
Can't figure it out.
But we got a proud tradition
here in this town.
Billy's great-grandfather
was at the First Bull Run.
My pa was
over in France in '18.
Don't forget, you were
over in the Pacific in '44.
Guadalcanal.
Is that right?
Yeah. Well, I guess
this family's fought
in every war that, uh,
this country's ever had.
I reckon we're ready
to do it again
if'n we have to.
'Course they never did know
what done happened and all.
There was a letter
from a colonel,
I think it was.
Colonel Moore.
That's right,
He said there was
a bad ambush one night.
Said that Billy distinguished himself
in the fighting.
He also told us that
Billy died real quick.
That's good
that he died quick.
I was
his squad leader.
I didn't know Billy
real well.
He was new,
kind of quiet.
We didn't talk much
to new guys.
He was 19,
is that right?
That's right, 19.
Only son?
Yes, sir.
My only boy.
I think he said
he was married
and you were pregnant?
I remember
the day he was killed.
Uh... it was a strange day.
We were out on patrol
near a beach area...
and, oh,
it was very confusing.
There was screaming
and firing.
Uh...
It was getting late,
and there were
these children, uh...
these babies...
that we killed
by mistake.
How awful.
And then it...
got really crazy.
And we had to pull back
because the NVA
were coming up on us.
And we got scattered
in the dunes.
People were yelling
at anything,
firing at anything.
And that was when it...
it happened.
I was, uh, confused...
scared.
I raised my rifle
three times...
and... shots...
The body fell
in the dunes.
God, this is...
this is very difficult
for me to say.
We don't have
to hear this, Ron.
But I think I was the one
that killed your son.
I was the one.
What's done
is done, sir.
I can't ever
forgive you...
but maybe the Lord can.
We understand, Ron.
We understand the pain
you've been going through.
Peace now!
Bring our brothers
home now!
1, 2, 3, 4,
we don't want
your fucking war!
1, 2, 3, 4,
we don't want
your fucking war!
1, 2, 3, 4,
we don't want
your fucking war!
1, 2, 3, 4,
we don't want
your fucking war!
1, 2, 3, 4,
we don't want
your fucking war!
1, 2, 3, 4,
we don't want
your fucking war!
1, 2, 3, 4,
we don't want
your fucking war!
Bring our brothers
home now!
Drugs. Marijuana.
Traffic violations.
Separate the hippies.
Tonight, I again proudly
accept your nomination
for President
of the United States.
And let us place ourselves
to win an even
greater victory
this November in 1972.
Four more years!
Can I break through
your complacency?
Do you have compassion
for the people
suffering in this war?
I'm telling you
this war is a crime!
I'm not as bitter
about my wounds...
Who do you
think you are?
Can I help you, sir?
You can't come through.
You can't
come through, sir.
I have a pass.
Who are these people?
You can't stop us!
You can't stop me!
Why are you
here tonight?
What do you
have to say?
My name's Ron Kovic.
I'm a Vietnam veteran.
I'm here to say
this war is wrong,
that this society lied
to me and my brothers...
Why don't you
shut up?
It deceived the people
in this country.
It tricked them
into going 13,000 miles
to fight a war against
a poor peasant people
who have a proud history
of resistance,
who have been struggling
for their own independence
for 1,000 years...
the Vietnamese people.
I can't... I can't find
the words to express
how the leadership
of this government sickens me.
Now, people say...
people say if you
don't love America,
then get the hell out.
Well, I love America,
but when it comes
to the government,
it stops right there.
The government is
a bunch of corrupt thieves.
They are rapists
and robbers.
We are here to say
we don't
have to take it any more.
We are here
to tell the truth.
They're killing
our brothers in Vietnam.
We want them
to hear the truth.
Traitor!
What are you,
a communist?
Is this what we get,
spit in the face?
Is this what we get?
Is this what we get, sir?
Spit in the face?
We're never going
to let the people
forget that war!
Four more years!
You're not sweeping it
under the rug
because you didn't
like the ratings.
This wheelchair,
our wheelchairs,
this steel, our steel
is your Memorial Day
on wheels.
We're your Yankee
Doodle Dandy come home.
We're your
Yankee Doodle Dandy.
Let's reject any philosophy
that would make us
a divided people of America.
Stop the bombing!
Stop the war!
Some sort of scuffle
has broken out
on the convention floor,
disabled veterans
protesting the Vietnam War.
We'll try to
get down there.
Why are they gassing us
in the parking lot?
Why are they fighting us?
Because it's a lie.
The truth is
they've killed a generation
of young men.
They have sacrificed
a whole generation
of young men.
Stop the bombing!
Communists!
Stop the war!
Stop the bombing!
Traitor!
Go home!
I say to you tonight...
in these times,
when there is so much
of a tendency
to run down those
who have served America
in the past and today,
let's give those
who have served in Vietnam
the honour and the respect
that they deserve
and that they've earned.
1, 2, 3, 4,
we don't want
your fucking war!
1, 2, 3, 4,
we don't want
your fucking war!
Get the car!
Shut the fuck up!
You're under arrest,
Kovic! Come on!
What?
Shut up!
You're a pig?
You should've died over there,
you traitor.
I don't have balance.
Give me
your hands!
O.K., I'll go
with you!
I'm not
under arrest.
I don't have to...
Hey, take it easy!
Get your hands
behind you!
I'm paralysed!
Get those cameras
out of here!
Hey!
I'm paralysed!
Get in the fucking car!
Hey!
My chair!
My ch...
Stop it!
Tactical line!
Advance and disperse
the crowd!
The whole world's
watching!
Let me go!
You O. K?
Doc, is he O. K?
I'm O.K.
How we doing here?
How many fingers
you got?
Your head is cut.
Anyplace else
hurting?
I'm O.K.
Where's my chair?
Bring his
chair over!
You're cut
over your eye.
The media's got
to see this.
We heard you
shouted down Nixon.
Eddie was arrested,
they beat Peterson,
O'Malley's
gassed real bad,
and Piscatelli's
got a concussion!
It's a fucking mess over there!
Frankie, bring the
media to the gate.
What?
The pigs are coming!
They're clearing the park!
They've arrested
like 30 people...
O.K., O.K., listen up!
Listen up.
Hey, hey, hey!
We're going
to take the hall back.
You hear?
We're going
to the gate,
we're gonna take
the motherfucking hall back.
Fall out! Let's move!
1, 2, 3, 4,
we don't want
your fucking war!
1, 2, 3, 4,
we don't want
your fucking war!
1, 2, 3, 4,
we don't want
your fucking war!
Let us reject the notion
of politics of the few,
by the few,
and for the few.
We dedicate ourselves
to the notion
this is a government
of the people,
by the people,
and for all the people,
black, brown, red,
yellow, white, women,
young, old,
workers, students.
This is our land
in this country.
Ransom, the feminist,
she's six minutes over.
I've got
the Jackson people
breathing down my neck.
Who follows?
It won't
be a problem.
You're next.
Mr Kovic?
We're just about
ready for you.
Can I get you
anything?
Coke, iced tea?
Let's do it.
O.K., Ron.
It's your time.
It's been a long way
to get here.
Tell them what
it is, Ron!
Come on, Ronnie!
Go get them, man.
For Eddie, man.
Ronnie for president!
- Whoo!
The whole world's
watching. I love you.
All right, Frankie!
I feel good.
Ronnie for president.
Whoo!
Congratulations.
I love what
you're doing.
Clear a path for me, please.
Stand back.
Thank you.
I had a dream, Ronnie.
You were speaking
to a large crowd,
and you were saying
great things.
Our next speaker
is one
of our Vietnam veterans
who has something
very special to say tonight.
Please!
Please be quiet!
Coming up top.
What will you
say tonight, Mr Kovic?
I'm going
to tell the truth.
Any plans
for the future?
I guess we'll see.
Mr Kovic, could you please
sign your book?
A young man
who comes from
Massapequa, Long Island...
All righty, coming through!
All right, sweetheart.
Straight on through.
How does it feel
to address the entire country?
Uh, overwhelming...
an honour...
It's been a long way
for us...
the vets... uh...
Just lately I've felt
like I'm home.
You know?
Like, uh,
maybe we're home.
Welcome home,
Ronnie!
Go get them,
Ron!