- If you had a choice...
- Yeah?
Would you rather love a
girl, or have her love you?
I'd want it mutual.
If you couldn't have it mutual.
Would I rather be the one
who loves, or is loved?
Yeah.
It's not that easy a question.
I think I'd rather be in love.
Me, too.
I wouldn't want to
get hurt, though.
You were in love with Gloria.
I was starting to be
in love with her,
then she let me feel her
up on the first date.
Turned me right off.
You kept going with her, though.
Well, she let me feel her up.
Yeah, what about Gwen?
Her I could talk to.
I've never been able
to talk to any girl.
I was really getting
crazy about her.
She's stuck up.
Wouldn't let me lay a hand on her.
So I went back to Gloria.
Well, you want perfection.
What do you want, wise guy?
She just has to be
nice, that's all.
You wouldn't want her beautiful?
She doesn't have to be beautiful.
I would like her built, though.
I want mine sexy-looking.
I wouldn't want her
to look like a tramp.
Sexy doesn't mean she has
There's a middle ground, you know?
I would want that, yeah.
Tall, very tall...
Eww, that would scare me.
She should be very understanding.
Start the same sentences together.
Yeah, I'd like that.
Big tits...
Yeah, but still a virgin.
I don't care about that.
Come on.
I wouldn't mind if she was
a little ahead of me,
with those big tits,
and knew hundreds
of different ways.
I want more of a companion.
The other stuff I can
get on the outside.
The first time I do it,
I want it beautiful.
I don't want to waste
it on some beast.
I feel the same way
about getting laid
as I feel about going to college.
I'm being pressured into it.
- You like that?
- Yeah.
- I give her to you.
- What's wrong with her?
- I'm a generous guy.
- Yeah, I'm grateful.
How do I break the news to her?
- You go over there.
- Yeah?
There's a way to talk
to girls, you know?
Tell her a joke.
What joke?
Tell her about your
unhappy childhood.
- That's not bad.
- But don't make it like an act.
No.
Go ahead.
Go ahead, schmuck.
If you don't, I will.
You?
You can't even stand up.
I fucked up.
It's my turn.
What do you mean, it's your turn?
She's mine, you gave her to me.
You struck out.
I get two more times at bat.
This is the first time
I've ever been to a college mixer.
- Me too. I hate them.
- I hate them too.
It's such a phony way
of meeting people.
Everybody puts on an act.
So, even if you meet somebody,
you don't know who you're meeting.
Because you're meeting the act.
That's right, not the person.
I'm not sure I agree.
- With what?
- With what you said.
No, I don't either.
You don't agree
with what you said?
How do you feel about it?
I think people only like to think
they're putting on an act,
but it's not an act,
it's really them.
If they think it's an
act, they feel better,
because they think they
can always change it.
You mean, they're
kidding themselves,
because it's not really an act.
Yes, it is an act, but they're
the act. The act is them.
But if it's them, then
how can it be an act?
- Because they're an act.
- But they're also real.
- No.
- I'm not real?
- I'm an act.
It's all right, I'm an act too.
Don't you behave differently
with different people?
No.
With your family?
I thought you meant
different people.
Well, sure, with my family...
And with friends,
you're another way.
Well, sure, with my friends.
And with your teachers,
you're still another way.
So which one is you?
Well, when you put it that way...
You ought to be a lawyer.
I'm gonna be a lawyer.
A lady lawyer.
You're from Smith, right?
Huh.
Do you like it?
Yeah, I like it all right.
Do you like Amherst?
Sure, why shouldn't I?
My parents worked
very hard to send me.
I'd better like it.
Do you have a name or something?
Susan.
I'm Sandy.
I think you can make out with her.
Think so?
She's stuff.
You think so?
I wouldn't kick her out of bed.
I shouldn't try
somebody else, then?
Who?
She was the best-looking
girl at the whole mixer.
I'll say that for her...
Wasn't she?
Her tits were too small.
Yeah, I was thinking that.
The hell with her.
But her legs were great.
You think so?
Standing so close, I really
couldn't tell about her legs.
I wouldn't kick her out of bed.
She's got some funny ideas.
Don't rush me, please.
What's the matter?
I like you very much, Susan.
It's our third date.
I like you too.
You let me kiss you last week.
And this week.
If I could kiss you
once last week,
I should be able to kiss you
at least twice tonight.
- Well?
- You're the only boy
I know that I can talk to.
I can't see you being
quiet for any guy.
No, not quiet, exactly.
But if you know
somebody's not going
to approve of what you are...
- Whatever that is.
Well, you just don't tell him.
I mean, if I like a boy and I
want him to keep liking me,
and I'm brighter than he is,
I have to not show it or
I'll lose him, so it's hard.
Well, I wouldn't want
anyone overly bright.
Yeah, but you wouldn't
feel threatened.
I might be bothered a little.
I don't think you would nearly
as much as some people.
Now, for instance, someday
I want to write novels.
Not now, but you know, later on,
when I have something to say.
Now, that doesn't
threaten you, does it?
No...
Maybe a little.
Don't press so hard.
See, it's better when it's gentle.
See?
What are you grinning at?
Did you feel her up yet?
Come on, I like this girl.
I don't want to ruin things.
Was I right about kissing her?
Listen, we had a
big fight over it.
And you won?
Well, I don't know
if I won or not.
Why are you letting
yourself be pushed around?
You're the one who's
pushing me around.
I guess I won. Sure, I won.
She kissed me five times.
Now, that's when you should've
put your hand on her tit.
Come on, when this girl's
nice enough to kiss me,
I should do that to her?
You act as if she's
doing you a favour.
Well, it is sort of
a favour, isn't it?
I mean, when a girl
lets you kiss her
and, you know, go on from there.
Feel her up and, you
know, the rest of it.
Go all the way and the rest of it.
I mean, isn't it a favour?
What's in it for her?
I mean, if she's not
getting paid or anything.
Fuck you.
Okay, okay, I'll feel her up.
Sandy, please take your
hand off my breast.
- Why?
- Because I want you to.
How can it be any fun for you
if you know I don't want it?
I didn't say it was fun.
Then why is your hand where it is?
Because, the way we're
going, by this time,
I should be feeling you up.
I don't feel that way
about you, Sandy.
I feel that way about you.
Well, you want me
to feel something
for you too, don't you?
I thought you liked me.
I do like you,
but I like you for other reasons.
So...
So... if we went any further,
there wouldn't be those
reasons anymore.
Well, we might have
something else, though.
What?
Something else.
You're the first girl I've
ever done that to, Susan.
I didn't know that.
It doesn't show?
No.
Well, it's something we both
have to go through, I guess.
Susan, are you a virgin?
What do I do with my other hand?
What are you gonna
do with your hands?
And then what?
She told me to take my
hand off her breast.
- What did you do?
- I said I didn't want to.
Then what?
She said how could it be fun
for me if she didn't like it?
Oh, Jesus.
- I said I thought she liked me.
- Yeah?
She said, "I like you
for other reasons."
Other reasons?
So, I told her how I
really needed this.
What did you tell her?
You know, that it
was my first time.
Your first time what?
What did you say exactly?
I don't remember exactly.
That she was the first girl
I ever tried to feel up.
- You told her that?
- Was it a mistake?
I wouldn't.
Then she got nicer to me.
What do you mean nicer?
She put my hand on her breast.
You mean you put it on,
she left it there.
No, she picked it
up and put it on.
She took your hand like this?
And put it on like this?
That's right.
So, I didn't know what to think.
You didn't, huh?
For just wanting to be friends,
she's suddenly getting
pretty aggressive.
Yeah, then what?
I asked her if she was a virgin.
- You're kidding.
- Was that a mistake?
Anyhow, she is.
She says.
So now you got, what, one hand
or two hands on her tits?
By this time, she's put the
other hand on the other one.
She put both hands on? Two hands?
So I said, "What are you
gonna do with your hands?"
You didn't say that.
It just came out.
Yeah, then what?
Let me see if I got this.
She unzipped my fly.
Bullshit artist.
Then what? Then what?
Then she did it.
Did what?
Bullshit artist.
She really did that to you?
- She did that?
- Yeah.
Hello, is this Susan?
Well, you don't know me.
I'm a friend of Sandy's.
His room-mate.
Yeah, Jonathan.
He told you about me?
Yeah, so, I'm just here at Smith
for tonight,
practically on campus.
I was just taking a
drive, you know,
and I found myself
practically on campus.
How do you like Smith?
What's your major?
Where did you go to high school?
What do you do in the summer?
Do you always answer a
question with a question?
Do you always date your
best friend's girlfriends?
Sandy told me you were beautiful.
He told me you were sexy.
I guess he's just a poor judge.
I guess he meant you
had personality.
Good grief.
You have a special quality.
I like girls who are special.
I'm hardly that special.
Some people you can
tell about right away.
Most girls I talk to
it's like we're spies
from foreign countries and
we're speaking in code.
Everything means something else.
Like, I say, "Would you
like to take a walk?"
And it means something else.
And she says, "I can't.
I've got a French test tomorrow."
And it means something else.
And you say, "I'll come
over and help you study."
And it means something else.
You're very sharp, I like that.
And that means something else.
You're too sharp.
Does that bother you?
It interests me.
Is that more code?
We'd be good together.
I'm dating your best friend.
He won't mind.
- How do you know?
- I won't tell him.
What if I mind?
You want to go out Friday?
I'm seeing Sandy.
Saturday?
I have a date.
Sunday?
I'm seeing my folks.
Where do they live?
Newton.
Sunday night?
I'll be too tired.
I'll help you get over your folks.
How about it, Susan?
What are you so afraid of?
Not you.
I think I'm in love.
Bullshit artist.
I really think so.
Did you get in yet?
What's that got to do with it?
How do you know if you don't know
how you are in bed together?
Well, that's not everything.
It's a lot.
She tells me thoughts
I didn't even
know I had until she
tells them to me.
It's unbelievable.
I can talk to her.
You can talk to me too.
Are you in love with me?
I can say things to her
I wouldn't dare say to you.
What, for instance?
Things you'd laugh at.
I'm laughing now.
She thinks I'm sensitive.
Sensitive?
Sensitive? Oh, boy.
Whoa-ho.
What do you talk to
her about, flowers?
Books.
Books?
You phony,
I read more books than you do.
Yeah, well, I'm gonna start.
I'm reading "The Fountainhead."
"The Fountainhead." What's that?
It's her favourite book.
You ever hear of
"Jean-Christophe"?
What's that?
It's a classic, you moron.
Gonna read it after
"The Fountainhead."
Yeah, you ever read
"Guadalcanal Diary"
- by Richard Tregaskis?
- No.
That was a best
seller and I read it.
Ever read "Gentleman's Agreement"
by Laura Z. Hobson?
You ever read "A Bell For
Adano" by John Hersey?
I'm gonna read
everything from now on.
I read more than you do.
So who's the one who's
sensitive? You or me?
Come on, who's sensitive?
I've had a very
messed-up childhood.
What does your father do?
He fails.
It's not funny.
I'm sorry. Were you very poor?
My father couldn't
hold on to a job.
He kept giving me advice.
The more he failed, the
more advice I got.
He's a Communist, my father.
We're Republicans.
Sometimes I think I'm
a Communist, though.
Me, too.
We have so much, and
other people have,
you know, so little.
After I get set up as a lawyer,
what I'd really like to
do is go into politics,
public service.
What really gets me is I was
too young to fight
in the war, because
what was that all about
except to prove that
if everybody pitches in,
the plain people have a chance.
So, even though I'm the first
in my family to get an education,
I don't ever want to
forget where I came from.
You're a lot more
serious than I thought.
I know.
Where did you meet her?
I'm another person with her.
You wouldn't recognise me.
The things that come
out of my mouth.
Boy, she really sounds like
something. Is she built?
She's, she's got a quality.
She doesn't talk much,
but the things she
says are so sharp.
We should double-date sometime.
Well...
I want to know her a
little better, you know,
before we double-date.
Gee, isn't it great?
A month ago, neither of
us even knew a girl.
What's her name?
Myrtle.
Bullshit artist.
You're kidding. You're not
kidding me? You really did it.
You bastard. You beat me to it.
What's up?
Next is my turn.
I don't think she'll do it, Sandy.
She will. I've just been
taking it easy on her.
Sandy, believe me,
find somebody else.
Are you crazy, when I'm
right on the verge?
I'll see her tomorrow night.
Sandy?
Yeah.
Do you ever talk to her about me?
Yeah, sure, sometimes.
Do me a favour, will you?
What?
Don't tell her I got laid.
Please, Susan.
Sometimes I want to do it,
and a second later, I
don't want to do it.
Let's do it.
I don't know why you
put up with me.
I don't think I can do it.
It really hurts, Susan.
Let me...
Not anymore.
Please, Sandy.
Susan, let's do it.
I love you.
Do you have anything?
How long have you had that?
Not too long.
Not a year or anything?
I'm sure it's okay.
I don't wanna take any chances.
These things have to be okay.
It's okay.
I'm positive it's okay.
It's as if you're the first guy
in history who ever got laid.
I'm the first guy in my
history who ever got laid.
I like it too, but you don't
hear me crowing about it.
There's such a thing as
good taste, you know?
- What's the matter with you?
- Jeez.
After you started scoring,
what did I get out of you?
"We did it standing, sitting,
in the car, under the car.
Myrtle, Myrtle, Myrtle..."
Maybe you forget, but I knew
Susan before you knew Myrtle,
and who scored first? You.
That didn't make me feel
very good, you know?
In fact, it made me
feel very jealous.
But did I try to shut you up?
Did I say, "I'm tired of
hearing about it already"?
I didn't say it, because I'm your
friend, so I sat through it.
Okay, okay. You made your point.
Sometimes I think
I'm a better friend
to you than you are to me.
Didn't you ever do that?
Of course, I...
I knew what the word
"misled" meant.
I just didn't know...
So, when I first saw it in print,
I thought it was "myzeled".
He had been "myzeled."
I kept wondering, what does
this word mean? "Myzeled"?
Sexy. Let's "myzle."
Has anybody ever heard
of "Round John Virgin"?
One of the guys in "Robin Hood."
That's Little John.
What did you say? Round John...?
Round John Virgin.
Is that in Falstaff?
"Round John Virgin
mother and child."
Round John Virgin mother...?
♪ Holy infant so tender and mild ♪
All right, gunshee.
Gunshee?
G-u-n-s-h-y, gunshee.
Gun-shy...
I always thought it was gunshee.
Susan, do the one about the bear.
You'll love this, John.
Oh, yeah, the hymn we
used to sing in church
about the bear with crossed eyes?
Whose name was Gladly.
Gladly the bear?
Don't you know it? Gladly
the cross-eyed bear.
Gladly the cross-eyed
bear, get it?
Gladly the cross... oh,
Gladly the cross-eyed bear.
All right, pronounce this:
c-h-o-p-h-o-u-s-e.
Chophuse...
Chophus...?
Chophouse.
This has to stop.
I don't know how to tell him.
You don't have any trouble
telling him a lot of other things.
- What does that mean?
- The way you talk to him.
I don't ever hear you
talking to me that way.
What way?
I don't know.
He's very vulnerable.
I don't want to hurt him.
You're hurting me.
He loves me.
That's no reason to
go to bed with him.
You would have just
gone on, wouldn't you,
if he hadn't told me?
I don't know.
I would have never known
a thing about it.
I don't know, maybe.
Boy, you're really something.
I don't feel like something.
I feel like nothing.
How much longer do you
expect me to take this?
I'm trying to tell him.
I see how you're trying.
It's not my fault. I don't
enjoy these fights.
Listen, it's me you're
supposed to be in love with.
- I'm gonna tell him.
- What?
I'm gonna tell him
about you and me.
No, Jonathan.
Why don't you give me some of
the understanding
that you give to him?
You're stronger.
You tell him everything else.
You can tell him about us.
What do you mean, I tell him
everything? Who says so?
He tells me, he's my best friend.
Are you going to tell him?
He's so helpless.
Susan, I love you.
Why can't you be more with me
like you are with Sandy?
She says she's no good for me.
Maybe she's trying to
let you down easy.
Go ahead and laugh.
It adds up.
You know every mood of mine like
you know every mood of his.
- No.
- How come?
I don't know.
You don't tell me thoughts
I never knew I had.
- Does he say I do that?
- Yes.
Then I guess I must.
You do it all right,
so do it with me.
I can't.
You can do it with him,
you can do it with me.
Now tell me my thoughts.
- I can't.
- Why can't you?
I can't with you.
This has gone far enough.
I cannot stand any
more ultimatums.
This is my last one.
Now, tonight, you tell him about
us, or tomorrow, I tell him.
Look at me, Susan.
Now tell me my goddamn thoughts.
Hello.
You didn't do it, did you?
No.
Why not?
He looks at me with such trust.
How do I look at you?
With bitterness.
It used to be trust.
At least you know my thoughts.
Did you tell him?
What do you think?
No.
So, what do we do now?
I don't know.
I guess I get an ultimatum.
Do you think there's
any sense in this?
In what?
In you and me.
That's up to you.
No, it's up to you.
I don't see any point in it.
I wish I were wrong.
I don't feel anything anymore.
Neither do I.
The reason I didn't say
anything to Sandy...
I knew he wouldn't believe me.
And I'd go into details
so he would have to believe me.
And I knew he'd come
running to you,
and I knew you'd tell him
everything I said was true,
and I knew then you'd
go to bed with him.
Yeah, that sounds like
what would happen.
So?
Jonathan...
I'll always be your friend.
Jesus, Susan, I hope not.
It's going to be buggy.
It's not going to be buggy.
It's the tropics. What do
you mean? It's the jungle.
You can't cover yourself
from head to toe.
I'll get eaten alive.
You don't know what it's like.
You've never camped out before.
Isn't he being silly, Jonathan?
- I am not.
- Are too.
- Am not.
You're a real city boy.
How about the cot?
Come on, sweetie, we've
got a sleeping bag.
You're really serious about
sleeping on the ground?
You are a baby.
Christ, this knapsack's heavy.
Well, I told you you overpacked.
What in the world do you plan
to do with a pillowcase?
Put it back.
Well, you are a nut.
Isn't he a nut, Jonathan?
You pack your things.
Let me pack mine.
I'm just trying to help.
Well, help your own stuff.
You have packing to do.
We don't even have room.
We're going in a little car.
Jesus...
You want her?
I wouldn't kick her out of bed.
Will you look at the pair on her?
Get a look at that schmuck
trying to keep up with her.
They're always with
guys like that.
That guy must be 60 if he's a day.
Maybe he'll have a heart attack.
You could save his life.
Get her number and fuck her.
You bastard...
Bastard...
How's Susan?
Couldn't be better.
I always said it,
and I say it now.
You found yourself a jewel.
She is a jewel.
Not bad, that one.
Listen, you must be getting
more than your share.
I'd get married in a minute if
I could find the right girl.
Bullshit artist. You and
your actress friends.
Are you kidding, Doctor?
You're the one
that's got the deal.
I mean, what can I say?
"Take your clothes off, baby,
I wanna check your capital gains."
I just look.
Sure, you do.
I really do.
Susan's plenty enough
woman for one man.
Hey, look at that.
That's Sally Joyce.
Didn't I see her on Ed Sullivan?
I fucked her once.
Bullshit artist.
We used to do her taxes.
She's with another firm now.
Why don't you say hello?
She wouldn't remember me.
She's a real
ball-buster, that one.
I've been through the
mill with her kind.
Yeah?
You think a girl goes for
you, and you find out
she's after your money
or your balls...
or your money and your balls.
Women today are better
hung than the men.
I should have your problems.
It's not as easy getting
laid as it used to be.
I don't think I fuck more than
a dozen new girls a year now.
Maybe I'm too much
of a perfectionist.
This last one came so close
to being what I wanted.
Good pair of tits on her...
Not a great pair.
Almost no ass at all,
and that bothered me.
Sensational legs.
I would have settled for the legs,
if she had just two more inches
here and three more here.
Anyhow...
that took two years
out of my life.
You don't want a family?
I don't want to put it
down, but who needs it?
You can't make fucking
your life's work.
Don't tell me what I
can and can't do.
You're so well-off?
Susan's a very good homemaker.
Very efficient.
I come home, everything
is in its place...
which I like, because it's tiring
putting in a full
day at the office,
then Doctors' Hospital
for a couple of hours.
So it's nice to have everything
in its place when I get home.
A Martini, dinner, the kids.
We don't watch much television.
We like to read aloud
to each other.
We used to have more
friends than we do,
but we don't have
that many anymore.
So, on weekends we might
entertain a little
or go over to see a friend.
Come into town, see a
play or a good film.
It's not glamorous or anything.
There are other things
besides glamour.
You have a long lifeline.
I like that.
The way you run your
nail across my...
You're difficult
to get along with.
Me?
Bobbie...
You always know your own mind.
Right this minute, anyway.
You won't stop going after
what you want until you get it.
Let me see your hand.
Well?
You are built.
You see that in my hand?
Even your hand is built.
I think you're a dirty old man.
I'm a dirty young man.
How old are you?
How old do you think I am?
19.
No...
You skipped 23.
You're getting warm.
28?
No.
29?
I like going out with older women.
Are you married?
Are you kidding?
You don't want to get married?
I'd marry you in a minute.
Can you cook?
Spaghetti.
I can cook spaghetti.
Good, you do the cooking.
What will you do?
What would you like me to do?
What would you like to do?
I asked you first.
Well, I'm not gonna
answer you first.
Well...
I can sew.
Doesn't sound like
much of a marriage.
Me cooking spaghetti,
and you sewing.
You want a divorce?
I'll take you for
every cent you got.
I didn't know I was
marrying a gold digger.
You won't take pity on me?
Only if you say you're sorry.
I'm sorry.
And you'll never do it again.
I'll never do it again.
And you'll always be a good boy.
Yes, Mama.
You like to be mothered?
I'd like to be smothered by you.
What else would you
like me to do to you?
Well...
How do you like it?
How do I like what?
My, you know.
What do I know?
You know everything.
I know you.
And I know you.
♪ Dream ♪
♪ When you're feeling blue ♪
♪ That's the thing to do ♪
♪ Just ♪
♪ Watch the smoke rings ♪
♪ Rise in the air ♪
♪ You'll find your share ♪
♪ Of memories there ♪
♪ So ♪
♪ Dream ♪
♪ When the day is through ♪
Wow... I almost came that time.
Help.
Oh, nurse?
What is it, Mr. Weisenborn?
Will you come in here
a minute, please?
Certainly, Mr. Weisenborn.
Why, Mr. Weisenborn.
Most guys I know are pricks.
I don't know anymore
what they want.
I'll be happy to tell you.
They want... the boodle.
But they ain't gonna
get the boodle.
Goddamn right.
Because this kid here
has got the boodle.
You're pretty sure of
yourself, aren't you?
You're a nice man.
And you're a very lucky girl.
You know something, Sam?
What is it, sweetheart?
You think it would
be a fatal mistake
in our lives if we shacked up?
It's very difficult, Bobbie.
These last couple of weeks,
we get along so well together.
The idea...
I like you very much.
So much...
this idea...
to be perfectly honest,
I mean,
it sounds very good to me.
Let's both give it
a couple of days
to think about it.
It sounds, like...
well, very good.
Very, very...
well... good.
Only, our eyes should be open.
If we should go into this,
we should know exactly
what we're getting into.
It's just a shack-up.
I'm not asking for
your hand in marriage.
Yeah, well,
as long as we both
understand that.
We do.
I just thought it's better
to get it all out on the table,
so later, there can be
no possibility of a
misunderstanding.
I don't know how many business
deals I've seen come to grief...
Okay...
Okay.
You're a real prick,
you know that?
Prick?
I could very easily get
serious about this girl.
She's a lot of fun to be with.
This is just between
the two of us,
but for the last year or so,
I've been having... I don't know,
a little trouble.
I wasn't worried,
but still and all...
a little trouble with...
well, myself.
You know...
getting hard.
It took a long time,
and you know how
girls are today, they judge you.
They judge you very quickly.
So...
I had a real rough time
a couple of times.
Some very nasty innuendos.
And, as I say,
I wasn't too worried, but...
I won't lie to you,
I was a little worried.
Then along comes this Bobbie.
I get one look at the
size of the pair on her
and I never had a
doubt I'd ever be
anything but okay again,
and I was, I was.
With all our kidding,
back and forth on our
first night together,
I don't mind telling you
I had tears in my eyes.
She's really the girl in
the airline commercial?
You lucky son of a bitch.
I don't know.
I don't want to get
in over my head.
I got in over my head
three, four times already,
and you have to be a real bastard.
I don't like being put
in that position.
What would you do?
If she looks anything like
she looks on television...
Size 38, with a D cup.
But looks aren't everything.
Believe me, looks are everything.
Maybe.
I'm hungry.
I'll get up.
Why do we always
have to eat so late?
Because I work late, dumb-o.
Why do you work at all?
Brings in extra money.
I make enough.
You want me to quit working?
I thought you were bored with it.
I am.
So quit.
What'll I do?
What do other women do?
Have children.
Well, you asked me.
♪ So until the day
that one comes along ♪
♪ I'll sing my song with you ♪
♪ For every little
fault that you have ♪
♪ Say I've got three or four ♪
♪ The human little
faults you do have ♪
♪ Just make me love you more ♪
♪ You may not be an angel ♪
♪ But still I'm sure you'll do ♪
♪ So until the day
that one comes along ♪
♪ I'll string along ♪
♪ With you ♪
Hey, was that you?
- Yeah, that was me.
- No kidding.
What about my beer?
We're all out.
I really wanted a beer.
Do you want me to run
out to the corner?
You're too tired.
I'm tired, but I don't mind.
I'll get it.
No, I'll get it.
It's my fault.
I knew I should have reminded you
when I called this afternoon.
I'm sorry, honey.
You're more tired now
than when you were working.
I'm in the house all day.
Did you get up at all today?
What do you do?
I mean, when you're
not telephoning?
I'm not on the phone that much.
It took me 45 minutes
to get through this afternoon.
I'll go get the beer.
No, I'll go.
I thought you were too tired.
I haven't been out all day.
Fresh air will do you good.
Will you walk with me?
Then I may as well go myself.
♪ To sing my love song too ♪
♪ And until the day
that one comes along ♪
♪ I'll sing my song with you ♪
♪ For every little fault
that you have ♪
Wanna make love?
We haven't in a week.
Is it a week?
It's funny.
Susan and I do all
the right things.
We undress in front of each other.
We spend 15 minutes on foreplay.
We experiment, do it
in different rooms.
It's a seven-room house.
We don't believe in
making a ritual of it.
We do it when we feel like it.
We don't feel we have to be
passionate all the time.
Sometimes it's even
more fun necking.
We're considerate of
each other's feelings.
I had a tendency...
Men, I guess, have...
To be selfish.
But I stopped. I
don't do that now.
We try to be patient,
and we are patient,
gentle with each other.
Maybe it's just not
meant to be enjoyable
with women you love.
Sandy...
do you want to get laid?
Please.
Very nice.
Very nice indeed.
Indeed. Watch out.
I almost had it.
Sure, you almost had it.
I almost had it. Right, Cindy?
See that, Cindy?
He was lucky.
That's all.
Bastard, that was out.
- Bullshit it was.
- Oh, bullshit.
Let Cindy be the judge.
We'll do it over, all right?
All right. Fair's fair.
Deuce.
You see that shot, Cindy?
Now we got some tennis.
Hey.
Game.
Luck.
Luck, my ass. Whoo-hoo.
You want to take me on, Cindy?
It's my turn.
Oh, come on, Bobbie,
you're so awful.
You serve.
Very nice.
Hey, you play well.
Hey, Sandy, will you
look at this girl?
Terrific, Cindy.
Whoo. Hey.
She's racking me up.
I'm not kidding.
Look at this. She's racking me up.
Beautiful.
Boy, will you look at this?
40-love.
And I'm not taking it
easy on her either.
You and Lord & Taylor's
are gonna have to work
out a trial separation.
I had the water running.
What did you say?
You and Lord & Taylor's
are going to have to work
out a trial separation.
Look at the date.
What do you mean?
Five months ago.
I'm sorry I cost
you so much money.
I want to get married.
Are you tired of me, Jonathan?
Am I ever.
- The answer is yes.
- I didn't say yes.
You said, "Am I ever."
I need more in life than this.
Who put you up to this?
Your psychiatrist?
After a long, exhaustive bed hunt,
you finally chose me.
Cindy's not a virgin either.
What?
Oh, I get it.
Is that what brought this on?
Your mind is unbelievable.
You have to have a
low opinion of me
thinking that I would
do that to Sandy.
Oh, no, you wouldn't
want to cheat on Sandy.
Oh, now it's Sandy.
Well, he spends half
his life over here.
Wait a minute.
A second ago you had
me screwing Cindy.
Who am I screwing now, Sandy?
You're going too fast for me.
I'm going too fast for you?
Your little mind operates like
an IBM, like a pinball machine.
First Cindy. Oh, no, not Cindy?
How about Sandy? How
about Cindy and Sandy?
Talk about the pot
calling the kettle.
The day I got an earful of your
chequered past, I
felt like a celibate.
You made me tell you.
Sure, I twisted your arm.
It got you hot.
Something has to.
You have such contempt for me.
Kid, you worked hard for it.
It's yours.
The way you paw me at parties.
Now affection is contempt.
Upside down. Everything
upside down.
Feeling me up in public
is not affection.
Will you come on?
I know I sleep all day.
I know I'm doing a terrible job,
but you're not helping me any.
And who helps me?
I help you.
Your kind of help
I can do without.
Can you? Can you really?
You'll do anything you can
to ruin my day, won't you?
I got up today feeling so good.
You couldn't leave us alone.
- We were doing so well.
- What?
At one time... at one time,
it was great what we had.
The kidding around. It can't
have a natural time span?
Affairs can't dissolve
in a good way.
There's always got to be poison.
I don't see why. I
really don't see why.
Jonathan, do you want
it over between us?
Why does it have to be
one way or the other?
You don't want me to leave?
I want you right here
where you belong.
And what about you?
When I'm here, I'm here. When
I'm not here, I'm there.
- Where?
- Wherever?
No.
I'm a man-eater or a
ball-buster and a castrator.
I want to get married.
All right, where the
fuck is my shoehorn?
This place is a mess. There's
not any food in the house.
Half the time, you look
like you fell out of bed.
You spend more time in bed
than any other human being
past the age of six months
than I ever heard of.
The reason I sleep all day is
because I can't stand my life.
What life?
Sleeping all day.
You say that sort of thing,
I fall in love with
you all over again.
Marry me, Jonathan.
Please, marry me.
You're trying to kill me.
Marriage isn't death.
Why now?
Because two years ago,
I slept eight hours.
A year ago, it was 12.
It's up to 15 now.
Pretty soon, it's gonna be 24.
What are you trying
to do, scare me?
- I need a life.
- Get a job.
I don't want a job. I want you.
I'm taken, by me.
Get out of the house.
Do something useful, God damn it.
You wouldn't let me
work when I wanted to.
That was a year ago.
You throw a tantrum every time
you call and I'm not home.
Look, sister, I'm out
there in the jungle
eight hours a day.
You wouldn't even let
me canvass for Kennedy.
You want a job?
I got a job for you.
Fix up this pigsty.
You get a pretty
goddamn good salary
for testing out this bed all day.
You want an extra $50 a week?
Try vacuuming.
You want an extra 100?
Make this goddamn bed.
Try opening some goddamn windows.
That's why you can't
stand up in here.
The goddamn place
smells like a coffin.
Oh... Bobbie.
You don't need me.
Why do you let yourself in
for this kind of abuse?
Walk out.
Leave me. Please leave me.
God's sake, I'd almost marry
you if you'd leave me.
You call that abuse?
You don't know what I'm used to.
With all your carrying on,
to me you're a gift.
So what's it gonna be?
You sure know how
to screw things up.
So where does that leave us?
Are you giving me an ultimatum?
Is this an ultimatum?
Answer me, you ball-busting,
castrating, son-of-a-cunt bitch.
Is this an ultimatum or not?
Because if it is,
I'm gonna tell you
what you can do with
your ultimatum.
I'm gonna tell you what
you can do with it.
You can make this goddamn bed.
That's what you can do with it.
Goddamn clean these filthy sheets.
She's not ready.
We're a little early.
You're looking good, Cindy.
I do my best.
Will Bobbie be long?
No.
Hey...
do we have to go to this party?
How about it, Cindy?
Where's the powder room?
Right there.
I'm going. You do what you want.
Man, she's really something.
I'm so bored, I'm
going out of my mind.
Bored? With that?
You must be kidding.
You have to go to this party?
Stick around.
No, it's better that I go.
Hey, I just did my hair.
I've got this at home.
How's your tennis game, Jonathan?
We'll have to have a rematch.
Anytime.
Is she always that way?
You know women.
Boy, is she competitive.
She is very competitive,
but I find that attractive.
You know her problem?
She wants balls.
She's all right.
I'm not criticising.
I wish she were more feminine.
She is a little masculine.
I just wish she wouldn't
always demand her own way.
She's got a great body on her.
I have to treat her like a child,
give her everything she wants.
I wouldn't mind
giving her something.
You got Bobbie.
I should only have it that good.
Bobbie.
Bobbie, are you kidding?
I've never seen a body like that.
She could do with a little
more of what Cindy's got.
She's so goddamn passive.
Yeah, I wouldn't mind Cindy
just lying still once.
She's so busy handing out
instructions in bed.
It's like close-order drill.
Yeah, I wouldn't mind
a little of that,
as long as she doesn't
forget who's boss.
Hey...
you wouldn't want to swap
sometime, would you?
Are you serious?
What do you say?
Might liven things up a bit.
She can miss one party.
Leave her to me.
What about Bobbie?
She's so mad at me,
she'll jump all over
you just for revenge.
Hey, you like that, huh?
Seriously?
She's in the bedroom.
If you're quiet, you can do it
and she won't even know.
You bastard.
Give me a minute.
Tell Sandy it's time to leave.
I hope you dance better
than you play tennis.
Sandy won't mind.
What's Sandy got to do with it?
You're his girl.
He said it would be okay.
What did Sandy say?
That you and me...
you know.
That was his idea. You had
nothing to do with it?
A little.
A little or a lot?
This much.
I'm surprised it took you this
long to get around to it.
Sandy and I have a party to go to.
Sandy's busy.
You wanna come around
sometime by yourself,
that's one thing.
I've been expecting that.
But you tell Sandy
that if he lays one hand
on that tub of lard in there,
not to come home.
So you call me.
Jesus.
She's semi-comatose.
Better send a resuscitation
unit and an airway.
Be ready to give her
an IV on admission.
It's on...
Tell him we'll put her
in intensive care.
Bastard.
Very slick.
Very clever.
Well, it's not going
to work, Bobbie.
That's Bonnie,
my first love.
She lived upstairs from us.
We started exposing ourselves
to each other at 10.
We got caught on the roof
one day by my mother
who washed my mouth out with soap.
I never got the connection.
Here's Emily, my first steady.
Until she moved off
the block at 11,
I never laid a hand on her.
Mildred,
I think, this one's name was.
She followed me around at school.
The fellas kidded me about her.
I warned her if she didn't
stop, I'd beat her up.
She picked up her skirt,
dropped her drawers
and shoved her ass at me.
So I got my first
sight of ass at 12.
Marcia, 13 1/2 or thereabouts,
I kissed her one night at
a spin-the-bottle party.
This one's Rosalie.
Rosalie looked just like Elizabeth
Taylor in "National Velvet."
I had a crush on
Rosalie from 14 to 15
and I never went near her.
In those days, we had illusions.
Here's Charlotte.
Not much on looks, but
great tits for 15.
That's Lenny Hartman's sister.
My first French kiss,
16 years old.
Here's Gloria,
the best-built girl
at Evander Childs.
I took her to the Bronx Zoo once
and on the bus,
copped a cheap feel.
Here's Gwen.
I went with her for a year
trying to get her to put out,
but she thought I was too nice
and was saving me for marriage.
Every guy at Evander
must have gotten into
her pants except me.
Here's my first... No,
that one was a mistake.
Here's Eileen, my very first fuck.
She was a modern
dancer at Swarthmore.
Great body on her.
What a waste... frigid.
Here's Nancy. Sweet kid.
She went into
biology. Very frigid.
Here's Bobbie.
My wife.
The fastest tits in the West
and king of the ball-busters.
She conned me into marrying her
and now she's killing
me with alimony.
Don't know how this
one get in here?
This is my little girl, Wendy.
"Princess," I call her.
Isn't she a dreamboat?
Here's a real cunt.
I forget her name.
A Nazi.
I banged her in Berlin.
Here's something I went with
for a couple of months.
First time I banged her
was on a yacht race to Nassau.
This slob I went with for a year
until I got so sick
of her ball-busting,
I couldn't get it up anymore.
I can't remember her name.
This was my Jap in the sack.
I heard that Oriental
girls were different.
Not in America, they're not.
Here's a 16-year-old
I gave 20 bucks to
one night in the village
when I was drunk.
Maybe you know her, Jennifer.
She gave me a dose.
That's all, folks.
What are you crying for?
It's not a Lassie movie.
Sorry about that.
Or something.
So, what else is new?
To tell you the truth,
I don't see anybody anymore.
Neither do we.
Well, you've got each other.
I thought she was your daughter
when you first came in.
In a lot of ways, she's
older than I am.
Yeah.
She knows worlds I can't
even begin to touch yet.
Sandy, please.
I found out who I am.
You're in big trouble.
Same old Jonathan.
Indubitably.
Let me talk to her
about you, John.
Talk to her about me?
I'm 40, she's nine.
You just don't get it, do you?
Oh, I get it, all right.
I've been getting it for a
long time. What's the point?
Sandy, you found a
good piece of ass.
God bless you.
You're my friend,
I'm happy for you.
As long as it lasts,
You deserve to be
happy. I mean it.
Why fight? Okay?
All those games.
Jesus Christ.
You don't need those
games, Jonathan.
I know. I've played
more games than anyone.
The obedient son game.
The bright student game.
- The cocksman's game.
- Some cocksman.
The respectable husband game.
The good father game.
- The specialist game.
- Good father?
Games don't impress Jennifer.
Just life, just love.
Yeah, well, I don't want
to argue with you, Sandy.
So let's just agree
to disagree, okay?
Don't make me mad, okay?
Jennifer knows more at 18
than Susan knows to this day.
You found yourself a
real jewel, okay?
She's my love teacher.
Finally got it up, huh?
You give off such bad vibrations.
Bad vibrations?
Sandy, I love you, but
you're a schmuck.
You were always
young, Sandy, open.
You were schmucky a
lot of the time,
but maybe schmuckiness
is what you need
to stay young and open.
Listen... don't listen to me.
You're doing great,
and I'm making money.
You can find what I
found, Jonathan.
Don't make me insult you.
Women...
All ball-busters, right?
You know it.
When you think of some of the
things he has to dip into,
any guy with a conscience
has a right to turn soft.
Am I right, Louise?
You're always right, lover.
I don't think we're going to have
any trouble tonight.
- You don't?
- No, I don't.
Are you sure?
You wanna bet?
How much?
The sky's the limit.
God damn it.
What did I do?
You're doing it all wrong.
I'm doing it like always.
You never said that before.
- Said what?
- "Sky's the limit."
Sure, I...
Never.
What do I say?
You forgot, didn't you?
A hundred.
I say a hundred.
Okay.
It just came out.
I just want it right, that's all.
I don't think we're going to have
any trouble tonight.
- You don't?
- No, I don't.
Are you sure?
You wanna bet?
How much?
A hundred?
You sound pretty sure.
You're a kind of man...
why shouldn't I be sure?
What kind of man am I?
A real man.
A kind man.
I'm not kind.
I don't mean weak kind,
the way so many men are.
I mean the kindness that comes
from an enormous strength,
from an inner power so
strong that every act,
no matter what, is more
proof of that power.
That's what all women resent.
That's why they try
to cut you down.
Because your knowledge
of yourself and them
is so right, so true
that it exposes the
lies which they,
every scheming one
of them, live by.
It takes a true
woman to understand
that the purest form of love
is to love a man who
denies himself to her.
A man who inspires worship,
because he has no
need for any woman,
because he has himself.
And who is better, more beautiful,
more powerful, more perfect.
You're getting hard.
More strong, more masculine,
more extraordinary, more robust...
It's rising.
More virile, domineering.
More irresistible...
It's up...
in the air.