Please rise.
Hear Ye. The court of the 22nd Judicial
District of Minnesota is now convened.
The Honorable Cass Timberlane.
Judge presiding.
Be seated.
Olliford versus Olliford.
Continued from yesterday's calendar.
Mr Criley.
Anything further on
behalf of the plaintiff?
We completed our argument
yesterday, Your Honor.
Does the defendant's counsel
have anything further?
No, Your Honor.
Mr and Mrs Olliford, will
you step forward please.
I have weighed the evidence in this
case and I have reached a decision.
In the last few years on this bench.
Particularly since the war ..
I am struck so much by the public's
careless attitude toward marriage.
Here in Grand Republic marriage once
meant something permanent and beautiful.
Our parents built their lives
and their happiness on it.
Maybe this is a selfish age.
Maybe we have lost the art of
loving deeply and permanently.
If we have, I think it's pretty sad.
Pretty frightening.
I don't know what the answer
is but I do know this.
Marriage is a sacred obligation
not lightly to be entered into.
And as long as I am judge here
not likely to be dissolved.
The evidence here does not warrant
granting the plaintiff's petition.
Divorce denied. Next case.
Tilda Hatter versus the
city of Grand Republic.
If it please, Your Honor.
It is our aim to prove the
gross negligence of the city ..
In failing to clear the sidewalk
of its snow and ice.
Thereby causing Miss Hatter to slip
and be thrown prone upon the sidewalk.
In a state of ignominy and sore pain.
"A dull case and a duller lawyer."
"The State of Minnesota doesn't pay
you to go to sleep, Timberlane."
To prove Your Honor that ..
It is the responsibility
of the municipality ..
To keep the sidewalks
free of snow and ice.
And.
Had there been an adequate
cleaning of this main thoroughfare.
The unfortunate accident
would not have occurred.
.. so help you, God?
- I do.
Your name please?
My name is Tilda Hatter.
Your occupation?
- I keep a boarding house.
Your place of residence?
179 and a half West Flandrau Street.
I was born right in that very
house on the ground floor.
Where the Lilac Lady beauty shop is now.
.. so help you, God?
- I do.
Your name please?
Eino Roskinen.
E-i-n-o R-o-s-k-i-n-e-n.
Your occupation?
- I am a writer.
But at the moment I'm a lathe
operator at the Wargate plant.
.. the evidence you're about to give
will the whole truth so help you, God?
I do.
Your name please?
- Virginia Marshland.
Your occupation?
'Artist' I guess.
You guess?
Part of my job is designing
boxes and packages.
And part of it is doing hand lettering.
Mr Recorder, Miss Marshland
is a designer.
Your place of residence?
179 and a half West Flandrau Street.
That is also Miss Tilda
Hatter's address, is it not?
I room there. Yes.
Now then, tell the court your version
of what happened on the night of the ..
Accident.
Well, I had gone to the
movies with Eino Roskinen.
He rooms at Tilda's too.
You see, I ..
He is on the top floor.
I am on the second.
Well, anyway.
Tilda was on the streetcar coming
home so we got off together.
Right in front of the West Side Police
Station she slipped on the ice.
Up went all of her packages into
the air and down came Tilda on ..
On the ice.
And was I mad.
Why were you mad?
Because a stupid policeman had tried to
make out that Tilda had been drinking.
I see. And that wasn't true?
She was as sober as a ..
Achoo!
Miss Hatter was as sober as ..
As sober as a ..
Pardon me.
Bailiff.
- Yes, Your Honor?
If this cat or any cat comes into this
courtroom once more making me sneeze ..
I'll have it arrested for contempt
of court. Get it out of here.
Yes, Your Honor.
It is 4 o'clock, Your Honor.
- So it is.
The court is adjourned until
ten o'clock in the morning.
As a judge.
I beg your pardon, Miss Marshland?
That's what Miss Tilda Hatter
was as sober as.
Have you got that, Mr Recorder?
- Yes, Your Honor.
Thank you, Miss Marshland.
Come in.
Busy?
Come in, Brad.
I'm sorry, Brad. I told you
the case would go against you.
Forget it, Cass.
I can't say I disagree
with you in principle.
Only what exactly did you
accomplish? The ends of justice?
My client goes to Reno tomorrow.
- Yeah, I know.
The homily on marriage.
It was eloquent, Cass.
It was beautiful. I mean that.
But it came thirty years too late.
There has been a war, Cass.
There have been a lot of wars, Brad.
That's no reason to hop in and out
of marriage like a lot of rabbits.
What is wrong with our people anyway?
Well, we live in a reckless age.
Transitional.
What the heck. I'm not going
to take anything too seriously.
I'll leave that for you and
Chris when you get married.
I haven't said I was going to
marry Chris or anybody else.
But I'll tell you this,
if I do get married again.
I will come and let you dance with
the bride on our 75th anniversary.
Not before?
- Not if I can help it.
Cass, you are wonderful.
You're the vanishing American.
You are as obsolete as the crossbow
but you are the hope of the world.
I love you. Marry me.
Come in.
What is it, Bert?
Someone left this in
the courtroom, Judge.
Holy cow, do I look like this?
That's contempt of court, Your Honor.
First degree.
Off with this head.
What is the criminal's name?
Looking for something, Miss?
Yes. Did you find a small notebook?
A notebook, huh?
The Lost-and-Found
department might have it.
Thank you.
- Second door along there.
- Go right in.
Excuse me, Your Honor. Sir.
The witness for Tilda Hatter.
They told me this was
the Lost-and-Found.
That depends on what you have lost.
Come in, Miss Marshland.
It was a little notebook.
A notebook? Do you know
anything about that, Mr Criley?
A notebook?
Come in, come in.
Let's have a description of it.
May I take the witness, Your Honor?
- You may not. Thanks for coming, Brad.
It was a pleasure.
I feel the young lady needs an attorney.
- No, no. This is an open and shut case.
Yes, Your Honor. See you
and Chris tonight, I hope.
Tonight? Oh yes, this
is Thursday, isn't it.
Thursday. That's right. Dinner
at the Havocks. Be prompt.
Listen to that 'be prompt'.
He was 20 minutes late last week.
Do you think it is so important
be on time at the Havocks?
I wouldn't know. Where I eat, if you
are not on time there's nothing left.
Take the witness, Judge.
- Yes. Thank you.
Sit down, Miss Marshland.
Now.
What was in this alleged notebook?
Some alleged drawings.
- Oh? You draw?
What sort of subjects interest you?
Uh, people.
People?
Even judges?
You found my notebook, didn't you?
Is this it?
Yes.
You're not going to send me to jail?
No, no. Not a fine day like this.
I'd like to have that.
Oh?
An authentic Virginia Marshland.
Compliments of the artist.
- Thank you.
I didn't know when I drew that,
that judges had a sense of humor.
Judges are often mistaken
for human beings.
That's nice to know.
I will tell Miss Hatter.
It will cheer her up. You see, she
needs that lawsuit money badly.
Dear Miss Marshland.
A judge interprets the law.
He is not Santa Claus.
Of course not.
Thank you, Your Honor.
- You're welcome.
I am glad you are not mad at me.
And I am glad that you are ..
Really human.
Oh, you would be surprised.
It's too bad you never
found that out before.
About judges I mean.
Well, it's only natural.
Very few judges come down to
Flandrau Street for dinner.
Goodbye, Judge.
- Goodbye.
Good afternoon, Judge.
- Hello Tommy.
How did you ..
Mrs Higbee.
[ Radio: ]
"Open that door!"
"Help!"
"The water is up to my neck."
"Jack."
"Do you know who it is?"
"No."
"It can't be."
"Yes."
"It's the Green Dragon."
She'll get out.
Mrs Higbee.
There is a cat in my library.
You know Judge, I've been
thinking a lot about you lately.
You are lonely and I ..
Mrs Higbee, I assure
you I am not lonely.
And furthermore, if I were
lonely it would not be for a cat.
Well, for something then.
Maybe it's this big old house.
Maybe you ought to sell it.
- Sell it?
Have you no respect for tradition?
- Tradition? Here? Ha.
I come from Massachusetts.
Mrs Higbee, you astonish me.
This town has one of the most colorful
histories in the State of Minnesota.
Of course, we don't have your puritans.
They weren't my puritans.
- But we had Indians here, you know.
We had Sioux and Chippewa.
Why, there used to be
a famous Indian fort.
Right down there where the
D & T.C. freight station is now.
Just off Flandrau Street.
Just to wander through those streets
when I was a boy would give me a thrill.
Flandrau Street.
I think I will ..
I'll be back in an hour.
I need some exercise.
Where are you going, Judge?
- To breathe that historic air.
Perhaps recapture for a moment
the spirit of those sturdy pioneers.
Who knows?
Come here.
Come here, cat.
Come on, cat.
Here, kitty, kitty.
Kitty, kitty.
Do you know who I am?
I am the Green Dragon.
There you are, dad.
- Thanks, Jimmy.
Hey. Hey.
Oh, hi Judge.
Hello. Hello.
I thought it was you but I
couldn't believe my eyes.
You looking for something?
Yes. Indians.
- Well, you've come to the right place.
I often walk around down here.
- Looking for Indians?
Sometimes just for exercise.
It's quite a ways.
You must like walking.
Yes, I do. And baseball.
Oh good. Say, maybe you can help us out.
Well, I haven't played
since college but ..
I meant, would you be umpire?
Oh.
You are such a good judge they say.
They say?
Come on, Ginny.
You're holding up the game.
Oh, they can wait.
Eino, this is Judge Timberline.
Timberlane. Hello Mr Roskinen.
- How are you, Judge?
I hear you don't like Ginny's drawings.
I didn't say such a thing. I'm trying
to get him to umpire the game.
Don't mind her, Judge.
She's a bit crazy.
So are some judges. Come on.
Play ball.
Strike 1.
Strike 2.
Ball 2.
Ball 3.
What was that, Judge?
Safe.
Hey, who asked you to be umpire?
You did.
Hey, Jimmy. Jimmy, Jimmy.
I thought you were a friend.
An umpire has no friends.
You are out.
Are you sure?
- Positive.
Strike 1.
Strike 2.
Run!
Go, Ginny!
Run.
You're out.
Out?
O-u-t. Out.
But everybody said I was safe.
That is why an umpire has no friends.
You got plenty of friends
up on the heights.
Oh, you mean that ..
I'd call one of them
safe if he were out?
I don't know you well enough
to answer that, Judge.
Miss Marshland. Three strikes
is out in any neighborhood.
Well, goodbye Judge.
Don't forget. On Thursday you must
be on time for the champagne.
I don't like champagne.
- I'm crazy about champagne.
Of course, I have never had
any but Thursday is coming.
Tomorrow night.
Where do you eat on Thursdays?
Thursday is beans at the boarding house.
I like beans.
- I hate beans.
So I have spaghetti on
Thursdays at the Café Italien.
Well, I ..
Say.
You go right by it on your way home.
Look. It only takes a minute to change.
Can you wait please?
- Where are you going?
This is a shortcut to
the boarding house.
Will you admit that you were out?
I was out a mile.
For crying out loud, Boone.
Look who's on time for a change.
Why shouldn't he be on time? Knowing we
serve the best darned food in Minnesota.
Haven't you heard, Queenie?
I have reformed.
Hello Brad.
Hello, beautiful.
- He hasn't reformed entirely.
What's the matter, Webb? Can't a
man tell your wife she's beautiful?
What's the matter with my wife?
Hello, beautiful.
- That's more like it.
See what I mean?
Well, here is the Doc.
Hello, Doc. Hello Lillian.
Hello Boone. How are you?
What's all this about being on time?
I may be late for an operation
but never for a free dinner.
Here.
That poison? Never touch it.
Hi, Roy.
- Hello John.
Hello, Roy. How are you?
- Hello, Greg.
Herman.
- Yes, sir?
I must be at the hospital by midnight.
What time is it, doctor?
- It's time to eat.
Yes, sir.
Another new maid?
Yes, Doctor. This is Dagmar.
Good evening, Dagmar.
You are not going to tell on me?
No, sir.
Doc is a great kidder
if you can take it.
His wife takes it.
They call her 'poor dear Lillian'.
My goodness.
Won't you be fired if
Mrs Havock catches you?
Queenie Havock has fired me
every week for eleven years.
But the chief always takes me back.
A great man, the chief.
You mean that is what
everybody calls Mr Havock?
They call him a lot of other
things but not to his face.
Now remember, Dagmar.
You are to serve Mrs Wargate first.
What does she look like?
There she is.
Louise Wargate and her husband.
King Webb the third.
The young fellow is Crown Prince
Jamie, just back from the war.
He looks nice.
Yeah.
And drinks like fish.
- My goodness.
That is his wife Alice.
Chris, where is the judge?
I thought Cass was coming with you.
So did I.
- Where is your boyfriend?
Couldn't face another
evening with me, I guess.
Bunk. Did you call his house?
Mrs Higbee said he went
down to Flandrau Street.
Looking for Indians.
- Indians?
Hold everything. I'll go find him.
I'll get you something.
- Thanks, Brad.
Just a bite.
No. No thanks. It will spoil my dinner.
I'll catch the Dickens alright.
Does it matter an awful lot to you?
- What?
That Mr and Mrs Boone
Havock are angry at you.
No, only ..
Are they ever late at you your house?
- Always.
Well then.
- I've a reputation for being on time.
You mean you had a reputation.
- That's right.
What are you going to tell your friends?
The truth, if anything.
Really?
That you picked up a girl
from Flandrau Street?
What is wrong with Flandrau Street?
Well, I doubt your friends are
going to like it very much.
No look here, Miss Marshland.
- Yes, Mr Judge.
There's something we must get straight
about my friends on the heights.
I like them but I have a
great many friends all over.
Some of them are down here.
You have?
Certainly. How do you think
a judge gets elected?
I didn't think he got elected.
I thought it was an act of God.
Good evening, Judge.
- Good evening, Pete.
Now you are in trouble.
- Am I?
The star witness in the
case of Tilda Hatter ..
Versus the city of Grand Republic
dining out with the Judge?
Oh. That is corruption.
It is not corruption if
I don't eat anything.
Would it be corruption if I
have another piece of pie?
Not if you don't have ice-cream on it.
Another piece of blueberry pie. Miss.
With a scoop of vanilla.
There won't be anything that
good at the Boone Havocks.
Yes, Charlie.
You have? Charlie has located him.
Where?
Where is that? On Flandrau Street?
No.
Who is she?
Well, I'll be a son-of-gun.
No. Thanks.
That is all. Much obliged.
- What is all this?
Our judge has strayed
off the reservation.
No?
Wait a minute. I have an idea.
You are sure this doesn't bother you?
- No.
My father smoked a pipe.
I loved my father.
He was so .. so independent.
I loved my mother too.
They were a wonderful two people.
They were good together.
Poor together.
They were very close.
One silly thing I remember.
What?
They kept their toothbrushes
in the same glass.
Boy. That is marriage, isn't it.
If I ever find a man
like my father, I ..
Do you mind being a judge?
Mind?
- Uhuh.
No, no. It isn't so bad.
As a matter of fact, I am
rather crazy about my job.
I wish I was.
Do you know something
I always wanted to do?
To go to college.
Find out about things like ..
Like poetry and anthropology and ..
Can you fly a plane?
No.
Someday I'm going to.
Can you play anything?
An instrument, I mean.
Yes.
What?
You won't tell anybody, will you.
The flute.
I promise I won't tell a soul.
Tell me, does your wife know about it?
You are married, aren't you?
I was married.
You was?
My wife died our first year.
Gee.
Hiya.
Hey Ginny, it's time to go bowling.
Not now. Maybe later.
Aren't you a little
off your beat, Judge?
Mr Roskinen.
The 22nd judicial district of the state
of Minnesota includes Flandrau Street.
Well, are you coming?
The whole gang will be there.
Later. Maybe.
Is he your idea of somebody
independent like your father?
Are you going to marry him?
Any legal objection?
I would fine you fifty dollars.
I would have to borrow it from you.
Are you engaged to him?
- I object. That's a leading question.
Objection overruled.
Alright. Eight o'clock.
The court is adjourned.
Time for you to sneeze, Your Honor.
You are no cat.
I wouldn't be too sure of that.
I guess I could take care of myself.
Grazie, Seńora.
Come again.
- Thank you. Goodnight.
What is this? Are we arrested?
Evening, Judge. Mr Havock
says whenever you are ready.
My friends are having a little fun.
You'd better go before they send
the truant officer after you.
Can I drop you anywhere?
Thanks for dinner, Your Honor. And don't
forget we can always use a good umpire.
Thanks. I won't forget.
Yes. Cass has broken off with Chris.
Of course, they weren't engaged.
But we all thought ..
Boone told Greg that Flandrau
Street is full of riff-raff.
Of long-haired artists who never pay the
rent and use banisters for firewood.
"A fine thing, even if
they weren't engaged."
Okay Queenie, there is no argument.
I am busy. Call me later.
Or candidate for the future
Mrs Timberlane has been overruled.
All of a sudden, Cass becomes Casanova.
As for me, I'm going to
see him stepping out.
That's a dumb remark for a lawyer to
make about any judge in this district.
Right.
Sorry, Boone.
But Lillian, she works at Flegans.
She's a stenographer or
even something worse.
Don't be silly, Diantha.
Cass and I will always be good friends.
Goodbye.
'My candle burns at both ends'.
'It will not last the night'.
'But ah, my foes and oh my
friends, it gives a lovely light'.
Do you like that one?
Should I?
A lot of people do.
They do, do they? Well, I don't.
That's my Ginny.
I'm not your Ginny.
Not yet you're not.
Why don't you like it?
What do you mean 'not yet'?
You will know when you
get older, my girl.
No, Ginny. No. Ow.
Whose Ginny am I?
- Your own. Ow.
That is more like it.
Now fix your hair. It's mussed.
You mussed it. You fix it.
That is justice.
- Yes, sure.
That is my Ginny.
That is your what?
- That's my head.
Now, some more poetry please.
If it doesn't bore you.
Who me? I used to write
poetry when I was in college.
Really. I would love to hear it.
- Over my dead body.
I was serious then. I was going to do
things about the world. Make it better.
Well, aren't you? Being a judge?
- I wonder.
Well, you are certainly
making my world better for me.
Do you know what I will
call you, Judge Timberlane?
No. What?
- I will call you 'Timber'.
Timber? That's what they yell
when a tree comes crashing down.
That may happen to me but never you.
So I will make it 'Tim'.
Cleopatra, meet Tim.
- Hiya, Cleo. How are you?
There's no reason for you to be against
this poem just because others like it.
I am not against a lot
of things others like.
Name one.
You.
- No.
But that doesn't mean I
have to like your friends.
You'll like them when you know them.
- Any bets?
That's just being childish.
- Childish?
You with your poetry about candles
burning at both ends and ..
I got over that years ago.
- Did you really?
And as for your friends, you are the
most sentimental baby I've ever known.
I am, am I?
'Good old Boone, dear old Roy'.
'Sweet old Webb'.
Ow! Cass. That tickles.
Who has the best friends
in the whole world?
Stop it.
- Come on.
Who's got the best friends?
- I take it back. You have.
You have the best friends
in the whole world.
Will you be nice to them
when you dance with them?
Dance with them? Where?
At the next country club dance.
Who, me?
At the country club?
Oh no.
- Oh yes.
Not on your life.
Besides, I haven't anything to wear.
Honest, I haven't.
Alright. Will you compromise?
Well, that all depends.
What is the compromise?
Will you marry me?
You have got the wrong girl, Judge.
No I haven't, Ginny.
Everybody would say so.
Everybody but me.
Look, Cass.
Next to my father you're the finest ..
I'm not asking to be your father.
I'm not even asking you to keep your
toothbrush in the same glass with me.
I'm not rich, Ginny. But I could afford
separate glasses for our toothbrushes.
Tim .. it's not that I don't
appreciate you and all you've ..
I don't want your appreciation.
I want you.
Very much.
No, Tim.
I can't explain it.
It is just something.
Something that I will have
to think out by myself.
Tim, just now.
Just now you called me a wildcat.
Well, maybe you are right.
Maybe I am a cat that
likes to walk alone.
And up there on the
heights with your friends ..
I would just be something
that would make you sneeze.
And that wouldn't be good for you.
Shall we go back?
Good evening, Mr Havock.
- Good evening.
Good evening, Mrs Havock.
- Good evening, Fred.
Now behave yourself, Queenie.
- I won't.
I won't have it. I won't. I won't.
- You will have it and you'll like it.
Has this girl something on you, you rat?
No.
I am doing this for Cass.
Has she got something on Cass?
- Not that I know of.
Then I won't.
She is nothing but a thing.
Good evening.
- Evening.
She's not a thing.
- She is.
Good evening.
Hello, Boone.
- Oh. Good evening.
You don't know a thing about her.
I know enough to know I'll not allow any
cheap shop-girl marry into our bunch.
Pick up your feet.
She hasn't married him yet.
Cass is our friend.
His friends are our friends.
That is a very beautiful thought.
But tell me. What is on your mind?
Cass is a judge.
You don't make enemies of judges.
You may need them someday.
I think I get it.
Smart girl.
Oh, here they come.
Hello.
Remember me? I am Brad Criley.
Yes. Of course I do.
I thought I wouldn't let you face
that gang of hyenas by yourself.
Thanks.
You were right about that dress.
Hi, Brad.
- Hi, Cass.
Don't shoot, girls, until you
see the whites of her eyes.
Cass Timberlane is one
of our big intellectuals.
Sure. He has the
biggest library in town.
A heavy thinker.
He subscribes to magazines
that nobody ever heard of.
Except the FBI.
But when it comes to a woman.
He picks a birdbrain.
I like her.
Well, I mean ..
I like Cass and he
likes her, so I like her.
How sweet, Lillian.
'Operation climber' has
found another beachhead.
If you should ever need a lawyer ..
A lawyer? What for?
Oh, to dance with.
You are hired.
I might need a lawyer at that.
To defend me against
some of Cass's friends.
Oh, but they love you.
Well, there's one or two who look as
though they'd like to sue me for living.
The living versus the dead.
I will take the case any time you say.
She is charming, Cass.
Yes.
Darn her.
Are you very much in love?
It's like being in an earthquake.
You are not exactly the
earthquake type, Cass.
No. No, but ..
I think this is something
that just had to happen.
Earthquakes have been known to do
considerable damage to a community.
And you are a very important
part of the community.
All of your friends hope
that she appreciates that.
That is up to me.
Yes, Cass.
I ..
Wish you both every happiness.
Thanks, Chris.
I don't know that she will have me.
She will.
I don't know.
Would you like to dance, Chris?
You've made a big hit.
Everybody is crazy about you.
I don't know. They pretend to like me.
Because of you.
They know I am wrong for you.
Really Tim, I am wrong for you.
Why?
Some girls make good wives like
your friend in there, Miss Grau.
You want me to marry her?
- No.
Why not?
You know why not.
It couldn't be because you love me?
Is love enough for you, Tim?
I will settle for it.
Are you sure?
- I'm sure that I love you.
And I am sure that marriage can
beautiful and permanent and great.
I'm not afraid. You shouldn't
be either if you love me.
Oh, Tim. I do.
Hold me, Tim.
Always.
Well, that leaves me the
last of the bachelors.
Uhuh.
You know, Roy. I ought to find
a girl like that and settle down.
Yes. I know.
Marriages always affect you like that.
Other men's marriages.
- No. I really mean it.
You always mean it.
That is your charm, son.
But you never do it.
That is your protection.
Did you enjoy your eggs, ma'am?
The best eggs I've ever tasted.
The best toast.
The best coffee.
The best evening.
Oh.
Yes, ma'am.
If you're not careful he'll
think we were just married.
That would be awful, wouldn't it.
- Awful.
That is a nice ring, Mrs Tim.
You like it, Judge?
- It's fine.
It is perfect.
In here.
Come on, dear.
Let's try it here.
- Where?
No, no. Not in there.
Where?
- Around.
Oh, my roses.
Wait. No. Round this way.
Tell you what, let's try it over here.
This will be better.
Can we ..
We can take this love seat out.
What do you think?
It's stood in that corner
for over 70 years.
Would you like to stand
in a corner for 70 years?
Darling, with you it
would be a pleasure.
Hey, remember me?
Listen, you lovebirds.
Make up your minds.
We know that belongs there.
Let's try it back over here.
There. What do you think, Brad?
It is magnificent.
Next week let's try it on the ceiling.
I'm a dead duck.
Alright boys, rest.
I'll get you something.
Something very good for dead ducks.
- I'll get it. I'll get it.
Brad, put the ladder here for me please.
- I thought you said 'rest'.
You can do it while resting, can't you?
- Oh, fine.
Right there.
Oh no, hand me those.
No. That is the wrong side.
- Oh, that's great.
Do you think I could have these? I can
have them made into some underdrawers.
Drape shaped.
You know, a few accordion
pleats, a little peplum.
But a very little peplum.
Watch it.
Brad, do you think Cass really likes it?
Well, you've turned this old mausoleum
into one of the loveliest homes in town.
And I quote.
Did Cass say that?
- Cross my heart.
Here we are.
The three beers.
Papa beer.
Mama beer.
And baby beer.
Well. Rest period is over.
Brad, you hang these curtains up.
Who is the husband here?
It is her husband's turn to rest.
I'll just sit right down in this chair
and make all the important decisions.
Why should he sit and tell us?
Because he is the judge.
Yes, ma'am. Objection overruled.
Speaking of being a judge, when are you
going to come and watch me in action?
Dear, I have been so busy.
But next week for sure.
- No hurry.
Brad.
Get it a little more over to the left.
Just a little.
Just a little more.
That's fine. Fine.
Mrs Boone Havock is on the phone.
She wants to know if you can play
bridge at the club Thursday afternoon.
Well, I don't ..
Wait.
'Monday. The country club.
Pick up the Drovers'.
'Tuesday. Women's Auxiliary'.
'Be nice. Vote'.
'Wednesday lunch. Mrs Prout. Thursday'.
Free.
Alright. And ask her for
dinner here Saturday.
No, wait. I will talk to her myself.
Well, they have surely
got her in harness.
She must love you a lot, Cass.
And that goes both ways.
I just hope she is as happy as I am.
Next on the calendar.
Joseph Allen on behalf of various
stockholders of the Wargate Corporation.
Against Wargate Havock and
other executives and directors.
Hearing on a motion by the plaintiffs.
Are you ready, gentlemen?
I represent the plaintiffs, Your Honor.
I appear on behalf of the
defendants, Your Honor.
Proceed.
As Your Honor may remember ..
This is an action by some stockholders
of the Wargate Corporation ..
Against the officers and
directors of the corporation.
For mismanagement and illegal practices
in connection with war contracts.
Yes, I know that. I read the pleadings.
What is your motion?
If the court please, I move that
the trial of this case be ..
Transferred to another judge.
We strongly oppose the motion.
On what grounds is this motion based?
On the grounds that ..
You, or that this court is ..
Is disqualified from giving a just
decision on this case because ..
Because of this court's ..
Long friendship with the executives and
directors of the Wargate Corporation.
It is the judgement of this court ..
That the charge of prejudice
is without foundation.
And that the accusation is not
in accord with the facts.
Or with the past record of this court.
The motion is denied.
The case will take its regular
pace on the calendar.
The court is adjourned.
Yes, Brad.
He did, eh?
- He did what?
Cass is going to stay on the case.
Alright, Brad.
He said Cass was okay?
He said Cass would judge the case.
Well, that is okay.
Then we have nothing to worry about.
Well, at least we have
a friend in court.
Cass doesn't suspect anything.
And the stockholders
don't know anything.
We can go on postponing
the case indefinitely.
Maybe.
There is always something.
There is nothing to this lawsuit anyway.
War contracts created a
lot of these situations.
Not like this one, brother.
Come in.
Hello, Jamie. Come in. Sit down.
Drunk driving again?
Not this time.
What's the trouble?
Everything.
You've been out of uniform
quite a while now, Jamie.
You can't blame the war much longer.
I don't blame the war.
But is it wrong for a
man to come home ..
And to want things good
again the way they were?
Is it a crime to expect a man's wife ..
Alice wants a divorce.
That is why I am here, Cass.
What are her grounds?
She wants to get away
from Grand Republic.
Live in a big city.
What has she got against Grand Republic?
Well, you're not going to
let her get away with it.
I am fed up.
Sit down, Jamie.
Come on, sit down. Sit down.
In the first place, people just can't
get a divorce because they're fed up.
Because their wives
are restless and bored.
And in the second place
you are no ordinary Joe ..
Who can just pack up and leave because
your wife doesn't like it here anymore.
One of these days you are going
to be running Wargate plant.
What you do means a great
deal to a lot of people.
This is your town. You are important.
Your future is important.
I have no future without Alice.
You do love her, Jamie?
Love her?
Love her? I ..
I am sorry, Cass.
What about, Jamie?
For saying it out loud.
That's what threw me, I guess.
I thought you might be able
to tell me what do to.
Being as, in a way we
are in the same boat.
What do you mean? In what way?
It wasn't anything
Ginny said definitely.
To me at least.
But to Alice.
What about?
- About not liking it here.
Wanting to move to
Minneapolis or Chicago.
Something about ..
A cage you were both in.
I guess I had better not
take any more of your time.
Jamie, you came home
covered with medals.
There are battles to
win in marriages too.
They don't give you any medals for it.
Good luck, Jamie.
Good luck to you, Cass.
Ginny.
[ Cat miaow ]
So, it's you, huh?
Are you comfortable?
Maybe you would like to go to Chicago?
Well, the joke is on you.
You are not going to Chicago.
And furthermore, I forgot your cat food.
Achoo.
Does the judge know yet?
No. I am going to tell him now.
Cass.
There you are.
Darling, we have to get dressed.
Where have you been?
Don't you wish you knew?
We'll be late for dinner.
- Dinner?
Where?
I told you the just this morning.
- Oh, Your Honor.
I can only say that I had something
more important to think about.
Ginny. Tell me something, will you.
- Tell you something?
You're meant to know everything, Judge.
- Well, it seems that perhaps I don't.
Goodness, what could that be?
Well, it might be something
or it might not be.
But you want to be fair before
you decide, don't you Judge.
Ginny.
Is there something on your mind
you haven't told me about?
Guilty, Your Honor.
- Look Ginny, this isn't funny.
Not for me it isn't.
- And certainly not for me.
You will get along alright.
Supposing I don't want to?
Well, you will just have to I reckon.
Has it ever occurred to that you this
might be nobody's problem but your own?
Well, I wouldn't say that.
Do you think it's Boone's
fault or Queenie's?
No.
Louise, Webb, Diantha?
They've all tried to be very friendly.
Oh, that is right. Yes.
Whose fault is it then?
The stork.
The what?
Ginny.
Ah, Ginny.
Ready for chapter 36?
I am ready for something.
Little Tim.
Little Tim has been
practising flip-flops.
Well, I'm sorry Cleo.
But we mustn't do anything
to disturb the judge.
You see, he's going to become
a father any day now.
Yes, Cleo.
When you get older, you'll understand
what a father goes through.
Go downstairs and give
Mrs Higbee a laugh with that one.
If you say 'Gesundheit' you're through.
Mrs Higbee thinks it
is going to be a girl.
I am sure it is.
Emily Timberlane.
The first woman President
of the United states.
I don't think Emily would
want to live in Washington.
Emily is going to live
where she wants to.
Like her mother.
[ Telephone ]
Hello?
Oh, hello.
Fine, Boone. She is fine.
She is resting right now.
That I will.
Thank you very much.
Goodbye.
They just wanted to know if
there was anything they could do.
That's very nice.
Everybody has been nice to me.
There is more interest in this
baby than the world series.
It won't be long now.
Shall I read to you?
- Hmm.
Chapter 36.
I love you very much.
Is that chapter 36?
And 37 and 38 and all the
rest of the chapters.
I like that book.
How does it end?
There is no end.
I just go on loving you.
Trying to make you happy because
you have made me so happy.
Have I, Tim?
I didn't know how really lonely I was.
And baby makes three.
Tim.
- What?
You'd better call the stork club
and tell them to get a bed ready.
Alright. Take it easy now.
I'll get a hold of them.
Mrs Higbee.
Hello. Get me the doctor, will you.
Dr Drover, yes.
Mrs Higbee. Hello. Hello.
Mrs Higbee. Mrs Higbee.
Hello, hello?
Mrs Higbee.
Hello? Mrs Higbee?
Oh, nurse.
That doesn't happen to be a young fellow
by the name of Timberlane, does it?
No, Judge.
This is little David Smith.
- Oh.
Hiya, Smitty.
How are you?
Any word about Mrs Timberlane?
I am afraid you will have
to wait a little longer.
Would you like to see our garden?
Pardon?
- Come with me.
That's our garden.
Like it?
- Wonderful, Wonderful.
You need one more for a baseball team.
Save that spot on the outfield
for young Timberlane.
Supposing the baby is a little girl?
- That is so much the better.
Mrs Timberlane is a very
fine ball player herself.
I'm sure she is.
Ginny. Is anything wrong?
Ginny is fine.
- Are you sure?
She didn't have a bad time at all.
You scared the daylights out of me.
Is it a boy or a girl?
- A girl.
Emily.
Only.
Only what?
A bit of bad luck.
Dead?
Some internal trouble.
Come on down the hall.
We'll have some coffee.
Does Ginny know?
I'll tell her later.
I'd like to tell her, Roy.
If you don't mind.
Later, Cass.
I'll let you know when.
Hello daddy.
Hello.
I wouldn't stay long.
Where is Emily?
You look fine.
You poor man. Did you have a bad time?
Roy said it wasn't bad.
Why won't they let me see her?
Have you seen her?
Tim, tell me.
Ginny.
Emily is ..
She had bad luck.
No, no. Wait. Don't tell me.
No.
Well, what's the matter?
You can't jump with a queen.
- Why not?
I don't know. Some rule.
Seems they had rules, even for queens.
Who made the rules?
Some Chinese I suppose.
I don't remember his name.
And I suppose women aren't
allowed to make rules.
How do you know this jump won't
make the game more exciting?
You'd like to bet on what would happen?
- Anything might happen.
Something new.
Something nobody's ever tried before.
Would you like to see?
- Yes.
Supposing you jumped
with your queen like this.
That would check my king.
Then I would have to move my bishop.
That would check your king.
So you would lose your queen.
That would mean stalemate.
And the end of the game.
And who would have any fun?
Poor little queen. You can't jump. Ever.
Because of a rule.
A stupid rule made by
some man centuries ago.
Oh, it ain't right.
Tim.
Tim darling, have patience with me.
Yes, my queen.
Hey, where is the hot drink?
Where's the others?
- They're coming.
My, don't you look happy.
Well, you look pretty fit yourself.
Thank you.
There is nothing like a stiff game
of chess to keep a girl in shape.
Poor Cass. Alone with me all afternoon.
Listen. I'll take poor Cass's
place any time you say.
And that goes for skiing lessons too.
I won't learn to ski this year.
It's almost March.
Well, how about flying lessons in the
spring? I'll have my new plane by then.
Me, fly?
Why not?
Tim.
That would be wonderful.
Let's drink to it.
To flying, and your wife.
And you.
The best husband in the world.
Well, let's just drink
to the three of us.
Right. To the three of us.
To the three of us.
See an opening?
- Not yet.
But don't worry.
Who is worrying?
Shall we take a look upstairs?
- That's a good idea.
Now we are in heaven.
Wherever you are is heaven.
You sound exactly like a fellow
I used to know named Brad Criley.
Whatever became of him?
He fell out of an aeroplane.
Or was pushed.
Poor fellow.
- Poor fellow.
Now that we've found heaven,
where do you suppose earth is?
Who cares?
Who cares? Not I. Aim for the sun.
No. The sun is too hot.
How about the moon?
The moon is too dark. For us.
Well, where?
What is your idea of a good destination?
I don't know about you but I am
rather partial to New York.
New York?
- Hmm.
What's good about that?
You mean you've never been?
Well.
First, we go to a restaurant called 21.
Very hard to get a table.
But we would get one.
- The corner table upstairs.
Mr Criley's table.
Should we start with a little
vichyssoise or a melon with prosciutto?
Prosciutto?
- Ham to you.
Oh. Prosciutto, by all means.
Then after that a little
Medayone Danielle.
Hello Kit. How are you?
That is Kit Cornell.
You know, the actress.
Katharine Cornell?
- Uhuh.
You really know people like that?
Sure. Authors, actresses, what have you.
You must come with me some time.
I wanted to go on the stage once.
You would be darned good.
Why don't you try out for the
Heather Club show next week?
I bet you and I could get
a couple of good parts.
Do you think so?
It's in the bag. Louise and Queenie
are going to be on the committee.
Cass will let you do it.
- Sure he will.
And speaking of Cass, he'll be awfully
sore at me flying in this weather.
MC-503-H calling Wargate Field.
MC-503-H calling for
landing instructions.
Come in, please. Over.
"Wargate field replying."
"Better not try to come
in, Mrs Timberlane."
"The ceiling is lifting
but it would be risky."
"Minneapolis might be safer."
Thank, Mac.
Well.
They have very good
prosciutto in Minneapolis.
It looks pretty thick, doesn't it?
You think she will be alright?
I see.
Thanks, Mac.
You haven't played that
lonesome flute for a long time.
I haven't been lonesome for a long time.
Where is the missus?
She went to Minneapolis.
She may not be back until morning.
Alone?
Why?
Because maybe you should be with her.
Now, Mrs Higbee.
This isn't a radio serial.
The green dragon doesn't
live in Minneapolis.
There's all kinds of dragons when
a woman is looking for something.
What is she looking for?
- The green pastures.
Are you going to have
another baby, Judge?
What do you mean, the 'green pastures'?
Someplace that ain't.
Cass.
- Ginny.
- Well.
Ginny, you didn't go to Minneapolis.
No. Of course not. We made a
forced landing in Anderson's farm.
You could have stayed the night.
I couldn't. Brad doesn't
know how to play chess.
Well, that is tough.
You sure had him worried.
What's for dinner? I'm starved.
Fried chicken and waffles, Mrs Higbee.
The prodigal returns
to the green pastures.
Make if for three.
I've asked Brad to stay for dinner.
Is that alright?
- Sure. Fine.
Brad is bringing a copy of the
Barretts of Wimpole Street.
He wants me to try out for
the Heather Club's show.
I think that is a good idea.
Do you mean it?
Yeah. Louise told me about the trials.
I think you would be wonderful.
Well, Brad is going to try out too.
Brad is a very good actor.
No.
What's up?
- He's talking to Washington.
Yes.
Alright. Goodbye.
False alarm. We are safe so far.
That's great.
- Shut up.
I won't shut up and if my
father has to go to jail ..
Nobody is going to jail.
Especially myself.
You didn't know anything about this.
- I do now.
Your father thought you ought to.
The stockholder's
committee knows nothing.
Washington doesn't know anything.
Nobody knows anything except us.
Jamie, what we did during
the war wasn't a crime.
I know, dad. You said that.
But it was against the law.
It was what lots of smart men have
done before and will do again.
Sure.
Right now, the important thing
is to hold Cass's friendship.
And keep postponing the
case until it blows over.
Now, let's get back to the drama.
Very well. Then I will say nothing.
You tell me I don't understand.
You are quite right. I don't.
You tell me he is devoted to you.
I don't understand devotion that demands
duty and respect and obedience and love.
Demands all and takes all.
I don't understand devotion
that grudges you ..
Any ray of light or a
glimpse of happiness.
Even before I passed through that door
and our eyes first met across the room.
I loved you.
And I have gone on loving you.
And I love you know more
than words can tell.
For pity's sake, leave me.
- No.
We must never see each other again.
I shall never let you go.
Robert, have mercy on me.
Elisabeth, my darling.
Robert.
I love you.
Great stuff, Brad.
Now let everybody come and eat.
We hadn't quite finished, chief.
That was swell acting.
Why, you old square-head.
You've got an actress in the family.
Why didn't you let us in on it?
You can never tell about
things like that, can you.
It's Katherine Cornell herself.
You were wonderful, darling.
- Thank you so much.
You were fine, Ginny.
- What about our leaving man?
Give me that kiss that Boone
interrupted and I'll tell you.
How is this?
- You get the part.
I thought I was pretty good myself.
What about it, chief?
Fine. Let's have some of my
special brandy to celebrate.
Good.
A great performance.
- Oh, it was nothing.
That's what you think.
Close the door will you.
This must be very special brandy.
Very special. Yeah.
Well.
Here is to our new legal
representative in New York.
New York?
A great place, New York.
Listen here.
If you think there was anything ..
- You will like New York.
Just let me ask you one thing.
If you're convinced I'm guilty ..
I'm convinced of nothing. I just say
to you that Brad has gone too far.
Oh, when a judge raises his voice
the boys go out and get the rope.
Now look, Ginny. I will be firm about
this. I'm going to be as tough as nails.
It's not easy for me because I love you.
But you don't trust me.
When you fool around
with a buzz-saw, no.
Brad is a buzz-saw, is he?
Are you criticizing your best friend?
Brad is a great guy on a golf course.
He'd steal a man's wife
and think nothing of it.
He would think he was doing
him a favor. And her.
What Brad might think was perfectly
casual could destroy you and me.
Just let me tell you one thing.
Brad is different.
Different from all those other friends
of yours and he has got courage.
If he wanted to get out
of this place he'd go.
If he were here right now
and you dared to hint ..
He'll have a chance for all
that in a few moments.
He is coming here?
- Any minute.
Does he know why?
No, but he will. And I'd like you to
hear what I'm going to say to him.
I wouldn't think of it.
- Now Ginny, hold that temper.
I've got a temper too, Ginny.
I hope you never have
to see it in action.
[ Doorbell ]
Ginny, I want you to stay.
I most certainly will not.
Hi.
- Come in.
Where is the great actress?
She is upstairs.
Let's go into the library.
Who else is dropping in?
- Nobody.
Good. I haven't had a real get-together
with you for some time.
Brad, I want you to be careful how you
answer what I am going to say to you.
Because I want to keep your
friendship if it's possible.
This sounds serious, Judge.
If it's about that suit ..
It's about Ginny.
You and she and I drank a toast
together not long ago up in my cabin.
To the three of us, wasn't it?
To the three of us.
I meant that then and I mean it now.
But I am calling you on the toast.
What have you got?
Now, just as minute, Judge.
- I'm not judging. I'm asking.
If I may do a little asking myself.
What suddenly started all this?
Being forced to admit tonight
what I already knew.
That means to intimate
the preposterous idea that ..
Yes.
What?
- I said yes.
What proof have you got?
I didn't have any until
you asked that question.
You call that proof
you are not asking me?
I'm telling you not to go any further.
Look, Cass.
I have faults and you have exaggerated.
But I think Ginny is the most
wonderful girl I ever met.
But nobody knows more than
I do that she is your wife.
Here's to the three of us. Still.
I'll drink to that.
I wish now I had told you something.
About a month ago I
decided to get out of here.
Why?
I don't know why, Cass. I've always
wanted to take a crack at New York.
A freelance?
Not at first. I asked Webb to let me
represent them there for a while.
Does Ginny know about this?
No. I wanted to be sure.
It may not work out.
One thing I do know.
I will never find better friends.
Want to come up and tell that to Ginny?
You tell her for me. Goodnight, Cass.
Goodnight, Brad.
Hey. You are in the wrong room.
Are we?
Really Mr Browning, I must ask you.
What?
You know very well that love has no
place and can have no place in my life.
As I have told you, I am a dying woman.
That's tough.
We must never see each other again.
You are breaking my heart.
- Oh, Robert.
I love you.
I love you. I love you.
Have mercy on me.
Even with my temper.
Oh Tim.
That's my Ginny.
Our friend just left.
No runs, no hits, no errors.
Tell me.
Oh, he was ..
Took it very well. Brad is a good
guy really. I'm going to miss him.
Miss him?
He's going to New York. He told me.
But don't worry about it. You can get
someone else to play Robert Browning.
I wasn't thinking of that.
I only meant ..
When did he decide all this?
Some time ago, I guess. He didn't want
you to know though until he was sure.
Oh.
Why is he going?
Ambition I suppose.
Brad is a good lawyer.
I suppose he wants to spread his wings.
Well, it does take a
certain amount of courage.
Yeah, sure.
You know, I am getting
worried about myself.
I can't hate Brad. I'm even getting
to the point where I like this cat.
Here is to the four of us.
I don't know Mr Browning at all but even
great poets want to settle down in time.
And have a home of their own.
And a wife and little ones.
It would be so dreadful if ..
I am sorry.
I didn't mean to interfere.
I will leave you now.
Begging your pardon Miss,
but Mr Browning is calling.
Show him in, Wilson.
Yes, Miss.
[ Door knocks ]
Come in.
My love.
Robert.
I went for a ride and
a walk in the park ..
And afterwards, I ran all the
way upstairs without help.
And without once stopping.
Of course, dearest. It's a splendid
feat and I am proud of you.
Come and sit down.
I tell you, Judge. I didn't know what to
do about it when they brought him in.
But nobody knows he's here.
I felt you could quiet him down and get
him home while everybody is at the show.
And Sadie, she couldn't take a chance.
She had to call us.
He was tearing the place apart.
Here is a friend of yours, Mr Smith.
Your Honor. I am guilty.
I'll be close by if you need me, Judge.
- Alright, Charlie. I'll call you.
You got a drink, Judge?
- No. Come to my house. We'll get one.
Did my father tell you
to come and get me?
No, Jamie. Nobody knows anything.
Right. You said it.
Nobody knows anything.
Especially judges.
Especially judges, Judge.
You know, I told you about Alice.
That I was fed up.
Well, Judge.
I am fed up.
- Take it easy, Jamie.
Take it easy. Take it easy.
Well, you going to put me in jail?
Go ahead and put me in.
Put my father in too.
Send us all to jail.
Why wait until the stockholders find
out what we did during the war?
Go on, go on. Send us all to jail.
Come on, Jamie.
Come on.
- Okay.
Do your duty.
Kick all your friends in the face.
I thought you had gone to bed.
Ginny dear, please be sensible.
I had to leave the theater.
Did you get my message?
- Yes.
Yes. It isn't that.
- Well, what is it?
It is me.
It's me.
What?
I don't know.
Tim. Why can't I be what
you want me to be?
Darling, what are you talking about?
You are what I want you to be.
You were wonderful tonight.
Everybody says so.
- It isn't that, I tell you.
I don't care what they say or think.
I cannot go on like this.
Ginny, you're just let down
after your performance.
No.
I can't pretend anymore.
I hate this place.
I hate this life.
I have tried, but ..
I am so bored.
There is no way out.
It's hopeless.
I am hopeless.
Ginny, I wouldn't say that.
- But I am.
I have tried to fit it.
But they don't want me.
No. I won't say that.
I don't want them.
You have pretty well
convinced me of that.
I've gotten to hate the name of Wargate.
Everything is Wargate.
You can't even sit in a theater and see
me act without some Wargate spoiling it.
I didn't do that for Jamie
because his name is Wargate.
Oh, Tim.
Don't be angry with me.
It's a little late for that.
Yes, Tim. It is.
And if I don't go soon ..
It will be too late.
I don't feel it happening.
I can feel myself dying.
Ginny, maybe you should see Doc Drover.
No. I don't need a doctor.
I need a scolding.
I've scolded myself.
Tim, I know I'm spoiled and selfish.
And married to the most
wonderful man on earth.
Ginny.
- It's true.
But it doesn't help.
Nothing will help that I can think of.
You love it here.
You love these people.
You want to stay here.
I can't ask you to give
up being a judge.
Give up being a judge?
Well, do you have to be one here?
- I don't have to be one.
Could you be a judge in ..
In Minneapolis or Chicago?
Just someplace where Boone and Queenie
and Webb and Louise don't own us.
Nobody owns us.
Don't they, Tim?
Can't we go away? Just you and I?
Tim, wouldn't you have much more
interesting cases to see in Chicago?
Darling, I couldn't be a judge
in Chicago right away.
If ever.
Does it mean so much to you being a
judge? You were happy as a lawyer.
Well.
I did have a pretty good offer not
long ago from a law firm in New York.
New York?
Yeah. Denny Thane's firm.
He is from here. We used to go to
school together. He has a big ..
What is the matter?
Well, I hadn't thought about New York.
You haven't anything
against it, have you?
Ginny, you're not afraid
of Brad, are you?
You can tell me, you know.
No, Tim.
I am not afraid of Brad.
Well, if we're going to make a change we
may as well make it as big as possible.
And if I'm going to give up being a
judge, I suppose I should notify them.
Anyway, it won't do any
harm to think it over.
And I'll tell you what.
While we are doing our thinking we
might just as well do it in New York.
Oh, Tim.
Look.
There it is.
Gee, and they got all that from
the Indians for 24 dollars.
And a bottle of rum.
Thank you.
Well, you say when.
- Yes, sir. Thank you, sir.
We hope you feel at home in our hotel.
- I beg your pardon?
That is our motto.
A nice motto.
Well now, where do we start?
- I've got a list of things.
I'll get hold of Thane and tell him
we'll be busy until next week.
We could go shopping this afternoon.
Would you get Hanover 26453 please.
These are the places
Queenie told me to go.
Let's not go there. Remember,
you're a free woman from now on.
Hello?
Hello. Mr Thane, please.
Judge Timberlane.
We'll shop for you first.
You need some new ties.
Hello?
You mean, right now?
Right away?
Oh. Well, just a minute please.
Thane has to go to Washington
tonight for a week.
Go ahead.
Hello?
Alright. I will come right down.
Yes.
Thank you very much.
Well, that's that.
- You'd be bored shopping anyway.
I'll be home by five or six and then
we'll go to dinner. Where will we go?
I don't know.
- We'll find a place.
Then the theater.
Now, you be sure to buy a dress that is
worthy of a successful New York lawyer.
[ Telephone ]
You take it.
Hello?
Hello, Brad.
We just got in.
When am I going to present you
with the keys to the city?
My time is your time.
How about this afternoon?
Well, I'm tied up this afternoon.
Wait unit I see about Ginny.
Brad is free this afternoon.
Why not?
How are you on shopping?
That is what I call a real friend.
Well, when can you come?
Well, don't you New Yorkers
ever work in the afternoon?
Right away, Ginny?
Half an hour.
How about in half an hour, Brad?
I will do something for you someday.
Right, Brad.
Now, you won't be lonely.
I wish you hadn't done that.
Why not?
Can you call him back?
- Why?
I don't know.
This is our trip.
Oh, he is just trying to be nice.
We have to see him some time anyway.
Now, when I come back I will
have good news for you.
It's square-head.
- Well, Mush-rat.
How are you?
You old son-of-a-gun.
I haven't seen you since ..
- Class reunion, '36.
That's right. Have a chair.
- Thanks.
Well, old square-head.
So, you want to be a New York lawyer?
- Well, it ..
It looks like nice work.
Yes. Very nice. Very nice indeed.
When I heard you were coming I dug
up something that may interest you.
Have you read any poetry lately?
- No.
No.
I had a long talk with the old
man about you this morning.
It looks pretty good.
- It does.
Of course, I told him you
are not much of a lawyer.
You mean, compared to you?
- Compared to me of course.
But I told him that in spite of those
high school ideals of yours ..
You are a hardworking ambitious fellow.
Good teeth and a full head of hair.
And a lot of friends.
Well, I'll try to keep the hair.
Of course, it didn't
hurt to tell him that ..
You might bring us some of that
Wargate eastern division business.
By the way, is there anything
in that stockholder suit?
It hasn't come up for trial yet.
What is it? Just the usual
screwball stockholders?
Well anyway, there is one period of
boredom you will be spared because ..
We will be needing you here right away.
Ah.
Here it is.
This is what I was looking for.
Does the witness recognise it?
Where did you get the old class book?
That's right.
The Class Book of the Grand
Republic High School.
And turning to page ..
Nineteen.
I find a poem entitled ..
'Memorandum to Pontius Pilate'.
Written by a certain senior
whose initials are 'C.T'.
Now listen very carefully, Timberlane.
This may be used against you.
'Judas or Pilate'?
'Of these two men ..'
'Which of them was the
worst, my friend'?
'Judas sold out for silver, forsooth'.
'While Pilate just smiled and said ..'
'What is truth'?
'Judas was stupid'.
'Pilate was smart'.
'No law could convict him'.
'Except his own heart'.
'He had nothing to answer
save conscience demands'.
'Pilate played safe'.
'He washed his hands'.
Timberlane. Are you guilty or not
guilty of having written that poem?
Guilty on all counts.
Of course, I didn't show
that to the old man.
I can't tell you how happy I
am about this whole set up.
I feel pretty sure that you could
start tomorrow if you can get away.
That would mean, by the end of
the year you would be earning ..
Well, let's not go into that.
But the future is magnificent.
And if you're not a full partner in
a year or two I'll be very surprised.
Pilate played safe.
He washed his hands.
Didn't you hear what I said?
Mush-rat, I wouldn't have believed it.
But you are worth it.
I can't believe that a man could lie to
himself the way I have lied to myself.
The ability of the mind to find excuses.
To keep from facing the truth.
Even love can be an excuse.
What in blazes are you talking about?
It was a close call.
I will never be able to thank you
and don't think I am ungrateful.
Goodbye.
- What is this?
This is a judge going
back where he belongs.
You are not going back to a
stupid job in a one-horse town ..
Tossing away a chance like this?
Yes. I am.
So long, Mush.
It is so chic.
So gay on your lovely head, Madame.
Ah, Madame. You make our
beautiful clothes come to life.
Good evening, Mr Criley.
- Hello, Robert.
Where is my sister, Robert?
- I will find her for you.
Thank you.
Mr Criley is here, madam.
Well.
Hello.
Avis, this is Ginny.
- Mrs Timberlane, of course.
My brother said you were very
pretty, and as usual he's right.
Thank you, Mrs Elderman.
Now, how do you like New York so far?
- So far so good.
So very good.
How is Cass?
I used to know him.
- He has to go downtown.
Too bad he couldn't be here.
Avis, there are an awful lot
of people here I don't know.
There's an awful lot of people
here who don't know each other.
That is because I am
married to a publisher.
He attracts celebrities like
blue serge attracts lint.
Oh, Mary Ann.
Yes, Avis?
- Mrs Timberlane.
This is Mary Ann Milligan, editor
of Modern Women magazine.
How do you do.
Look her over Mary Ann, and tell
the world what she's wearing.
Certainly.
The speciality of the house.
A 'devil's disciple'.
Well, my first Devil's disciple.
Your first of a lot of things, Ginny.
Brad, can I see you a second?
- Hello, Jack.
Excuse me for a moment, Ginny.
What do you think of it?
Well, I don't understand it.
I will explain it to you.
It is absolutely no good.
As a matter of fact it
is a wretched thing.
You she, she never comes to life.
She never emerges.
- Hello there.
Ça va mon ami.
Congratulations. My sister tells me
you took an academy prize with this.
Second prize.
But if this charming lady will pose
for me, I swear the next time ..
It would be the first prize.
I will have to ask mother.
Say, isn't that ..
Tell him I was here.
You were with us that night, Joe?
It is. Walter Pidgeon in the flesh.
I just saw him at the Bijou
back home a few days ago.
And this gentleman is
a critic of the drama.
I know. I heard your
lecture in Minneapolis.
I remember you, my dear.
You are the one who stayed awake.
Please come after the
theater tomorrow night.
I'm throwing a party for some
Chinese dancers. They are terrific.
It's a tough town in the daytime.
But when the lights go on there is
nothing like it anywhere in the world.
If I had been a man I'd
have been here long ago.
Sometimes there is a fog
and then it is fantastic.
I would love that.
You are very satisfactory, Ginny.
I am glad.
I have thought of you so often.
Of showing this to you.
You are lovelier than
I have ever seen you.
I like you better than I
ever did and that is a lot.
Brad. Why did you leave Grand Republic?
There was nothing else to do, Ginny.
I decided the town was
too small for you and me.
The time had come to stop
kidding myself and I knew it.
Brad, I didn't know you felt like that.
Here in New York I can say it, Ginny.
I couldn't back there.
Here you say what you
like, do what you like.
The values are different here.
New York is big.
It takes the crap out of your soul.
My brother is monopolising
you and we won't have it.
Some of my special guests just arrived.
You must come and meet them.
I wish we could start all over again.
What is to stop us?
What are you doing tomorrow?
- What are you doing tonight?
Ginny.
- No, Brad.
You are in love with me.
Don't spoil it.
- You belong here.
Yes.
- With me.
No.
It was amazing to watch you
today Ginny and know for real.
I loved it. They were wonderful to me.
- Why not?
You came to life. You were brand new.
Of course they were wonderful to you.
Brad.
Did you really mean what
you said a while ago?
You know I love you.
You are going to find that
you belong to me, Ginny.
You are going to come to me and say so.
Never mind. Here she is now.
Thank you very much.
Sorry I'm late.
That's alright. Well, look at you.
Why, you're the prettiest thing
I have seen in New York.
Thank you.
Have fun? Where have you been?
- Places and places. A penthouse party.
My first look at New York with the
lights on. And was that something.
Well, where was the party?
- Brad's sister's place.
Say, her husband must have millions.
It's a lovely place. Way up in the sky.
He is a publisher.
Brad's sister's husband.
Oh, and such wonderful people.
Exciting people.
Gee Tim, the way they treated me.
You would think I was somebody too.
You are somebody.
Maybe you've guessed I had a good time.
Oh, Tim.
Thank you again.
Darling, I'm the happiest
girl in greater New York.
Points east.
West, north.
South.
And that's certainly enough about me.
How is Brad?
Oh, he's in good form.
He wants to take us to his sister's
house in Connecticut for next weekend.
Brad was certainly made for this town.
Well, I guess some men are and ..
Some men just aren't.
What is the matter, dear?
Didn't it go so well?
Oh, it went fine. Sure.
They offered me the keys to the city
of New York and part of Brooklyn.
And a partnership to boot.
Oh Tim, that is wonderful.
I turned it down.
Turned it down?
- Ginny.
Wait a minute. Hold everything.
- You're going back.
I had no right coming
here in the first place.
Well, I am not going back.
- Oh, Ginny.
Don't say that until you hear why.
- But I don't care why.
Don't you want to hear me?
- No, it is too late.
Ginny, it's never too late to
hear the truth about yourself.
And that is what I heard this
afternoon: the truth about myself.
If I go back I'll die.
Here, I am happy. Alive.
Now wait a minute. Let's be careful.
- Be careful?
Be careful of what?
Our marriage?
Why don't you try being careful of it?
A fair judge should tell people marriage
is the most special thing in the world.
What are you trying to say to me?
I'm saying I've a right to live my life.
- Now listen to me, Ginny.
No. I've heard it.
You have to go back because the
Wargates want you and the Havocks.
And you want them?
I didn't marry a man.
I married a country club.
Brad Criley said that, didn't he?
He didn't have to say it.
I knew it all along.
But I wouldn't admit it.
Any more than I would admit
the truth about Brad.
He loves me.
He has loved me from the very first day.
So. Go back if you want to,
but I'm staying here with him.
Ginny.
So, you've lied to me. Both of you.
No!
Brad has been decent about it.
He's not a coward.
He had the courage to get out of
that town. To live his own life.
He had the courage to be different.
So you want somebody different?
- I am staying. Do you hear?
I'm staying, so go.
Go on back to your friends.
Yes, I am going back.
But I am not going back to my friends.
I go back to something more important
than friends or marriage or you.
So you want somebody different, do you?
Well, you are going to get it.
From now on you are on
your own. You are free.
Hello?
Brad.
"I know this sound crazy, darling.
But I am just leaving for Chicago."
"Just got orders."
I'm at the airport now.
Only for a few days, tell Cass.
Then I'll be home.
We'll have dinner at 21, supper at
The Stork and dance at El Morocco.
I got to run.
"Goodbye, darling.
I'll be seeing you soon."
But Brad, I ..
Mr Timberlane asked me to give you this.
Thank you.
In regard to the request of the Wargate
Corporation for further postponement.
I would like to remind the
attorney for the defendant ..
That it is a truism of law that justice
too long delayed is justice denied.
This case must come to trial
before the end of this term.
The request for postponement is denied.
[ Telephone ]
Hello?
Hello, Brad.
I was never so glad to hear
a voice in my whole life.
Well, I've hardly been out of this room.
The weather has been so awful.
I've had a little cold.
I hate this room.
I hate New York so it is
about time you got back.
Now that I'm back I'll fix everything
for you. I'll even fix the weather.
Listen. I've a table reserved for three
at the College Club at one o'clock.
Can you make it?
Well, you had better make
that reservation for two.
Why only for two?
What happened to that
fellow you're married to?
I'll tell you all about
it when I see you.
Okay. One o'clock.
Fine. Bye.
This way, Mr Criley.
Well. How you been?
The whole world ran out on me.
Left me flat.
Even your sister.
She went off to Connecticut for the
weekend and didn't come back.
This has been a ghost town
as far as I am concerned.
Now that you're here I feel better.
Where was the judge?
Couldn't he do better than that
for a girl who looks like you?
Drink, Mr Criley?
Martinis?
- Hmm.
Two.
Now then, where is Cass?
He has gone back to Grand Republic.
- To pick up the furniture?
No.
No. He has gone back for good.
You are kidding?
- No.
You couldn't say it that
easily if it were true.
It is true.
I have ordered.
- Yes, sir.
Well. Good luck, Brad.
So you and Cass are washed up?
Absolutely.
Was I the reason for it?
No. Not really.
- Well, that's good.
Well, now you know why I was
so glad to hear your voice.
Just what did happen?
Well, when he went downtown to see about
the new job everything was alright.
And?
I don't know what happened but when
he came back everything was changed.
We were going right
back to Grand Republic.
He was going to stay on the
bench for the rest of his life.
I was going to stagnate
for the rest of mine.
I see.
You can imagine how that hit me.
I wish to heaven I'd gone in with
you when I brought you home.
Brad, you couldn't have done anything.
Was my name mentioned in any way at all?
Yes.
Of course.
- In what way?
I said I was going to
a man who loved me.
You said that?
Yes.
I wonder what Webb and Boone will say.
What business is it of theirs?
- I happen to work for them.
And I thought you were different.
Different.
- Watch it, Ginny.
I guess I thought I did
exactly what you hoped I'd do.
Any chance of patching it up?
No. I suppose not.
Somebody else, maybe.
From the very first minute I knew you ..
You made me think.
Don't be childish. Of course I love you.
Excuse me.
Get my car, will you.
- Yes, sir. Right away.
A cab please.
- Taxi.
Never mind the taxi. Here is my car.
Let's have it clear, Ginny.
We go through with this all the way.
There's no other way.
You won't stay in New York.
Not for one night.
You'll stay at my sister's
house in Connecticut ..
Until you establish a residence.
Shut up, Brad. Why aren't you honest
with me? You never wanted to be free.
I didn't want a smash-up like this.
- No.
What you wanted for me was
just a cheap, contemptible ..
For heaven's sake.
- Stop the car.
I'll drive you to your hotel.
- Stop the car and let me out.
Ginny, behave yourself.
- Stop it.
Stop it, stop it!
Where are you going, Judge?
- The country club.
Dr and Mrs Drover's 25th anniversary.
That's fine.
You go and have a good time
with your friends now, Judge.
Thanks for tying my tie.
It's like old times, isn't it.
Not quite.
So you think you ought
to go out, do you?
You want your freedom too, huh?
Go ahead. Nobody is stopping you.
Go on.
Go to New York if you want to.
Who are you talking to?
I was rendering a decision. It seems
the plaintiff wanted her freedom.
I'll get her to the vet.
Happy anniversary you old codgers.
It's my anniversary too.
Don't I get kissed?
Come on up somebody and kiss
my wife and see if I care.
How could you put up with
this rotten egg for so long?
She's had to.
Her old man needs the 80 bucks a month
he gets from his roughneck son-in-law.
Chris. For crying out loud I thought
you said Cass was coming.
Well, he's going to be late.
He telephoned about a sick cat.
Not the sick cat he
is married to, I hope.
I don't think that's so funny.
Cheer up, Chris. You'll get him yet.
To Chris and Cass.
- Now you're talking.
You are talking nonsense.
And you are blushing.
Well, it's the judge himself.
- Hiya, Boone.
You are late.
- Yes. I had to go to the vet.
With Ginny's cat. But it's alright now.
Old square-head, we
don't see enough of you.
After all, we're your best friends.
What is on your mind, Boone?
Well.
We need that postponement, Cass.
I do a lot for my friends.
That's why I don't mind asking a favor
from a close friend like yourself.
I don't think this is a question
of friendship, Boone.
But maybe it is.
I certainly think you are my friend.
So I want to get it straight with you.
There's something about this
Wargate suit I don't like.
That's why I came back.
I don't know what you're talking about.
I hope you don't, Boone.
I hope I'm wrong about it.
It's the Judge.
Our old Cass came back to us.
Hiya, Cass.
Come on, let's eat.
Thank you very much.
How are you?
You look lovely tonight, Chris.
- It's a trick I learned.
It's just a question of going
to the right beautician.
You can buy it these days
the way you buy a hat.
It's nice to see you, Chris.
I've thought about you.
Wondered what you were doing.
Oh, I have been catching
up on my education.
I've learned a lot in the
last two years, Cass.
For instance?
For instance.
If I had known two years
ago what I know now ..
I could have made you marry me.
I should have done it.
I suppose so, Chris.
I.
Could still make you happy
and comfortable, Cass.
I ..
I think you need me.
If you do.
You could have me.
Chris, dear.
Chris, you have always been so sweet.
I ..
I was unfair to you once, Chris.
This would just be doubly unfair.
You are the only consistent thing, Cass.
In this whole cockeyed world.
[ Crying noises ]
Lillian.
What is the matter, Lillian?
I was crying.
Because my glass is empty.
Cass. Go to her.
To whom?
They aren't your friends here.
They aren't anybody's friends.
What is the matter, Lillian? Tell me.
I am not supposed to.
But I am going to.
Is this about Ginny?
Do you know Mrs Elderman?
Yes. Brad's sister.
They took her to
Mrs Elderman's apartment.
She is very ill, Cass.
How do you know this?
The doctor there telephoned Roy.
- When?
Yesterday.
Why didn't you tell me Ginny was ill?
Why should I? She is going
to marry Brad, isn't she?
Well, how ill is she?
There was a bad accident.
Internal injuries. She may not live.
They called me for her case history.
Now don't be a fool, Cass Timberlane.
She left you, didn't she?
Personally, I think you are lucky.
Good riddance, I say.
Happy anniversary.
Twenty-five years.
The happy Drovers.
Let me get to her in time.
Please, God.
I am Judge Timberlane.
Avis.
Oh, Cass.
- Ginny?
She is very bad.
How bad, Avis?
- Very.
She's been unconscious since yesterday.
You have no idea how hard
it has been on us, Cass.
Where is she?
I don't think you should see her now.
- Where is she?
Up there.
What is it? What do you want?
- I'm her husband.
Look, if you'll just wait downstairs.
Has she a chance, doctor?
I am doing what I can.
She isn't helping.
She is a bad patient.
She doesn't really want to live.
Ginny.
Ginny, dear.
Ginny. It's Tim.
Ginny.
My candle burns ..
At both ends.
It gives a lovely light.
It's so foggy.
And there is no sky.
Tim.
Ginny. Don't cry.
Don't, Ginny. Don't.
Tim?
Yes, Ginny. It's Tim.
Where are you?
Right here, darling.
Oh, Tim.
I want to die in my own home.
Take me home.
Cass.
How is she?
Get out of here.
Cass, if she lives ..
- Get out.
Is she ..?
For the present at least.
But hasn't Cass said anything?
No.
No. He's been very kind.
Very thoughtful. Very busy in court.
Have you seen the afternoon papers?
- No.
Webb and Boone have been indicted.
How could anyone be as mistaken
as I was about Cass's courage.
I think Cass is waiting
for you to say something.
Say what? That I am sorry?
He knows that.
Even if he doesn't know what
I've gone through since.
He brought me back.
Here in this house with him.
Our house.
Loving him more than ever.
And not being able to
break through to him.
Oh Lillian, I've been such a fool.
I am sorry it's ended this way.
Mrs Timberlane.
The judge says when you're alone
he wants to see you in the library.
Thank you.
I am sorry too, Lillian.
Has Lillian gone?
Yes. She just left.
How do you feel?
Well enough to go.
Would you like to?
Well, I ..
I think it would be better all around.
To New York?
If I can get a job there.
Brad is coming back here.
Oh?
What's that got to do with it?
I just thought.
- You are wrong.
I don't know much about how deep
those things go or how long they last.
Cass, listen.
Brad was something a girl ..
Well, maybe not all girls.
But he was something
that I had to go through.
Brad was my .. my postgraduate course.
He was a great teacher.
You're not telling the
whole story, Ginny.
I am not telling any story.
I don't mean that I doubt you.
- Why not? You have every right to.
For heaven's sake, Cass.
Don't be so fair.
This isn't a chess game.
I kicked the board over.
Your queen has turned into a rook.
Stalemate.
Do you want a divorce?
I want peace within myself.
I've broken up my marriage.
And I want to set you free.
Where would go for the divorce?
- Oh Reno. Florida.
We could get it in New York.
No we couldn't.
I see. Brad the perfect gentleman
would like to protect your honor.
And his I suppose.
- Brad wouldn't have to lie.
No?
Would you like me to swear on the bible?
No, Ginny. We're not in court.
Cass, for heaven's sake
let's get this over with.
Let me go.
Ginny, listen to me. I'm not your judge.
You wanted your freedom, didn't you?
Your freedom from this set up.
You thought that Brad
did too and that I didn't.
That I was owned by my surroundings
and by my country club friends.
I never knew the truth, Cass.
- No. You didn't, Ginny.
But if I hadn't been so blind myself
about some of those things ..
You never would have needed to go to ..
To another man to help you in your
rebellion against those things.
I know a little bit more
about myself now, Ginny.
I don't know about you.
But if it will ..
Ease your mind and make
you happy to get a divorce ..
I shan't say anymore.
Say something more.
- Ginny.
Freedom isn't a question of
marriage or where you live.
It's a fight inside
yourself all the time.
And a wife can be an awful lot of help.
Tim.
Me?
You, Ginny.
Oh, darling.
..r-o-s..
Watch Movies, TV Series & Live Sports
www.admitme.app