- There they are. Plenty of room for them.
- Cut that out, Kid, and get out.
Hey, isn't that young Mr. Cravat, there?
By golly, it is.
Over here. What do you say?
I know what will fetch him.
Watch his ears perk up
when he hears the old Travelers.
Let's give it to him.
High rickety! Well, you old...
Hello, buddy. Old Buck.
Well, hate to be making it into a firefight.
If it ain't the old honker, himself.
Got yourself hitched?
Yeah, I've got a wife and son,
four years old now.
Aye, this is like a Fourth of July
celebration on Judgment Day.
- Beats all Creation.
- Say, where are you heading for, Yancey?
- I'm cutting dirt for the Little Bear Creek.
- That's the spot, believe me.
Yes, indeed.
You're Yancey Cravat, aren't you?
- And you?
- Lee, Dixie Lee.
- Indeed.
- Going for a town site?
No, I'm going for a quarter-section ranch
out at the Little Bear Creek.
That's funny,
I'm heading for Little Bear, too.
Well, I know just the piece of land I want.
It's deep in the gully
and a lot of scrub over.
Ready, aim...
- You near flummoxed. Are you hurt?
- No, I'm all right.
But his legs are broken.
I heard them crack.
Please shoot him.
And in no time, no time, mind you...
they'd snapped up every piece of land
that was worth having...
and by nightfall...
By nightfall there wasn't an acre.
Think of it, Louis, not an acre
left out of that two million.
The only spot I wanted
was the ground we stood on, and...
Well, the girl got that quarter section.
Yancey Cravat...
you let that hussy in black tights
have your claim...
after having been gone a whole month,
away from your wife and child.
- Now, Mama...
- Don't you "Mama" me.
Isaiah, go on with your fanning.
Yes, Mrs. Venable.
- Well?
- The land was hers by right of claim.
I don't believe a word of it.
Why did you let her keep your land?
Lt'd been a man, I could have shot him.
You can't shoot a woman.
- Why not?
- Oh, Felice.
I don't suppose you'd recognize the lady
without her black tights.
"Let there be no strife
between thee and me."
That's from the Old Testament, Dabney.
You may not recognize that.
It's all tommyrot.
Perhaps now, Yancey,
you'll stop this ranting up and down...
and be content to settle down
here in Wichita...
run that newspaper of yours, and conduct
your law practice, such as it is...
with no more talk of Oklahoma.
Don't you realize
that this is a new empire?
Why, folks, there's never been
anything like it since Creation.
Creation? That took six days,
this was done in one.
History made in an hour. Why, it's like
a miracle out of the Old Testament.
- Don't be blasphemous, Yancey.
- Like a miracle out of the Old Testament.
Cities of ten thousands,
springing up overnight.
Well, I'm going back.
I'm going back and help build a new state
out of the last frontier of the nation...
and it'll be a state someday,
mark my words.
Yancey, you're not leaving me again?
Leaving you, my beauty?
Not by a long shot, sugar.
This time you and Cim
are coming with me.
Louis Venable, can you sit there
and see your daughter dragged off...
to be scalped among savages?
- But I want to go, Mama.
- You don't know what you want.
We start Monday week,
fresh and fair, with two freighters.
One with a printing outfit
and the other with the household goods.
- Why, we can make it in nine days.
- I forbid it.
You're going to stay here with your father
and mother in decent civilization.
- I've heard enough.
- I'm going with him, Mother.
That's it, honey.
Why, we've had enough of this Wichita.
We're going out to a brand new two-fisted,
rip snorting country...
full of Indians, rattlesnakes, gun- toters,
and desperados.
- Isaiah, I declare.
- Miserable brat, you Boon boy.
Master Yancey.
Take me with you to Oklahomy.
Please take me, Master Yancey.
You ain't going to no Oklahomy.
You're going to take a bath.
- Mammy, I want to...
- Get out. Get out.
Well, I'll go see
about those freighters, huh?
Come on here, Cim. Atta boy.
My son, you're going to see more Indians
then you ever thought of.
I never heard of such a thing.
What do you mean, Sabra?
You're not going.
Why a Venable should ever
marry such a man, a buffalo hunter.
- Quite right.
- Annie.
A quart of whiskey a day,
living in that dreadful Cimarron country.
- What is Cimarron?
- Savage, Cousin Hewitt.
It means wild, unruly.
Yancey's idea of a name for the boy, Cim.
You don't like anything Yancey does.
You never have.
And that newspaper of his,
Wichita Wigwam.
Editorials about Indian's rights.
You might think Yancey
was an Indian himself.
Who knows?
Some half-breeds are no darker.
- Don't you dare say that.
- I heard he killed a man.
I won't listen to you any longer.
I don't care about Yancey's past.
I married him because I loved him,
and I'm going with him.
- Sabra.
- I never heard of such a thing.
Yancey, where's that iron skillet?
I can't find it anywhere.
- Right here, sugar, with the stove.
- Why didn't you tell me?
Cim, honey, get up off the ground.
It's too damp.
You know, I think we ought to
get out that old rag rug...
and put it down here for supper.
Right you are, honey.
I think Aunt Cassandra must have put
the andirons in here, sugar.
- High rickety!
- Isaiah!
Please let me stay,
Master Yancey, Miss Sabra.
I'll help, I'll work, I'll do everything.
I'll help you in Oklahomy.
Please let me stay.
Well, you're here,
I reckon you can stay, Isaiah.
I hope you go to heaven when you die.
Let me do that cooking, Miss Sabra.
I'll fix them.
Yeah, you start right in
by getting some wood.
- Now, scoot.
- I'm scooting.
There's loyalty, Sabra,
that money can't buy.
We're going into new things, pet.
A new empire...
and I want to help build it for you.
And we'll have just
the prettiest little house we can find, too.
- With flowers and things.
- With flowers and trees...
and morning glories growing all over.
It'll be our first real home, alone...
and I want you to be happy
all the way, sugar.
Our first real home...
alone.
Hold that iron. Don't move.
I ain't aiming to check you through.
All I want is your ready money. Come on.
This is the first time I ever fronted
your iron, Kid.
- Well, if it ain't Yancey. Howdy.
- Howdy.
- I'm sorry I disturbed you folks.
- This is my wife.
- Howdy, ma'am.
- My son's inside, asleep.
I'm heading for Osage,
aiming to make it my home.
Osage, huh?
- Gonna start your newspaper there?
- Yeah.
Good.
- Got to be loping.
- Need you hurry away like this, Kid?
I got overdrawn at the bank at Red Fork
and they're looking for me.
Luck to you.
- Stay away from Osage, will you, Kid?
- Sure thing.
Unless you send me an invite. Cut dirt!
It's a poser, honey. All this in six weeks
right up from the raw prairie.
Next time you come here, Chief,
you go through the roof.
He shot him.
Esteban Miro, a half-breed and a bad one.
I didn't think he had the brash.
Must have some friends around town.
Don't you worry, honey.
Look, sugar,
they've named the streets already.
Pawhuska Avenue,
that's an Indian name, son.
Paw-hu means hair and ska means white.
White hair.
Pawhuska was an old Osage chief.
- I'm an Indian, old White Hair.
- Cim.
- Howdy.
Lots of watermelons there, Isaiah.
- Yes, sir. I sure glad I came to Oklahomy.
- Just a minute.
- I'll appeal to the highest court.
- You're a sooner.
- Don't you call me...
- Gentlemen.
Step right inside.
We'll determine the status of this case.
I don't let anybody call me a sooner.
- By the way, have you each $10 with you?
- Yes, we have.
Step right inside, men,
and tell us all about it.
All right. I want to know who...
Plenty of law practice.
Three or four claimers
for some of these lots.
Look, honey. Look, folks working late.
Plenty of good water...
Here you are. That's right.
Now, lady, what can I do for you?
There's Louis Hefner's emporium.
I saw old Louis stake that claim.
Furniture in an undertaking parlor?
They have plenty of combination stores
out here until the town gets larger.
If you've a mind,
you can fly out of there, Elmer.
Hold it there, partner.
Hold her, don't let her buck you down.
Get away from that weeping thing.
- Why don't you do something?
- I'm doing all I can, honey.
Old Elmer's been uncorking
the red eye, I see.
Yancey, do get out of here
so we can find a place to sleep.
I'm nearly dead and so is Cim.
I'm sorry, honey. I...
Say, where's the Bixby Hotel?
Left turn.
You just passed it on the other corner.
Honey, we passed right by it. Get along.
See you later, folks.
Giddyup. Come on here, boy.
I won't bring up my boy in a town like this.
I'm going back home.
Well, don't you think you better wait
until morning, honey?
You know, a good night's sleep...
and things are gonna look
entirely different.
I'll be back soon.
Louis Hefner, one of the town's
leading merchants now, I gather.
- Hello, Yance. I'm glad to see you here.
- I'm glad to be here.
I trust the furniture end of the business
is doing better than the other.
Yeah. Only been three killings so far...
but we'll have to start a full jail
pretty soon, I guess.
- You're gambling?
- No.
Just watching where the money goes.
Yancey! Yancey Cravat!
- Old Grat!
- Yes. Come this way.
Yancey Cravat.
Why, you old letch monger.
You are still wearing that white hat.
And you're still making
lightning calculations.
- You know the boys.
- Most of them.
Esteban Miro.
So, you're Cravat, huh?
Yeah, and you?
Yountis, Lon Yountis.
- Howdy.
Gents, what are you going to have?
This is on the house.
Brandy.
I'll have brandy.
- Are you going to start the newspaper?
- Yeah, Grat.
Yeah.
I understand the former editor here,
a man named Paigler, died.
Was shot in the back, huh?
What are you aiming at?
Here you are, gents.
Have another one.
All right.
Mr. Cravat, I'd like to talk to you a minute,
if you have time.
You see, I'm a printer and a darn good one.
And you see, I heard you were gonna
open up a newspaper office called...
The Oklahoma Wigwam, see.
And I'd like to have...
Well, I'd like to go to work.
- Howdy.
- Howdy, Yance.
- Howdy, Bull.
- Morning.
Morning.
"...saffron-robed, arose from the ocean...
- "to bring light to gods and men."
- Ocean?
Yarns and laces, celluloid collars...
knotting yarn, drawstrings,
shoestrings, suspenders.
- Have you any fancy braids?
- Yes, ma'am, I have some fancy braids.
That's Sol Levy, a walking notion counter.
...suspenders, darning yarn,
celluloid collars...
Howdy, Sol.
Howdy, Mr. Cravat. Howdy, ma'am.
Yes, ma'am, here's some drawstrings...
...fancy braid and I'll give you
a real good bargain.
I never saw anything like it in my life.
I'm afraid they think my dress
is a little too elaborate.
Why, Milton would have no words
for such beauty.
Howdy, Cim.
He called you Cim.
- The boys are up to something.
- Who are they?
I can't say for sure, but I think
they're the ones that did Paigler dirt.
Paigler? Who's that?
Isn't that the editor?
The one who was found shot dead?
- You mean they did it?
- I don't say they did it, exactly.
They know more than is comfortable.
Still wearing that white hat, huh?
Who's that?
That's Lon Yountis.
Nothing to be alarmed about.
Don't be frightened, honey.
Stand right where you are.
The dirty scum.
Inside. Get out of here.
Half-circle cut.
You'll find that's the Cravat brand.
- Can't you take a joke, Yancey?
- Joke, nothing.
- Lf your missus wasn't with you.
- Don't you "missus" me...
you dirty scum.
You're a lot of good for nothing louses,
that's what you are.
Shooting at people in the street.
You leave my husband alone.
- I declare, I've a notion to...
- Honey. Sabra.
Why, it'll be all over the Southwest...
that Yancey Cravat was hiding
behind a woman's petticoat.
But you didn't. They can't say so.
You shot him very nicely
in the ear, darling.
Well, you shouldn't interfere when men
are having a little friendly shooting.
Friendly?
A bullet within an inch of your head?
He knew where it was going.
Well, come on, sugar.
I think we better find that house
we're gonna live in, don't you?
Come on.
Down a little. A little more.
Now a little more. Hold!
Just nail it.
I'll bushwhack her.
- Well, honey, we're here.
- Yes, we're here.
We're getting started, too.
You know, when I think of those five years
in Wichita...
- I thought you liked it in Wichita.
- A prison cell, my pet.
Five years in one place,
that's the longest stretch I've ever done.
Five years.
Back and forth like a trail horse.
House, office, Venables, vegetables.
A little while, I'd have turned into either
a Venable or a vegetable, one or the other.
Well.
We better get this office
and print shop settled...
if you're ever gonna get out an issue
of that newspaper.
I guess Rickey can attend to it.
He's a printer and a darn good one.
I gotta see
about these real-estate transfers...
and write up some editorials and news...
and we got a clue
to the Paigler killer last night.
- I wanna follow it up.
- I wish you wouldn't.
If I can find out who killed Paigler...
I'm gonna print it in the first edition
of the Oklahoma Wigwam.
Well, did you see the...
Well, we got the shingle hung out all right,
Mrs. Cravat.
- Look fine, Miss Sabra.
- Come on, now, colored boy.
We'd better pitch in and unsnarl things.
Never mind, Rickey.
I'll straighten this room.
- You go on into the print shop with Isaiah.
- Yes, ma'am.
Well, we'll unmantle the printing press...
and dust off the adjectives.
Thank you.
Look, Mama,
see what an Indian just gave me.
Cim, how many times have I told you
not to talk to those dirty, filthy Indians?
Here, take this into the kitchen.
Be careful, now.
Don't drop it, and come back
and help Mother.
All right, Mama.
Safety pins, collar buttons...
needles, thread, thimbles,
crochet cotton...
celluloid collars, safety pins,
crochet cotton, needles.
Here comes that little shrimp again.
Let's see how he feels today.
Hey, Sol! Come here!
I wanna buy a little fancy lace!
Come on over here. Come on.
...cotton, needles, thread...
Come on, Sol,
I wanna buy my gal a bustle.
- How much for a bustle cover?
- Bring me a pair of tights.
Safety pins, cotton gloves, needles.
Please, don't start, please.
Please don't, mister. Please don't.
Please, mister. Please, don't.
- Bring him here.
- Please. Please. Please don't.
- Well, howdy, Mr. Levy.
- Please don't do it, mister.
- Please, mister, don't...
- That's all right. That's all right.
- Let's you and me have a drink.
- No, thank you. No.
Please don't do it, mister.
I don't want any. Thanks.
- What? You don't want it?
- No.
Be a real pal and have a drink. Come on.
No.
- What do you think about...
- Where you going, there?
Where you going, there?
Come here, you little runt, and have a...
Come up here.
Please, mister.
Take a drink.
Please don't, mister. Please.
When I tell them to take a drink,
they drink, don't they?
Well, they better.
You're a rough, eh, Yountis?
Just whip your weight on wildcats, huh?
Who asked you?
Come on, Sol. You're all right, huh? Sure.
That's their idea of a joke.
You go ahead about your business.
- They won't be bothering you none, now.
- Thanks, Mr. Cravat.
Thank you.
Threatening to make Osage
the terror of the Southwest...
as in the old days of the Cimarron, huh?
- Now, you as the editor...
- Yeah, me as editor...
I'm interviewing citizens of note
regarding their sentiments.
- What's yours?
- Stick to your lawn.
Come on, Yountis. You know
what I'm aiming at. Who killed Paigler?
I'm advising you to keep your mouth shut.
Or the next time,
it won't be your sombrero.
Thanks for the sentiment. Mine is...
Cherokee death cry. Means, you or him.
The second button on his coat
is about the spot for his wishbone...
maybe a couple of inches higher.
Get your real-estate papers filed all right?
Yancey, dear.
You're not going to bother anymore
about that Paigler man, are you?
Don't you be worrying your pretty head
about that.
Oh, please. What does it matter?
He's dead.
Maybe he did shoot himself.
Besides, you've got Cim and me
to think of.
Paigler was shot in the back
trying to do what I want to do:
Make a model empire
out of this new Oklahoma country.
No, sir, I'll show them first crack.
The Oklahoma Wigwam
prints all the news, all the time...
knowing no law except the law of God...
and the government
of these United States.
Say, that's a pretty good slogan.
Top of the page,
just ahead of the editorial column.
Yancey, let them alone.
I don't want you to be killed.
- I don't.
- Honey...
I'm gonna clean up the Paigler killing,
or I won't be alive myself.
You don't wanna lose me just yet, do you?
No, dearest.
There he is.
- Howdy.
- Howdy, ma'am.
Yancey, our womenfolk
think it's about time...
that some contact be established
between the town and Providence.
There ain't a minister here,
and we've come to ask you...
to conduct divine service next Sunday.
Divine service?
- Why, sure. I'll be pleased to.
- Then that's settled.
- Fine.
- We'll have to arrange a place.
Well, let's see, there's Grat Gotch's.
- The gambling tent?
- It's the only place in town big enough.
That's right.
Yeah, I know Grat well. I'll speak to him.
Come along.
Back soon, honey.
Good morning, Mr. Cravat.
Do you feel nervous
about your sermon, dear?
I'd rather plead to a Texas jury
than preach to this gang of...
What's everybody laughing at?
How can you laugh?
- Isaiah.
- Can't you understand?
I didn't go to fret nobody.
You all dress up fine
for a church's meeting...
so I pleased to dress myself up
Sunday style.
That's right, Isaiah.
We take it as a personal compliment.
- Why, you look finer than any of us.
- I just fixed my twily like you all.
Say, Isaiah, would you like to have
a real suit of Sunday clothes?
A Sunday suit for me to wear? For true?
I don't want you to go
to that church meeting.
Oh, now, now. You don't understand.
Now, listen close.
I want you to do
something important for me.
Now, the house is all alone, see.
I want you to go down there
and keep watch...
till we come home
from that church meeting.
Patrol duty. That's what.
Patrol duty? Yes, sir, Master Yancey.
Now you take this and if anyone tries
to break in, shoot.
- I'll kill them dead.
- Fine.
And then you get a new suit and boots,
besides. Now, scoot.
Yes, sir. I'm scooting.
Do you think... Yancey, let's not go.
Tell them you're sick or I'm sick.
Tell them anything...
We're late, honey.
Hi, Yance. Hiya, preacher man.
Now, Preacher, where's your Bible?
Right here, boys.
Now no loafing in the entrance.
Either come in or stay out.
Did you see that man, Yountis?
He looked at you so...
That's fine, honey.
I always like to have the members
of my flock right under my eye.
Quite a shindig, ain't it?
Some of these folks look as queer
in church as a mule does in the front...
parlor.
How do, Mrs. Cravat?
I'm Mrs. Tracy Wyatt.
How do you do?
It was so nice of your husband
to conduct this service this morning.
About time the intellectual life
of this community was stirred up a bit.
Yes.
I was a schoolteacher back East,
that is in Cairo, Illinois.
- Indeed?
- Yes, indeed.
I can trace my ancestry right back
to William Whipple...
one of the signers
of the Declaration of Independence.
Lands, yes.
Some pumpkins.
I'll say. Hey, Annie.
Come along, girls.
- Dixie Lee, just arrived in town.
- Dixie Lee?
Why, I thought you'd heard of her.
Why, she's a...
Right here, sister. Take my pew.
Get up, webfoot, and give the gals a seat.
Rest the velvet, lady.
Look out for them splinters.
Sit down. Take off your hat.
- Ain't she a huckleberry?
- Lollapalooza, field up, pert and chipper.
Those girls. Red Fork.
Excuse me, please.
Is it all right if I'm here?
You can stay here just as long as I do.
Thanks.
Fellow citizens...
I have been called upon
to conduct this opening meeting...
of the Osage first Methodist...
Episcopalian, Lutheran, Presbyterian,
Congregational, Baptist, Catholic...
Unitarian, Hebrew church.
During the course of my career
as lawyer and editor...
I've been required to speak
on various occasions on many subjects.
I've spoken in defense of my country
and in criticism of it.
I've been called upon
to defend and convict...
horse thieves, harlots, and murderers.
And while I know my bible
from cover to cover...
and many of its passages
are graven on my heart...
this, fellow citizens, is the very first time...
that I have ever been required to speak
the word of God in His temple.
For any shelter,
however humble or however sordid...
no offense, Grat...
becomes, when His word is spoken in it...
His temple.
Therefore, let us open
this auspicious occasion by singing...
What do you know, boys, anyway, huh?
How about...
Who Are You At Home, for a starter?
Thanks, Rickey.
It's a good song, though a bit secular.
But you all know it. That's the main thing.
Here, wait a minute. Wait a minute.
While we are singing,
we'll take up a collection.
What for?
Because, Pete, you infidel...
part of a church service
is in taking up a collection...
and your donations, fellow citizens,
ladies and gentlemen...
and you, too, Pete...
will be for the new church organ.
Great guns, Yancey.
We ain't even got a church.
Now, that's all right, Pete.
Once we buy an organ, it stands to reason
we'd have to build a church to put it in...
and, members of the congregation...
anybody contributing less than two bits...
will be thrown out of this tent by me.
Indians not included.
All right, Jesse,
will you please favor us with a pitch?
Will the ladies please join in
with their sweet soprano voices?
Now, once again, please.
Fellow citizens...
the sum of the collection for the organ
for the first Osage church...
whose denomination shall be nameless,
is a gratifying total...
of $133 and 55 cents.
Wait a minute, Grat,
did you say 55 cents? 55?
That's right, Yancey.
Some miserable, tightfisted,
skinflint of a...
Well, maybe it is an Osage by mistake.
How about a Cherokee, Yancey?
Not a Cherokee, Sid.
I recognized your voice by the squeak.
If you knew anything at all, you
and Yountis and the rest of your outfit...
you'd realize that a Cherokee
is too smart...
to put anything in the contribution box of
a race that's robbed him of his birthright.
Friends, we've come to the sermon.
Anyone wishing to leave,
kindly do so now.
Please make way
for all departing worshippers.
My text is from Proverbs.
"A lion is in the way.
There's a lion in the streets."
Friends, there's a lion
in the streets of Osage.
I have a confession to make.
I have gone about seeking information
of this lion.
I might say this jackal or dirty skunk...
if it wouldn't be sacrilegious.
But this jackal in a lion's skin...
who by threatening sudden death...
has held this little town
abjectly terrorized.
I intended to announce from this pulpit...
this platform...
that I would publish this knowledge...
in the first issue
of the Oklahoma Wigwam...
coming off the press next Thursday,
thereby starting my paper off with a bang.
Friends, and fellow citizens...
I repent of my greed...
and my desire for self-advancement
at the expense of this community.
I no longer intend to withhold the name
of that yellow, skunking murderer...
who shot down Jack Paigler
when his back was turned.
I will tell you all now the name of that...
Was Lon Yountis.
Stay where you are.
Louis Hefner...
as coroner, do your official duty
and remove the body.
Okay, Yance.
It's self-defense and justifiable homicide.
This town needs a boot hill,
and I'll start it with this burial.
Come on, boys.
Fellow citizens...
under the circumstances...
we will forego this sermon...
and conclude this service
with a brief word of prayer.
Bless this community, O Lord.
Amen.
I swan...
that's the most surprising church meeting
I ever attended.
But I must say,
your husband did the proper thing.
The cleaning out of that gang
is one of the first moves...
to make this town fit to live in.
Thanks to you, Yancey.
- Horrible, he might've...
- But he didn't, honey.
Everything's all right.
- Did you have to kill him like that?
- No, I could've let him kill me.
Congratulations, Mr. Cravat.
Haven't seen you since the run.
Well, how do you do Miss...
Lee?
No wonder.
- I heard you were in town.
- You've known.
Yes, I'm here.
Thought you'd settle down
on that quarter section that I didn't get.
Well, I tried to be a farmer,
but I had to give up the land.
The neighbors' wives formed a vigilance
committee, and I left by request.
A vigilance committee would.
You haven't said a word
all the way home, pet.
What's stirring you?
That woman, smirking and smiling.
And you stood there actually
talking to her, holding her hand...
after she'd stolen your land in the run, too.
She wanted that land because she was
trying to give up her way of living...
- was desperate.
- Well, what's she doing here, then?
Driven out by the neighbors...
she heard the railroad was coming
through and came down here.
You talk as though
you know a lot about her.
A little. Comes from a good family,
victim of circumstances.
Well, in a way, she's a good girl.
A good girl?
I know a lot of people
scattered over Oklahoma...
that shouldn't cast a stone at her.
Don't you quote your Bibles
and Magdalenes at me, Yancey Cravat!
- Hello, Bill.
- Well, well, well.
First anniversary numbers.
Say, you've been meaning to pull some
blood for a year. Why don't you subscribe?
Well, it cost $1.
Cravat could use that dollar
to buy the new baby a rattle.
And a pair of rubber boots
till the streets get paved.
You sure need rubber boots here,
or go barefoot.
I got to get a pair of new boots...
Darling, she's awake.
Hello, baby Donna. Hello, sweetheart.
Look, this is Daddy.
This is Mama,
much more important to you just now.
Yancey, darling, I'm so happy.
I'm highfaluting myself, sugar,
smiling as a basket of chips.
I'm gonna do so many things.
Build a porch for Donna.
Start a woman's club, a real one.
Make this town better for Donna to live in.
No saloons. No women like Dixie Lee.
And I'm gonna have a hired girl
as soon as the newspaper...
Yeah, all those things, sugar,
but you mustn't try too much.
The garden looks fine, Miss Sabra,
and them morning glories sure is climbing.
Thank you, Isaiah.
Hi, there.
Look, she know me.
Who you rolling your eyes at
and making faces?
Just wait until you get
a little more bigger.
I've got a lot of things
I is gonna teach you.
May I come in? I brought you some of
the nicest chicken broth, made it myself.
Watch Movies, TV Series & Live Sports
www.admitme.app