Oh, the Queen! Where's the Queen?
The Queen is gone! Cleopatra!
Cleopatra's gone! What on earth do you mean?
Pothinos.
Here is your new kingdom, Cleopatra.
Here you can command the asps
and scorpions of the desert.
Maybe they will bow low
and whisper "Majesty. "
If my hands were free, I'd
kill you. But I am more kind.
I leave you this mighty
schoolmaster. Set him free.
Apollodorus.
With his help, you might
reach Syria over there.
And the way to Egypt? Is death.
Set foot in Alexandria
again, and I'll kill you.
I have heard that Caesar comes
to Alexandria, Prime Minister.
I'm returning to meet
with Caesar, Philosopher.
Goodbye, Cleopatra, Queen of the Desert.
You'll find, to your sorrow,
I'm still Queen of Egypt.
Untie me.
You understand, my Queen, he
returns to meet with Caesar.
Is this a time to talk of Romans?
I've had no breakfast. I'm hungry.
So is Caesar hungry. For Egypt.
You see how wise your father was...
to make Rome the protector of you
and your brother, King Ptolemy?
They've got you out of the way
to deal with your brother alone.
They can handle him.
I'll get back to Alexandria.
Majesty, it's death.
It's certain death to go.
How old is this Caesar?
I am told you have
arrived at a conclusion, Caesar.
I have.
Is it your judgment to support
the cause of Ptolemy or his sister?
Your young King Ptolemy has raised an army...
to crush his sister, Queen Cleopatra.
It must be disbanded.
As the general of that
army, suppose I refuse?
Well, we'll go into that if you
do, but I don't think you will.
Good model. Build it.
By what authority do you
judge the destiny of Egypt?
I am here to see
that there is peace in Egypt.
With a Roman army waiting at the border?
Excellence, would you not enter
into a treaty with the King...
if the Queen has disappeared? Has she?
Rumor says that
Cleopatra has fled to Syria.
She must have. She's not here.
Maybe she was assisted in
her flight. Who can tell?
Who can tell?
Well, from what I hear of
her, small loss to Egypt.
In such a case, your
king would be sole ruler.
Under Roman guidance.
And you would pay to
Rome each year one million denarii.
One million denarii! One million denarii!
And 10 shiploads of Egyptian
corn for the unemployed in Rome.
Ten ships of corn. Ten thousand
votes in Rome for Caesar.
A hundred thousand maybe.
Who can tell?
Well, I'm waiting.
Agreed.
Let him sign it.
A letter. Julius Caesar to the Senate, Rome.
A rug of Persia. A gift for
Caesar from Nahigian the merchant.
We give nothing to Romans here.
Did you say for Caesar?
Pass on.
What do you think you own,
the Earth? Yes.
And we have made a settlement with Egypt
whereby we support young Ptolemy as King.
Your seal, Excellence.
Against the sedition of
his sister, Cleopatra...
who, by all reports, has fled to Syria.
A gift for Caesar, fit even for his eyes.
Thanks. Give him something.
The wax is ready for your seal, Caesar.
The rug, Excellence. Will you receive it?
What? Yes, yes, put it down.
Excellence, the wax is cooling.
Observe, Caesar. A most unusual design.
What? Well!
Greetings to Caesar from Egypt.
A very amusing joke.
Very good.
But I'm too busy.
Huh?
What's the matter? Tell him, Pothinos.
Tell him what's the matter, if your
lying tongue can find the words.
I am Cleopatra. Huh?
Yes, a good joke.
She is Cleopatra, and I am Caesar.
Come on. I'll take her away. No, you won't.
Enough of this. Caesar, you must listen.
He abducted me to the desert
and left me there to die.
But nothing could stop me from greeting you.
Are you to be fooled by a...
No, I am not to be fooled.
It's dangerous to lie to me, Pothinos.
But, Caesar, I thought it would
be best all around if she...
Then you did lie to me.
So you would match wits with Caesar?
Oh, no.
All right, run along now.
The seal, Caesar. Not yet.
This quarrel with your brother
will be settled in Rome.
That's all. Withdraw.
Come, Majesty. Enough.
Before I go, one word more?
Well? Well?
It seems strange to see you working.
I've always pictured you
either fighting or loving.
Well, I have had some
experience with fighting.
But none with loving, I suppose.
Well, none with pretty little queens.
Oh. That was nice.
And now, with your permission,
I'll go to work again.
The dispatches from Gaul.
What... Oh, run along.
If I leave
you now, I'll be killed.
Pothinos has sworn to kill me.
Pothinos has said that if I ever set
foot in Alexandria again, he'd kill me.
The map of Gaul.
Well!
He usually does those things, you know.
Can't you see I'm busy?
India.
Of course.
Of course I know you're very busy...
but I thought you might
like to talk about India.
What? What about India?
It's the treasure house of the
East. With enough gold to...
Oh, but you're much too busy. We'll talk
about it tomorrow. If I'm still alive.
What about India?
Well, the road to India lies through Egypt.
And the Queen of Egypt,
allied with Caesar could...
Why didn't you say that right away?
My tongue was bewitched by Caesar.
The man in you seems even
mightier than the general.
Egypt.
Sit down.
Pretty girl. Charming.
Now.
Now, what do you know of India?
Oh, nothing much.
Ah.
But its gold would pay
Caesar's legions for a century.
Well! Now that's something to talk about.
Yes, but not here.
Come to my chambers and
dine. We'll make such plans.
Are your plans for India or me?
Both.
Shouldn't a queen choose
for her confidant a king?
The word "king" is not well-liked in Rome.
Caesar takes what he wants.
Flavius.
My own guard for the Queen's safety.
I had to walk miles across
the desert to the sea...
to find the fishing boat
that brought me to you.
But just seeing you is
magic, immortal Caesar.
That's quite a speech.
Your tongue is no longer
bewitched by Caesar, eh?
No.
It's my heart now.
That's strange, too. I've never loved before.
Love?
If you'd bring true the dreams of
empire that fill your pretty head...
leave love alone.
I can't. It's too late.
Ah.
It's too late.
Will you do something that
will make me very happy?
I am here to make you very happy.
Then drive Pothinos out of Egypt.
Drive him? Where?
Into the desert where he drove me. No.
I came to talk of India,
not the quarrels of Egypt.
But I am Egypt.
If I make you so.
I was wrong.
Let's not talk at all tonight.
Perhaps there's nothing to talk about, ever.
You don't trust me?
No.
And if I said I really love
you, you wouldn't believe me?
No.
And if I implored you to
marry me, you wouldn't?
I'd have to ask my wife in Rome.
As if you'd care about that.
Divorce her. Together we
could conquer the world.
Nice of you to include me.
I will be Caesar's wife and ally.
You rate yourself highly, my child.
So a woman isn't strong enough
to help the mighty Caesar?
Caesar.
Have you ever thought
what your life is worth?
Well, it's worth a great deal to me.
It must be worth a great
deal to others. Mine is.
And I'm only the Queen of Egypt...
while Caesar, if he lives,
will be Emperor of the world.
If he lives?
Life is a precious thing, isn't it?
I think so.
Hadn't you better put that javelin down?
And if a man swears to
take the life of another...
death is justice for him. I think so.
Pothinos.
He came to kill you.
Or you.
Passage to the tombs. I saw
his sandal beneath the curtain.
And now am I worth talking to?
More...
Well, far more than Pothinos.
Guards!
Take it away.
Let's not talk anymore.
I picked a flower in Britain
once, the color of your eyes.
This is the first morning he's
been late since the day he was born.
Ho, there! Caesar comes!
Well, well, come on,
come on. Let's go to work.
Hold that letter to the Senate.
But the agreement with
the King's Prime Minister.
Destroy it.
Even I can't reach an
agreement with a corpse.
The Prime Minister is dead.
Then we deal with the King?
The Queen. Cleopatra is sole ruler of Egypt.
And I find that I shall be
here longer than I thought.
But the galley, Caesar, is ordered to sail.
When I say so.
A letter to Marc Antony, Rome.
Here, you're with me.
Nobody ever hears from him.
Except Marc Antony. He gets
a letter every week or so.
Is it true that Caesar is really
in love... Child, child.
But he doesn't come back to Rome, does he?
Well, he's missing a lovely party today.
He doesn't miss very much any day.
The Queen of Egypt gives parties, too.
You mean Cleopatra?
Whoa! What? Have you heard of Cleopatra?
Of course. All kinds of things. Is she black?
Calpurnia.
My lady.
How beautiful you are. Is there
anything I can get for you?
Yes, a little luck.
The loveliest party you've
ever given, Calpurnia.
Thank you, Flora. Wonderful.
The wife is always the last one to know.
So is the husband, when it comes to that.
They say he's planning
to move the capital to Egypt.
We were talking of the games.
Have you seen the new circus, Calpurnia?
I haven't been to the
games since Caesar left.
You should enjoy life more, Calpurnia.
Even Caesar's wife should play.
Why not? She's above suspicion.
We waited two hours for you
yesterday. What kept you?
Oh, I'm sorry. I'll explain it later.
When is Caesar coming back? Ever?
Tullius, I'm so sorry to hear
about your brother's exile.
I shall ask a pardon for
him when Caesar returns.
I hope he grants it.
If Caesar returns.
It's rumored all over Rome.
It's been known for days.
If what you say is true, Cassius...
we're in a desperate situation.
But I can't believe it.
It is true, Brutus.
I heard with my own ears.
Quiet, Casca. Let Brutus speak.
The people love you, Brutus.
They love Caesar.
But he would make himself king.
And then, where are we?
If I had proof of that...
He plans to divorce
Calpurnia and marry a queen.
This Cleopatra.
And call himself King of Rome. Of us.
Emperor of the world.
Was I not born as free as
Caesar? And you? And you?
Caesar.
He's everywhere.
Rome is a republic.
It wants no crown.
It will have no king.
Octavia. Hello, dear.
Hello, dear. Hello, Octavian.
Oh, it's a delightful party.
Sit down with us a moment.
Where's Antony?
Does any wife ever
know where her husband is?
Calpurnia knows where her husband is.
Sit down just for
a minute. You look tired.
Just for a minute.
No news at all from Caesar, eh?
I don't expect any. He's too busy, Octavian.
Well, he shouldn't be
too busy to write to me.
He writes to Marc Antony.
Why Antony and not me?
Why? Tell me why.
Wouldn't you think he'd know the last
people you write to are relatives?
But I'm more than Caesar's
nephew, I'm his heir.
You're my brother, and Marc's my
husband. I know you both pretty well.
And if I were Caesar, I would
certainly write to Marc Antony.
Ho, there! Marc Antony comes!
Oh, Marc Antony's here!
Wait, wait, wait. I have news.
News?
Another letter from Caesar?
More than a letter. Caesar is entering Rome.
Caesar is entering Rome!
Marc Antony, please. I
must see you for one day.
No, no, not now. I came to get Calpurnia.
Slave. Take them.
Did you all hear? Yes.
Well, well, and who is this pretty maid?
Hello, darling.
"Hello, darling"?
You'd think she had met me
before. Or is it my fame she seeks?
Oh, he hasn't been to bed. He always
talks like this when he hasn't...
Sleep. I'm above sleep, my beloved wife.
I'm glad you're above something.
Ah, in his usual gay mood.
But, come on. We must
hurry. You ready, Calpurnia?
I'm not going. Sorry?
I shall wait for my husband here.
What's the matter? Nothing.
Oh, yes, there is. There's
a great deal the matter.
And I'm in no hurry to watch
Caesar's triumphal entry into Rome.
Why, what's the matter with you?
Do you take us all for fools?
Don't you think we know
what Caesar plans to do?
And what does Caesar plan to do?
Well, go and listen to him
in the Senate tomorrow...
and you'll learn what he plans to do.
We don't have to. It's no music
to our ears to hear him desert us.
He's drunk with Egypt, and he's deserting us.
Antony! Antony! No! Octavian, no!
Antony...
I know.
There he is! There he is!
Caesar! Hail! Hail, Caesar!
I thought she gave money.
Her dress is all gold.
She's too gorgeous.
In the shape of a sphinx.
But she is beautiful. She is.
Oh, I don't know.
Oh, but look
at all those chariots!
Caesar.
Beware the Ides of March.
One date is as
good as another for a funeral.
Beware.
You may go now. We need nothing more.
Well, Brutus, was I right
about... Be careful.
Must we whisper what all Rome growls?
Yes, I believe.
Now that I know he's divorcing
Calpurnia to marry her.
That might be his private affair...
but tomorrow he'll force the Senate
to declare him Emperor and King.
And present Cleopatra to them as... Queen.
Our Queen, Brutus. Our Queen.
No, Rome cannot be turned
into another Orient...
with golden thrones for a king and queen.
But I suppose he'll sway
the Senate as he always has.
Oh, no, he won't.
We'll greet Caesar before
he greets the Senate...
and a little blood will be spilled for Rome.
So today you go before the Senate to...
Well, all I can say is I
think it's your first mistake.
All I can say is I don't care what you think.
You always did care what I thought.
You always agreed.
Ah.
I don't hate women for nothing.
Enobarbus speaks. And speaks well.
What's this?
Antony hates women, too?
Out of their place, I do.
They've no place amongst men.
They can't think, and they can't
fight. They're just playthings for us.
Most of them. All of them.
A woman's a woman.
We speak freely to you
because we are your friends.
I know that.
You say that the whole idea of
this marriage to Cleopatra...
is to capture India and then the
world. Does that sound like you?
When did you ever ask anyone's help?
Anything you wanted, you took.
It'll be easier to take it this way.
Well. Easier.
A strange word from Caesar.
Women soften all men.
He sounds like a lover talking.
An Egyptian lover.
That woman's making an Egyptian out of you.
You bring Egyptian ships
and men back with you.
You change the calendar of Rome to Egypt's.
But you cannot make an Egyptian
queen a ruler over Romans.
Words.
Look at the Roman eagle with
half the world in his claws...
tamed by a woman.
I'm leaving for the Senate.
But, Caesar, you... Are you coming, Antony?
No, I'll take no part in it.
Any man who wants to make a
fool of himself over a woman...
can do so, as far as I'm concerned.
I don't know what the young man
means, but he means it violently.
And I agree with him.
Then you'd better follow him.
Caesar! Caesar!
Oh, Caesar.
Oh, you haven't gone.
Don't go! Oh, don't go.
Don't go. Calpurnia.
I've had a dream, a terrible vision.
I saw a flaming star falling, and
it was you, your body dripping blood.
I saw your toga torn by daggers, wet
with blood, your blood, my husband.
Oh, please, please don't
leave this house today.
It's an evil omen. I know it. I know it.
Calpurnia, my dear...
the world's affairs cannot be
stopped because you've had a dream.
Casca the Senator.
Caesar. Caesar, the Senate waits for you.
No, no, no. You shall not
go. I'll keep you here.
Calpurnia has seen a day of
evil for me in her dreams.
Perhaps...
Shall I return and tell the Senate, which
waits to offer you the world's crown...
that they must wait until
Calpurnia's dreams are pleasanter?
I'll come. Oh, no, no, Caesar. I beg you.
Not for myself but for you.
Oh, please, please, Caesar.
Evil is on every
side. I know it. I know it.
For what I have done, Calpurnia, pardon.
For what I am about to do, courage.
No. No!
The swan's feather.
Iras, be careful.
I'm trying to keep my hand from shaking...
but, Majesty, I'm so excited.
Majesty. Majesty.
Royal robes for the Empress of the world.
Up the stairs.
Before the Queen.
And, Majesty, wait until you see
them. They're beautiful, marvelous.
Take the lid off.
Beautiful!
The Roman Senate will get a thrill today.
Choose, Majesty.
It's not the Senate I'm worried
about but their fat wives.
Here.
Do you know anything
about senators, Charmion?
Well, we only got here yesterday, Majesty.
Caesar! My sandals.
Hail, Caesar! Caesar comes!
I only stopped for a last salute.
Oh, no, wait just a minute. There's
something I want to tell you.
Too late, my love. And
get dressed. Get dressed.
I'll be ready. But the Senate is waiting.
Let them wait. I want a
moment all alone. But...
No, put your arms around
me. Hold me close to you.
I'm frightened of something.
Frightened? What's the matter?
I love you so much.
And that frightens you?
Nothing must happen to you, my Caesar.
Nothing will.
I'll send for you the
moment my speech is done.
You must be ready.
Emperor! Empress!
He passes here.
Tullius. Decimus.
Solinus.
Casca. You, there.
Brutus, beside the column.
Listen!
He must be just arriving.
How long will the speech take?
He's sending for me right after.
You'll be ready. And how you'll look.
Do you think you might wear this
dress when you get married, too?
What?
I was just thinking of the
great Caesar trying to unhook it.
Charmion.
Listen. Listen to the cheers now.
Hail! Hail, Caesar!
Hail, Caesar! Caesar, hail!
Caesar, I warned you. The Ides of March.
The Ides of March are here.
But not gone.
Caesar!
Caesar comes! Ah, Caesar.
A pardon, Caesar, for my
brother in exile. Denied.
You tyrant! Stand back!
Take your hands off me!
Let me get out of here!
Get off me!
You! You, too, Brutus!
A great day for Rome.
Am I all right? Marvelous.
Beautiful. The senators' eyes
will pop right out of their heads.
Caesar is dead! What?
Caesar is dead!
Caesar is a traitor to Rome!
His speech is over. It must
be. I hear the shouting.
Apollodorus, has the messenger come?
Not yet.
I never saw anything so beautiful.
Let me show you.
How do you like this?
Gorgeous.
Or do you like this?
I am only a man. How can I tell?
The Queen! The
Queen! Where's the Queen?
Stand! Stand!
Stop! Stop!
Caesar has been murdered!
Royal Egypt, Caesar is dead.
How was this? By whom?
I don't know, but I heard
them cry, "Brutus! Cassius!"
As I galloped through the
streets, I heard them shout:
"Caesar is a traitor to Rome!"
Where is he? Where is Caesar?
Dead, Majesty.
The body lies at the foot of Pompey's statue.
No one will touch it.
I will.
Majesty, you cannot.
No, my Queen. No.
Majesty! Majesty!
They come this way. They
cry for Egypt's blood!
Man the small boat at the foot of the garden.
## Come, my Queen.
Come. We must go. We must
escape. They will kill you.
Think of Egypt.
"Think of Egypt"?
Always Egypt!
But Caesar is dead.
My Emperor.
That dream is gone.
Gone.
Yes, gone.
What do I care for empire now?
Caesar is dead. My lover is dead.
He didn't love you.
You lie! You lie! You lie!
Majesty.
It wasn't in his arms
he wanted to hold Egypt.
It was in his treasury.
It's true.
You were blind.
He didn't love you.
Blind.
Antony. Always Antony.
Sit down, Octavian. Sit down.
That's all I do, sit.
Well, then sit down. I won't sit down!
See, he can't even sit
down. Antony, Octavian.
Caesar dead only two weeks, and you
fill his house with your quarrels.
The Senate has decreed that you
both shall rule Rome together...
and that Antony shall avenge the
death of Caesar upon the traitors...
and shall punish Egypt.
But why Antony? I'll govern
with you if I have to.
But if there's any fighting
to be done, I'll do it alone.
Alone. You want to do everything alone.
You took advantage of Caesar
lying on his funeral pyre...
to gain the public's support for yourself.
You used my uncle's dead
body to win control...
holding up his bloodstained
toga like any playactor...
to make the crowd cheer you.
You, with your, "Friends,
Romans, countrymen. "
That's enough! Steady.
I accept the Senate's order. Good.
And you, Octavian?
Oh, I suppose so.
And how do you propose to punish Egypt?
I shall write a letter
to the Egyptian Queen...
demanding that she meet me in
the public square in Tarsus.
A letter? The great Marc Antony
fights with friendly notes.
Really, Octavian, you
must... No, it's all right.
Octavian's right, for once.
It will be a friendly note.
Well, but I don't
understand. Friendly?
I see.
She will think the meeting
a friendly discussion...
on Roman and Egyptian affairs.
Yes.
Instead, my legions will be with me in
Tarsus on our way to take Egypt by force.
From Tarsus, I shall send
Cleopatra to Rome in chains.
That's more
like the real Marc Antony.
We're approaching Tarsus.
Are we?
And no plans yet, Cleopatra.
If you fail, it means slavery
for Egypt and death for you.
If you had listened to me, at least
we'd have ships and men with us.
Where do we meet Marc Antony?
In the public square at noon.
Well, why doesn't she
come? How should I know?
Where are the two generals
you sent to bring her?
Waiting for her, I suppose, like
you and me and the whole Roman army.
Waiting for a woman. A woman!
Six hours. While you
stand here and do nothing.
Go and get her.
Well, it's about time.
What? Apologize!
I apologize.
Watch your tongue, or I'll
cut it out of you! Wait here.
I'll go down to her boat and get her myself.
Stop there!
Who nears the Queen's barge?
I'm Antony of Rome.
You're late.
Where are my men?
Oh, Charmion.
Where are the Romans who
came here today? Do you know?
They're sleeping, my Queen.
Sleeping? What for?
They're... Well, I should
say they were a little tired.
You mean a little drunk!
No, awfully drunk.
Come and see.
Get someone to fling them ashore.
We'll go now. Get ready.
Were you speaking to me? Who do you think?
I sent orders for you to come to the
square. I'm not used to being disobeyed.
And why should I obey you? Your letter
said we had things to talk about.
The letter said that we would meet
in the public square in Tarsus...
and that's where we're going.
Oh.
We can't talk here then?
No, we cannot talk here.
Talk? With all this?
Oh, how different from your generals.
Well, I guess I must confess everything.
I must tell you why I wanted to
meet you here instead of the square.
Well?
Do you see the way I'm dressed?
What about it?
I'm dressed to lure you, Antony.
You see all this? It was
all a plan. And you know why?
Because it was my only chance.
Don't you think I know you're my
enemy, you and your hungry Rome?
But I suppose it was the most
stupid thing I could have done.
Why, do you know I had show after
show with which to dazzle you?
But Antony is not a man to be
dazzled if he doesn't please. No.
What do you care for this, for instance?
Watch.
I wish you could see your face. Huh?
I'd have more chance with a stone wall.
Will you forgive me for being such a fool?
I should have known that Antony
is not Antony for nothing.
Well, shall we go now?
Yes, we'll go. My wits have
failed, and I'm in your hands.
But what could I do? No,
what would you have done?
Pretend you're me and I'm you.
No, no. No, no. You're
Cleopatra and I'm Antony.
Do I look like that?
Well, do I?
I think you'd better stay as Cleopatra.
Oh, no, no. Don't drink that. No,
that was part of the plan, too.
I was going to get you so irresponsible.
You didn't think one
goblet would do it, did you?
Yes, wouldn't it?
Well, that does amuse me.
But it's such a large goblet.
Yes, isn't it?
Well.
I hope that you know that I
know you want me to do this.
Dear Antony, I hope you think
I know that you know I know.
Oh.
No, we're not dining here after all.
No, wait.
What is it? Reed birds from the Nile.
Are they any good? Oh,
they're supposed to be.
There's not very much to it,
is there? Then we may dine here?
I'm really very hungry.
So am I, when it comes to that.
Your little reed birds aren't enough for me.
No, wait, Antony.
Clams from the sea. They're
catching them now. Come and see.
Jewels.
You are a good fisherman.
The golden streams of Egypt never run dry.
Throw them.
Roman dogs.
Yes, Egyptian cats.
# Starlit night #
# Let enchantment bright #
# Weave a spell on him #
# Whom I love #
# Grant me the heart I crave #
# Hear the prayer of thy slave #
# Isis #
# Great Queen of Night and love #
# Hear thy slave #
# Hear thy slave ##
A song to the stars.
They must think we're funny people...
scheming to destroy each other
as if we had forever to live.
They must wonder:
"Why don't Egypt and Rome
meet in the public square...
"to plan union instead of conquest?"
Yes, it's very funny.
I said things to Caesar I wish I hadn't.
Oh?
There's beauty in the Egyptian
Queen besides her face.
Do you miss him?
No, he didn't love me.
Is that really the reason?
No, not really. I admire
men who don't love women.
What do you mean by that?
Oh, I don't know.
Women should be but toys for
the great. It becomes them both.
To you for that.
Oh.
And to you for that.
Why, Antony. What?
Did I hear you hiccup?
Not me. I never hiccup.
Well, it certainly wasn't
me. Queens don't hiccup.
Well, I don't know whether they do
or not. They most certainly do not.
Queens only talk of stars.
Well, who do you suppose it can be?
Because I'm sure I heard something.
It's somebody under the couch. Ah.
Come out. Come out!
They're gaining.
I'm very much afraid it's the
Queen of Egypt who's hiccupping.
Oh, but doesn't that
seem a little absurd? Yes.
I'll stop them for you.
Don't you ever have hiccups, Antony?
No, not tonight, I don't.
Does it hurt? Oh, no, not a bit.
Well, it did it, didn't
it? Oh, yes, it did it.
What would happen if you hit me like this?
I'd knock your head off.
And it would go rolling
down the deck into the river.
Wouldn't even touch the deck.
You're charming.
All right, I'm ready to go now.
Why? Oh, you don't find me charming.
Yes, I do.
I could fall in love with
you, but I don't intend to.
What for?
Do you mean that?
There's no one like you.
Octavian! Octavian!
Hail! Hail, Octavian!
Your cheers at last!
And they can only mean that
at last you agree with me...
that Marc Antony is a traitor to Rome.
Antony's a
traitor! A traitor, I tell you!
Two months, two long months have
come and gone, and what has happened?
Nothing! Not a thing!
Has he attacked Egypt with his legions there?
No! No!
Has he brought Cleopatra back in chains?
Has he done anything?
No. Nothing.
Yes, he's done one thing,
and that completely.
He's sailed to Egypt with the Queen...
and lived there ever since
with no thought of Rome.
He's forgotten Rome.
Who is this poisonous
snake that wrecks our men?
Caesar first, and now Antony.
When will it end? I'll tell you when!
Now! Now!
This time it's my turn. There
will be no more talk of war.
There will be war! War!
No more shining words, but shining steel!
Rome will be paid with Antony's blood...
and the Egyptian snake will be
destroyed, and there shall be war!
War! War! War! War!
What? I never can believe it.
What? I should want to leave you right now.
Why should you?
For a little while, I should.
Why? So that you won't tire of me.
Aren't you afraid I might tire of you?
No.
I should want to go out and
get drunk with a lot of men.
Or find another woman.
Well, why don't you?
Because you are another woman.
New. Always new.
Completely new.
Majesty! Majesty!
Majesty!
What is it?
King Herod has arrived.
Had you forgotten? No, no. Where is he?
He's waiting in the audience
chamber. I beg of you. Hurry, Majesty.
Come now, what's the hurry? Oh, please.
What do you care for the king of Judea?
But he's my guest. Oh, now, be a good
boy and stop frowning. I have to dress.
All right, but kiss me first.
Now run along.
Welcome.
I hope to renew an old
friendship. I hope so, too.
Well, time has made you older and wiser.
And me younger and more beautiful.
And any news? News, indeed.
I come directly from Rome
on my way to Judea. Ah.
Yes, directly from Rome.
As a friend and ally of Rome?
And as a friend and ally of Egypt.
And the news?
If you'll dismiss your court, I...
Charmion.
Well?
For the moment, I'm tongue-tied
before so much beauty.
The news. The news.
You go to great length for
the sake of Egypt, don't you?
You know, I...
I wonder how far you would go, really.
Octavian doesn't like Antony...
but Octavian is in power now.
If Antony were dead...
Octavian would be a very
good friend and ally of Egypt.
He told me to give you that message.
Oh.
I thought you were a friend of Antony.
I am. I am.
I always said there was no man in the
world that could drink with Antony...
but not now.
But listen... No, no, no.
My friend, when a man is drunk with love...
he can't divide his
concentration with wine, you know.
All major emotions are greedy.
And tell me, my friend, aren't you
happier with her than with a grape?
Or anything else.
I'm mad about her.
Of course you are, my boy. Of
course. That reminds me of something.
Something very funny, too, that I
heard recently in Rome from Octavian.
Octavian? It must have been funny.
It was, Antony. It was.
Listen, this is what he said.
If Cleopatra would poison Antony...
Rome would forgive her for everything,
and that would be the salvation for Egypt.
Poison me?
Uh-huh. Poison you.
Just imagine, Cleopatra poisoning you.
What did I say? Isn't it funny?
It's the funniest thing I've ever heard.
As if love didn't conquer
all. As if it didn't.
Poison me? I can't wait to
tell her! How she'll laugh.
I'll go and tell her. I'll be right back.
Yes, do that, Antony. Do tell her, please.
She...
You poison me!
You must for Egypt.
Egypt.
Now you ask me to do murder for Egypt.
I can't. I can't.
It's only one life against
the freedom of your people.
You don't love him.
What's your crime?
Murder. I killed my wife
and child while I was drunk.
What punishment has been decreed?
Crucifixion.
How long will it take
you to die on the cross?
I am strong, Majesty.
Two days. Maybe three.
Would you like to die in three seconds?
Majesty, you're merciful.
Take this.
Drink it.
Was there any pain?
A little, a very little.
There must be no pain.
What's this? The Queen is testing poisons.
A wine we've never had before,
dear Antony. I've been saving it.
What for?
For a night when the mood strikes.
I see.
And tonight is that night?
Tonight.
Now, can you think of a pretty toast?
It would please me very much.
You're very gay.
And you're very solemn. Is there any reason?
I'm thinking.
Evidently.
Well, let's drink first.
Perhaps pretty words will follow.
But you don't drink.
Neither do you.
I don't wish to drink alone.
And I don't think I wish to drink at all.
Well...
he is in a strange mood tonight.
Now tell me, what's the matter?
Oh. For some reason, I've...
I've no thirst tonight.
I'd far prefer just to
sit and watch you drink.
You really mean that?
Yes, I do.
If that's what you prefer, I
always try to please you, Antony.
Oh, my dear.
The strangest man on the face of the earth.
The happiest man on the face of the earth.
Come on. Let's drink.
Look, Antony. What?
The reed birds again.
Not much of a meal for a man. These
things get smaller and smaller.
Do you remember the stars?
Yes, and the river.
And the rose. When I put it in
your hair, and you were Cleopatra.
Yes, and I threw it back at you.
And I sweetened your wine with it.
That was a night.
Let's drink to the river.
To the river.
Majesty. What is it?
A carrier pigeon from Rome.
Rome has declared war.
War? Let me see that.
Octavian declares me a traitor, eh?
Octavian!
Octavian to meet me!
I'm laughing now.
Go get Enobarbus. Send him here.
I take orders only from my Queen. What?
Now, get up and get him!
You keep out of this!
Another word from you, and I'll
smash you to powder. Now, get him!
All Egyptians, eh? I need Roman soldiers now.
You, get my 10 generals
and send them to me at once.
Yes, my lord. Well, jump to it!
Maps. My maps. Yes, lord.
You, get my war chests.
Yes, lord.
Send carrier pigeons to Ventilius
at Tarsus, Drusus at Athens...
and to my legions in Philippi...
to get under way at once and meet
me and my 10 legions at Actium.
Yes, lord. Slaves, bring tables!
Yes, and get chairs, chairs for my
generals! I need Roman soldiers now.
So I'm a traitor, am I? They'll
take that back on their knees!
And as for you and your Egypt,
take your choice: Rome or Antony?
It's
all the same to Antony.
Here, you! All right, set it down.
I want galleys tomorrow
morning to transport 10 legions.
Ten legions to Actium. Tomorrow morning?
Manned and equipped for six months' siege.
The legions will assemble
under my generals in the square.
Tomorrow morning? At dawn.
Now, get out.
What answer will you send Octavian?
Octavian?
Send that to Octavian!
I'm at war again! No!
Antony! Antony! What's the matter?
What is it?
At last, I've seen a god come to life.
I'm no longer a queen.
I'm a woman.
You choose me, Cleopatra, against the world?
Against the world.
Then we'll meet it.
We'll smash it to pieces, put it
together again, and call it ours!
War!
Ah, Enobarbus!
Come over here. I've my plans all ready.
A trap that Octavian will
fall into like a little mouse.
There'll be no war.
Why, what's happened? Disaster.
Disaster?
Yes, and for Octavian, complete disaster.
Where are my generals?
They're all here, Antony.
And can you blame them?
They're Romans. They won't
serve under an Egyptian queen.
They won't
fight for Egypt against Rome.
They have gone. They've
taken their legions with them.
Now they're Octavian's
generals, and you are alone.
There'll be no war.
There will be war! And
what will you fight with?
The Egyptian army against all of Rome?
If that's all we have
left, we fight with them.
We?
What?
I'm not here to fight with the Egyptian army.
I'm here to tell you that Rome
is still yours if you want her.
Rome will always love you, Antony.
All that Rome wants is your love in return.
And there's one way to prove that love.
One way, and overnight
Octavian will be forgotten...
and Rome will take back to her arms her hero.
One way. Well?
Say the word, and I'll plunge
that through a woman's heart.
And the report will be that you did it,
and Rome will take you back to her heart.
There's no room in Rome for Octavian and me.
You mean, there's not room
enough in your world...
for anything else but Cleopatra.
Yes. Yes, that's what I mean. Yes.
That's what you mean.
And you're the man I
once heard say to Caesar:
"They can't think. They can't
fight. They are playthings for us. "
No man can speak to me like that. Get out!
I'm getting out, but I'm
taking nothing of yours with me.
There's Brittany back.
And there's the campaign in Syria.
This, you've long forgotten.
When I saved your life.
And this...
when you saved mine.
And this... Put them back!
No!
Our long campaign together lies
with the plans on the floor.
The war goes on.
Is that all you have to say?
That's all.
Well.
Goodbye, Antony.
You, who might have been
the world's great man...
ends all for a woman.
For that, I give you the world's contempt.
But for what you might have been...
I give you my last salute.
So Rome would forgive and take you back?
And all they demand is for us to part.
Why don't they ask the sun
to fall right out of the sky?
Yes, we'll fight them.
We'll fight them all if
we have to fight alone.
Forward march!
Watch the cavalry!
Burn the boats! On fire!
So you've got it all, eh?
All my generals, all my
legions, all the Egyptians.
Everything I had on land and sea,
you've lured and brought away.
You've got it all. You've
got it all except me!
Come down and surrender.
You come up and get me!
Words. He fights to the last with words.
Words. All right, you listen to them.
I'll come down and fight you alone!
I can think of easier ways for you to die.
Well, if you're afraid,
I'll fight the lot of you.
One by one. Two by two.
And if that bores me, I'll
fight you three by three!
You've forgotten how
to fight! You've lost your army!
And if I decide to grant your request
and choose to be the first you meet...
what's the prize? The Egyptian Queen?
Wait! Shut up!
The Egyptian Queen is no man's prize.
She is a warrior of her
own and fights by my side.
Closer to the wall. Closer to the wall.
It's coming down.
Don't lower that bridge,
you fools! Put it up!
Closer to the bridge. He mustn't see us.
Put it up again, I say!
Majesty, did you see him on the wall?
He looked so... Oh, can't I tell him?
No! No. He wouldn't
believe I could help him...
but it's our last chance.
I've got to take it.
Forward.
Look, somebody's coming out.
Can you see who it is?
The olive branch! They're
carrying the olive branch.
The Queen of Egypt!
Look. Cleopatra. It is the Queen!
Cleopatra surrenders!
Cleopatra.
Come back. Come back.
Come back! Come back!
He couldn't even keep her!
She's a warrior, all
right, but she fights by our side!
Jump, Antony! Jump!
All you've got left now is the wall!
He can't keep his woman.
Where you going?
What's your hurry?
Wine. Bring me wine.
Look, this is Antony the Roman leader.
This is Antony at the square in Tarsus.
To send the woman back in chains,
then on to Egypt with marching men!
Here's to Antony!
My lord, can I...
Get out.
But Tarsus isn't here it seems.
Instead, a couch.
A couch to lie on.
A woman to give your
arms to instead of chains.
Antony, who can't think or fight.
Antony, the plaything of a woman!
And there is Egypt.
Yours.
All I ask is to save his life.
Spare him, and I promise
you'll never see him again.
I shall take him away, far up the Nile...
and leave with you Egypt.
I suppose of all the requests
that have ever been made...
yours is the most hopeless.
Spare Antony's life? I'd
sooner be dead myself.
And as for you, this time you
do go back to Rome in chains.
This time you face a man!
Take her away.
We can't do that, Excellence.
She came bearing the olive branch.
What's the difference? We've
only to smash the city's gates.
Oh, we'll smash the city's gates, all right.
But she must have safe conduct back.
We are Romans.
Oh, all right.
Go back and kiss him goodbye.
Thank you, soldier.
When you smash the gates...
you had better come in behind your men.
I failed, but there's still a way out for us.
I have horses waiting beyond
the passage to the tombs...
and a boat with trusted rowers
will take us to the upper Nile.
Antony, we can lose ourselves
there and still be happy.
Antony, listen.
I never wanted to see you again.
How deep does a man have to stab to die?
Antony!
Antony, what... No, no more Antony!
Antony's gone. You go back to Octavian.
He's the Caesar now.
You thought I went to him?
You... You thought that of me? Am I blind?
I went for your sake. I
went to plead for your life.
To plead, Antony.
I was pleading for your
life, and you were taking it.
Antony.
I am blind indeed.
I am dying, Egypt.
Dying.
Listen. There's little time.
Away from war in upper Egypt with
you would have been very sweet...
but this, this is a better end.
A Roman by a Roman conquered.
No, no, no. Don't pity me. Don't pity me.
We were born for war.
It was the soul of our love, and
we part at the top of our glory.
My precious Cleopatra, I'm happy.
The end is in your arms.
My love.
Take me away with you into the shadows...
as close as if you could
carry me in your arms.
I am taking you with me,
Egypt. I am taking you with me.
Forever.
Antony.
Hurry, Majesty. Hurry! They're at the doors.
Prepare me.
The Queen of Egypt goes
to meet the conqueror.
The doors are breaking.
Royal Egypt, let me die before I see
you go to Rome in chains, defeated.
I'm not going to Rome, Charmion.
Now, give me the basket.
It holds victory.
It works.
Little Iras.
Charmion.
Look well for love.
Look well.
And not finding it, give nothing.
But if blessed with Cleopatra's fortune...
give all.
Now, go.