And so it fell out
that at Pharsalia...
the great might and manhood of Rome
met in bloody civil war...
and Caesar's legions
destroyed those of the great Pompey...
so that now only Caesar
stood at the head of Rome.
But there was no joy for Caesar
as in his other triumphs...
for the dead which his legions
counted and buried and burned...
were their own countrymen.
The smoke of burning Roman dead
is just as black...
and the stink no less.
It was Pompey, not I,
who wanted it so.
Let what I have said be set down.
You may stand.
Do not try and impress me by looking
either too penitent or too proud.
As field officers,
you fought miserably for Pompey.
Men under your command will be
permitted to enlist in my legions...
and returned to Rome as Romans.
You shall have the same privilege.
I'm not magnanimous. Your names
are marked. You'll be watched.
First sign of treachery,
you'll be killed.
What is it, Flavius? Antony?
Oh, yes. Canidius.
With news of Pompey, I hope.
- Hail Caesar!
- Drink that in my name, Canidius.
To all Marc Antony's cavalry,
Caesar's left wing and right arm.
What news of Pompey,
or what's left of him?
Pompey's gone, Caesar.
Slipped through our fingers,
disguised as a peddler.
- Leaving most of his merchandise.
- Gone? Where?
He has a galley waiting at the coast.
Provision enough for Egypt, they say.
Egypt. Possibly.
They owe him a great deal.
He'll ask for sanctuary.
Borrow money, borrow time.
I thought it was over.
It seems it's not.
Rufio, consult the augurers.
I want to know.
In Egypt, will Pompey face me at last?
But surely Caesar will now
return to Rome!
I must go to Egypt in any case.
Young King Ptolemy and his sister
have a civil war of their own...
intent on destroying each other,
and in the process, Rome's wheat.
That cannot be so urgent.
Let the Romans welcome
great Caesar properly at last...
in this greatest of his triumphs.
Triumph? Over what?
Over whom?
- Canidius.
- Caesar?
Leave me the 10th and 12th.
Antony's to take the rest to Rome.
- When can he start?
- Whenever you say.
Then at once.
And in Rome,
Marc Antony is to speak for Caesar.
His authority is not to be questioned.
His word will be yours.
As always, Caesar's word is law.
Of course.
But remind him to keep his legions
intact. They make the law legal.
Caesar.
And even as Caesar's galleys
sailed the great sea to Egypt...
it was happening that,
just as the Romans...
so the Egyptians made war,
one upon the other...
for young King Ptolemy would no longer
share the throne...
with his sister Cleopatra...
but drove her
from the city of Alexandria...
and sought to destroy her.
We've arrived on their market day.
Once a week they're allowed
in the royal enclosure.
Where's the guard of honor for Caesar?
Some representative
of the royal or military?
We have the privilege of watching
Caesar battle through our marketplace.
Marcellus, a dozen front-rank men,
swords only.
Clear a direct line
to the palace steps.
Then as many more to keep it open.
It's precisely what they hope we'd be stupid
enough to do: manhandle their people.
No. This is their market day,
we will go marketing.
- You're not serious.
- We'll shop our way to the palace.
Have you my money?
Everything is to be paid for by coin.
Tell them to put away the swords
and carry moneybags.
Olives. Oil of olives.
The wine of Samos.
How much for your wine? Four drachma.
Sixty of your wine for my men.
Pay him.
You said they'd push the people
and make them angry.
Why aren't they doing
what you said they'd do?
Your king has asked a question,
Lord Chamberlain.
The Romans have degenerated minds,
Most High Majesty.
They do the unexpected.
Particularly one Roman.
Master of the unexpected.
But with so few men.
You all look so impressive.
Any one of you could be king.
His Divine Majesty, my Lord Ptolemy...
lord of the Upper
and Lower regions...
son of Ra, of Horus and of Thoth,
beloved of...
Et cetera, et cetera. You welcome me.
And I, Gaius Julius Caesar,
Pontifex Maximus...
et cetera, et cetera, thank you.
From the Senate and people
of Rome, hail King Ptolemy.
And his sister and co-ruler,
Queen Cleopatra?
They won't tell you so,
but Cleopatra's dead.
She tried to kill me,
and we chased her into the desert.
And there she died.
Whereas it is true
that His Majesty's sister...
repeatedly plotted
to have him killed...
it is not true
that Cleopatra is dead.
Whereas it is true that she
fled from Alexandria...
I seem to always interrupt you...
but the search for truth
can go on and on.
Pothinus, is it not?
Lord Chamberlain and chief eunuch
to King Ptolemy. An exalted rank.
Obtained not without certain,
shall we say, sacrifice.
Theodotus, am I right?
Tutor to His Majesty in history,
philosophy and ambition.
And Achillas.
They say you're a good soldier.
- As one to another, where is Cleopatra?
- With her army.
And how many of your men
between her and Alexandria?
- Enough.
- May I speak?
Surely you have come in peace.
And we present ourselves to you
in warm and respectful welcome.
Our only problem being an
internal one, of concern only to us...
why have you come, Caesar?
As we all know, when the father
of both Ptolemy and Cleopatra died...
he named the two of them
to rule jointly over Egypt.
Rome was appointed their guardian
and the executor of his will.
I have come in the name of Rome to ask
why Cleopatra has been deposed...
to resolve the differences
between her and King Ptolemy...
and to see that they peacefully
resume their joint rule of Egypt.
That will be difficult.
Cleopatra has forfeited her right.
I shall try to decide justly.
Don't you see he'll send for her?
He'll bring her back!
The sun which sheds its grace
upon the ruler of the two lands...
burns too brightly perhaps.
If Lord Ptolemy wishes to retire...
I wish nothing of the kind!
I won't be put out of the way
until I've watched you give him that!
A thousand pardons,
I had almost forgotten.
Lord Ptolemy wishes to enhance his
welcome by a gift of some importance.
Most generous.
The ring. Give him Pompey's ring.
And now the token of
His Majesty's affection for Rome...
and regard for Caesar.
Pompey the Great.
Dead men, they say, do not bite.
Does it please you, Caesar?
They said it would
please you very much.
The sun does shed its grace
too brightly.
It has become too hot here for kings.
My Lord Ptolemy will retire.
For His Majesty,
a Roman guard of honor.
It was not by your hand, of course.
If, as you say, you've been told
of me, you know better, Caesar.
My men shall be
properly housed and fed.
- May I speak?
- Not until you're spoken to.
I'll require rooms in the palace.
I shall consider myself
honored to escort you.
Anyone but you.
Find the rest of Pompey.
Tear out a thousand tongues,
but find him.
Have him purified...
the coin in the mouth
and the rest, honorably.
Of course.
For now, this is what we must hold.
Moon gate and three others.
Here, here and here.
How are we placed?
The 10th slingers on the moon gate.
The rest in reserve.
The 12th holding all other positions.
Very thin.
For now, deep enough.
- Have we tested the wells?
- The water's brackish, but drinkable.
So far. Keep an eye on them.
Watch the corn and wheat.
With our supplies secure,
we can hold indefinitely.
For a week, perhaps.
For the time being, time enough.
What do you want?
Is the man to be trusted?
Seems someone's brought me a gift...
from Queen Cleopatra.
Apparently, a rug peddler.
Flavius doubts it.
He seems to know the palace very well.
He appeared through a secret passage
which none of the men knew.
Pothinus might send an assassin
in Cleopatra's name.
Have the man brought in.
Are you the one
who brings a gift from Cleopatra?
Put it down and go.
It is the command of my queen
I deliver her gift personally.
I am Caesar. Lay it here before me.
Forgive me, Admiral Agrippa,
but you're not Caesar.
Nor you, General Rufio.
Nor you, Germanicus.
My queen's gift is for
the eyes of Caesar...
alone.
- It seems harmless enough.
- No, Caesar!
You can lend me your sword, Rufio.
It may require some cutting.
Odd way to carry a rug.
Isn't it easier
to sling it over your shoulder?
It was less comfortable that way.
- For you or the rug?
- That sword, Caesar.
The rug is such a delicate weave.
If I may untie it for you.
Turn it over first.
- But the rug is right-side up.
- I want it the wrong side up.
- Should I flip it over with my sword?
- No, no, no.
I find one can tell more
about the quality of merchandise...
by examining the back side first.
All hail Cleopatra,
kindred of Horus and Ra...
beloved of the moon and sun,
daughter to Isis...
and of Upper and Lower Egypt,
queen.
Thank you.
Here.
Take this to the captain
of the night watch.
He'll see the queen's quarters
are made ready to her.
Stay where you are.
- Have I dismissed you?
- No, Your Majesty.
This is my palace, Caesar.
All of it
is available to me at my will.
I am not your prisoner.
If anything, you are my guest.
Most kind.
And as for having my quarters,
as you put it, made ready...
my chief handmaiden has, by now,
brought the others out of hiding.
They should almost be finished.
Impossible.
The doors are under guard.
There are doors, and doors.
Oh, yes. Of course.
You must take me on a tour someday
within the walls of your palace.
- What are you waiting for?
- Permission to leave.
Granted.
Apollodorus.
Thank you.
I'm pleased you received my summons
and were able to...
Summons? I'm pleased to say
I received nothing of the kind.
I'm surprised you thought
I would answer one.
Young lady, the voyage
in your non-magic carpet...
has apparently not tired you,
but I'm exhausted.
Caesar, it is essential
we understand each other.
Only through me
can you hope to escape...
the desperate situation
in which you find yourself.
I wouldn't bite into that.
Did you bring it with you?
Have you had it tasted?
If neither, it's probably poisoned.
At least it's another way out of the
desperate situation in which I'm found.
You're being tolerant of me,
aren't you?
Is it because you're so much older?
Your maps are inferior.
Out-of-date, compared to mine.
They and I have aged together.
The lakes to the west
are poorly marked...
certain important hill positions
not even noted.
I must arrange for you to address
my mapmakers and general staff.
We've gotten off to a bad start,
haven't we?
I've rubbed you the wrong way.
I'm not sure I want to be
rubbed by you at all, young lady.
It is permissible
for me to sit, is it not?
As quickly as possible you must
set me alone on the throne of Egypt.
My mission is to put to an end the tiresome
squabbling between your brother and you.
You're not a fool. Or are you?
Immodestly, perhaps, no.
You've seen my brother
and listened to him?
And that truly evil man
to whom he belongs?
Yes.
Shall we agree upon what Rome
really wants...
has always wanted of Egypt?
Corn, grain, treasure.
It's the old story.
Roman greatness built
upon Egyptian riches.
You shall have them.
You shall have them all and in peace.
But there is only one way.
My way. Make me queen.
That sounds very much
like an ultimatum.
There is no other way.
For one whose assets,
up to a few moments ago...
was a devoted slave
and a rolled-up carpet...
But I have you now, Caesar.
Besides, there are my armies...
and the simple fact that
no mortal hand can destroy me.
Yes, I recall some
mention of an obsession...
you have about your divinity.
Isis, is it not?
I shall have to insist
that you mind what you say.
I am Isis. I am worshiped
by millions who believe it.
Do not confuse what I am...
with the so-called divine origin...
that every Roman general acquires
together with his shield.
It was Venus you chose to be
descended from, wasn't it?
I must now do a little
insisting of my own.
First, your journey has tired you
and you wish to retire.
I am not your servant, Caesar.
Do not dismiss me.
Secondly, you have no armies,
young lady.
They are gone because
you could not pay them.
Egypt's riches are not
available for your own use...
much less to give away.
Perhaps in a day or two...
- ...we can speak again.
- That may be too late...
for both of us.
Your safety will be
my responsibility.
And what about your own?
I am prepared, I believe,
for the time being.
I hope so.
I hope you are as wise,
as brilliant...
the god they say you are.
You Roman generals
become divine so quickly.
A few victories, a few massacres.
Only yesterday, Pompey was a god.
- They murdered him, didn't they?
- Yes.
Because they thought
it would please you.
- It didn't, did it?
- No.
Today I found myself remembering
how much my daughter loved him.
She died trying
to bear him a son.
She gave him this ring.
Sleep well tonight, Caesar.
These next days may
be difficult for you.
Good night.
Germanicus, a guard to escort
Queen Cleopatra to her apartments.
Guards!
The corridors are dark, gentlemen.
But you mustn't be afraid.
I am with you.
Haven't we covered everything
we can tonight, sir?
- Perhaps a fresh start in the morning.
- No, a few more matters.
Rufio, has it occurred to you
that our maps of this area...
are not quite what they should be?
Why, no. What makes you
think they're not?
I have an instinct about these things.
Actually of Macedonian descent.
No officially-admitted Egyptian blood.
"Reputed to be extremely intelligent
and sharp of wit."
Queen Cleopatra is widely read.
Well-versed in the sciences...
and mathematics.
She speaks seven languages
proficiently.
"Were she not a woman, she'd be
considered an intellectual."
Nothing bores me so much
as an intellectual.
Makes a better admiral of you,
Agrippa.
Here's something
of more interest to the navy:
"ln obtaining her objectives, she has
been known to use torture, poison..."
and even her own sexual talents,
which are said to be considerable.
Her lovers, I am told, are listed
more easily by number than by name.
It is said that she chooses
in the manner of a man...
"...rather than wait to be chosen
after womanly fashion."
Well, there's more reason
than we thought...
for not wanting to leave
you two alone, eh, sir?
I'm sorry, I wasn't listening.
Are you inclined to trust Cleopatra?
Trust? Not for a minute.
"Trust." The word has always
made me apprehensive.
Like wine, whenever I've tried it,
the aftereffects have not been good.
So I've given up wine...
and trusting.
Oh, it's been a long
and difficult day, gentlemen.
The next few may be even longer
and more difficult.
- Good night.
Flavius!
It is autumn again, my best-loved Lesbia
Look, the torrents of Roman leaves
Are falling, falling
And lovers revive in kisses
The promise of spring
Which will end the winter world
With new nightingales calling
I taste your food, daughter of Isis...
and if there be harm in it,
let the harm fall upon me.
But love must bring
Despair one day
As beauty, sorrow
- Why do you stop, Phoebus?
- In the corridor, there is movement.
That's how the Romans
frighten the enemy...
- ...by stamping their elephant feet.
- No, this is one man...
followed by others.
- Caesar, I would say.
- Would you?
We must not disappoint
the mighty Caesar.
The Romans tell fabulous tales
of my bath...
and handmaidens...
and my morals.
Cleopatra's requested an audience
with me.
- That was yesterday, Caesar.
- I've been occupied.
The queen is occupied with her bath.
Perhaps Caesar could return later...
- ...or tomorrow.
- I'm afraid not. Hold him.
No, don't hurt him.
You're a good man, Apollodorus.
I hope you're appreciated.
Wait here for me.
Then let us live and love
Without one thought
For the gossip of virgins
Now grown old and stale
Suns go down and may return
But once put out
Our own brief light
We sleep through
One eternal night
An intruder! A man!
Oh, it's you.
You wanted to see me?
I summoned you yesterday...
to an audience in my throne room.
I was told I was not
permitted to go there.
It's too close to the quarters
occupied by your brother and the rest.
I will not be told where
I can go and where I cannot go!
Since there's nothing you want...
Except my throne!
At least you've dressed
properly for my presence.
Your best armor?
Almost, but I'm afraid
it's not being worn in your honor.
I know.
This morning, you paid a formal
visit to the tomb of Alexander.
You remained alone beside
the sarcophagus for some time.
I'd like to know how you know.
Just staring down at him.
And then you cried.
Why did you cry, Caesar?
That man recites beautifully.
- Is he blind?
- Don't you hurt him.
I won't. Not anyone
who speaks Catullus so well.
Catullus doesn't approve of you.
Why haven't you had him killed?
Because I approve of him.
My desire to please you, Caesar
Is very slight
Nor do I greatly care to know
If you are black or white
Achillas is moving
his entire army to Alexandria.
By tonight, he'll outnumber you
20-to-1, 30-to-1.
He'll have the royal enclosure
entirely surrounded.
Except to the sea.
Do you plan to sail away,
great Caesar?
Not for the time being.
Achillas may attack tomorrow,
the next day...
- ...whenever it suits him!
- Very probable.
In your wildest dreams, Caesar,
how can you possibly hope to hold...
the gates of this enclosure
against such odds?
And if you say once more,
"For the time being"...
My officers say anything
from a week to indefinitely.
What would you estimate?
Before you're without water...
without food...
your troops slaughtered,
picked off from the rooftops...
poisoned in the brothels?
A few days, Caesar.
At the most, a few days.
I'm inclined to agree with you.
Young man, do you know this
of Catullus?
Give me a thousand
And a thousand kisses
When we have many thousand more
We'll scramble them
And forget the score
So evil envy will not know
How high the count
And cast its evil eye
It couldn't have been
as pleasant in the throne room.
"My desire to please you, Caesar,
Is very slight..."
Be still!
Caesar, a word. It's important.
The Egyptian galleys in the harbor
have been taking on men and armaments.
- When will they be prepared?
- Tomorrow, with the morning wind.
Burn them tonight.
Their ships lie close to shore.
- The fire may spread to the city.
- Let's hope it doesn't.
I can't risk a blockade.
Remember, not before tonight.
Prepare as secretly as possible.
I need this day.
Good luck.
Why not before tonight, my lord?
Why does Caesar need this day?
I can't give you that information,
for the time being.
Flavius.
Here it is, Caesar. Just arrived.
The gods shouldn't
tantalize us so, Rufio.
It's even better than I'd hoped.
- Be on your way, you haven't much time.
- Hail Caesar.
It's called an epilepse because of the
arching caused by muscular spasms...
the contortions.
The early Greeks considered...
those who suffered from it
to be favored by the gods.
The great Alexander, they say...
had this falling sickness.
And, so they say,
the mighty Caesar too.
Your Majesty, forgive me.
Sosigenes, the library.
- What are you saying?
- The Romans set fire...
- ...to the Egyptian fleet.
- It's about time.
Come see for yourself.
The fire's spread to the city.
- The city?
- Just a few buildings...
but the library is burning.
The great library.
Aristotle's manuscripts.
The Platonic commentaries,
the plays, the histories.
The Testament of the Hebrew god.
The Book of Books.
- Wind blew into the merchant shipping.
- Four or five burned and sank right here.
- And our ships?
- Safe and dry.
Prisoners are surrendering in droves.
I need help.
- Not one man. I may need your sailors.
- Halt!
Take your hands off me!
You should attack my guards more
often. Battle seems to become you.
You grow more beautiful
each time I see you.
And you grow bolder.
And busier.
- Actually, we're extremely busy...
- Do you smell smoke?
We found it necessary
to burn the Egyptian fleet.
The ships were in the water.
Did you find it necessary
to burn them in the streets?
Merchant ships caught fire.
The burning masts fell.
Some houses...
One of them, the great
Library of Alexandria.
Yes, I've been told.
I'm extremely sorry.
- Now, if you don't mind, I must ask...
- I do mind.
Are you putting the fire out?
We're forming prisoners
into fire brigades.
Oh, I see. Romans only start fires,
is that it?
Have you broken out of your nursery
to come irritate the adults?
Another time, we're working.
- Shall we remove her for you, Caesar?
- Use that Roman genius for destruction.
Tear down pyramids, wipe out cities!
How dare you and the rest of your
barbarians set fire to my library?
Play conqueror all you want,
mighty Caesar.
Rape, murder, pillage thousands,
millions of human beings.
But neither you nor
any other barbarian...
has the right to destroy
one human thought!
Enough!
Leave me alone with her.
I will send for you when I finish.
It won't be long.
Swords? Javelins?
Or are you going to set me on fire?
The time has come for us
to understand each other.
Whatever else I may be, in your
opinion, first of all, I am Caesar.
And I am Cleopatra,
queen, daughter of Isis!
If I say so and when I say so,
you are what I say you are...
nothing more.
Hail Caesar!
You, descendant of inbred generations
of incestuous mental defectives...
- ...how dare you call anyone barbarian.
- Barbarian!
Daughter of a drunkard who
bribed his way to the throne.
- Your price was too high, remember?
- I've had my fill with you pretenders...
- ...parading on ruins of your past glories.
- Only the future concerns me.
- Keep out of my affairs, do as I say.
- Do as you say?
Literally?
As if I were something
you had conquered?
If I choose to regard you as such.
Am I to understand that you're free
to do with me whatever you want...
whenever you want?
Yes, I want that understood.
Won't you at least wear
your laurel wreath...
so I can be reminded it's
the divine Caesar that honors me so?
You talk too much.
I promise you...
you won't like me this way.
Caesar! An attack on the moon gate!
The moon gate.
An attack in force!
Those ballistas need eliminating.
Send out a turtle.
Form the turtle!
Now is the time for us to attack!
- No.
- We have a full legion in reserve.
We hold our positions here.
Two hours till dawn.
We'll hold where we are.
- And what happens at dawn?
- I thought you knew.
The sun comes up.
Tell the men they've won.
Liberty and wine
for defenders of the gate.
All reserves, cavalry, every man
available, move out behind Achillas.
- We have him in a vise.
- What is the other half of this vise?
Rufio and the armies of Mithradates.
He left last night to meet them.
Mithradates? How could
he get here this fast?
I sent him when we sailed for Egypt.
No general in his right mind can
hold Alexandria with two legions...
as you and others have repeatedly
pointed out to me.
I taste your drink,
daughter of Isis...
and if there be harm in it,
let the harm fall upon me.
Lotus.
You wiped the rim of the cup
after you tasted it. Why?
Why? So my mouth would not soil it.
Lotus...
taste it again.
Pothinus said he would have me killed.
Forgive me, Majesty.
Forgive me. Forgive me.
I forgive you.
Now drink it.
Apollodorus!
Great silence
for Gaius Julius Caesar...
consul of the senate
of the people of Rome.
You will all stand.
Let what is said be recorded...
as the judgment and decree
of the Senate and people of Rome.
There is no judgment here.
And the decree not Rome's,
but Cleopatra's.
She has lied to you, Caesar.
She and her slaves lie to you.
You have not been accused, Pothinus.
Thus far.
You are now charged with inciting and
abetting war against the Roman army.
You are now charged with plotting
to assassinate Queen Cleopatra.
You are guilty of both.
You are sentenced to death.
It's too bright in here.
Shut out some of the sun.
Are you going to kill me too, Caesar?
What am I accused of?
King Ptolemy is hereby removed
from the protective custody of Rome.
He'll leave within the hour...
and be conducted safely
to the camp of Achillas.
Achillas! You're going to send me
back to my own troops?
He is to be accompanied
by his learned tutor, Theodotus.
Do you hear that?
You'll be saved along with me.
Stop grinning, you little idiot.
May I speak?
You know that Achillas is trapped...
between your own legions
and the armies of Mithradates.
To send His Majesty to fight
them may mean his death.
An occupational hazard
for those who will be king.
But then certainly not I, Caesar.
I'm no king, nor general.
What do I know of war?
A simple scholar.
A man of thoughts and words.
Too many words. Enough.
Let all be done properly as decreed.
Flavius.
Find Apollodorus.
Return his dagger to him.
You might clean it first.
It has Pothinus all over it.
Yes, yes, I know I'm tired.
I promise I'll sleep.
You have my apologies
for what almost happened to you.
Caesar, will you talk with me
for just a minute?
Yesterday was full.
Tonight was long.
This morning has not been uneventful.
Did you know that Apollodorus
would kill Pothinus?
He was kind enough to wait until Rome
had passed sentence of death.
And my brother...
and Theodotus?
They too will be killed, possibly.
Probably.
Your Majesty, I'm truly weary.
You knew all along, didn't you,
that there was no real danger.
That Mithradates was on his way
to reinforce you.
Why didn't you tell me?
I said I was prepared.
You wouldn't believe me.
- I really must insist...
- I would've believed you.
- You didn't trust me.
- Not for an instant.
And yet, in these last few minutes...
you have made me undisputed queen.
The sole ruler of Egypt. Why?
Perhaps tomorrow, later in the day,
we could talk.
- Why, Caesar?
- It was best for Rome. Please.
- Best for Egypt.
- For Egypt too.
Cleopatra, get out.
I beg of you, get out.
That will not be needed.
It wasn't necessary
for me to betray myself.
I could have
called out for Flavius.
How many new spy-holes
have you dug in the walls?
Are we being watched even now?
If you see Flavius,
you might send him to me.
- Still trying to dismiss me?
- What is it you want?
- What more do you want?
- To be of help to you.
There never has been help.
There never will be.
Now there is.
One day it'll happen
where I cannot hide.
Where the world will see me fall.
I shall tumble down before the mob...
and foam at the mouth
and make them laugh.
And they'll tear me to pieces.
The gods themselves had your sickness.
Hannibal, even the great Alexander.
And in the end, they fell.
Were torn to pieces by the mob.
Not you.
I will see to that.
In the name of the Senate and the
people of Rome and by their will.
Isis herself would surrender her place
in heaven to be as beautiful as you.
You're not supposed
to look at me. No one is.
If they aren't looking,
how do they know I am?
You should be kneeling.
Would that do
before all these visiting kings?
Making believe
they're not watching us?
You have such bony knees.
Not only bony, but unaccustomed
to this sort of thing.
If we're to get an early start
in the morning...
What will it be tomorrow?
More wheat?
What I've seen already could feed
more legions than Rome ever had.
There's enough to feed the world.
More gold then.
Why not buy the world?
Surely you have enough.
At least enough to pay more legions
than even Rome has ever had.
More granite, more marble...
more millions of slaves
to build whatever needs building.
Better routes to India,
shorter routes to the East.
What can there be in Egypt
that I haven't seen?
Egypt itself. The reason for Egypt.
My responsibility is Rome.
Alexander understood it...
that from Egypt
he could rule the world.
He was very young.
And you, even younger.
At your age, such dreams have a
reality which grows less in time.
Caesar no longer dreams?
Dangerous to a man of my calling.
Necessary, I would have thought.
I can't stay away from Rome too long.
There are problems.
Messages from Marc Antony
endlessly demanding my return.
And on my way back, wars
to be fought in the east and north.
Even in Rome itself
I'm not without opposition.
Do to them
what you did to Achillas.
This is opposition
of a different sort.
They weave it cleverly, lightly,
like a cobweb.
You know what happens when cobwebs
are not regularly swept away.
Do you trust this Marc Antony?
If anyone in the world,
I trust Antony.
Let him brush away the cobwebs
for you and stay with me.
You've been declared
dictator for a year.
You can do what you want
with your time.
Everything but make it stand still.
If... When you return to Rome...
these wars that have to be fought
on the way, are they important?
Well, there's no such thing
as an unimportant war.
I've been reading in your commentaries
about your campaigns in Gaul.
How does my writing
compare with Catullus?
Well, it's different.
Dull.
Perhaps a little
too much description.
You're being tactful.
Some of my critics, Brutus, for one...
tell me my Latin is not only
ungrammatical, but common.
You spared his life more than once.
People say it's because
Brutus is your son.
Is that true?
I have no son.
- Calpurnia, your third wife...
- Fourth.
Married to you how long?
12 years?
And still, Caesar has no son,
no child at all.
It is well-known that
Calpurnia is barren.
A woman who cannot bear children...
is like a river that is dry.
I see no purpose in discussing
the subject further.
A woman, too, must make
the barren land fruitful.
She must make life grow
where there was no life.
Just as the Mother Nile feeds
and replenishes the earth.
I am the Nile.
I will bear many sons.
Isis has told me.
My breasts are filled
with love and life.
My hips are rounded
and well apart.
Such women, they say...
have sons.
That first time
when you stood here alone...
why did you cry?
Will you tell me now?
Because I had lost something.
- What?
- A lifetime.
- Mine.
- Nonsense.
Having conquered the world,
he died at 32.
I am 52.
My remaining ambition is to keep
the world from conquering me.
Your ambitions
must always have been his.
They still must be.
Shall I tell you something?
When I was 32 in Spain...
I came upon a statue of Alexander.
I wept then too.
Even then.
I want you to have his sword
to take back with you.
- Too deeply embedded.
- It can be removed.
It's buried in time.
- And Alexander's mantle?
- Too heavy for Caesar.
His dream then.
Make his dream yours, Caesar.
His grand design.
Pick it up where he left off.
Out of the patchwork of conquests...
one world.
And out of one world, one nation.
One people on earth living in peace.
So you have told me at last
what it is you want of me.
Of us!
At the center, the capital of this
world, one people, one nation...
Alexandria?
- He chose it.
- I am Roman.
He was Greek! What will it matter
when we're all one people?
I am 52. He was 32 and failed.
We will succeed.
Your dreams, your ambitions.
One lifetime is not enough
for such dreams, such ambitions.
The cloak of Alexander
cannot be too heavy...
for Rome and Egypt
to carry together.
And what if his sword
is too deeply embedded?
Yours will replace it, Caesar.
You have a way of mixing
politics and passion.
Where does one begin
and the other leave off?
That did not start,
nor will it end with me.
Cleopatra, whatever it is,
however it comes out...
leave me my destiny.
Your destiny
is no longer just yours.
It's mine too.
Soon, there will be someone to
carry both the cloak of Alexander...
and the sword of Caesar...
and the name of Caesar.
And in that name he will rule Egypt.
And whatever part or all
of the world that we give him...
our child...
will be a son for you, Caesar.
By Isis, I swear it.
Could you put off
your return to Rome...
just long enough?
I came as quickly as I could.
Antony is welcome to Caesar's house
as often and as quickly as he likes.
As Caesar's wife, before truth
is distorted into vicious gossip...
- I wanted you to hear...
- That my husband has married Cleopatra.
There's some fresh wine.
One of your many favorites.
The ceremony, according to vicious
gossip, was in the Egyptian religion.
Even if true, that can't be
taken seriously.
During which he was formally
declared an Egyptian god.
Officially divine, at last.
That must have pleased Caesar.
Calpurnia, we know Caesar, you and I.
This so-called marriage
has no validity under Roman law.
There must be political purpose to it.
Perhaps a symbolic ceremony
to ratify Rome's alliance with Egypt.
Perhaps merely
indulging some barbaric custom.
You've been loyal and kind.
You came as quickly
as you could.
Unhappily, vicious gossip
travels even faster than you...
and the truth.
Have you heard, for instance, that
Cleopatra is carrying Caesar's child?
Yes, Antony.
We know him...
you and I.
There shall be...
Rome.
Mighty and alone and unloved.
A mistress.
A mistress shall raise thee again
from earth to heaven...
and all the world shall know
a golden age ofjustice and of love.
A son shall be born to Isis!
Rome shall know him in cloth of gold.
The East shall see him laden
with jewels and treasure.
A son of Egypt and of Rome!
Here shall he find his destiny!
Do exactly as I tell you.
When the child is born...
after he is anointed
and named royal prince...
take him to Caesar.
Bring Caesar here.
No. Exactly as I tell you.
Take the child to Caesar,
in front of his men.
Do you understand?
In front of all the Romans.
Lay him at Caesar's feet.
At Caesar's feet.
I will do just as you say.
Fear not.
We have never lost a Caesar.
That remark was insubordinate
and in bad taste!
Caesar, remember Roman law.
If you pick up this child
you acknowledge it's yours...
and a citizen of Rome,
as your heir.
A son.
I have a son!
- Hail Caesar!
He's been made king of Egypt.
They have named their bastard
Caesarion.
Prince Caesarion.
What better name for the heir
to the throne of Rome.
There is no throne of Rome.
Nor shall there be,
nor would Caesar tolerate one.
But a son!
We know how much he's wanted one.
I am happy for Caesar.
Your happiness
is understandable enough.
Now that Caesar has
publicly recognized a son...
one need no longer
wonder about Brutus.
Is it a relief not to be
wondered about, Casca?
To be known openly
as you are for what you are:
Liar, swindler, bully and coward.
Brutus, you'll turn Casca's head
with your flattery.
And Casca's head, if turned,
will see Marc Antony.
A part of Caesar more to be feared
than his infant son.
But it is for the good of Rome that
Caesar has stayed so long in Egypt.
In his absence, the people
have come to worship him as a god.
Why should he return to show himself
as mortal as the rest?
There are those
who fear Caesar's ambition.
But what is there to fear?
That he will destroy the republic?
Yes, he will.
I promise you he will.
Your tongue is old but sharp, Cicero.
Be careful how you waggle it.
It may cut off your head.
It will more likely
be your sword, Antony.
'Tis just as sharp and quicker...
and frightened of heads.
There'll be a strong smell
of wine in the Senate today.
We must breathe with restraint.
Octavian, this what's his name,
this son of Caesar...
does it upset you?
No.
You run off at the mouth so...
one thinks your words
are as precious to you as your gold.
Like my gold, I use them
where they are worth most.
And your virtue?
My friend has a friend.
That too.
You know, it's quite possible,
Octavian, that when you die...
you will die without
ever having been alive.
I can't leave without saying
goodbye to my son and to you.
We thought, your son and I,
that if we came to you...
we would have those
few minutes more.
A good thing to remember, my son:
What you will not let go,
no one will take from you.
Hail and farewell, little Caesar.
Was it a century ago when I was dropped
at your feet, wrapped in a carpet?
Or was it last night?
When will you send for us? When?
- Soon.
- How soon? When?
So much time must go by
before even I reach Rome.
And then how soon?
Within reasonable time.
Time is never reasonable.
Time is our enemy, Caesar.
Am I to conquer it for you?
What plan of battle do you suggest?
I must bring your son to Rome.
Rome must see Caesar's son...
who will one day rule
over Caesar's world.
Caesar?
I'm afraid the tides
will soon be against you.
Not only time, but the tides.
Even as divinities, there seems
little we can do about either.
But only after more than two years...
and many wars
in Africa and Asia Minor...
was Caesar able to cross over
to Italy and come home at last...
to celebrate his triumphs
and see to his affairs.
"In recognition, the Senate
has bestowed upon Caesar...
the rank, privilege and title
of dictator of Rome for life."
Dictator for life!
At long last, he is master of Rome.
Apollodorus,
everything must be made ready at once.
- Ships, servants...
- We've been ready for some time.
Surely now nothing
can prevent his sending for us...
if only to attend
his coronation as he did mine.
- Your Majesty...
- Three long, wasted years!
Why should the Senate
have taken so long...
to recognize what the world
has already known?
That Caesar was master of Rome.
Rufio wishes to speak.
Your Majesty seems to misunderstand.
It seems quite clear. Caesar has been
declared dictator of Rome for life.
True. However, to the Roman...
there is a vast difference
between dictator and master.
No man can call himself
master of Rome.
Why not?
It has a meaning far too close
to a word no Roman will tolerate:
King.
And to be dictator of Rome for life?
Is to be granted the lifelong respect
and honor of the Roman people.
And the dictates of the dictator?
Must in each case, of course,
be approved by the Senate of Rome.
Thank you, Rufio.
The enemy! The enemy! The enemy!
Sosigenes.
You must think it odd that I propose
an invitation to Queen Cleopatra.
Do you?
Egypt, after all, has been
officially declared ally of Rome.
Still, I confess I was surprised
at some of those who voted in favor.
Were you?
May I express my gratitude for being
permitted to attend today's session?
It was truly inspiring...
to witness the free will
of free men so fearlessly expressed.
He seemed most anxious to be present.
- I saw no harm in granting him permission.
- Didn't you?
After today, never again shall I
doubt the extent of Egypt's wealth.
I don't like Cicero's implication.
There's not enough gold in Egypt
to buy the honor of a Roman senator.
More than enough, it seems,
to buy his vote.
How was it now?
"Rome will know him in cloth of gold."
According to reports, the reception
in the streets has been extraordinary.
The queen has instructed
the procession to move slowly...
for the people's enjoyment.
I might almost believe Cleopatra set
out to capture the citizens of Rome.
One would have every reason
for believing exactly that.
Nothing like this has come
into Rome since Romulus and Remus.
How unafraid he is.
Your queen has conquered
the people of Rome.
The people, yes.
Now then, walk like a king.
Head up.
Listen to them cheer.
Take your throne.
Bow to the right, left.
Now an angry glance at someone
who's displeased you.
Very good. I tremble.
See me tremble?
No, don't smile.
Not when they're trembling.
It makes them stop.
Now the prisoners
are dragged before you, one by one.
This one has no power anywhere,
therefore means nothing.
But you wish to be known
as a noble ruler. What do you say?
I pardon you.
Louder, boy. You pardon somebody,
you want it known.
I pardon you!
Now, who comes here?
Once your friend. You trusted him,
and he turned against you.
He has power, wealth and family.
He kneels.
He begs you to be his friend again.
To have you trust him again.
And then? What then, little king?
Caesar must wish
what needs commanding.
To drain the Pontine Marshes.
To free Rome from malaria.
To fill my belly.
To control the Tiber's floods.
To improve the harbor at Ostia.
To please my ambition.
And must I wish roads to be built,
libraries for public use?
The free men of Italy to be equal
citizens to those of Rome?
Many of these have merits
and merit our approval.
"Merit your approval." Is Caesar
to come before the Senate each day...
like a schoolboy with his lessons,
now passing, now failing?
Do you suggest the Senate no longer
deliberate the welfare of Rome?
To end the process of Roman law?
I must be the law! And my word
must be the welfare of Rome.
Else, take from me
this meaningless title of dictator.
I've carried a sword for too long.
I cannot now pretend
with an empty scabbard.
Surely Caesar recalls the symbolic
nature of the title "dictator"...
at the time it was conferred.
It was to honor Caesar
above all men...
and to indicate Rome's gratitude
for Caesar's triumphs in its name.
Brutus, I recall them well,
those triumphs.
Do you?
Pharsalia, for one.
You trembled in Antony's hand...
when Antony was hot
to separate you from your head...
with just cause.
My command spared your life.
There was no deliberating body.
It was not my wish, but my command.
By my dictate that you stand here
dribbling virtue out of your mouth.
Sit down.
No, I want no more meaningless
privileges and considerations.
No more honors designed to pacify me.
I would rather have nothing.
Remain what I am at heart.
A humble man, anxious only to serve.
Why are the eyes of a statue
always without life?
Have any of you here seen the Nile?
Spare yourselves the journey.
She carries it within her eyes.
I suggest, Caesar,
that the hour is late.
Very late for Rome.
I was speaking, Cassius! I was...
Now, where was I?
"Anxious to serve."
Yes, I've served.
Served for all of my life.
I've won for Rome
more than half of the world.
Most of you owe your honors
and fortunes to me.
And now I want you to do as I say.
You will appoint me...
emperor of Rome.
There is no need to resume your seats.
On behalf of all, thank you,
Majesty, for your hospitality.
Good night.
Thank you and good night.
They resent being summoned here for
meetings properly held in the Senate.
Resent it, do they?
I cannot understand...
that the eyes of a statue
should be always without life.
They resent me.
To flaunt me like this.
They'll use it to keep from you
that which is already yours.
By divine right, is that not so?
Yes. It is.
By divine right.
We shall have the Senate,
in its deliberations, deliberate that.
Are you quite sure
what it is you want...
so desperately?
I've always been sure.
And Caesar?
Does anyone speak for him?
No.
Good night.
Tell me, Brutus, is it proper
to stand before this new goddess...
- ...Caesar has set here in the temple?
- Or must we, as Romans, kneel?
Not yet. See there, where room
has been left for another deity?
When the god Caesar stands beside
the goddess Cleopatra...
then Rome will crawl before them.
When that day comes, if it comes.
- He demanded we make him emperor.
- Once. That one night, it was his sickness.
His sickness grows worse.
In the end, it will kill us.
He asked once to be made emperor,
but he's since decreed himself a god!
Emperor and god. No longer just king,
but emperor and god!
- Brutus, open your eyes!
- What do you want of me?
When the people think
upon the honor of Rome...
they think upon one man:
He is Brutus.
By that honor and
by the responsibility you carry...
Brutus, save Rome from Caesar!
You cannot ask me to destroy him.
Then let Caesar destroy Rome.
Antony has just come from a meeting
of my friends with good news.
Tomorrow at the Senate, Lucius Cotta
will move that I be made king.
It will pass.
But I don't understand.
King and emperor.
And it will pass?
The last few months,
I've been enjoying...
one of the few privileges
of being dictator.
I have been appointing senators.
Slightly more than half the Senate
has been appointed by me.
Once again, the army of Mithradates...
on its way all the time.
It will pass.
Tomorrow, the ides of March,
a day to be remembered...
the Senate will declare me
king of Rome.
King, yes, but not of Rome.
Not of Rome? What are you saying?
They'll offer you king
of the Roman Empire, outside Italy.
They're afraid, Caesar.
Even your friends.
Afraid of the people.
- Perhaps in time...
- To be afraid of the people.
To waste time on the people.
King of all but Rome?
What is there? The huts of Gaul?
The caves of Britain?
The whole of the empire outside Italy.
I will not accept.
They mean it to be an empty gesture.
Another title to please your fancy,
flatter your ego.
Nothing more.
And it will pass.
Then accept it, Caesar.
I have never settled
for half a victory.
Nor will you now.
Caesar, mighty Caesar...
all I can say
is what you've taught me:
Take a little, then a little more
until finally you have it all.
Let them declare you king.
Even if it's only
of a tree in Asia Minor.
The rest will come to you.
To redo once more everything
I have already done?
It's what you have never done, what
you never conquered that waits for you.
The great legions of Rome in the outer
empire that will become your legions.
The gold, the power of Egypt.
Your Egypt.
Caesar, you can conquer
and hold the world as your own.
Won't you understand?
Kings are not elected.
Gods are not elected.
Why, not only Rome but all of Italy
upon which Rome stands...
must fall in your hands
like a drop of sweat.
Let them make you what they choose.
I'll serve with you.
My legions with yours.
Together we'll conquer a world beyond
the wildest dreams of even Alexander.
Rome.
What was Rome when Sulla died...
when Crassus lost the armies
in Parthia?
These same men came after me
through the streets...
howling like frightened dogs,
"Caesar, save us!"
They would've made me king then.
I wouldn't let them then.
He was thrown over the wall.
It's not a pretty sight.
Titus, the moneylender.
Why should he be killed savagely
and brought here?
Obviously, I am being warned.
Perhaps I am next.
They dare to threaten you?
- Caesarion. Where was my son...?
- Not far away.
It frightened him.
- Lepidus, how many legions has he now?
- Fifteen. Perhaps more.
- Where?
- Scythia.
You and I will dine
with Lepidus tonight.
We'll talk of armies and battlefields
and lists of men to die.
Tomorrow in the Senate, let them offer
the sands of Libya as my kingdom...
I will accept.
This is great Caesar...
beloved by Rome...
and at least one of us...
who must die so that Rome may live.
If it must be done, then let us do it
unashamed and unafraid.
If the world is to know that
it is Rome that will not have a king...
then let us make it the honorable
act of free men in the light of day.
In the light of what day, Brutus?
Tomorrow?
In the curia of the Senate?
And shall we be armed, all of us?
Decimus, come to Caesar's villa early
tomorrow to escort him to the Senate.
Cimber, Marc Antony must not enter
the curia with Caesar.
On a pretext, lead him aside to speak
of what you heard at Lepidus' house.
I remember something odd.
At one point,
Caesar asked of each of us...
what manner of death
we would choose.
And Caesar, when it came to him,
looked straight at me and said:
"Sudden."
Odd, isn't it?
I was afraid I'd find you
still asleep.
Caesarion is.
He was awake most of the night.
Did the storm frighten him?
He said not, but it did.
I could tell.
Have you time to come in?
Decimus awaits. He came by expressly
to accompany me to the Senate.
Decimus? Has he done this before?
A shrewd politician.
He hopes to benefit
by arriving with me, this day of days.
Keep Antony close by.
You too?
The ladies of Rome seem to have caught
each other's fears this morning.
Like a head cold.
Calpurnia pleaded with me
not to go to the Senate at all.
Why? Why would she
not want you to go?
Oh, the bad night. Nothing else.
She awoke screaming in her sleep.
The thunder, the lightning.
She dreamed that she saw me murdered.
That she saw me...
or a statue of me covered in blood.
The servants told her of seeing
men of fire in the heavens...
odd happenings and so forth.
Strange birds were seen in the Forum.
One flew into the Senate carrying a
sprig of laurel which it dropped...
at the base of Pompey's statue.
Pompey?
- Caesar, I'm afraid.
- You must not tell me to stay away.
Shall I too be afraid?
Can it be said of Caesar, he gave up
the world because of a thunderstorm?
That such divinity that was in him ran
before mortal superstition?
I feel you need me now...
and I cannot help you.
Then help me to live as I have lived,
always differently from the rest.
The others, for whom life is merely
an endless fear of dying.
Your gods...
and mine go with you, Caesar.
The world, except for you,
is filled with little men.
Fire burns.
The winds of destruction blow.
Rome...
mighty and alone, the winds of
destruction blow down upon thee!
Storms and hail
shall cut down wheat...
shall cut down birds
and living things of earth.
The heavens...
and the gods themselves.
My son!
Caesar! Caesar!
I would've come sooner.
There was much to do.
And it seems you have
done it extremely well.
Is that where...?
Yes.
In Egypt, we build eternal monuments
to our dead heroes.
Here, you burn them like rubbish.
Goodbye.
I've brought the 10th Legion
and Rufio. You have nothing to fear.
Nothing to fear?
That's no reason for staying.
So much has happened so quickly.
Suddenly I have the pieces
of a broken world to pick up:
Caesar, you running off
at night like this.
Do you suggest that I stay? Why?
Don't ask me to be clear about
my feelings right now. I'm tired.
And with you,
it's never easy to say my meaning.
But you speak so well, Antony.
I've been told how excitingly
you read Caesar's will...
to the sobbing, murdering,
free citizens of Rome.
Naming as his heir
his great nephew, Octavian!
I knew Caesar's will
and the reasons for it.
If Octavian hadn't been named...
how many hours or minutes
would you and your son have survived?
And if Caesar had become truly king...
do you believe he would
still have named Octavian?
In any case, it's over.
Caesar...
and the dream
that was murdered with him.
First Alexander's...
then Caesar's.
Now over. Finished.
- First, Rome must be put in order.
- Rome again.
Brutus, Cassius and the others
must be found and killed.
- Then?
- Then in death...
Caesar must be granted the power
and title he was denied in life. Deified, even.
A dead king, a dead god.
Safe enough even for Rome.
Caesarion as Caesar's son could claim
both the title of king and his deification.
And to what court of law
would my son and I take our claim?
I will present it
to the Roman Senate myself.
I believe you would.
And after the noble senators
have stopped laughing...
do my son and I
then declare war on Rome?
No. For this,
a Caesar would be needed.
You have very little time.
Another Caesar.
But thank you.
I shall remember your kindness to us.
- You give up too easily.
- Do I?
Let me come to Alexandria
and talk more with you.
- Whenever you like.
- Now. Tonight, if I could.
In any case, try to remember.
For more than two years did Antony
seek out the assassins of Caesar.
At last, at Philippi...
he was able to set against them
his legions and those of Octavian...
who was Caesar's heir.
Cassius was the first to die...
by his own hand.
Then Brutus and the others.
Hail Antony!
Hail Antony's legion!
You remember Philippi.
He won it.
My lord.
- This way.
- But my tent is this way.
Later. I'll see him later.
Octavian depresses me.
You promised.
Well, the fighting's over.
We've won it all.
Your health should improve
quickly now.
Even if I die,
my place is with you on the field.
- You were wrong to prevent me.
- Caesar was ill.
Caesar? Yes. I keep forgetting.
I have inherited the name.
I have made it mine.
Why not? You'll never be confused
with the other one.
At least your troops
fought bravely, under my command.
Agrippa has kept me fully informed.
What were you doing there?
The battle was fought on land, between
men, not wood bumping on water.
Why did you bring Agrippa?
Were you expecting rain?
Shall we choose a piece of land,
just you and I?
Be quiet. There are matters
to talk about.
Have you an objection
to Agrippa remaining?
I object to Agrippa at all times.
Lying here, indisposed...
you must have had time
to consider the problem.
I think it is best
to continue the Triumvirate.
You and I and Lepidus.
Very well.
Lepidus shall have Africa and
the islands. You, Spain and Gaul.
Rome and Italy to be administered
by the three of us, jointly.
- And you?
- All the rest.
Then, with Lepidus in Africa
and you in the East...
bringing order to Rome and Italy
will be my problem.
- So it seems.
- Spain and Gaul aren't enough.
I'll need money.
- There have been tax riots in Rome.
- So I've heard.
Done.
And done.
Would Caesar approve, do you think?
Definitely. Perhaps the veil of Isis
would have bothered him a bit.
Three years...
and Rome remembers him
only by the image on a gold coin.
Are they those I brought back with me?
When Octavian had them struck off...
it was to commemorate
Caesar's deification.
So that he could inherit Caesar's
divinity together with all the rest.
Even a dead god
cannot rewrite his will.
Antony did present
Caesarion's claims to the Senate.
He kept that much of his promise.
And he will keep the rest of it.
After almost three years
since Caesar's death...
more than a year
since Philippi?
Antony will come. He will need Egypt.
Egypt is you.
That's what I meant, of course.
Antony will need me.
Finances! My head hurts
when you talk of money.
Change the subject.
All right. News from Rome.
Octavian has forced Lepidus
out of his command and into exile.
I wish I hadn't...
I wish I had not drunk so much today.
So do I.
Do I trouble you, Rufio?
Yes, you do.
I'll wager Caesar was never befuddled
by wine. Nothing befuddled Caesar
The campaign against Parthia
won't be easy.
- How many legions have we left?
- It's hard to tell.
- So many desertions.
- Desertions?
They haven't been paid in months.
You remember when
we started into Greece?
I lived with them, ate with them.
I was one of them.
They seem distant to me now,
as if they were a memory.
We must find the gold to pay them...
the wheat to feed them,
supplies, ships, armor.
And where do you suggest
we look for all these?
- I thought perhaps further to the east.
- Syria?
- Perhaps more to the south.
- Ethiopia?
To the north...
- I forbid you to mention her!
- I didn't.
I won't crawl to her!
Why hasn't she offered assistance?
- She may not know.
- She knows everything.
- If only out of gratitude...
- Perhaps she'll express it in person.
Then let her come to me.
Am I so much less than Caesar?
Nor is she less than Cleopatra,
queen of Egypt, and you promised...
Queen. Strip them naked,
they're no longer queens.
It is also difficult
to tell the rank of a naked general.
And generals without armies
are naked, indeed.
All right. I'll meet her halfway.
I'll send you to her.
- You order her to come.
- If I am to order her, I need not journey.
- Then summon her.
- Even worse.
Then beg, entreat, cajole,
find the word you like...
pour perfume, whinny like a stallion.
But see that she comes to me.
I understand your position, Rufio.
Surely you must understand mine.
I do not intend to join
that long list of queens...
who have quivered happily
at being summoned by Lord Antony.
But surely I didn't say "summoned."
You said "invite." He meant "summon."
In any case, I am the queen of Egypt.
And I choose to remain
on Egyptian soil.
Tarsus is not the other end
of the world, Your Majesty.
If it were one step from Egypt,
that would be too far.
I will meet with Lord Antony...
but only on Egyptian soil.
My lady, a way must be found,
a time, a place to satisfy you both.
Must it, Rufio?
Cleopatra.
Cleopatra!
It is.
It must be.
She said never,
except on Egyptian soil.
"Never." Something
women say to begin with.
Welcome Queen Cleopatra on my behalf.
Extend my invitation
to a banquet in her honor.
- Don't you think...?
- Still not convinced Rufio?
Hurry back, there's much to be done.
Have the cooks sent to me.
Forgive me, noble Rufio.
It is you who do not understand.
Queen Cleopatra, at present in her
chamber, is on Egyptian territory...
and intends to remain on it.
Most learned Sosigenes, forgive me...
but this is Tarsus, not Alexandria.
You are on Tarsus, noble Rufio.
I am on Egypt.
Tonight and tomorrow night, if Lord
Antony desires to meet Her Majesty...
he will come to her, to Egypt.
I shall do my best, learned friend,
to prevail upon Lord Antony to attend.
Marc Antony, how prompt you are.
If I had not been,
it would be unforgivable of me.
I had hoped to be here to
welcome you as you came aboard.
If you had been, it would be
unforgivable of me.
Be more tolerant.
Forgive yourself now and then.
Almost three years. Have you
possibly become more beautiful?
Almost three? That long?
The time has passed so quickly.
Your necklace.
It seems to be made of gold coins.
Coins of Caesar.
- Do you find it attractive?
- Very.
And I find what you're wearing
most becoming.
Greek, isn't it?
I have a fondness
for almost all Greek things.
As an almost all-Greek thing,
I'm flattered.
An unusual necklace.
Nothing but gold coins of Caesar.
- How did you come by it?
- I had it made.
I wear it always.
A fabulous feast.
One is so limited
when one travels by ship.
This fabulous ship...
together with its queen,
the fabulous Cleopatra.
The name of Marc Antony
is not exactly unknown to the world.
- In the last year or so since we met...
- Almost three.
By now you have become
one-third the master of Rome.
You don't permit yourself
to forget him, is that it?
That's an odd way of putting it.
"Don't permit myself"?
Is it necessary
to wear him around your neck?
You forget, Antony,
in these almost three years...
how full your own life has been.
They can't have been uneventful
for you. You rule Egypt alone.
Oh, they have been busy, but not full.
There's a difference.
There cannot be enough hours
in the days of a queen...
and her nights have too many.
- So I fill them with memories.
- Of Caesar?
And of a dream...
that almost came true.
You may remember.
I remember that night in Rome,
saying it could still come true.
You said so much that night
to so many.
Let me get rid of them all.
Why? I have arranged
an entertainment.
A dance in the Greek fashion
to welcome the god Bacchus.
If I make a great show of going,
they'll have to leave too.
Then I can return...
and we can talk alone, you and I.
- When would you return?
- In an hour, no more than two.
- How long would you stay?
- Until we had nothing more to say.
Are you a strong swimmer?
We sail at sunrise.
I don't understand.
Home to Alexandria, to Egypt.
You've come all this way for one
night. All to make a fool of me.
Perhaps you would feel less a fool...
if you stayed the night with me,
is that it?
I've told you before.
With you, words do not
come easily to me.
There is too much unsaid
within me that I cannot say.
Then I cannot know it.
There is much unsaid within you too.
That is probably true of everybody.
Stay for a while.
I have known you so long
but so little. Give me time.
Not I. Not Egypt and Rome together.
Not even the gods
have time to give you.
But, Antony, use what you have.
Don't waste it by playing
at god here in Tarsus...
while Octavian in Rome
becomes a god.
The dance, I take it, is over.
Sit up.
I want to see whether you sleep
with your memories.
With so much left unsaid
within you...
it must be a relief
to break and tear things.
- I want to say something now.
- Perhaps some other time.
Now!
Caesar.
Conquer and conquer.
Bring the world to its knees.
"You're not a Caesar.
Did you know that?"
Be braver than the bravest...
stronger than the strongest.
Still no Caesar.
Caesar's done it first and better.
Ruled better, loved better, fought better.
Run where you will, you can't get out.
There's no way out.
The shadow of Caesar will cover you
and cover the universe for all of time.
"Whenever you like," you said in Rome.
"Come to Alexandria
whenever you like."
"Now, tonight," I said.
To bow to the throne
upon which Caesar put you.
To talk of a new treaty.
Caesar's can't be improved. Copy it.
Of Caesar's son. Of the dream you shared
with Caesar that still fills your life.
Alexander's design for a world
to be ruled by you and Caesar.
Where is Antony?
Where is Marc Antony?
Antony the Great! The divine Antony!
Here.
He's...
here.
One step behind Caesar.
At the right hand of Caesar.
In the shadow of Caesar.
Tell me, how many
have loved you since him?
One? Ten? Anyone? No one?
Have they kissed you with Caesar's lips?
Is it his name you cry out in the dark?
Afterwards, has he reproached you
and have you begged forgiveness?
You've come here, then, running over
with wine and self-pity...
to conquer Caesar.
For so long now,
you've filled my life...
like a great noise
I hear everywhere in my heart.
I want to be free of you,
of wanting you...
of being afraid.
Yet, Caesar would not permit it.
But I will never...
be free of you.
From the first instant I saw you...
entering Rome
on that monstrous stone beast...
shining in the sun...
like a little gold toy.
How I envied Caesar.
Went suddenly sick with it.
Not his conquests or his triumphs.
Not his titles
or the roaring of the mob.
I envied him you.
When we first met in Rome,
I remembered you.
I wondered that I could
ever have forgotten.
Remembered me?
Years ago, when you were
a young cavalry officer...
stationed at the palace in
Alexandria under that fat Roman general.
- What was his name?
- Gabinius.
Gabinius.
I was 12 years old, and I loved you.
- Nonsense.
- It's true.
Lovers always want so much
never to have loved before.
It's possible, you know.
It becomes a game.
Who loved whom first?
I did.
If you noticed me at all then,
you were probably terrified of me.
With good reason. Everybody knows
Romans cut up little children...
and feed them to their horses.
We'll make this our beginning.
Beginning with tonight...
you must never envy Caesar...
or anyone, anything again.
After all...
this is nothing new.
For so many years...
Antony has fed upon the crumbs...
that fell from
Julius Caesar's table.
I say...
they are deserving of each other.
Let him stay in Egypt.
Let him fritter away
his life as he chooses...
but not the possessions
and the empire of the Roman people!
The Roman people!
The Roman people. What are
glory and possessions to them?
Is their Antony content?
Then so are they.
Does their Antony sweep
their empire...
under Cleopatra's bed?
His adoring Romans sigh
and remain content.
Let him stay however distant
for however long...
with never a thought of them.
The Roman people hold him
close to their hearts.
Distant?
Perhaps from Rome
but not from Caesar, I think.
Nor from Caesar's son.
Germanicus, do you speak of me?
No, Octavian, I speak of Caesar.
I am Caesar.
Only while Antony remains...
distant from Rome.
Antony!
Stay not too long in Alexandria!
Germanicus...
stay not too long in Rome.
- How much of this is known to Antony?
- All of it and more.
I've written him regularly. Letters,
dispatches by personal messenger.
And what has he answered?
He wrote he was no longer interested
in the matters I described.
That he would not return to Rome.
That he understood quite clearly
what was at stake, what he would lose.
But that he would not leave you.
Let's try the goat.
Let's have that goat again.
There. Not too much.
There.
The milk of a cow...
of a goat and of an ass.
Which is best for softening the beard?
Is it true Octavian shaves
but once a week?
Even then, he has merely to face
the wind and let the fuzz blow away.
You knew, didn't you,
Germanicus was here from Rome?
Yes.
Have you strong feelings about beards?
I had one. Bright red.
Why haven't you seen him?
When you go...
must it be for very long?
I must take some of these with me.
They don't have them.
At least, they didn't
when I was last...
in Rome.
While they were digging
the foundation of my tomb...
the workers found an old wall.
Someone had scratched on it
hundreds of years ago:
"You were not here last night,
and I could not sleep.
Will you be here tonight?"
Do you suppose they ever met again?
Everything that I shall ever want to hold
or look upon or have or be...
is here now with you.
I must not be sorry for myself.
Queens are sometimes no better at that
than kings, or even princes.
It doesn't seem fair.
What I feel I should have felt
long ago when I was very young.
When I could say to myself
that this was how love was...
and how it would be.
But to have waited so long,
to know so suddenly...
this late...
how it hurts.
How love can stab the heart.
Be careful with Octavian.
Let him be careful with me.
The Romans want no war
between the two of you.
In any case, you are not ready yet.
War? The world is filled with love.
There'll be no more wars.
You must have your share.
Your titles and powers
must be spelled out exactly.
There can be no question of your
complete authority in the East.
Antony, how will I live?
The same as I.
One breath upon the other.
Each bringing us...
one breath closer.
You take so much of me
with you so far.
Remember, remember.
They'll want you to forget.
- Please...
- Forget? How?
I can never be more
far away from you...
than this.
He will come first to Brindisium.
Agrippa and I plan to welcome
his arrival with a great ceremony.
Antony must see how dear to the hearts
of the Romans, of us all...
he is and has been.
He has been away for a very long time.
Perhaps we can persuade him
to stay with us even longer.
Perhaps, Octavia, if you came
to Brindisium, you could help.
You may have forgotten.
It is only six months since...
Begging the pardon
of Agrippa and our ancestors...
I do not agree that a young widow
must retire from life.
You haven't left my house
since your husband died.
If only for the sake of your health,
the change alone...
Then, begging the pardon of
Lord Agrippa and our ancestors...
I would look forward
very much to the change.
Nothing, no one, could possibly
shine more brightly in the sun.
Not only Antony.
I know of no man who would not
hold out his greedy fists for Octavia.
After all, what greater pledge
could I offer...
of my goodwill toward him?
And how could Antony better show
his love of peace and Rome...
than by accepting?
And Cleopatra?
Are you suggesting
we invite her to the wedding?
You remember when
Julius Caesar returned...
and those months
while she was in Rome?
There was a poison
in his heart, in his brain.
Yes, the falling sickness.
But more than that.
- Cleopatra.
- I remember well.
- Antony is no Caesar.
- I am grateful for that.
Granted that he marries Octavia,
will he forget Cleopatra?
- Will she permit him to forget?
- Most probably not.
- Have I permission to speak?
- Tell me, quickly.
A galley came to Pelusium
with news from Rome.
Antony and Octavian
have sealed a great pact.
Antony has 10 more legions
and all of the East for his domain.
Egypt will be declared ally of Rome.
It is done.
- There is more.
- No. No more, my lord.
- He's afraid.
- Is there anything more?
Forgive me, Divine Majesty.
There has been a marriage.
A marriage of state.
Between Octavia,
the sister of Caesar...
and Lord Antony.
Anything more?
They're presently in Athens.
Sometime within the year,
Lady Octavia is to return to Rome.
Antony will come Alexandria to negotiate
the alliance of Rome and Egypt.
Leave me.
No.
Completely alone.
Antony!
Do you find it pleasing, my lord?
Oh, yes. Very.
It was made here in Athens.
Not as practical
as our Roman ones, of course.
The Greeks have such
a weakness for beauty.
Does the dinner
not please you, my lord?
Very much.
I'm not particularly hungry.
If anything would please you more...
Believe me, I am pleased.
The gods know you do
nothing but please me...
in every way.
Word from Domitius?
He never even reached the palace.
He was not permitted
through the city gate.
If I may be excused.
There's no need for you to go.
When I hear matters of state
discussed by men...
invariably I find myself
wondering about...
why the wine has gone sour.
Good night, Rufio.
Good night, my lord.
Domitius turned away at the gate.
That makes how many?
Five of your ambassadors
turned away within this year.
- If you'd gone when...
- It was the only favor I ever asked of you.
You granted it.
The treaty with Egypt must be made.
We've received no wheat, no gold...
I cannot go to her
to negotiate a treaty!
She'll have no one else.
And what if she should...
turn me away?
That would be quite impossible.
Have you ever really left her?
No.
Three days I've waited
for an audience with you alone.
What is the purpose?
Get out, all of you.
I'll see her privately.
- You're before the throne of Egypt.
- I know where I am!
State your purpose!
Matters I won't discuss publicly.
I do not grant private audiences
to unidentified persons.
I am Marcus Antonius.
I know who you are.
What are you, at the moment?
Envoy of Rome, proconsul of all
the Roman Empire to the east of Italy.
An impressive title.
Worthy, perhaps,
of a private audience?
Without a treaty of alliance
with Egypt...
you could not hold the territories
under your command. True?
Possibly.
Then, Lord Antony, you come before me
as a suppliant.
- If you choose to regard me as such.
- I do.
You will therefore assume the position
of a suppliant before this throne.
You will kneel.
- I will what?
- On your knees.
You dare ask the proconsul
of the Roman Empire...
I asked it of Julius Caesar.
I demand it of you!
Now...
you may have the treaty
you asked for...
on the following conditions:
By your authority
as proconsul of Rome...
you will cede to Egypt immediately
the following territories:
Judea, Jordan, Armenia, Phoenicia,
the provinces of Sinai and Arabia...
the islands of Cyprus and Crete.
You ask for one-third
of the Roman Empire!
Put it another way.
I give to you two-thirds.
Most generous.
I cannot accept.
I suggest you deliberate further.
Perhaps consult with your superior
in Rome.
My superior?
Octavian.
Caesar Octavian?
You have not been dismissed!
You are now dismissed.
Outside, all of you. Her Majesty
and I will speak in private.
Out! Before I chop you up
and feed you to my horses.
That's how Romans
frighten little girls.
They like to frighten little girls.
Wait outside.
I married Octavia
at her brother's insistence...
as a gesture of faith, of peace.
A bargain sealed.
With a kiss? Or did you simply
shake hands on your wedding night?
Rome was celebrating the marriage even
before I arrived. How could I refuse?
By saying no.
As you have said no to all my demands.
They're unreasonable! The kind
laid down for a helpless enemy!
You're not helpless... yet.
I can't cede the territories. It would
lead to a break between Rome and me.
Why do you think
I asked for them?
It would be playing into
Octavian's hands, what he hopes for.
It would not be wise!
What is wise?
To hand over Rome, Italy,
the world to Octavian?
To grovel publicly
before his authority?
Take his sister to wed and to bed.
As if to beg forgiveness...
for having stayed so long
with your Egyptian harlot.
What has angered you?
That I dealt with Octavian how I could...
or that I married his sister to do it?
Jealousy or politics? Which?
Both! And damn you for not
understanding either.
I wouldn't look to you
for instruction.
Which is why you have come back
chained to Octavian like a slave.
- Slave!
- And with such exquisite chains.
So softly spoken, so virtuous.
She sleeps, I hear, fully clothed.
I come back.
That's all that should concern you.
Should it?
How long before your master snaps his
finger and you run back to him, or her?
I have only one master.
My love for you.
No.
Your master must not be love.
Never love.
Give yourself to love and you
give yourself to forgetfulness...
of what you are and who you are
and what you want.
And what you want
is worth so much more?
I will not have love as my master.
- Then you will not have love.
- Nor will I have Octavian.
- Never fear.
- How confident you are.
And has Octavian a master?
His ambition: to rule the Roman world
as emperor and god.
The Roman world, to begin with.
And what stands in his way?
- You and I.
- And my son!
The rightful heir to the name
and glory of great Caesar.
Octavian has already stolen those
and he will now destroy...
in the name of his sister,
the love Rome has for you.
And by your marriage to her...
he has made of me, unmistakably,
your whore.
Never fear Octavian?
It is he, now, who I think
must be unafraid.
Show me a city
and I'll tell you how to take it.
I'll find an army's weak points
and hit them hard where they are.
But make me to sit down and talk
in whispers of this and that...
with an emphasis here and a shrug there,
and I'm soon confounded and defeated.
Meaning to do the best...
I suppose I could not
have done worse.
There is still time.
Let someone ask me what I want:
To live with you in peace and love.
Do you have...
conditions for total surrender?
First, as did Caesar...
you will marry me
according to Egyptian ritual.
That's not a condition,
that's a reward.
You'll declare, by your authority...
Caesarion to be king of Egypt...
and we will rule together
in his name.
Happily granted.
You will cede to Egypt
all the territories I have demanded.
You must.
If only to assert
your own authority and power.
Otherwise, inevitably,
in time we will lose everything.
Can't you see that?
I can see nothing...
but you.
I am no longer content
to forgive Antony!
To marry this Egyptian
according to their barbaric rites!
Meaningless under Roman law!
Great Caesar himself...
Yes. Bit by bit,
Antony crawls behind his memory.
But tell us this, Germanicus:
Did great Caesar also toss one-third
of the Roman Empire...
into Cleopatra's
undoubtedly deserving lap?
The territories in dispute
were subjugated by Julius Caesar.
The right to rule over them
is the heritage of his son.
And in the name of the mighty Caesar
I grant to King Ptolemy Caesarion...
that right.
Let it be known the greatness of Rome
lies not in what she takes...
but in what she gives.
"Rome's greatness lies
in what she gives," he says.
Then calmly gives what is not his.
And Cleopatra takes...
and will take more.
And war will come.
She knows and I know...
that war will come.
But I will not speak for it...
nor will I speak against Antony.
I must be forced into war.
The people of Rome
must force this war upon me.
They must storm the doors
of the Senate, crying for it.
If we move quickly, the Romans won't know
we've crossed the Mediterranean...
until we land in Greece.
You and General Rufio will start
embarking the troops at once.
Yes, Your Majesty.
If it is decided
to move our armies into Greece.
It has been decided.
My men do not...
travel well by sea.
They fight on land.
They move on land.
Your men will do
as they are told, as mine will.
My men will do as they're told by me.
They have not yet become...
They are still Roman.
However...
since I do as I'm told...
The final decision will,
of course, be Lord Antony's.
And I'm sure that in time
he will make it.
That is all.
It would be wiser not to disagree
in the presence of our officers.
Your officers.
What final decision
have you decided I am to make?
Why do you oppose transporting
our armies to Greece?
Because I do not want war
against Rome.
One hundred thousand men
led by Marc Antony.
Octavian is no fool. He won't fight.
He'll have to, instantly,
on the spot where they land.
Rome will not declare war against you.
I do not agree.
I have not asked for your opinion.
Not for some time.
Not since I doubted the necessity
of building 300 ships.
The way to prevent war
is to be ready for it.
Have 300 warships ever been
built for war without war?
We shall have what we want
without it.
Your Majesty, please hear me.
I think we are very near the edge.
Strings are being pulled,
and not by us.
We are being managed and maneuvered
without our choosing.
The deputation sent on behalf
of Lady Octavia...
chosen from the most
highly revered men of Rome.
Why? They can take back to their
people nothing but Lord Antony's...
forgive me, insulting and
unnecessary divorce of her...
and his rejection of them.
It was done at my bidding.
The responsibility is mine.
The doing was mine.
What do you propose?
Let me go to Rome and approach
Octavian, possibly the Roman people...
and assure them that we want peace.
Go then.
Go to Rome.
Sosigenes!
Take care.
He's very dear to you,
that old man.
Your concern and worry
are written all over you.
Forgive me, but it's a kind of love
that you're showing.
Let them talk. Let them
negotiate all they want.
Time is on our side.
We can only grow stronger.
These walls must not
believe their ears...
to hear such silence...
from the right...
from the left.
The call of the Roman people
can be clearly heard...
yet the Roman Senate...
has no answer.
Shall we then just sit...
and listen?
There is not one of us that would not
willingly make war upon Cleopatra.
But how...
without also making war
upon Marc Antony...
loved by Rome and loving Rome?
"Loved by Rome and loving Rome."
I have here the last will
and testament...
of Antony, who so loves Rome.
Read for yourselves...
how dearly Antony loves you,
loves Rome...
in this, his last will
under his seal.
Only lately brought from Egypt...
and deposited in our holy temple
at Antony's request...
by the distinguished Sosigenes.
An extraordinary mission
for an extraordinary man.
So wise, so close to Cleopatra,
so trusted by her.
Read in Antony's will...
at the end.
Commit to memory the last request
of your beloved Antony.
It bears witness to his love for Rome.
When he is dead, it says...
when Marc Antony has died...
it is his wish to be buried...
in his beloved Alexandria!
In Egypt!
Among Egyptians.
Beside his Egyptian whore!
Is what I say the truth?
Do I speak the truth?
- War!
War! War! War!
I hold before you
the Golden Spear of War.
Placed into my hands
without dissent...
by the command and will
of the Senate of Rome.
And now it is you,
the people of Rome, who must direct me.
Where is the enemy?
Where is Egypt? Show me the way!
No!
There!
There is Egypt.
And so once more,
the Romans warred upon each other.
And just as Antony had foretold...
the forces of Octavian
came to meet them...
on the spot where they landed...
which was at Actium, in Greece.
Action begins
with the rise of the sun.
Your plan is brave and simple.
It's possible on land...
but we debate
its wisdom upon the sea.
I have an enemy on land with fewer
troops, on sea with fewer ships.
Let him debate the wisdom
of his position.
I have a happy choice. To destroy him
wet or dry. I have chosen wet.
I think it best, Euphranor, you report
to Cleopatra aboard her vessel in the harbor.
There you may point out to her...
the reasons why my brave simplicity
has failed.
In any case, you are relieved
of your battle command.
This final commitment of yourself,
your ships, of all of us...
to fight at sea,
when did you decide?
- Forgive me. I had...
- We've worked hard for many months.
We've trained an army
of 200,000 men from 20 countries.
- They won't be wasted...
- Of which, tonight, 20,000 of them...
will be herded onto those ships and
dragged out to sea, puking and afraid.
- Why, my lord? Why?
- Because I have decided it will be so!
I consider it an honor...
to fight beside Lord Antony
at any time, anywhere.
Spoken like a Roman, Ramos.
And you shall fight at my side,
in Rufio's place.
Rufio, you will remain with
Her Majesty aboard her vessel.
As you command.
Canidius, you will remain
with the land forces...
cheering from the hilltop,
if you like.
- As you command.
- Exactly.
As I command.
You're all dismissed.
Antony.
What has happened?
To me?
You have happened to me.
Do the lookouts have
Octavian's insignia?
- A golden eagle. Sighted at sunrise.
- By sunset we'll have those gold feathers.
Let Octavian know we're coming!
Let the enemy hear the voice
of Antony's legions!
He's on his way.
Signal my lord Caesar's ship.
Does it fly his insignia?
My orders are to be followed
exactly as issued.
And may the gods grant that Antony
has not changed his plan of battle.
There he goes...
as he's done 100 times on land.
Straight for the center.
If only it were on land, and we
were there to protect his flanks.
But we're not.
This and all dispositions are
to be signaled...
to Admiral Euphranor
aboard Cleopatra's barge.
But Euphranor's in command of...
In command of moving toy ships
on a painted ocean...
so that Egypt's queen can more
clearly follow her war upon water...
to which she has committed
Marc Antony and 20,000 Romans.
Just as he said he would.
Antony and his escorts,
by themselves, are after Octavian.
- He's already broken through their center.
- They let him through.
They Roman line will close behind him.
Not if we engage, as Antony said.
They won't engage. Agrippa will pull
them back and back, behind Antony...
as Antony chases Octavian.
What report?
Lord Antony is already through
the center of the Roman line.
He is now deep within the Roman fleet,
in pursuit of Octavian.
Faster! Faster!
They've increased their own speed.
We're too heavy to catch them.
Then we'll slow them down.
Start the ballistas.
Javelin throwers.
Aim high.
Overshoot rather than under.
Ballistas. Javelins.
Ballistas!
Octavian's ships are so much faster
than our Egyptian tubs.
Why doesn't Agrippa keep him away
from Antony's ballistas?
Ballistas!
Ballista!
My lord! My lord!
A direct hit on the enemy!
A bank of oars has been destroyed!
He's coming around broadside.
We've got him!
Collision course.
We'll ram him, board and destroy him.
Octavian!
Now is your time to be a Caesar!
- Where is he hiding?
- My Lord Octavian is not on board.
And now we close the trap.
Now we hit my Lord Antony
with everything we have.
No word of Lord Antony?
By now he must have Octavian.
You said he rammed Octavian's ship.
It may be Lord Antony rammed a ship
flying Octavian's insignia.
But if it is Octavian's ship,
if Octavian is on board...
If he finds and kills Octavian, he's
still surrounded by the Roman fleet.
- Then send him help.
- I've none to send.
They're pulling our ships apart now.
They've got Antony
alone and cut off...
closing in on him
like a pack of dogs on a wounded bear.
- Lord Antony's ship?
- Gone.
- And Octavian's ship?
- Burning, helpless.
Would you say, admiral...
that Lord Antony is dead?
How is the wind for Egypt?
Fair.
We'll sail at once.
Man the oar banks. Hoist anchor.
We sail for Egypt!
My Lord Canidius!
Remember always,
that after the battle of Actium...
with Octavian dead
and Antony dead...
you saw the victor...
sail away on her golden barge.
She's going.
Cleopatra's going!
Leaving me!
My lord.
My lord, our casualties are heavy.
We have little armor left.
Our men need regrouping,
someone to give them courage.
The dying are calling for you.
The living need your help.
You can't leave them.
Listen to me!
Help!
Caesar, news!
Great news! Cleopatra is leaving
the battle. Antony is following her.
We have won a great victory.
Weigh oars!
Her Majesty is most anxious
to see you. Will you come below?
Perhaps if you wish to remain here,
she will come to you.
Shall I send you food? Wine?
Her Majesty's orders.
She's afraid you might...
harm yourself.
Please.
Octavian has crossed
from Syria into Egypt.
He can be here in a matter of weeks.
There are two full legions
here in Alexandria...
who have remained loyal to you.
They and their officers...
are waiting for you
to command them.
If not to me, won't you speak
to Rufio at least...
or to anyone you choose?
Antony, just say what you want done
and it will be.
It's been so long since you've
looked at me. Don't turn away...
even like this...
with your eyes filled with hate.
How they burn with hate.
Why, Antony? Why?
Because I ran away?
They told me you were dead!
What...
could I do?
Where could I go...
in a world suddenly without you...
except to my son and my country...
Caesarion and Egypt?
I wanted to save them from Octavian.
You would have wanted me to go.
You would have commanded me to go.
Tell me you would have!
They told me you were dead.
You were quite right.
I am dead.
The armies of Gaius Julius Caesar...
are advancing without opposition
upon Alexandria.
Gaius Julius Caesar?
So now Octavian has
stolen all of the name.
Caesar wishes it known he has
no quarrel with Cleopatra of Egypt.
Then let him take his armies
out of here and go home.
He has charged me to say
that the choice of war or peace...
now rests with Egypt.
And that for himself,
he desires only peace.
And what are his terms
for this unconditional peace?
A small token.
A demonstration. A gesture.
An indication of Queen Cleopatra's
goodwill and good faith.
What does Octavian want?
Marc Antony.
The...
head of Marc Antony?
Take this to him as my answer.
Egyptian generosity.
Octavian may have two heads
for the price of one.
Either two...
or none.
I'm told you come here to sleep.
Not to sleep.
To pass the night then.
I'm not alone.
The old boy and I
exchange memories of life.
It's like having a roommate,
or should I say, "tomb-mate"?
If he were in your place,
would I find Caesar here?
Hidden away, wrapped in moonlight
and endless self-pity?
Self-pity again! You repeat yourself!
Find new reproaches!
Until now it has just been
a part of your being drunk.
Singing sad songs for Antony.
Your time would be better spent
negotiating with Octavian.
Why did you not give my head to Agrippa?
It's no great loss to me.
Dying the second time is painless
and possibly an advantage to you.
The basis, perhaps,
of a great new alliance with Rome.
I do not want a great
new alliance with Rome.
What do you want?
I have come for Marc Antony.
What is left of his army,
Rufio, my son and I...
all of Egypt are waiting for him.
There is little time.
Marc Antony?
There is no one here by that name...
alive.
Time for what?
For Marc Antony
to appear in shiny armor...
swords flashing in both hands?
Agrippa. Octavian.
Stand back! Rejoice!
Marc Antony will save the day!
Antony, you say?
He died at Actium...
running away.
He tried to run on the water,
the story goes...
but you weren't there to hold his hand!
Rufio, my legions, waiting.
For what?
To ask me
what they carry in their eyes...
in their hearts, in their sleep,
as I have in mine.
Why are you not dead?
Why do you live? How can you live?
Why do you not lie
in the deepest hole of the sea...
bloodless and bloated and
at peace with honorable death?
You begged forgiveness from me
for running away.
You wept and gave your reason. A mother
to her child, a queen to her country.
Where and how can I weep and beg?
From whom?
The thousands and thousands
who can no longer hear me?
Shall I give my reason?
Shall I say simply, I loved?
When I saw you go, I saw nothing.
Felt, heard, thought nothing
except your going.
Not the dying and dead,
not Rome, not Egypt...
not victory or defeat,
honor or disgrace...
only that my love was going
and I must be with her.
That my love, my master, called.
And I followed.
And that only then...
I looked back...
and I saw.
How right you were.
"Have as your master
anyone, anything...
but never love."
How wrong.
How wrong I was.
Antony, the love you followed is here.
To be had upon payment of an empire.
Without you, Antony...
this is not a world
I want to live in...
much less conquer.
Because for me...
there would be no love anywhere.
Do you want me to die with you?
I will.
Or do you want me to live with you?
Whatever you choose.
Are we too late, do you think,
if we choose to live?
Better too late...
than never.
My lady, there is disturbing news
from the city.
The people are frightened. Some are
beginning to leave their homes.
During the night, hundreds of notices
were secretly posted everywhere.
They were found
stuck up in the marketplace.
Even painted on temples
and other holy places.
Signed by Octavian Gaius
Julius Caesar Augustus...
promising the Egyptian people
peace if they surrender to him...
and destruction if they do not.
I've had all of the notices removed
and I've ordered the death penalty...
for anyone who spreads the false rumors
that Antony's men might desert him.
And what penalty
if the rumors might come true?
How do you know?
I know the Romans.
There is only one commander
they will never desert.
His name is "Victory."
But yet, just now,
you let Lord Antony go as if...
If you could have seen him,
how proud he was...
unafraid...
as he used to be.
All of my attendants, have they been
given their freedom? Have they gone?
Yes. They wanted once more
to tidy up.
Octavian can do his own housecleaning.
The captain of the guards and three
of his best men are to report to me...
disguised as merchants.
They are to escort
Caesarion out of Egypt...
for the time being.
And you?
Your Majesty, please reconsider.
There are two of Euphranor's ships,
very fast, in the east harbor.
And would you roll me
on board in a carpet?
No.
There are no more Caesars to go to,
at least not for me.
- Then it is still your intention...
- To remain in Alexandria.
In the last possible place
anyone would look.
Literally, the last possible place.
Your Majesty, I have never
questioned your decisions.
This is not the time to begin.
Let me stay with you.
Charmian and Eiras will look after me.
If Lord Antony should...
When Lord Antony returns...
you will be here to tell him
where to find me...
waiting for him.
Together, we will then do...
what he thinks best.
Is that clear?
- Yes, my lady.
- Was there anything more?
I have always loved you.
And I have always known.
Rome has never known such an army.
We should be taking on all of Asia.
It seems a waste to slaughter what's
left of Antony's army and Antony.
There will be no slaughter.
I doubt there will be even bloodshed.
Has a battle ever been won without
a blow being struck? I wonder.
At any rate, let me
make it clear once more.
I want Antony alive,
and I want her alive.
She must be taken alive.
Queen Cleopatra's second procession
into Rome...
will surpass her first.
The ring your father gave you.
It is yours now...
to keep.
Wear it with pride and with honor.
I'm afraid.
I know I shouldn't be.
Who told you that?
All kings...
and especially queens, are afraid.
They just manage not to show it.
Something ordinary people cannot do.
Hail Antony!
- How near is Octavian?
- Very near. Over that low ridge.
As it grows darker, the glow from
his campfires will light up the sky.
Our troops must find it
attractive to watch.
Inviting, even.
Antony's legions warm themselves
at their own fires.
Yes.
I could feel the warmth as I rode by.
- How many legions has he?
- Twenty.
- And we?
- Two. The 12th and one made up...
Made up from what was left
of the others.
As I remember it, Caesar
held Alexandria with two.
How are they deployed? Rufio.
Cavalry to the left, cavalry
to the right, infantry to the center.
Three elephants deployed
to stamp out a fly.
My lords Octavian and Agrippa have
all the strategic brilliance...
of two vestal virgins.
We can draw back here
to softer ground...
too soft for cavalry
and make our stand against their infantry.
Stand? And let them stamp on us?
No. Let the elephants stand.
We flies will bite
and buzz and tickle.
At the first light of day...
while Octavian's glow
still lights up the sky...
we will attack.
By sunset, both our loyal legions
will have grown larger...
and even more loyal, I promise you.
Good night.
Rufio, tell the guards, please...
I am to be awakened
just before dawn.
Of course.
And, Rufio...
if, for whatever reason, the guards
should forget or misjudge the time...
will you, yourself, wake me?
The guards will wake you.
- But if they don't?
- Then I will. Never fear.
I never fear.
Not anymore.
Rufio!
Rufio.
Fight!
Why don't you fight?
Is there no one
who would grant Antony...
an honorable way to die?
Before me...
this was carried by another Roman
killed by Rome.
Another...
Caesar.
No.
We will have him.
We will have them both together.
Where is she?
Her Majesty said to tell you...
she can be found in the last
possible place anyone would look.
Literally, the last possible place.
She might have waited.
Once more, it seems...
Cleopatra is out of reach...
and I must hurry after.
Throughout life...
and now beyond.
One woman, one love!
Nothing changes...
except life into death.
Will you help me?
Help me to die, Apollodorus!
I want to!
But I can't.
I've always envied Rufio...
his long arms.
The ultimate desertion:
I from myself.
Else, how could I have missed what
I must have aimed for all my life?
Will you finish me now?
Where is my sword?
I beg you to finish me.
I lied to you.
I let you think the queen is dead.
But she's alive in her tomb,
waiting for you.
Cleopatra waiting?
There will be just enough time...
if you'll help me.
Perhaps, my lady, if we were
to bind his wounds tightly...
It would only give him pain.
Let him sleep.
Sleep.
Will you come tonight...
so that I can sleep?
The dark sleep.
They did meet after all...
the lovers.
They will always meet.
Be lonely for me.
But not for very long.
I promise.
I thought always I would die...
so well...
as becomes a soldier.
A soldier's death.
I lived always as I saw fit.
Unfittingly.
I would make it up, I thought,
in death.
I expected...
I expected too much of me in death...
as in life.
Are you holding me?
Never so closely.
Even closer.
You and I will prove death...
so much less than love.
You and I, we will...
We'll make of dying...
nothing more than one...
last...
embrace.
A kiss...
to take my breath away.
There has never been...
such a silence.
Turn him over.
Strange people.
Poisons that smell like perfume.
Find more. Have it analyzed.
Test it on one of the badly wounded.
My lord, they have
found Queen Cleopatra.
She is locked in a building,
that is to say, a tomb.
Hurry.
Oh, Marc Antony is with her,
they say. He's dead.
- What?
- Lord Antony is dead.
Is that how one says it?
As simply as that.
Marc Antony is dead.
Lord Antony is dead.
The soup is hot. The soup is cold.
Antony is living. Antony is dead.
Shake with terror when
such words pass your lips...
for fear they be untrue and Antony
cut out your tongue for the lie!
And if true...
for your lifetime boast...
that you were honored
to speak his name even in death.
The dying of such a man...
must be shouted.
Screamed.
It must echo back
from the corners of the universe.
Antony is dead!
Marc Antony of Rome lives no more!
You needn't lower
your head before Caesar.
I never did.
But if he were here, I'd be happy to.
I am Caesar.
If it pleases you, Octavian.
Look at me.
If it pleases you.
After all this time
and all that has happened...
I suppose you are still beautiful,
in a way.
You flatter me.
My interest is impersonal.
Should you have any intention...
Now you flatter yourself.
The fighting is over.
Your country, your possessions
and you are mine by right of conquest.
I will permit you to rule Egypt as a Roman
province and return your possessions.
There is one condition.
You will first accompany me to Rome.
Behind your chariot?
Look at me!
Would the proud citizens of Rome
wait for hours in the hot sun...
to see my dead body
dragged through the Forum?
I'll have you closely watched.
Octavian...
when I am ready to die...
I will die.
What if I promise
no harm will come to you...
that you will be returned
safely to Alexandria?
Look at me!
What more could you ask?
You have not spoken...
of my son.
Your son. I'd forgotten him.
Where is he?
Safe.
If I go with you to Rome...
would you permit my son
to rule Egypt?
And his sons?
And theirs?
I'll do everything I can.
Do I have your word...
as a Roman emperor and god?
Yes.
When will you require me to go?
As soon as possible.
At the moment, I am very tired
and would like to rest.
If you'll leave me now.
Do I have your word...
that you will not harm yourself
in any way?
I swear it.
On the life of my son.
Must the guards remain inside?
I have sworn...
after all...
on the life of my son.
And now I must make ready to go.
There's little to do.
First, I shall want something to eat.
Something to sustain me on my way.
Some fruit, perhaps?
Bring it to me.
Charmian.
You then, Eiras.
You have never been without us.
You cannot leave us behind.
Perhaps...
there may be enough for us all.
Bring me a tablet to write on.
I want a message
brought to Octavian.
Words are wasted on such a man.
I have wasted so many on so many men.
A few more. One last request.
Will he grant it, do you think?
I may never know.
In this case...
I think I shall.
I will serve Her Majesty as always.
I have always served her.
You will both wait...
to dress me for my travels.
I will wear...
I want to be as Antony first saw me.
The dress of gold?
He must know at once...
even from a great distance...
that it is I.
This will be the last thing you do.
Drop this to one of the guards outside
for Octavian.
But be sure to wait.
And now let me see if the figs
are as they should be.
The taste of these, they say,
is sharp...
and swiftly over.
How strangely awake I feel.
As if living
had been just a long dream.
Someone else's dream.
Now finished at last.
But then now...
will begin...
a dream of my own...
which will never end.
Antony?
Antony, wait.
From the Egyptian queen,
a message for Caesar.
Read it. Whatever she wants will be
granted upon her arrival in Rome.
We will discuss it
as she walks beside my chariot.
What is it?
"My one wish,
which I implore you to grant..."
is to be buried at the site of
Antony and to remain there...
"...until all things end."
Was this well done of your lady?
Extremely well.
As befitting...
the last of so many noble...
rulers.
And the Roman asked:
"Was this well done of your lady?"
And the servant answered:
"Extremely well."
As befitting the last...
"...of so many noble rulers."