(BETSEY) How is she.?
(DR CHILLIP) She is a he.
(BETSEY) What.?
(DR CHILLIP) The baby is a boy.
A boy? A boy!
(DAN) You're most welcome,
Master Copperfield.
You'll find us rough,
but you'll find us ready.
(YOUNG DAVID)
Let's always be friends, Emily.
(YOUNG EMILY) I'd like that,
but you'll be a gentleman one day.
Argh!
(CREAKLE)
So you like biting, do you.?
(STEERFORTH) Stings, don't it.?
(YOUNG DAVID) A bit.
You're as fresh as a daisy.
My name is Steerforth, by the way.
There's no need to "sir" me.
(CREAKLE) It grieves me to tell you
that your mother is very ill
She is very dangerously ill
In fact, she's dead.
(PEGGOTTY)
Listen to me, my darling boy.
Don't lose heart, and never forget
how much your Peggotty loves you.
(MICAWBER) I am convinced
that you will, in short, go far.
To Copperfield.
Not just a lodger - a friend.
I never will forget you.
(BETSEY) You broke her heart,
then punished the boy,
because of your own guilt!
Oh, Mr Dick. You'll consider yourself
joint guardian with me of this boy.
I think perhaps
he should take the name Trotwood.
(MR DICK) Trotwood Copperfield.!
(BETSEY) Trotwood Copperfield.!
Perhaps you'll be
a partner in Wickfield's business one day.
Oh, no, Master Copperfield.
Ambition ain't for me.
A person like myself
had better not aspire.
Do not concern yourself.
I will look after him.
(DAVID) As you have always done.
(SPENLOW) My daughter
is holding a picnic next Saturday.
Perhaps you'd care to join us.?
Oh... Irresistible, Mr Copperfull
Watch Movies, TV Series & Live Sports
www.admitme.app
My new life had begun.
I was independent, a young man
making his way in the world.
But what did any of this mean
without Dora.?
I was determined to win her heart.
I knew my happiness depended on it.
Miss Spenlow.
In honour of your birthday...
What a dear bouquet!
They're beautiful flowers,
Mr Copperfield.
I thought them beautiful
until I saw you.
Come. Join us.
(DORA) # Des jeunes filles si belles
# Des gar? Ons vifs et joyeux
# Dansant tous ensemble
tra-la-la-la-la-la
# Prenez-moi la main,
allons sous les arbres
# Cherchons la musique,
dansons avec joie
# La douce nuit est tombee
la lune vient de monter
# Dansons dans la foret
tra-la-la-la-la-la #
Little had been said,
but I was filled with the hope
that some vital understanding
had been reached between us.
For the next few days,
greatly to Mrs Crupp's discomfort,
I lived on nothing
but Dora and coffee.
Skittles, Mr Copperfull
When there's a young lady
in the case, skittles is healthy.
Diverts the mind, does you good.
Oh...
I satisfied my appetite
by writing her numerous letters,
hoping that she would detect
the desperate passion
that lay beneath their formal exterior.
Thankfully, for my sanity,
I was at last distracted by an invitation
to join Agnes at a London party.
Trotwood!
Agnes! How wonderful
to receive your invitation.
We see you so rarely these days.
My dear sister, I've so much
to tell you about what I've been doing.
Uriah. How are you?
Much obliged for your condescension
to an 'umble person, Master Copperfield.
Take no notice of me. I am invisible.
Things have changed
since you left, Trotwood.
Papa is to make Uriah his partner.
- But he's not to be trusted!
- Uriah has made himself indispensable.
I have a good mind to...
Promise me you'll do nothing
to offend Uriah.
You fell in love on the spot.
More than that.
I completely and utterly adore her.
But what about you, Agnes?
Have you no admirers
to tell me about?
Of course not.
I have no time for anything like that.
Have you seen
the new play at Covent Garden?
(STEERFORTH) A miserable business!
(DAVID) Steerforth!
You don't remember me.
David Copperfield.
My God! Little Copperfield!
- I'm overjoyed to see you.
- You haven't changed a bit, Daisy.
This is Miss Wickfield, an old friend.
Delighted. You have the prettiest girl
in the place on your arm, Daisy.
Why do you call him "Daisy"?
Merely a nickname from school
You don't mind, do you, Daisy?
Not in the least.
I'm staying at my mother's.
You must call on me.
I want to know what you've been doing.
I feel as though you're my property.
Of all people! What luck.
Sometimes it is wiser
to leave the past alone.
Perhaps you shouldn't go to see him.
Why not? He's the best friend
I ever had in the world.
Going home, Master Copperfield?
Indeed, Uriah. Perhaps you would care
to join me for some coffee?
Oh, really, Master...
I mean MisterCopperfield.
I'm sure you wouldn't want
a 'umble person like me in your house.
I wouldn't ask you if I didn't.
Do you remember saying to me once
that perhaps I should become a partner
in Mr Wickfield's business one day?
What a prophet you have
shown yourself, Mr Copperfield.
I don't suppose
I really thought it likely.
Oh, who would have?
But the 'umblest persons
may be the instruments of good.
Mr Wickfield is the worthiest of men,
but, oh, how imprudent he has been.
- Has he been imprudent?
- If anyone else had been in my place,
Mr Wickfield would have been
under his thumb by now.
Without me, there would have been
loss and disgrace,
and Mr Wickfield knows it.
Did you think Miss Agnes
looked very beautiful tonight?
I thought her looking
as she always does,
superior to everyone around her.
Thank you.
Thank you very much for that.
Why should you thank me?
You will not think the worse
of my 'umbleness
if I make you a little confidence,
Mr Copperfield?
Of course not.
The image of Miss Agnes
has been in my breast for years.
Oh, with what pure affection
do I love the ground she walks on!
Does she know of these feelings?
Oh, no! Oh, dear, no!
You see, I'm just emerging
from my lowly station,
but I rest my hope
on my usefulness to her father.
She's so much attached to him,
she may come, on his account,
to be kind to me.
If you'll keep my secret
and not go against me with my Agnes,
I will take it as a particular favour.
You wouldn't wish
to make unpleasantness.
Who knows what
the consequences might be?
(CLOCK STRIKES)
Dear me. One o'clock.
My boarding house
will be locked by now.
Dear Agnes.
Too loving and good
for anyone I could think of.
Was it possible she was reserved
to be the wife of such a wretch as this.?
You walk at a somewhat
lively pace, Mr Copperfield.
I wouldn't want you
to miss your coach.
I'll be back with the law
next time, Micawber!
Mr Micawber!
Open up, it's Copperfield!
Mr Micawber! It's David Copperfield!
(MICAWBER) Is it possible?
Have I again the pleasure of beholding
the infant scourge
of the pawnbroking profession?
Come in, come in.
Mr Heep.
Any friend of Copperfield's
is a friend of Wilkins Micawber.
(MICAWBER) My dear!
There is a gentleman here
who wishes to be presented to you!
Copperfield, come to renew
his acquaintance with you, my love.
Lord, can it really be?
Oh, what happy memories
of my youth!
Oh, here!
Oh, I...
You may perhaps have surmised
that Mrs Micawber is in a state of health
which renders it not improbable
that there will be soon be
an addition to the infantine group.
In short, she is expecting.
It is a happy event,
though one that strains Mr Micawber's
already depleted resources.
But I know that he will,
as always, rise to the challenge.
We must celebrate.
Will you come to dinner next week?
Oh! A noble and generous proposition.
If I had listened to Agnes's advice,
if I had never taken up
Steerforth's invitation,
many honest lives would have
continued untouched by tragedy.
But I was blind to her wisdom then,
as I was blind to so many things,
and it was with
nothing but joy in my heart
that I went to visit my old friend
at the house he shared with his mother
and her companion, Rosa Dartle.
James has told you he is
an Oxford man now, Mr Copperfield?
I am sure he will make you proud
and take a high degree.
My dear Daisy, I doubt whether
I shall bother to take a degree at all
Don't torment me, James.
You know you will
There is no better mind
in the whole college.
You must forgive Mother.
She is quite horribly vain about me.
But you give her
every reason to be, do you not?
We hardly see you, and surely that
can only be because you work so hard?
Ah, good, the claret.
Daisy, this is Littimer, my manservant.
I'm delighted to make
your acquaintance, sir.
I trust I find you well tonight.
Very well, thank you.
How will you spend
your holiday, Mr Copperfield?
I intend to visit my old nurse.
I haven't seen her in years.
Her brother lives in a boat
on Yarmouth Sands.
You remember him. He and his
nephew visited me at Creakle's once.
I think I have some recollection.
Rustic types, weren't they?
Their home is a magical place.
You really ought to see it.
Ought I? Well, why not?
I have nothing else very pressing.
I'll come with you.
- Do you mean it?
- Certainly!
It might be amusing
to mix with that sort of people.
But do tell me. "That sort of people".
Are they really animals and clods
and beings of another order?
- I would so like to know.
- They're not as sensitive as we are.
I dare say
they are wonderfully virtuous,
but their natures are very coarse.
Their delicacy is not to be
shocked or hurt very easily.
Really? It's so consoling to find
that when they suffer, they don't feel!
Sometimes I have been quite uneasy
for "that sort of people".
But now I shalljust dismiss
the idea of them altogether.
(HARP BEING PLAYED)
I was fascinated by Miss Dartle,
and the strange hold
she had over Steerforth.
Don't stop, Rosa.
You haven't played for me in years.
Come, Rosa. From now on
we shall love each other very much.
- What happened?
- You have to be careful with Rosa.
She is always dangerous.
Have you noticed
that remarkable scar on her lip?
Of course.
I did that.
I was a young boy
and she exasperated me,
so I threw a hammer at her.
What a promising young angel
I must have been!
This is delightful, Daisy.
Just the tonic for a weary soul
(DAVID) I don't believe you are
half as jaded as you say.
I don't believe you can possibly be
as honest and good as you pretend.
Not compared to you, at any rate.
I'll see you back at the inn when
you've grown tired of being cried over.
Does Mr Barkis still
go over to Blunderstone, ma'am?
He do, but he's bad abed
with the rheumatics.
I want to see an old house.
The Rookery, I think it's called.
My darling boy!
Peggotty!
It's better than a pint of liniment
to see you again, Master Davy.
What was the name
I wrote up in the cart, sir?
We had some grave talks
on that matter, didn't we?
I was willing a long time.
A long time, Mr Barkis.
I don't regret it.
C.P. Barkis is the usefullest
and the best of women.
All the praise that anyone
could give C.P. Barkis
she deserves, and more.
I'm a poor man, sir.
And I am sorry to hear it.
Very poor indeed.
Old clothes.
I wish it was full of money,
but it ain't. It's old clothes.
I understand.
Barkis has grown
a little nearer with time.
I remembered Mr Peggoty's boat
as a quiet, homely place,
but as Steerforth and I approached,
it soon became clear
that this was no ordinary night.
(SHOUTING AND LAUGHTER
FROM INSIDE)
(DAN) This is the happiest day
of my life!
Master Davy, it's Master Davy!
(HAM) Master Davy!
(DAN) Davy boy!
Mr Peggotty, this is Steerforth,
an old friend from school
- You don't look a day older.
- Good to see you after so long.
Why that you two
should come to this here roof
tonight of all nights of my life.
What do you think, then?
What do you think?
Only that this girl,
who I brought up from a baby,
and loved better than a daughter,
only that she's going to be married!
Emily!
(DAN LAUGHS)
My warmest congratulations.
And who is the lucky fellow?
- Ham!
- Who else but Ham?
Two years past, he asked her
and she comes to me
and says she couldn't have him.
"Him that I've known so intimately
all my life," she says.
"And loved like a brother,
I can never have him."
And that was the end of it.
Until tonight, when he comes crying out
to me alljoyful, "She'll be my wife!"
And she says, "Yes, uncle. I've
changed me mind, if you please."
If I please!
I'd lay down my life for Emily.
She's all to me that ever I can want.
There ain't a gentlemen in all the land,
nor yet sailing upon the sea,
that can love his lady
more than I love her.
Ham.
I give you joy. May you always
be as happy as you are tonight.
(STEERFORTH) He's
a chuckle-headed type for the girl
You're not with
Miss Dartle now, Steerforth.
I could see for myself
how much you liked him.
You see clean through me, Daisy.
I am defenceless against you.
Thank you.
Emily!
I'm not good enough for Ham.
I'm cross and changeable with him
when he is never so to me.
Why am I so often harsh when all
I should think of is making him happy?
You do make him happy.
Anyone can see that.
It would have been better
if he'd found someone else.
Ham would rather die
than be with anyone but you.
Don't say that!
I'm not worthy of him!
I should be a hundred times
more thankful for his goodness.
I should feel what a blessed thing it is
to be the wife of a good man
and to lead a peaceful life.
Once you are married, all these
worries and fears will fall away.
- What do you think of her, Daisy?
- She's handsome enough. Why?
I've just bought her.
- But you might never come back.
- I don't know about that.
I find I've taken a fancy to the place.
She must be newly-rigged, though.
I'm leaving Littimer behind
to see it done.
I've decided to give her
a new name - "The Little Em'ly".
(DAVID) All she ever wanted
was to love and be loved in return.
Think on the happy times, Davy.
Not what came after.
I felt many emotions
as I lingered by my mother's grave,
but it was the thought of Dora
that stirred me from my melancholy.
Reflecting on the past, I knew with
certainty that my future lay with her
and that I could not rest
until I had declared myself.
If your poor mother
could see you now,
she'd be that vain her pretty head
would be completely turned.
Goodbye, Peggotty. When I come back,
I'll have important news for you.
- What news?
- I'm going to be married.
Only the lady in question
doesn't know it yet.
- Who is she?
- Dora. Her name's Dora!
My darling boy!
(COACHMAN) Go on!
Steerforth?
I wish to God I had had a judicious father
these last twenty years.
I wish with all my soul
I had been better guided.
I wish I could guide myself better.
- What do you mean?
- Nothing, Daisy, nothing.
I am bad company for myself
sometimes, that is all
If anything should ever separate us,
you must promise me
that you'll think of me at my best.
- Will you do that?
- Why should we ever be separated?
Just promise me, can't you?
Remember me at my best.
Never more would I
touch his hand in friendship,
never more hear his laughter or feel
the warmth of his companionship.
May God forgive you, Steerforth.
I cannot.
My dear Copperfield!
This is luxurious.
A way of life which reminds me
of a period when I was myself a bachelor.
Happy days, now, alas, gone forever.
- Micawber! Have I deserved this?
- Deserved what?
- You wish that we had never married.
- My love!
This is my reward, Mr Copperfield!
- I who will never desert him!
- Forgive me, Emma!
I am a wife and mother,
and I swear I never will desert him.
My dear, no one is urging you
to do anything of the sort, least of all me.
- You don't regret our nuptial vows, then?
- Impossible! Unthinkable!
Oh...
- Sit down, my dear.
- Yes.
Ah! Shall I do the honours,
Copperfield?
Are you aware, Mr Copperfield,
that we are shortly to leave the metropolis
to cast our lot among strangers?
In short, Copperfield,
something has at last turned up.
Where?
I have recently
entered into arrangements
by virtue of which
I stand pledged and contracted
as a confidential clerk
to a mutual friend.
Heep.
A man of remarkable
shrewdness and perspicacity.
I am convinced
Micawber will flourish in a situation
so suited to his fertile resources.
I am sure he will be a judge,
or even a chancellor, one day.
To Copperfield,
the companion of my youth.
And to Heep, my friend and protector.
The time had come to know my fate.
I called on Dora at the first opportunity.
Happiness or misery
was now the question,
and only she
could give the answer to it.
Be quiet, you naughty boy!
I came here today to tell you...
Jip! Quiet, please!
- I came here today to tell you...
- Jip, come back here! Bad boy!
Mr Copperfield!
I came here today
to tell you that I love you.
I have loved you
since the first moment I saw you
and I will always love you.
- We hardly know each other!
- One minute was enough.
I love you, Dora.
With all my heart.
Forgive me.
I shall go now.
Please don't.
Dora...
Aunt! Mr Dick!
I'm ruined.
Betsey Trotwood - I don't mean
your sister, Trot, but myself -
had a certain property and
for years that property did pretty well
and returned good interest.
But her man of business,
being no longer the man
of business he once was,
she took it into her head
to remove it from his hands
and invest it for herself.
First, she lost it in the mining way.
Then she lost it
in the shipping and banking way.
And finally, she lost the lot.
And the least said about it,
soonest mended.
- Is Mr Wickfield to blame for this?
- The blame is entirely my own.
Well, the cottage is let
at 70 pounds per annum,
which is all which we have to live on.
So here we are, my dear Trot.
And you haven't a penny in the world!
What do you have to say to that?
You know I've often
thought about writing.
Mm?
I could work in the mornings
before I go to Doctor's Commons.
- And I have 100 pounds a year.
- Which you should keep for yourself.
- We must meet our reverses boldly.
- Boldly!
Boldly. And not suffer them
to frighten us.
We shall act the play out
and live misfortune down!
- A beggar? Love a beggar?
- I am now a beggar.
How can you be such a silly thing
and sit there telling stories?
- I'll make Jip bite you.
- This must be our secret for now.
I cannot speak to Mr Spenlow
about our engagement
until I've begun to make my fortune.
A secret engagement?
How romantic, Doady!
When we are married,
if our income is to be small,
we must try to be practical
Please don't be practical
because it frightens me so.
If you will sometimes
look at your papa's housekeeping
and perhaps study cookery...
You are determined
to frighten me out of my wits!
With perseverance and strength
of character, we can bear anything.
But I haven't got
any strength. Have I, Jip?
Oh, do kiss Jip
and stop being so disagreeable.
Jip will have to wait his turn.
I will feel happier when I've spoken
to Mr Wickfield about our situation.
And no doubt you will be
glad of an excuse to see Agnes.
I can't feel comfortable until I know
her opinion of my engagement to Dora.
Oh. So you imagine yourself
in love, do you?
Imagine?
Yes, I suppose you think
you were made for each other,
and are to go through
a children's party kind of life
like two pretty pieces of confectionary!
Blind, Trot, blind!
We are young and inexperienced,
I know, but we love one another truly.
And she's neither silly
nor light-headed, I suppose?
Dora is fascinating
and sweet and beautiful
Blind, Trot, blind.
Returning to Canterbury,
I felt Agnes's gentle influence
reaching out to me.
It seemed to pervade
even the city in which she dwelt.
Yet as I approached
Mr Wickfield's house,
my happiness gave way
to a growing sense of dread
about what I might find within.
(DOOR BEING CLOSED)
This is a bad business of your aunt.
I came here to discover
if anything might be done.
Nothing, Mr Copperfield,
nothing at all
It's all gone
and no one is to blame but herself.
She has been very reckless.
Isn't that right, Mr Wickfield?
Quite right.
You'll stay with us, Trotwood,
while you remain in Canterbury?
Uriah is a great relief to me.
It's a load of my mind
to have such a partner.
My dear Copperfield!
So how do you like the law,
Mr Micawber?
It is a great pursuit, sir.
To a man of higher imaginative powers
such as myself,
it is perhaps over-reliant on detail
A mind is not at liberty to soar
to any exalted forms of expression.
Still, it is a great pursuit.
Do you see much of Mr Wickfield?
Mr Wickfield is a man
of very excellent qualities...
...but he is, in short, obsolete.
I am afraid his partner
seeks to make him so.
My dear Copperfield.
I am here in the capacity
of confidence and trust.
The discussion of some topics,
even with Mrs Micawber herself,
is incompatible with the functions
now devolving upon me.
Do not ask, 'umble as I am,
to speak of the affairs
of my friend Heep.
(FOOTSTEPS)
Wouldn't you say my Ury
is quite the gentleman these days, sir?
Indeed, Mrs Heep.
(WHISPERING)
How long has she been living here?
- Months.
- Does she never leave you alone?
It is certainly difficult
to avoid her company.
My dear sister.
I have missed you so much lately.
I wanted to talk to you
about Dora.
We are to be married.
She is the most wonderful girl
in the world
and I know that you
will come to love her as well as I do.
How could I not love anyone
who thinks so much of you?
Promise not to abandon me
when I become an old, married man.
You know how I rely on you.
It is Dora you must rely on now.
Of course.
I will always be
your devoted friend and sister, Trot.
Wherever our separate paths
may lead us, you may rely on that.
(AGNES) Shall we retire, Mrs Heep?
Father, go to bed soon.
I'll give you a toast, gentlemen.
To the divinest of her sex.
I'm a 'umble individual
to give you her health,
but I do admire, no, adore her.
Choose some other toast, Uriah.
Agnes Wickfield,
the divinest of her sex.
Who else can propose it
if not the man who would be her husband?
Never! Never!
Have you gone mad, Wickfield?
I have as good a right to her
as any other man.
I have a better right
than any other man.
Look at my torturer.
Always at my elbow,
whispering his venom.
In my house, in my business...
Like a millstone around my neck,
bringing me to my ruin!
Take care, Wickfield!
Without me you would have
no house or business, nor reputation.
(WICKFIELD WAILS)
Your safety is in my hands, remember?
Oh, what have I come to, Trotwood?
My weak indulgence has ruined me.
God knows what I have done
in my misery of oblivion!
Have you ever picked a pear
before it was ripe, Mr Copperfield?
What?
I did that when
I spoke of Miss Agnes.
But the pear will ripen yet.
I can wait.
There must be two parties
to a quarrel, Copperfield.
And I won't be one.
- Father is quite recovered.
- Is there nothing that can be done?
His first words when he woke
were to send apologies to Uriah.
- He is more in his power than ever.
- Promise me one thing.
Promise me you will never sacrifice
yourself to a mistaken sense of duty.
Agnes, you can't be
considering marriage to that...
...reptile!
Goodbye, Trotwood.
My return to London
was tormented by thoughts
of the fate that lay in wait for Agnes.
Little now stood between Heep
and the final success of his scheming.
It was with a heavy heart
that I made my way
to Mr Spenlow's office
at the Doctor's Commons,
only to find that
a further catastrophe awaited.
You have abused my confidence and
committed a dishonourable action!
- I love Dora to such an extent...
- Miss Spenlow, if you please!
And I beg that you won't
speak to me of love or engagements.
My daughter is not
to be thrown away on a clerk!
Now let there be
an end to this nonsense.
Take these letters away
and throw them on the fire.
You must forget her, Mr Copperfield!
Soon after this disastrous encounter,
a letter arrived from Peggotty informing
me that Barkis was in a very poor way
and she feared he would soon
be making his final journey.
I resolved to go
to Yarmouth immediately,
though not before attending
to the matter closest to my heart.
I'll never give Dora up
and the sooner Mr Spenlow
knows that, the better.
I'll see him this morning
on my way down.
Mr Spenlow?
Mr Spenlow's death from a heart
seizure threw everything into confusion.
I was desperate to see Dora,
but she blamed her attachment to me
for her papa's untimely end.
She cannot see you, Mr Copperfield.
The floodgates of sorrow are open
and her grief is not to be assuaged.
If I could just send her a note
or a token of my sympathy...
Powerless to do anything for Dora,
I finally made my way to Yarmouth.
- How is he, Peggotty?
- He is fading fast.
This is kind of you, Master Davy.
Uncommon kind.
Barkis, my dear. Here's Master Davy,
who brought us together!
Old clothes!
Old clothes...
He's going out with the tide.
People can't die along the coast,
except when the tide's pretty nigh out.
Barkis, my dear.
C.P. Barkis.
No better woman anywhere.
Barkis is willing.
I have looked over Mr Barkis's will
and opened the box.
- There was over 3,000 pounds inside.
- 3,000?!
He leaves the interest
on 1,000 to Mr Peggotty
and the rest goes to you.
Not bad for old clothes!
Mr Littimer!
I ain't a person to live with them
as has had money left.
Things go too contrary with me.
I had better be a riddance.
How should I spend it without you?
Don't I want you now more than ever?
I know'd I was never wanted before,
and now I'm told so!
How could I expect to be wanted,
being so lone and lorn?
Lord!
(MRS GUMMIDGE WEEPS)
Master Davy?
Will you step outside for a minute?
I would have died for her.
I'd die for her now!
She's gone, Master Davy.
Emily's gone.
And not alone.
How am I ever to break it to him?
When? How did this happen?
Read it, sir.
Slow, please, so I can take it all in.
"When you, who loved me
so much better than I deserved, see this,
"I shall be far away, never to return,
unless he brings me back a lady.
"Try to think as if I died when I was little,
and was buried somewhere."
She begs forgiveness and tells Ham
to find another more worthy of him.
Who's the man?
I want to know his name!
It ain't no fault of yours.
You couldn't have known.
The servant was seen
with our poor girl last night.
He's been hiding about here
this week or more.
He was out this afternoon
on the Norwich road,
only now his master was with him.
Steerforth?
No, no! He couldn't!
(DAN WAILS)
I knew in my heart
she didn't love me like I loved her.
If I hadn't pressed
my affections on her,
she might have come to me
in the old friendly way
and told me what
was struggling in her mind.
I might have saved her.
You are not to blame, Ham.
Never think that.
I'll take care of Ham, my love.
Don't you worry yourself about that.
My duty here is done.
I'm going to seek my niece.
That's my duty now.
Why do you come here.
What do you want of me?
I want to know if he will do
as he promised and marry her.
Impossible.
A marriage to someone
so far below him
would destroy his career and
ruin his prospects. It will never happen.
If there is any other compensation...
You offer me money as compensation
for my niece's disgrace and ruin?
What compensation can you make for
opening a pit between me and my son?
What is your love to mine?
What is your separation to ours?
My son has been
the object of my life.
My every thought has been devoted
to him, his every wish indulged.
And now he takes up
with a miserable beggar girl
and repays my devotion
with deception.
You speak of your injury?
I come here with no hope,
and I take none away.
Good day, ma'am.
You do well to bring him here!
He's deeply injured,
though you don't seem to know it.
I would have his house torn down
and see her branded on the face!
If I could hunt her
to the grave, I would do it.
Chances are they're
in foreign parts by now.
The sooner I go,
the quicker I'll find them.
You know where I may be reached.
Look out for yourself, old girl
I've got my garden and a little money
now, Dan. Don't worry about me.
If any hurt should come to me,
remember the last words I left for
my child were "love" and "forgiveness".
(DOOR BEING CLOSED)
Aunt!
You remember Peggotty?
For the love of God, don't call her
by that South Sea island name!
She married, didn't she?
What is your name now, Pegg...?
Barkis, ma'am.
You see, that's human.
It sounds less as if
you needed a missionary.
We are older than we were, I see.
How are you, Barkis?
I am heartily sorry for your loss.
Thank you, ma'am. I'm quite well
Oh, yes! Yes, Mr Dick.
It came from Doctor's Commons
while you were away, Trot.
The firm has collapsed
with heavy debts.
Mr Spenlow was bankrupt.
There is nothing left.
Does this mean
Miss Spenlow is destitute?
- I must go to her.
- Oh, Trot!
Oh, Mr Dick!
Shh... That's all right.
It's all right.
I shall take care of you now.
You are still mine, aren't you, Dora?
Of course I am!
It's just that I am so frightened!
There's no need to be afraid.
But we have nothing!
We have everything.
I took with fear
and trembling to authorship.
I wrote a little something
and sent it to a magazine.
It was published.
I wrote more and quickly began
to make a steady income,
enough for Dora and I
to contemplate the future with optimism.
(COACHMAN) Whoa!
I have forgotten what relation
Agnes is to you, Doady.
No blood relation, but we were
brought up like brother and sister.
Dora.
Agnes is so warm and kind.
I was quite frightened of her before,
but now I feel so calm
and peaceful in her company.
I wonder that you
ever fell in love with me.
How could I see you
and not love you?
Don't you think that if I had been
her friend a long time ago,
I might perhaps
have been more clever?
You would prefer me
if I was, wouldn't you?
- What nonsense!
- Is it, Doady? Are you sure?
And so we were married.
The bridesmaids were gone
and the celebrations were over,
and Dora and I
were left alone at last.
Are you happy now, you foolish boy?
But Doady, what shall I do with this?
Jump, Jip.
My love, do you think Mary Anne
has any idea of time?
- Why, Doady?
- Dinner should be at five. It is now six.
I doubt whether two young birds could
have known less about keeping house
than I and my pretty wife did, for the
same thing happened again and again.
- Don't!
- Why not?
- She looks so tired, poor thing.
- Tired? She's drunk!
But she has so many children,
who are a great trial to her.
- Would you carve, Mr Micawber?
- No, no, no.
My pride at hosting
our first dinner together knew no limits,
but alas, the outcome was not
the triumph I had anticipated.
Mutton should always be rare.
Perhaps we should start
with the oysters.
I'm afraid there's something the matter
with them. They don't seem right.
There's nothing wrong.
Capital oysters, in fact.
Only, they have never been opened.
All that is required
for a delightful repast is an oyster knife.
(MICAWBER) No? No matter.
How does Micawber
seem to you, Mr Copperfield?
A little subdued, perhaps.
He is entirely reserved.
He is secret.
He has become severe
to his children
and even looks with an eye of coldness
on the unoffending little stranger
recently added to our familial circle.
It's hard to bear.
Mr Micawber is not the same
since he fell in with Uriah Heep!
(MICAWBER GROANS)
Erm...
Soup, perhaps?
Soup?
Oh, dear...
(BETSEY) You must have
patience with her, Trot.
Just a few words here and there.
Teach her
a little firmness, you mean?
Don't ask me such a thing, Trot.
The outcome would only be failure,
misery for Dora,
and division between us.
(BETSEY) Judge her by the qualities
she has, not by those she lacks.
I was content
to heed my aunt's advice,
but the happiness I had once
anticipated for myself eluded me,
and there was always
something wanting.
I had no equal partner
in the toils and cares of our life.
Yet my decision
to adapt myself to Dora
made our second year
much happier than our first,
and when I learnt
that she was expecting a child,
it seemed our joy
might yet be complete.
But already, dark clouds
had begun to gather around us.
You may go up now. She's resting.
She might still have a child one day?
Your wife is very weak,
Mr Copperfield.
When I can run about again,
I shall make Jip race with me.
You are getting quite slow and lazy.
He has a worse disorder
than laziness, my dear.
Age.
Oh, poor Jip!
How strange that he should be old.
Even little Jip.
Let Jip have his rest.
I'll give you another dog to race with.
Oh, I couldn't have any other dog.
You are not so old, Jip, are you,
that you'll leave your mistress yet?
We may still keep each other
company a little longer.
We shall both be running about
again soon, as we used to do.
Anxious as I was about Dora,
I never forgot Dan Peggotty,
who travelled restlessly
across Europe,
never wavering in the certainty
that he would find his niece.
- How long is it since your return?
- A month.
And still no news?
If she were ever to leave him, London
is where she'd come to lose herself.
These are the places
I must look for her now.
Emily?
Emily!
If you need me, sir,
send word here.
Many a time in me sleep,
I heard her cry out, "Uncle!"
And fall like death before me.
Many a time I raised her up
and whispered to her,
"Emily, my dear.
I am come for to bring forgiveness,
"and to take you home."
I sent for you because there is news.
She has run away.
Tell him what you know.
Mr Steerforth and myself have been
abroad with the young woman
ever since she left Yarmouth
under his protection.
She was much admired
wherever we went.
The whole thing lasted longer
than anyone might have expected,
but, at last, Mr Steerforth grew restless
and charged me with breaking the news
to the young woman that he was gone.
Mr Steerforth proposed
that the young woman should marry
a very respectable person who was
fully prepared to overlook the past.
- You!
- Her conduct was surprisingly bad.
- She showed no gratitude at all
- Get him out of here.
This low girl he picked
out of the tide mud may be dead.
If not, it is in both our interests
that she be found.
She must not be allowed
to prey on him again.
You wrong her most grievously.
Is he informed of everything, Rosa?
Then there is nothing else
to detain you here, Mr Copperfield.
I am told you have
some reputation as a writer now.
I find my name
connected with a little praise.
It is a pity you have no mother.
She would have been proud of you.
Do you mind if I say
something very, very silly?
More than usual, I mean.
I feel so foolish sitting here quite idle.
I want to do something to help
while you are so industrious.
Please. Let me hold the pens for you.
Thank you, sir.
Stop here!
Go to the inn in Buckingham Street
and ask for a Mr Peggotty.
Bring him here in ten minutes
and I will double it.
(EMILY)... it was before I turned
my back on everyone I ever loved!
(ROSA) Your home? Do you think
I care about your home?
You were bought and sold like any
other commodity your people deal in.
- Say anything you like...
- (DAVID) Emily!
(EMILY) I believed him, loved him!
- (DAN) Master Davey, where are you.?
- She dares to speak of her love!
- Emily! Oh, my girl!
- Uncle!
Tell this piece of pollution
to hide herself beyond reach
or to seek some obscure death.
If she is still here tomorrow,
I will see her whipped.
Nobody is going to say
a cruel word about my darling again.
We'll go where nobody knows us,
to the ends of the earth if we have to.
Mr Peggotty resolved that
they must start a new life in Australia.
Knowing that she would
never again return to her home,
Emily begged me
to take a letter to Ham.
I solemnly accepted her commission,
but on my arrival in Yarmouth,
I found the town deserted
and a dreadful storm raging.
(BELLS ARE RUNG)
- What's going on?
- A clipper from Spain has foundered!
She's breaking up!
- Davy!
- Is there nothing can be done?
- (PEGGOTTY) It's too dangerous!
- God have mercy on his soul
It's Steerforth!
For God's sake, Ham,
don't go in there.
I can't stand by
and watch a man drown.
It's Steerforth!
(PEGGOTTY) Ham! No!
Please don't go!
(PEGGOTTY) Ham!
(PEGGOTTY) He's reached him!
Pull them in! Pull!
(DAVID) Pull! Pull!
(DAVID) Pull harder! Haul them in!
For God's sake, pull!
Pull harder!
(DAVID) Ham!
Ham!
HAM!!
(BELLS TOLL)
(WOMAN WAILING)
The other's come ashore, sir.
Dead? In Yarmouth?
(DAVID) No one will ever know
why he was there.
I can only hope that he came
to make amends to Emily and her family.
(ROSA) Why did you not forgive him?
(MRS STEERFORTH WEEPS)
Look at your dead child's handiwork.
Your pampering
of his pride and passion did this!
- Look and cry for what you made him.
- Miss Dartle!
I will speak!
I could have loved him
and asked for no return.
I would have been his slave
for one kind word a year.
Your love was proud and selfish!
At least show some feeling
for a mother's grief.
Who feels for me?
There, there. Hush.
Hush.
It was an evil hour
he ever brought you to this house.
Is there something wrong, Doady?
No, I'm fine. Nothing at all
Mr Micawber.
I put my hand in no man's hand,
until I have blown to fragments
that detestable serpent Heep!
You must go to Canterbury, Doady.
If you don't I shall be very cross and
disagreeable and make Jip bark at you.
Trot can go. I shall stay here.
Why shouldn't you both go?
I have Peggotty now.
I'm not so very ill, am I?
- No, of course not!
- What a question!
Well, then. You must go,
or I shall begin to think
I'm really ill and cry all day!
- Is Miss Trotwood with you?
- She is on her way.
Everything is prepared, Copperfield.
Well, I am sure,
this is an unexpected pleasure!
Don't wait, Micawber.
Go along. I'll talk to you presently.
If there is a scoundrel on this earth with
whom I have already talked too much,
that scoundrel's name is Heep!
Oh, I see it now...
This is a conspiracy.
You have corrupted my clerk.
Deal with him
as he deserves, Mr Micawber.
- Ury...
- Hold your tongue, Mother.
They'll gain nothing
listening to this pompous fool
Approach me again, you heap of
infamy, and it will be your head. Chair!
This scoundrel, Heep,
employed me
in the belief that I shared
the baseness of his nature.
I found my services constantly required
for the falsification of business
and the mystification of Mr Wickfield.
Ask this wretch, Heep, if you will,
who lives in his house after him.
You do, you imbecile.
Ask him if he kept a pocket book
of his transactions
in that house
which he later tried to burn?
Ury, be 'umble
and make terms, my dear!
This villain, Heep,
tricked the honourable Mr W.
Into believing that he had withdrawn
a sum from Miss Trotwood's trust fund,
namely 12,000 pounds.
Which, in truth, Heep took out himself
with a forged signature.
Ever since, he has
used this supposed criminal act
to torture, constrain
and bend him to his will
Proof of all this lies within, madam.
In short, Mr Wickfield
has been for years
deluded and plundered
in every conceivable way
to the financial advantage of
the avaricious, false and grasping Heep!
No, my son will be 'umble,
Mr Copperfield,
if you willjust give him time to think.
Where is my property?
Blame Mr Wickfield
for mishandling it, would you?
I should have guessed all along
that you were responsible for my ruin!
Your money is quite safe, Aunt.
I only took her money
to ruin you, Copperfield.
I have always hated you.
You've always been against me
and my love for Agnes.
Love?
Your selfish, grasping desire would have
forced me into a marriage I didn't want,
and you talk about love.
- Mr Dick?
- Yes.
Will you go around to the Guildhall
and bring a couple of officers?
I shall return post-haste
with the forces of the law.
- Shall I go now?
- Post-haste, Mr Dick.
Running is futile.
You have nowhere to go.
I shall send for my family immediately.
The veil that has long been interposed
between Mrs Micawber and myself
is now withdrawn.
And my children
and the author of their being
can once more meet on equal terms.
Mr Micawber. It seems
you are in need of a fresh start.
Indeed, madam.
I wonder if you have ever
turned your mind to emigration?
It was the dream of my youth.
Why not go now?
Capital, madam, or rather
the lack of it, is the issue.
You have done us a great service.
What if we were to find you
the capital in return?
I could not take it as a gift.
But if a sufficient sum could be
advanced at five per cent per annum...
It shall be done in any way you wish.
One question arises.
Are the circumstance of the country such
that a man of Micawber's abilities
would have a fair chance
of rising in the social scale?
I will not say, "Might he aspire
to be Governor?" at present...
- There is no better opening anywhere.
- No better.
No better.
Then it is evident that Australia
is the legitimate sphere of action for him!
Passage was booked
for the Micawbers
and suddenly it was time
to say farewell
(DAVID) Mr Micawber?
You look very well equipped,
Mr Micawber.
We have abandoned the luxuries
of the old country, Copperfield.
Forest dwellers such as ourselves
cannot expect to participate in
the refinements of the land of the free.
I am sure there are towns
of some description in Australia,
but I feel it wise to be prepared.
- Wilkins Micawber?
- Yes.
I have a warrant for your arrest
on a matter of non-payment
of certain outstanding bills.
All hope is extinguished!
Convey my family to the workhouse
and forget that a being
such as I ever lived.
- We shall never leave without you!
- What is the value of the bills?
Nine pounds,
nineteen shillings and sixpence.
Ha! A mere trifle.
(MICAWBER) A noble gesture, ma'am,
that will be repaid, with interest.
Thank you, ma'am.
Copperfield. The time has come
for us to take our leave.
- There will be no speeches on my part.
- I don't believe a word of it.
I say, there will be
no speeches from me.
Only, in short...
...farewell, old friend.
God go with you, Mr Micawber.
God go with all of you.
(MICAWBER) Come on, we must board.
(MR DICK) Bye!
- Bye.
Bye. Bye.
Bye-bye!
Thank you!
Mr Micawber and his family
were not alone on their journey that day.
The time had also come
to say goodbye to other old friends.
Fearful for Emily's health, Peggotty
insisted that the news of Ham's death
should be kept from her
until she was stronger.
We'll start a new life together.
It is so good to see you well again.
When you gave Ham my letter,
did he say anything?
His love is with you always.
And forgiveness?
Did he send forgiveness?
With all his heart.
I did ask this one to come with us,
but you see, she's that fond of you
and your, Master Davy,
that it wouldn't be
hardly fair to let her go.
I told him straight out,
"My place is here now, Davy."
(STEWARD) Passengers on board!
(WAILING)
Will I ever see my little boy again?
Be 'umble, Ury, as you always was!
I was dreaming a moment ago.
I thought we were in the park again.
Walking together arm in arm.
It was so pleasant.
I am quite sad to wake up.
Don't be sad. We'll go there again soon.
Doady, dear.
I am afraid
I was too young to be married.
Don't say such things.
I was such a silly little creature.
I think it might have been better
if we had only loved each other
as boy and girl, and then forgotten it.
I don't think I was fit to be a wife.
- As fit as I to be a husband.
- Perhaps.
But you are clever...
...and I never was, and never could be.
We have been happy, Dora.
Very happy.
But as the years went on,
you would have wearied of your little wife.
I would have tried,
and disappointed you.
And you might not have been
able to love me half so well as now.
Do not speak to me so.
Every word seems a reproach.
I love you too much
for reproachful words.
It's the only merit I have,
except being pretty.
Oh, how my poor boy cries.
Will you ask Agnes
to come up, Doady?
I want to speak to her quite alone.
Don't cry, Doady.
It is better as it is.
Not tonight, Jip. Not tonight.
I went as far away as I could,
not knowing, even then,
how great the shock was
that I had to bear.
A long and gloomy night
gathered about me,
haunted by the ghosts of many hopes,
many errors, many sorrows and regrets.
Agnes wrote to me often.
She gave me no advice,
she urged no duty on me.
She only told me
what her trust in me was,
how a nature such as mine
would turn affliction to good.
But I mourned for Dora, taken so
young from the world she loved.
For Steerforth, who might have won
the love and admiration of thousands
as all those years ago
he had won mine.
And for broken- hearted Ham, who
found peace at last in the stormy sea.
I worked early and late, patiently and
hard, until my first book was finished.
It was published and was successful
I began another immediately.
Three years passed in this way.
I might have gone on the same forever,
but one day I looked up from my work
and suddenly I knew
it was time to return.
It was as though I could hear
a voice calling me home.
Agnes's voice.
Thank you, Peggotty.
What will you do now, Trot?
I thought I might ride over
to Canterbury tomorrow.
- Is Mr Wickfield well.
- A better man in all respects.
A reclaimed man.
- And Agnes?
- As good and beautiful as always.
Has she any admirers?
Dozens.
D-d-dozens.
- But is anyone worthy of her?
- I suspect she has an attachment.
I think she is going to be married.
(AGNES) Will you go away again.?
(DAVID) Perhaps. There is
little enough to hold me here.
You have a secret.
Let me share it.
- A secret?
- There is someone close to your heart.
My aunt told me. Confide in me.
Let me be your friend and brother
in this as in so many other things.
- What have I done?
- I am not myself.
Don't speak to me now.
We'll talk later.
If you have a burden,
let me lighten it.
I must go.
If you have a lover, you can tell me.
The attachment I have is not
a new one. It is not what you suppose.
I cannot reveal it! It has long been mine
and must remain mine.
Agnes...
You love me?
I have loved you all my life.
- For God's sake, let me go.
- What have I ever been without you?
- You mean as a sister?
- No.
Much more than that.
I went away loving you,
I stayed away loving you,
and I have returned home loving you.
Do you remember how Dora
sent for me the night that she died?
She made me
promise something to her.
What was it?
She told me that only I could occupy
this empty space in your heart.
(CHILDREN'S LAUGHTER)
Trotwood! We have a visitor.
(DAN LAUGHS)
Maybe things were a little hard at first,
but what with sheep farming
and one thing and another,
we are as well to do as well could be.
And Emily?
She might have married
any number of times.
"But Uncle," she says to me,
"that's gone forever."
That's my Emily.
There's happy news of someone else
you might recall, sir.
"Mr Wilkins Micawber,
magistrate, writer, famed public orator,
"and manager of
the Port Middlebay Bank,
"was fted at a public dinner
this Thursday last.
"Far be it from us to follow
our distinguished townsman
"through the smoothly-flowing periods of
his polished and highly ornate address!"
...and the Lord Chancellor
turned to me and said,
"By God, Micawber, you're right.
The law must be changed."
(LAUGHTER)
"It was a masterpiece of eloquence,
"and those passages in which he traced
his own brilliantly successful career,
"with particular emphasis
on the importance
"of avoiding
pecuniary liabilities at all costs,
"brought a tear
to the manliest eye present."
I would like to introduce you to
the greatest person I have ever known.
My lovely wife, Emma.
(APPLAUSE)
(CLOCK STRIKES)
And so my story
draws to its close.
There was a night much like this
many years ago, Trot.
Except perhaps for one more item
that demands to be recorded.
Our first two children had been boys.
It's a girl
A beautiful little girl
(BABY IS WHIMPERING)
She shall be called
Betsey Trotwood Copperfield
in honour of her godmother.
Watch Movies, TV Series & Live Sports
www.admitme.app