Look, what is this? I'm supposed to...
Colonel Tan-Sun Moon's H.Q.
De-Militarised Zone North Korea.
Open the bag.
That will teach you to lecture me.
Retract the blast doors.
Find me a new anger therapist.
I am Zao.
You are late.
Mr. Van Bierk. I've been looking
forward to this meeting.
Me too.
My African military friends owe
you many thanks, Colonel Moon.
Few men have the guts to trade conflict
diamonds since the U.N. embargo.
I know all about the U.N. I
studied at Oxford and Harvard.
Majored in Western hypocrisy.
From your modest collection of
cars, I wouldn't have guessed.
Show me the diamonds.
Show me the weapons.
Bring the weapons.
Hiding weapons in the de-militarised zone.
- It's a bit of a minefield out there.
- America's cultural contribution.
One million landmines. And my
hovercrafts float right over them.
RPGs, flamethrowers, automatic weapons...
and enough ammunition to run a small war.
My diamonds?
Check it over quick.
Don't blow it all at once.
I have special plans for this consignment.
His name is James Bond, a British assassin.
Mr. Van Bierk, let me show you something.
Our new tank buster.
Depleted uranium shells, naturally.
Naturally.
And how do you propose to
kill me now, Mr. Bond?
It's pathetic that you British still beliee
you have the right to police the world.
You will not live to see the day
all Korea is ruled by the North.
Then you and I have something in common.
Who is it?
Where's my son?
It's the General.
Hello... Father.
Why is there a fire?
I'll be there in five minutes.
Get the weapons out of here.
And kill the spy.
Saved by the bell.
My son is dead.
14 months later
I don't condone what they do here.
Tell it to the concierge.
Still you jest.
Defiant to the last.
Your people have abandoned you.
Your very existence denied.
Why stay silent?
It doesn't matter anymore.
Things are out of my hands.
We reach the end, Mr. Bond.
Spare me the unpleasantries.
Fifty years after the superpowers
carved Korea in two...
and then you arrive.
A British spy, an assassin.
And now the hard-liners have their proof.
We cannot trust the West.
You...
You took away my son.
Your firing squad should
have done the job for me.
I hoped a Western education would
help him become a bridge...
between our worlds.
But all it did was to corrupt him.
Let's get this over with, shall we?
My son had an ally in the West.
For the last time, who was it?
Who made him betray his country and name?
The same person who betrayed me.
Turn around.
Start walking.
Keep walking, please.
Keep moving.
Zao.
I'm being traded...
for you.
Keep moving. Keep walking, please.
Your time will come.
Not as soon as yours.
Keep walking, please.
Look at him.
Double check.
You'd think he was some kind of a hero.
- Reference nine.
- Sir.
Section four.
Okay, hold him tight. Got him.
Watch his legs now.
All right, let's go.
No biological agents in the prelim scan.
He's clean.
Pulse, 72. Blood pressure, 120/80.
Indications of neurotoxins, histamine,
serotonin and enzyme inhibitors.
Scorpion venom.
Note also traces of a venom antiserum.
They'd sting him then
administer the antidote.
Yet his internal organs seem unaffected.
Liver not too good. It's
definitely him then.
Morning.
Welcome back.
Such hospitality.
You don't seem too pleased to see me.
If I'd had my way, you'd
still be in North Korea.
Your freedom came at too high a price.
Zao.
He tried to blow up a summit
between South Korea and China.
Took out three Chinese
agents before he was caught.
And now he's free.
I never asked to be traded.
I'd rather die than let him loose.
- You had cyanide.
- Threw it away years ago. What is this?
The top American agent...
in the North Korean High Command
was executed a week ago.
The Americans intercepted a signal
from your prison naming him.
- And they think it's me?
- You were the only inmate.
They concluded you cracked and
were hemorrhaging information.
We had to get you out.
And what do you think?
With the drugs they gave you, you
wouldn't know what you said.
I know the rules.
And number one is, no deals.
Get caught and you're given up.
The mission was compromised.
Moon got a call exposing me.
He had a partner in the West.
Even his father knew.
- Whether that's true or not, it's irrelevant.
- No, it isn't.
The same person who set me up
then set me up to get Zao out.
So I'm going after him.
You're going to our evaluation
center in the Falklands.
Double-O status rescinded.
Along with my freedom?
For as long as I deem necessary, yes.
You're no use to anyone now.
- He's in cardiac arrest.
- Get the crash cart. Notify his superiors.
- He's flat-lining on the ECG.
- Stand by.
Two hundred joules.
Three hundred.
Get me some atropine. We're losing him!
Stand by. Clear.
I'm checking out.
Thanks for the kiss of life.
Security breach on level three. All
personnel, defensive code red.
Apprehend and detain with force.
Security breach on level three. All
personnel, defensive code red.
Apprehend and detain with force.
Security breach on level three. All
personnel, defensive code red.
My goodness, standards are falling.
No tie, dear me.
My usual suite, please.
Do you have a credit card?
Or even any luggage, sir?
Mr. Bond, so good to see you.
- It's been a long time.
- Mr. Chang.
Open the Presidential Suite.
Send up my tailor. And some food.
The lobster's good, with quails'
eggs and sliced seaweed.
- And if there's any left, a '61 Bollinger.
- Of course.
Do it... quickly.
Been busy, have we, Mr. Bond?
Just surviving, Mr. Chang. Just surviving.
I am Peaceful Fountains
of Desire, the masseuse.
I come with compliments of the manager.
I'm sure you do. Come in.
On the bed, please. Face down.
Yes, of course.
I'm not that kind of masseuse.
I'm not that kind of customer.
You think I haven't always known
you're Chinese Intelligence, Chang?
- Hong Kong is our turf now.
- Don't worry about it.
I'm not here to take it back.
Put your hands down.
What the hell do you want?
Just to help you settle a score.
Zao killed three of your men.
You get me into North Korea,
I'll take care of him for you.
What's in it for you?
Chance to get even.
Zao has information I need.
- I'll have to ask Beijing.
- Do it.
Now get out.
Unless you really wanna give me a massage.
Mr. Bond.
A little thank-you from us.
Cuba?
It seems Mr. Zao has
lost himself in Havana.
If you find him, say goodbye from us.
With pleasure.
HAVANA
I'm here to pick up some Delectados.
Delectados? We haven't made
Delectados in 30 years.
Universal Exports. Check with your boss.
Raoul...
Universal Exports.
Follow me.
Your passport, se? Or.
I'd come to think the Delectados
would never be smoked.
They are particularly hazardous
for one's health, Mr...?
Bond.
Mr. Bond.
Do you know why?
It's the addition of the Volado tobacco.
Slow burning.
It never goes out.
Just like a sleeper.
Sorry for the rude awakening.
I love my country.
I'd never ask you to betray your people.
- I'm after a North Korean.
- A tourist?
A terrorist.
One man's terrorist is another
man's freedom fighter.
Zao has no interest in
other people's freedom.
I still have some friends in high places.
Favors called in. Some
dollars spread about.
We find your friend is here, on an island.
In Los Organos.
There is a strange clinic
run by Dr. Alvarez.
He leads the field in gene therapy.
Increasing the life expectancy
of our beloved leaders.
And, of course, the richest Westerners.
We may have lost our freedom
in the revolution...
but we have a health system second to none.
You didn't do too badly
out of the revolution.
We all have our ways of getting by.
You'd be surprised how many
government officials come to me...
- ...for reminders of the decadent times.
- Yeah, well...
- Mind if I borrow these?
- Please.
My sources tell me this
Zao is very dangerous.
I wish I could give you more help.
I could use a fast car.
Mojito, por favor.
Mr. Krug, your admittance
papers for the Alvarez Clinic.
About bloody time, Fidel.
Round up more girls and
take them to room 42.
Unless you want to be
known as Fidel Castrato.
Magnificent view.
It is, isn't it?
Too bad it's lost on everybody else.
Mojito?
You should try it.
Giacinta Johnson. My friends call me Jinx.
My friends call me James Bond.
Jinx, you say?
Born on Friday the 13th.
Do you believe in bad luck?
Let's just say my relationships
don't seem to last.
I know the feeling.
The predators usually appear at sunset.
And why is that?
It's when their prey comes out to drink.
Too strong for you?
I could learn to like it.
If I had the time.
How much time have you got?
Until dawn. What about you?
I'm just here for the birds.
Ornithologist.
Ornithologist, huh?
Now there's a mouthful.
So you're gonna be busy
tonight with the owls then?
No owls in Los Organos. Nothing
to see till the morning.
Not out there anyway.
So, what do predators do...
when the sun goes down?
They feast...
like there's no tomorrow.
Are you always this frisky?
I've been missing the
touch of a good woman.
Who says I'm good?
What do you want?
- I don't need a wheelchair.
- No?
You do now.
Se? Or.
- Okay.
- Gracias.
Isla Los Organos.
So you are to have DNA-replacement therapy.
Let me explain the two phases.
First, we kill off your bone marrow.
Wipe the DNA slate clean.
Phase two:
Introduction of new DNA
harvested from healthy donors.
Orphans, runaways...
people that won't be missed.
I like to think of myself as an artist.
And this is when I create.
Thank you.
It is a painful process, I'm afraid, but...
all great art is.
I'll certainly enjoy working on you.
Of course, most artists are
only truly appreciated...
after they're dead.
My father was a sergeant.
We lived in Hampshire.
I have fond memories of the countryside.
Good.
Got your attention.
Who's bankrolling your makeover, Zao?
Same person who set me up in North Korea?
James? What's going on?
Jinx, you gotta get out of here now!
Move! Move!
Move it!
Let's go!
You see, my friend, the
chemical composition shows...
this is from Sierra Leone.
Conflict diamonds.
There's some kind of marking here.
- "GG."
- Let me see.
Yes.
From the Graves Corporation in Iceland.
That's his laser signature.
A man called Gustav Graves
discovered diamonds there...
a year or so ago.
Yet they're identical to conflict diamonds.
What an amazing coincidence.
How can he escape from a British warship...
in the middle of Hong Kong
harbor, right under your nose?
- Interesting station, Moneypenny?
- I got a storm warning.
You were supposed to throw away the key...
not leave the door wide open.
Are you implying I had
a hand in his escape?
Well, Bond got away real fast, didn't he?
It is what he's trained to do.
Your boy's been very busy.
He torches a clinic in Cuba.
Listen, you put your house in order...
or we're gonna do it for you.
Your drink, sir.
Lucky I asked for it shaken.
- When's he coming?
- I don't know.
- Looks like your man won't make it.
- He's right on time.
Wonderful day to become a knight.
Will you be using your title, Mr. Graves?
I'm proud of my adopted nation,
but I'd never stand on ceremony.
After that entrance, you
can't be surprised...
you're called a self-publicizing
adrenaline junkie, can you?
I prefer "adventurer."
We've heard about the Icarus space program.
What's the secret?
It's a surprise. You'll
soon be enlightened.
You work 24/7. Is it true
that you don't need sleep?
You get one shot at life.
Why waste it on sleep?
Aren't you trying out for
the Olympic fencing team?
- We hear you're training furiously.
- I never get furious.
As they say in fencing, "What's the point?"
Thank you.
We don't want to keep Her
Majesty waiting any longer.
- Mr. Graves.
Hit.
That's a hit.
Verity?
James Bond.
Your lesson.
I see you handle your weapon well.
I have been known to keep my tip up.
Do you mind? I think I've come undone.
Why not?
Hit. Positions. Play.
Feast your eyes on the
finest blade in the club.
Gustav Graves?
His publicist, Miranda Frost.
Gorgeous, isn't she?
She took the gold at Sydney.
- By default, if I remember.
- Default?
The one who beat her OD'd on steroids.
Miranda deserved that gold.
Now she's teaching Graves how to win one.
He only plays for cash.
He's won so much, nobody
else wants to fight him.
You wanna meet him?
Absolutely.
Lead on.
- Gustav?
- Verity.
- And Mr...?
- Bond.
James Bond.
- Have we met before?
- I think I'd remember.
Of course you would. My mistake.
- Are you a gambling man, Mr. Bond?
- If the stakes are right.
A thousand a point too much for you?
Care to place a bet, Verity?
No, thanks.
I don't like cockfights.
Shall we?
Excuse me.
Best of three hits?
Positions.
Ready. Play.
En garde.
Hit.
Positions.
Play.
Hit.
Two-nil.
Do you want to continue?
- You wanna up the wager?
- How much can you afford?
Let's play for this.
I picked it up in Cuba.
I believe it's one of yours.
My, my. They do get around.
But then diamonds are for everyone.
Brilliant specimen. Completely flawless.
And chemically identical to
African conflict diamonds.
Then you're about to lose
something very precious.
Positions.
Ready.
- Play.
- En garde.
Oh, dear.
You want to continue?
Of course I want to bloody continue!
But since we're upping the wager...
let's up the weapons, shall we?
Let's do this the old-fashioned way.
First blood drawn from the torso.
That is enough!
It's just a little sport, Miranda.
Seems you beat me, Mr. Bond.
Settle downstairs, shall we?
You're a rare challenge, Mr. Bond.
I'm putting on a scientific demonstration
in Iceland at the weekend. Icarus?
Perhaps you could join us.
Miranda, make the arrangements.
Once I've smoothed things
over with the club.
What would I do without you?
Can I expect the pleasure
of you in Iceland?
I'm afraid you'll never have that pleasure.
Excuse me, Commander Bond.
Someone left this for you.
Place needed redecorating anyway.
I heard of this place.
Never thought I'd find myself here.
Some things are best kept underground.
An abandoned station for abandoned agents.
- Your calling card.
- So, what have you got on Graves?
You burn me...
- and now you want my help?
- Did you expect an apology?
I know you'll do whatever it
takes to get the job done.
- Just like you.
- The difference is, I won't compromise.
Well, I don't have the luxury of
seeing things as black and white.
- While you were away, the world changed.
- Not for me.
You're suspicious of Graves, or
I wouldn't be here right now.
- So, what do you have?
- Nothing beyond the official biography.
Orphan working in a diamond mine...
learns engineering, makes a huge find in
Iceland and gives half of it to charity.
From nothing to everything
in no time at all.
- And his demonstration this weekend?
- Probably just another publicity stunt.
Tell me what you know
about this Cuban clinic.
Gene therapy.
New identities courtesy of DNA transplants.
So-called "beauty parlor." We'd heard rumors.
I didn't think it really existed.
It doesn't anymore.
Zao got away, but he left these behind.
All from Gustav Graves' mine.
I think it's a front for laundering
African conflict diamonds.
We need to tread carefully.
Graves is politically connected.
Lucky I'm on the outside, then.
It seems you've become useful again.
Then maybe it's time you
let me get on with my job.
Forgive my mentioning it,
but a perfect marksman...
isn't really supposed
to shoot his own boss.
Check the replay.
You'll find he's dead and
she's only got a flesh wound.
There's always an excuse,
isn't there, double-O zero?
Give me the old firing range any day.
Yes, but it's called the
future, so get used to it.
So this is where they keep
the old relics, then, eh?
This is where our most cutting-edge
technology is developed.
- Point taken.
- Must you touch everything?
Does this still work?
- Now, look...
- So where is this cutting-edge stuff?
I'm trying to get to it.
Weapon, please.
One pane unbreakable glass, one
standard-issue ring finger.
Twist so. Voilo.
Ultra-high frequency single-digit
sonic agitator unit.
- You're cleverer than you look.
- Better than looking cleverer...
than you are. Follow me.
Now, a new watch. This will
be your 20th, I believe.
- How time flies.
- Yes, well, 007...
why don't you establish a
record by returning this one.
Your new transportation.
- Maybe you've been down here too long.
- The ultimate in British engineering.
- You must be joking.
- As I learned from my predecessor...
I never joke about my work.
Aston Martin call it the
Vanquish, we call it the Vanish.
- Very good.
- Adaptive camouflage.
Tiny cameras project the image they see...
onto a light-emitting polymer
skin on the opposite side.
To the casual eye, as good as invisible.
Plus, the usual refinements:
Ejector seat, torpedoes, target-seeking
shotguns to shoot down mobile objects.
The manual. Should be able to shoot
through that in a couple of hours.
Just took a few seconds, Q.
Wish I could make you vanish.
Come in.
Before you leave on your
mission for Iceland...
tell me what you know of James Bond.
He's a double-O. A wild
one, as I discovered today.
He'll light the fuse on any
explosive situation...
and be a danger to himself and others.
Kill first, ask questions later.
His method is to provoke and confront.
A man nobody can get close to.
A womanizer.
You're going to be seeing a
lot more of him in Iceland.
With great respect, a man
like him could blow my cover.
You volunteered for this, but in three
months, you've found next to nothing.
Graves seems to be clean.
Bond thinks differently, so I'm going to
let him do what you so ably described:
Mix things up a little with Mr. Graves.
With you there...
things won't get out of hand.
In your three years in Cryptology, you've
kept business and pleasure separate.
You haven't fraternized with any of your
fellow agents, despite several advances.
It would be foolish to get involved
with someone within the community.
Especially James Bond.
I'm Mr. Kil.
Well, there's a name to die for.
Three hundred and twenty-four miles an hour.
A new personal best.
Thruster two cut out again. Get it fixed.
- Glad you could make it. Like my run?
- You were on the edge of losing control.
It's only by being on the edge that we
know who we really are. Under the skin.
Take your Donald Campbell. 1967, the Bluebird.
Water speed record.
- Campbell died on his return run.
- But he died chasing a dream.
- Isn't that the way to go?
- I'd rather not go at all.
- You don't chase dreams, you live them.
- A virtue of never sleeping.
I have to live my dreams. Besides, plenty
of time to sleep when you're dead.
Mr. Bond.
- Miss Frost.
- I'll show you your room.
A palace of ice. You
must feel right at home.
This was built for tonight's demonstration.
The human element necessitates
a balance of heat and cold.
Built on a lake? Hope
Graves got things right.
- What's that property next door?
- The diamond mine.
And Gustav's living quarters.
Thank you.
This is you.
Wonderful. Would you like to show me more?
Vodka martini. Plenty of
ice, if you can spare it.
Mojito?
James. Here for the penguins this time?
- Or for the view again?
- I'm only interested in endangered species.
Well, does that include me?
- Depends on what you're up to this time.
- So I left you in an explosive situation.
Figured you could handle yourself.
- No wonder your relationships don't last.
- I just don't like to get tied down.
You look terrible.
You aren't looking too good yourself.
- You're still feeling the side effects?
- The insomnia is permanent for me.
An hour on the Dream Machine keeps me sane.
- What happened to you?
- Bond.
He knows nothing. I've
been this close to him...
and he didn't know who I really was.
- You saw my father after your exchange?
- Yes.
- General Moon still mourns your death.
- My death.
Mr. Bond.
- And Miss...?
- Swift. Space and Technology magazine.
Really? I take it Mr. Bond's been
explaining his big-bang theory?
- Yeah, I think I got the thrust of it.
- I see.
The demonstration's about to
begin in five minutes. Shall we?
Shall we?
- Not "Jinx" anymore?
- I'll always be a jinx to you.
I'm always trying to give the
planet something in return...
for what it has given me:
Those little shards of
heaven known as diamonds.
Diamonds aren't just expensive stones.
They are the stuff of dreams.
And the means to make dreams real.
Imagine being able to bring light and
warmth to the darkest parts of the world...
being able to grow crops year-round,
bringing an end to hunger.
Imagine a second sun...
shining like a diamond in the sky.
Let there be light.
I give you Icarus!
Icarus is unique. Its miraculous silver
skin will inhale the sun's light...
and breathe it gently
upon the Earth's surface.
You have no idea how much Icarus
is about to change your world.
And now let us brighten this
night with our inner radiance.
All right, that's a wrap.
- Vlad, show me the modifications.
- Yeah.
Here is the self-defense mechanism
you asked me to build in.
- Fifty-thousand volts?
- A hundred.
Armed...
- and very dangerous.
- Very.
M warned me this would happen.
That's why you tried not
to be interested in me.
God, you're even worse than your file says.
They don't look too convinced.
Come on, put your back into it.
I know all about you. Sex for dinner, death
for breakfast. Not gonna work with me.
- No?
- No.
- You're getting good at this.
- Stop it. Are we still being watched?
- They left ages ago.
- God, you're impossible.
Let's get out of here.
You'd better stay here. Keep up
the charade of being lovers.
All right.
I admire your restraint. You were here a
full two hours before anything blew up.
The way you're going,
you'll get us both killed.
James, tell me what really
happened in North Korea.
I was betrayed.
That was all.
Occupational hazard.
This is crazy. You're a double-O.
It's only a number.
James...
be careful.
Go back to your room.
I'll come back for you.
Why do you want to kill me?
I thought it was the humane thing to do.
Who sent you?
Your mama.
And she's really disappointed in you.
I'll let you in on a little secret.
This mine is fake, but the lasers...
are real.
She won't talk.
Let's make it permanent.
I'll use the laser.
Don't leave a mess.
- Jinx?
- James! James! No, no!
Turn it off! Off! Off!
James, I could use a little help here.
Switch it off...
or I'll be half the girl I used to be.
So, the girl who hates
to be tied down, huh?
Are you gonna get me off this?
- What are you, CIA?
- NSA.
- We're on the same side.
- Doesn't mean we're after the same thing.
Sure it does. World peace,
unconditional love...
and our little friend
with the expensive acne.
- Zao?
- Yeah, Zao.
He's back there with some
weird, psychedelic light mask.
Probably brought it from
the clinic in Cuba.
He couldn't have brought it.
It was already here.
It belongs to another Korean.
His boss.
- We need Kil to help us get out of here.
- I got a better idea.
- I'm going to get backup.
- Wait.
Go to Miranda first. She's MI6.
Warn her to get out.
And what are you gonna do?
Unfinished business.
So you live to die another day...
colonel.
At last. I was beginning to
think you'd never guess.
Was it painful?
- The gene therapy?
- You couldn't possibly imagine.
Good. I'm glad to hear that.
But there have been compensations.
Like watching you flail
around in your ignorance.
Granting you life just to
see if you'd get wise.
It's been fun.
Well, the fun is about
to come to a dead end.
We only met briefly, you and I...
but you left a lasting impression.
When you forced me to present
the world with a new face...
I chose to model the disgusting
Gustav Graves on you.
Just in the details.
That unjustifiable swagger.
Your crass quips, a defense mechanism
concealing such inadequacy.
My defense mechanism is right here.
So, Miss Frost is not all she seems.
Looks can be deceptive.
Yes.
Did you find out who
betrayed you in North Korea?
Only a matter of time.
You never thought of looking
inside your own organization?
She was right under your nose.
It was so good of you to
bring your gun to bed.
Yes. Occupational hazard.
You see, I have a gift.
An instinct for sensing
people's weaknesses.
Yours is women. Hers and mine
is winning, whatever the cost.
When I arranged for the fatal overdose
of the true victor at Sydney...
I won myself my very own MI6 agent...
using everything at my disposal:
Her brains, her talent...
even her sex.
The coldest weapon of all.
Hello.
Miranda?
There will be others after me.
You mean your American friend, Jinx.
Soon to be the victim of a tragedy.
- An ice palace can be a treacherous place.
- Hand over the toys.
Oh, yeah.
You know, I've missed your
sparkling personality.
How's that for a punch line?
Kill him.
I enjoyed last night, James...
but it really is death for breakfast.
Kill him, quietly.
Kill him. Now!
- He got away.
- No matter.
The pleasure of the kill is in the chase.
Bring me the generals.
Gentlemen...
I promised you a demonstration.
Now you will see the true power of Icarus.
The Western spy runs, but he cannot hide.
Icarus will lock on to the heat signature
and concentrate the sun's power.
Hey, boss, he beat your time.
Time to draw the line.
Global warming is a terrible thing.
Yeah, nice moves, just like Bond.
He was pretty vigorous last night as well.
He did you?
- I didn't know he was that desperate.
- He's not coming for you.
He just died running, trying
to save his own skin.
That's pretty good tailoring.
I hope it doesn't shrink when it gets wet.
Soon, we will be victorious.
We've got one hour to wrap this up.
Let's move.
Come on, Jinx, where are you?
All units report. Now!
Warning, adaptive camouflage failure.
Time to give the American her bath.
Adaptive camouflage restored.
Vlad, does the word "ergonomics"
mean anything to you?
Man? Machine?
This is still a suitcase.
Finish it, will you?
Come on, it's warm in here. Come on.
The cold kept you alive, huh?
It must've kept you alive.
Come on.
What took you so long?
I'm sorry.
Agent Johnson.
- James.
- Charles.
Okay, bring us up to speed on this.
Another division mobilized north of the DMZ.
80,000 troops and counting.
- And another million in reserve.
- Moon's father won't allow a war.
General Moon's under arrest.
Hard-liners staged a coup.
You deliberately misled
me by implicating Bond.
- If you'd told us about your agent...
- She'd be dead.
- Your mole would've made sure.
- We wouldn't have a mole...
if you'd told us that Frost and Moon were
on the Harvard fencing team together.
Knowing who to trust is
everything in this business.
Well, well, James Bond.
- Just in time for the fireworks.
- Let's get down to business.
We're at DEFCON 2.
And if the North goes south,
they're gonna go south big-time.
You don't just stroll through a minefield.
You need some kind of an edge.
- Icarus.
- We're taking care of that...
with an ASAT launch in one hour.
- Where's Graves?
- In a North Korean air base.
They're right where we can't touch him.
You can't...
- ...but I can.
- Look...
we're here in case things escalate,
not to make sure that they do.
No incursions into the North.
President gave me a direct order.
And when did that ever stop you?
You make your own decision.
I'm sending in 007.
You think I'd leave this in
the hands of the British?
You go with him.
Approaching drop zone.
Okay, let's go!
- They've entered North Korean airspace.
- Relax, Robinson.
If our radar can't see those switchblades,
the North Koreans sure as hell can't.
Hey, boss, they launched against Icarus.
Leave it on automatic.
I hope nobody here is superstitious. That's
one big mirror we're about to break.
Oh, my God.
Mobilize the South Korean troops.
And get me the president, now!
Still no news of Bond?
Vehicles.
Some big shots.
It's him.
- Three hundred meters.
- Windage, one and a half.
We gotta get on that plane.
You, have my father brought down.
Father...
I regret our meeting had to be like this.
You can't tell it's me?
I don't know you.
You've always found it
difficult to accept me.
That made my exile easier to bear...
but I never forgot what you taught me.
In war, the victorious
strategist only seeks battle...
after the victory has been won.
You see, Father, I
remember my Art of War...
and this is what guarantees that victory.
My son...
What have you done to yourself?
Come, Father.
Watch the rising of your son.
The second that hits the 38th parallel...
hit them with everything we got.
That may not be enough.
Do you see, Father?
Icarus is clearing the minefield...
creating a highway for our troops.
If the Americans don't run,
Icarus will destroy them.
Japan is a bug waiting to be squashed...
and the West will shake with fear.
But the Americans will
send nuclear warheads.
Icarus will swat them from the sky.
You will destroy us.
You would kill your own son?
The son I knew died long ago.
Father... you disappoint me.
Caution. Caution.
- Manual.
- Up!
Manual.
- Up! Up!
- Caution.
- Manual.
- Come on!
Okay, guys.
Okay.
I got it.
My, my. You get around. Let's see your gun.
Left hand.
That's it.
Now drop it.
Looks like your friends have bailed.
Push on autopilot.
Come on.
That's it. Good girl.
Well, drowning you didn't seem to work.
I'll have to try something
more to the point.
One thousand meters and closing.
I can read your every move.
Read this.
Bitch.
Look, parachutes for the both of us.
Not anymore.
You see, Mr. Bond, you
can't kill my dreams.
But my dreams can kill you.
Time to face destiny.
Time to face gravity.
I think I broke her heart.
Looks like we're going down together.
Not yet.
- Get the back open.
- Okay.
Come on!
- Come on.
- I told you I was a jinx.
I should have warned you...
my relationships don't last either.
At least we're gonna die rich.
Come on. Come on, come on. Come on.
Come on.
Now...
you said something about
going down together?
James.
Moneypenny.
Oh, James.
Moneypenny?
I was just testing it out.
It's rather hard, isn't it?
Yes. Very.
Wait, don't pull it out. I'm
not finished with it yet.
See? It's a perfect fit.
- Leave it in.
- It's gotta come out sooner or later.
No, leave it in, please. Few more minutes?
We really have to get these back.
Still the good guys, huh?
I'm still not quite sure how good you are.
I am so good.
Especially when you're bad.