You surprise me again,
John.
This is becoming
an ugly habit.
I don't have the time right now,
Simon.
A deal's a deal.
Where's the school bomb?
On the contrary,
you have lots of time.
You have...
2 hours and 47 minutes
precisely.
Plenty of time to test
those wits of yours.
Listen,jerk-off,
I got a bad
fucking hangover!
Now, where is
the school bomb?
Temper,John.
The road to truth
has many turns.
You'll find an envelope
under the rim of the fountain.
When you undertake
the trip it suggests,
ask yourself
this question--
What is 21 out of 42?
We're behind.
We should abandon
the rest and go.
Relax, Targo.
There's not a cop for 20 blocks.
He's sending us to the home team dugout
at Yankee Stadium.
We supposed to find
something there?
What's 21 out of 42?
21 again.
Half of 42.
42 what?
How many players
on the Yankees ball club?
25.
What else is 21 ?
Blackjack.
It's a club.
It's a wild goose chase
is what it is.
Where's the nearest
"A" train?
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
You know,
some kid might find that.
You're right.
Come back here,
you little sons of bitches!
Hey, you!
I remember you!
Ha ha.
Hey, where you going?
What are you doing?
Let me go, dickhead!
Watch your mouth.
You going to juvenile hall
for a Butterfinger?
Look around.
All the cops are into something.
It's Christmas!
You could steal City Hall!
Come on.
My bike.
That's my bike!
Hey! Hey!
Where you going?
Yankee Stadium's that way!
You asshole!
[ Horn Honks ]
Why don't you run over
everybody in the street?
What the fuck
are we doing?
What is it that Wall Street
doesn't have?
You're talking in riddles.
What is it that Wall Street
does not have?
What? Schools.
And what do they have
a shitload of?
What?
I'll be back in a minute.
What am I supposed to do
with this?
Give it to those guys
over there.
He's here.
Perhaps you could be
more specific.
McClane is here.
He's walking toward
the bank.
The black man
is coming toward me.
And after we've gone
to all that trouble at the stadium.
Simon...
kill him.
Stop toying with him
and kill him now.
O.K. So be it.
May he rest in peace.
I'll inform Karl
in the lobby.
Pack up your team
and get out.
And this one?
Officer...
I'm going to need an answer
on that issue.
Let him go.
Understood.
Yes, sir?
John McClane says
to give you this.
Jesus, don't open it.
It's a bomb.
Another?
Yeah.
Oh, I see.
We'd better move now.
Thank you for your assistance.
We really appreciate it.
Thank you.
Hey, y'all leaving
this place unguarded?
[ Tires Squeal ]
How you doing?
All right.
John McClane...
N.Y.P.D..
Are you all right?
Yes...
laundry day.
What can I do for you,
Lieutenant?
It's been quiet
all morning here?
Well--
Except for
that big explosion
a couple of hours ago.
Seen anything strange
happen in the last hour?
No. We've had cops
in here pretty steady
since the subway thing.
We were going to make a round
on the vault floor
if you want
to tag along.
Sure. Think I will.
What do you think
of this heat?
Indian summer, huh?
Feels like it's going to rain
like dogs and cats later.
Here's one of your guys.
Detective, uh, Otto, isn't it?
John McClane.
Mike, how you doing?
I keep telling myself
I'm going to
take the stairs
just for the exercise...
but on a hot day like this,
it seems I always end up
riding the lift.
What was the lottery number
last night?
You play the lottery?
No?
My wife buys me two tickets
every week.
Plays the same two numbers
all the time.
I say, " Why don't you play
a different number?"
She goes,
"Those are my lucky numbers."
I got the tickets
right here--
Put that fucking gun down!
Put it down now!
Put it down!
Hello!
Anybody down here?
Freeze! Put your fucking hands
in the air!
No,John! No! No!
It's me!
You almost gave me
a heart attack.
You all right?
Huh?
You all right!
Yeah. It's not my blood.
What's going on
down here?
Go take a look.
Hey, McClane.
Where the hell
is everybody?
Simon fuckin' says!
I should've seen it coming
a mile away.
This was never
about revenge.
It's about a goddamn heist.
What was in the room?
This.
What is this?
Oh, shit!
Is this gold?
Yeah, it's gold.
Damn, this is heavy!
They cleaned out
a whole room of this?
Yeah.
That would take
a tank or...
A dump truck.
1 4 great big
dump trucks.
We almost got hit
by a dump truck.
Damn! Slow down! Shit!
Put that shit down.
No fuckin' way.
They ain't going to
let you keep it.
We'll need a car.
Can you hot-wire this?
Of course I can.
I'm an electrician.
Only problem is...
[ Motor Starts ]
Takes too fuckin' long.
[ Tires Squeal ]
[ Horn Honks ]
[ Tires Screech ]
Not on the bridge!
Down there, McClane!
the FDR!
Let's go! Let's go!
Come on!
Oh, shit!
What?
Shot the phone.
Aw, too bad.
What's 21 out of 42?
I don't have a clue.
What about Yankee Stadium?
We'll get there,
after we stop him.
- [ Horn Honks ]
- Oh,Jesus Christ!
Who do you think you are, lady,
Hillary Clinton?
That's it! Hillary Clinton.
the 42nd president.
She'd be the 43rd president.
All right, all right,
but who's the 21 st?
- I don't know.
- You don't know?
No! Do you know?
No!
Well?
This engine's shit.
Step on it!
It's a Yugo.
It's built for economy, not speed.
Whoa! What are you doing?
Getting us
another phone.
[ Horn Honks ]
[ Screech ]
Wait, Wait!
Wait, wait, wait!
Who was the 21 st president?
Go fuck yourself!
That guy was pissed.
He'll feel better when he looks
in the backseat.
Shit, that was
my gold bar!
This is McClane.
Get me Inspector Walter Cobb.
Where the hell are you?
It's not revenge.
It's a heist.
There's gold
in the Federal Reserve.
They took a shitload of it.
They're headed north
in dump trucks.
Have you been drinking?
Not since this morning.
There's a lot of
dump trucks northbound
on the FDR
at about 7 0th.
Close the bridge.
Get some helicopters over there.
I couldn't close
a hot dog stand now.
I'm spread all over.
What about this damn bomb?
It's got something to do
with the 21 st president.
John,John, the 21 st what?
Walter!
Shit. Goddamn cellular fuckin' phones!
Reach Munsen
On the Triborough.
Tell him to close
all the East River bridges
north of 59th street.
Looking for dump trucks.
Dump trucks?
McClane says
there are dump trucks
headed up the FDR
loaded with gold.
They don't allow dump trucks
on the FDR!
- Connie!
- All right!
I won't argue,
no matter how stupid it is.
K-9. Check out
the boiler room.
Find anything, Charlie?
I could spend a week here
with an X-ray machine
and still not find it.
You've got five minutes.
Then we're moving up to 86th street.
Going as fast as we can.
What's up?
McClane was mentioning something
about the Federal Reserve building.
Isn't that near that
Wall Street bomb site?
Yeah.
How long do you want us
to stay here?
The men at the stadium.
Stay or go?
Karl should've
checked in by now.
Moment.
[ Telephone Rings ]
[ Ring ]
Come on, come on.
Stay where you are.
McClane may still turn up.
[ Ring ]
Relax, Targo.
If he is still alive...
[ Dialing ]
he won't be talking
to anyone.
It's the next turnoff.
Hi. It's Elvis Duran.
You're on the air. What's up?
First I want to tell you what
a great show you got.
I listen to you
all the time.
Thanks. What's on your mind?
Those cop cars speeding
around everywhere--
you know what
they're up to?
There's a bomb
in a school.
My cousin's a cop.
Somebody put a big bomb
in a school somewhere.
Only they don't know
which one.
so they're searching
all of them.
Shh! Shh!
Every school
in the metropolitan area.
Holy shit.
Doris. Annie?
Doris, can you reach my wife?
Turley! Half the goddamn city
just called 91 1 !
They're gone.
What?
They're gone!
Who is this guy,
Houdini?
Down there!
This thing got air bags?
Your side does.
I don't know about mi--
McClane!
[ Horn Honks ]
In the truck!
Let me see the hands!
Put them on the door!
Don't kill me!
Don't shoot me.
Truck driver?
No, I'm a beautician.
Of course I'm a truck driver!
Where you taking
this truck?
The aqueduct.
Why you taking this
to the race track?
No, the aqueduct!
The--the water aqueduct!
Aqueduct?
See? Goes from here
all the way up
to the Catskill Mountains!
What does?
That! The water pipe!
Goes for about 60 miles!
- Hey, you the foreman?
- Yeah.
N.Y.P.D.!
Any extra dump trucks
come through here
the last couple minutes?
I'm writing
those fuckin' clowns up!
They better start paying attention
to work orders.
What happened?
A dozen idiots
tore ass up the tube.
We're not loading up there anymore.
We're loading over here.
So much for bridges
and helicopters.
Got a map showing
where this tunnel goes?
Yeah, right here.
We run pretty much
up under the saw mill
till you get up
to the coffer dam.
After that, we've already brought
the reservoir water down.
Any way in or out
of there?
There's vent shafts
every 2 miles.
I mean with a truck.
At the coffer dam.
You can get a truck in there.
Follow saw mill parkway up there.
It's about 20 miles.
I'll meet you right there,
O.K.?
What am I doing?
You're going up
to Yankee Stadium!
McClane!
Go. We got less
than two hours!
Goddamn it!
Hey! Is something wrong?
480 yards of rock
moved so far.
Now, that's 1 0 times
the Hoover Dam.
Right now, there's 560 feet of rock
above our head.
This part is phase three
of tunnel three.
Planning for it
began back in 1 954,
But construction didn't begin
tillJune of 1 97 0.
You know what the most interesting part
of tunnel three is?
What's that,Jerry?
The valves. Each one...
Main departure
from tunnels one and two.
[ Honks Horn ]
Come on!
What a hell of a place
to break down.
Hold it. Let me have your hard hat.
Got a jacket?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Here.
Wait here a minute.
Wait until he gets
alongside the door.
Hey! Fellas!
Mickey O'Brien,
aqueduct security.
We got a report
of a guy coming through here
with eight reindeer.
Yeah, they said he was
a jolly old fat guy
with a snowy white beard.
Cute red and white suit.
I'm surprised
you didn't see him.
What's with you guys
and these phones?
Give me something.
Holy shit.
Is that guy dead?
Yes,Jerry.
I'm afraid he is.
Jesus Christ.
I want you to get ahold
of a guy named Cobb.
walter Cobb. C-O-B-B.
He's the head of my police unit.
Get him down here.
Tell him you were with John McClane.
Tell him to find out
who the 21 st president was.
Chester A. Arthur.
What?
1 881 to 1 885.
Nominated vice president
in 1 880.
Did you know he was
Collector of Customs here in New York?
No, I didn't know that,Jerry.
Take care of yourself.
[ Speaking German ]
We got to release
these traffic guys.
No. Traffic jams
we can take care of later.
What's wrong with this?
Frequencies are jammed.
What about Ricky?
Can't reach him. Walter.
Federal Reserve.
Yeah?
Biggest gold storage
in the world.
Get a unit
back down there.
Find Ricky. Find out
what the hell is going on.
Walter! You got to hear this!
I thought we were
going in the back way.
This is the back way.
You're about to have
a riot at every school in the city.
Start at the top floor,
20 men per floor.
Send the other 50 men to the basement
with us. What about McClane?
Not a word. I'm getting nothing.
Busy signal.
This is kind of putting all our eggs
in one basket, isn't it?
What if McClane's wrong?
Walter. This is Principal Martinez.
Inspector Cobb.
How do you do, inspector?
Principal, I don't want to alarm
your children.
Move them all into the auditorium
and keep them calm.
We're coming to the dam.
You can call the rear guard.
Rear guard.
You can close up now.
We've reached the dam.
You can come up now.
Nils.
You can close in now.
Attention, attention.
Nils is dead.
I repeat--
Nils is dead, fuckhead.
So's his pal...
and those four guys
from the East German all-stars--
your boys at the bank--
They'll be a little late.
John.
In the back of the truck
you're driving,
there's $1 3 billion
worth in gold bullion.
Would a deal be out
of the question?
I got a deal for you.
Come out of hiding,
and I'll drive this truck up your ass.
How colorful.
I told you not to toy with him!
Thank you.
That's very helpful.
You jeopardized the mission
and the contract.
Ivan.
[ Speaking German ]
Herr Vogle will help me
reach the ship.
I'm going to put
an end to this.
Stop!
Targo!
Here! Come here!
We blow the dam.
What?
We drown him.
[ Speaking German ]
Up there!
Walter!
Take a look at this.
Janitor said it was delivered
this morning. About 1 0:30, right?
Not hooked up.
Yeah?
O.K. Now take a look
at the front.
We drill the hinges.
Get everybody out.
Unh!
Unh...
[ Rumbling ]
Whoa...
Whoa!
Aah!
Uhh!
McClane!
[ Gasping ]
Where are you?
Over here!
Hell of a way of flagging
somebody down.
Did you go to Yankee Stadium?
Yeah. There's nobody there.
You didn't see nobody?
Nobody was following you?
He's jerking us around.
[ Gunshots ]
Come on! Come on!
Holy shit!
Go! Go! Go!
It's not rigged.
Pull it.
[ Beeping ]
Well, I'd say you could
call off your search.
Can you stop it?
I shouldn't even touch it.
Who knows what booby traps
this thing's got?
What about the code?
No word.
When do we evacuate?
Simon says he sees one kid
leave the building--boom.
We can't stand here
with our thumb up our ass
waiting for this
freaking thing to blow up!
Shit!
Keep your head down!
Hold it steady!
Go! Go!
They're in our way!
Go around them!
I found out who's
the 21 st president--
some guy named Arthur.
Chester A. Arthur?
Chester A. Arthur
elementary school?
That's it.
* Gently down the stream *
* Merrily, merrily,
merrily, merrily *
* Life is but a dream... **
[ Whispering ]
Hi, kids.
I know you usually have
assembly on Fridays,
but today is special.
Mr. Lambert here
is from the Fire Department.
Today he wants us to practice
a brand-new fire drill.
I want you to divide in half.
Half of you go over here
and line up against the wall.
The other half go
in this direction.
Do it very quietly
and very quickly.
Everybody up, please.
Teachers, please help them.
Fire drill, my ass.
The Fire Department...
Maybe it's because of the radio.
You mean,
like they're after us?
Tommy squealed on us.
No, he didn't.
Come on.
Where you going?
Let me drive!
Go! Go!
Goddamn it!
Of course he put the bomb
up in that school.
Why would he do that?
To get your complete attention.
Find the fuse panel.
What?
Where's the fuse panel?
Pull out the antilock-brakes fuse.
Which one is it?
Yank them all out.
Put your head down.
Put your head fucking down.
Listen to me.
Hang the fuck on,
all right?
What the fuck happened?
You got a " Triple-A" card?
Keep moving.
I've got the janitors
making a last sweep of the building.
Thank you, Miss Martinez.
Come on.
[ Laughing ]
All right.
3s and 9s are wild.
Stay down.
Stay low.
Oh, man.
What are you doing?
Interrogating him.
What's he going
to tell you?
I won't know
till I ask him.
See if there's aspirin
in that glove box.
No way. You do it.
1 0 quarters.
The guy in the dump truck
had 1 0 quarters.
Exactly 1 0 quarters.
Maybe they were making
long-distance phone calls.
No.
They're for the bridge,
it's for the toll
on the bridge.
There! There!
Down on the wharf--
dump trucks.
Right there.
[ Horn Honks ]
They got it loaded
on a ship already.
Shit!
How about the Coast Guard?
Take them an hour
to get here.
Shit!
We can jump.
What?
It's 1 00 feet
down to the deck.
But not to the crane.
The cables would
cut you in half.
I can make it.
Get down.
Look in the car for some gloves.
Six booby traps,
four dead ends,
* And a partridge
in a pear tree **
O.K., honey...
let's dance.
We're going to have a race.
When I say " go,"
run like crazy.
Follow the police officer
and the firemen.
Walter, I think we're cutting this
a little thin.
No. We're going to wait.
McClane still
may get the code.
[ Horn Blows ]
Line me up
with that crane.
Right there.
You're O.K.
This will take a miracle.
Keep your fingers crossed.
You almost got it.
Yeah! All right.
Where you going?
You in a hurry?
I'm going first this time.
We have the intercom rigged, sir.
Walter, the kids may be fine,
But you wait much longer
and I'll pee
in my pants.
We're going to wait,
Connie.
Six more minutes.
Yo.
McClane.
Down there.
Oh, shit.
Go, man.
Go. Go. Go.
Aah!
Whoa!
Ohh...
Boy, am I glad
you talked me
out of jumping.
Fuck.
Get his feet.
You go find Simon
and beat the fucking
code out of him.
Here. Take this.
How's it work?
You don't know how
to shoot a gun?
All brothers don't know
how to shoot guns.
Yank back on that,
pull the trigger.
That's it?
Just don't shoot yourself.
Hey. Don't be no hero.
You find him, come get me.
[ Laughter]
[ Speaking German ]
Stupid!
You have the autopilot set?
Yes, sir.
Good.
Don't fucking move.
Oh, the samaritan.
Give me the goddamn code.
Code?
Oh.
You mean for the school.
I'm sorry.
I can't do that.
You call in that code
right now,
or I blow your sick ass
into the next world.
If that's what
you got to do...
[ Click ]
You've got to take
the safety catch off.
Ugh!
God!
See? That works.
Now where's McClane?
Nicht schiessen!
What was that?
He said, " Don't shoot."
O.K., Charlie, we'll have to go
with the evacuation.
We're going to go.
You heard the man!
Let's go!
We're going to go.
On my mark...
5, 4, 3, 2, 1 ...
go!
Go! Go! Go! Go!
Let's do it.
O.K., gang. Let's go!
Go! Go! Go!
Hip-hop! Hip-hop!
Run! Run! Run! Run!
We're going to win!
Go! Go! Go! Go! Go!
Let's go! Keep moving!
Hurry up!
[ Shouting ]
Ugh!
Keep going!
Look what they doing.
Yo! Where you going?
- What's going on?
- Where you going?
I see you all day,
little man,
policeman...
and you don't go away.
I'm like that fucking
Energizer bunny.
Where you going now, huh?
Going to arrest me, bunny?
Huh?
I think I'm going rest.
I'm kind of weak.
I knew it was bullshit.
There's nobody watching.
Time to get Charlie out.
Time's up.
Give me another 30 seconds.
It takes a minute 1 5
if you're a kid.
Last I looked,
you weren't too light on your feet.
Oh, my God!
Get them out of there!
The rooms are locked.
Out of my way!
Hey!
Any one marked " 4."
What's going on, Walter?
We still have kids
in the building.
I'm staying.
No, Charlie.
Get out of there.
Ever see that show
The Addams Family?
They got a motherfucker
on there called Lurch.
You don't think I'm going to let you
get to that gun?
Oh.
Fuck!
[ Muffled Voices ]
Four...four...
Get out of the way!
Where are they, Walter?
Still in.
No guts...
no glory.
We can jump
to the next building!
Shit!
O.K.
O.K. Come on.
Come on.
Come on,
get them up here.
Come on. Come on.
Mayday! Mayday!
Bridgeport Coast Guard!
Coast Guard, come in.
[ Beeping Faster]
Come on, kids!
Shit! It's too far!
No guts, no glory.
It's a big fucking white boat.
Please stay
on the line.
[ Ding ]
Pancake syrup?
Stupid...
stupid...
Hello,John McClane.
There was never
any bomb in the school.
Of course not.
I'm a soldier,
not a monster,
even though I sometimes
work for monsters.
No.
The real bomb
is on this ship.
Coast Guard.
I was telling them
where the boat was.
Game over, huh?
Not quite over.
Bridgeport Coast Guard,
come in, please.
They put you on hold?
She told me
to stay on the line.
Oh, God,
I love this country.
You know,
your brother was an asshole.
He really
was an asshole.
He was an asshole.
You got his number.
Yeah, O.K.
Forgive me.
Would you help
Mr. McClane below?
Ohh.
Careful now.
Now, do you have
the communique ?
Bridgeport radio.
Come in, please,
Bridgeport.
Coast Guard.
Oh, you're there, dear.
Yes, we're here.
Will you be able
to record a message?
Yes.
Then please begin now.
This is a communiqué
from the CRF.
For too long,
the West has conspired
to steal the wealth
of the world,
consigning the balance of humanity
to economic starvation.
Today, we will level
the playing field.
In minutes, the contents
of the federal reserve bank--
the gold your economies
are built on--
will be redistributed
by explosive
Across the bottom
of the Long Island Sound.
If you are not
in gridlock,
come and watch.
You going
to blow it all up?
That's the idea.
Some gentlemen
in the Middle East
think they'll make
lots of money.
See the men
safely off the ship,
and I'll see you
on the launch.
What's this got to do
with killing McClane?
Life has its little bonuses.
Didn't you say you didn't
even like your brother?
There's a difference
between not liking one's brother
and not caring when
some dumb Irish flatfoot
drops him out a window.
I didn't even know
that motherfucker.
I never invited you
aboard this ship.
No riddle's going to stop
this motherfucker?
No code, no riddle,
no fancy countdown.
Hey, fuckhead.
Yeah, you--fuckhead.
Just one thing
I got to know--
you got any aspirins?
I've had a bad
fucking headache
all day long.
Must be your lucky day.
Keep the bottle.
Right.
Where is the gold?
He's betrayed us.
The containers
are filled with that...
[ Speaking German ]
If I hadn't saved
your fucking ass,
I wouldn't be here about to blow up
with $1 00 billion.
You're only going
to blow up with me.
There's no gold
on this boat.
How do you know?
I know the family.
Only thing better than blowing up
$1 00 billion
is making people
think you did.
Well, where is it?
He must have
switched it somewhere.
That supposed to make me
feel better?
You're wrong.
You're not
going to die.
You know some cop trick
about handcuffs to get us out?
Yeah. Use a key.
You know how
to pick this lock?
Is this some
black shit again?
Are you a fucking locksmith
or not?
I need something
to do it with.
How about a splinter
of that cable?
Hold on.
What the fuck
are you doing?
Uh!
Fuck! Shit!
How's that?
that big enough?
Yeah. That might work.
I'm going to drop it
in your hand.
Cup your hand.
Don't drop
this motherfucker.
Get it in the right.
You ready?
1 ...2...spit it.
Yeah!
Get it?
Move your hands.
O.K.
Damn, McClane,
I was just starting
to like you.
Don't. I'm an asshole.
What are you
talking about?
I lied to you.
About what?
Remember I said Weiss
found that bomb up in Harlem?
They found it
down in Chinatown.
That's low even for a white
motherfucker like you.
[ Beep ]
What the fuck was that?
I don't know.
Look, it was the only way
to get you to come with me.
You got a wife?
I'm surprised anybody
could stay with you
long enough to be married.
She didn't stick around.
We're sort of separated.
She was in L.A.,
I was in New York,
we had a fight
on the phone,
she hung up,
I didn't call her back.
How long ago was that?
About a year ago.
[ Laughing ]
What the fuck
you laughing about?
You threw away
your marriage
because you were
too fucking stupid
to pick up the phone?
You think that's funny?
I bet you blame your wife, too.
My wife is a very stubborn woman.
You better stop
fucking laughing
and undo these cuffs.
They're almost...
there!
How's that
for concentration?
[ Clatter]
Oh, shit!
I dropped the pin.
Goddamn it!
Where'd it go?
Find it!
I don't see it.
[ Beeping ]
What the fuck is that?
I think I made it mad.
Go, McClane,
get the fuck out of here.
Goddamn it!
Listen to me!
Just go.
It's hard enough
getting through the day
without your death
on my conscience.
All right. Tools...
Check the engine room.
There's no time!
What the hell's it doing now?
It's mixing.
Shit!
What the hell
are you doing?
Lean forward.
Lean forward,
goddamn it!
What--
What the fuck
are you doing?
Lean forward.
Oh, no!
Get ready!
Fucking shit! Shit!
Oh, goddamn!
Goddamn!
Come on!
My leg. Ow!
Get up the stairs
Go! Go! Go! Go!
Get up the stairs!
Oh, shit!
Damn it!
Let's go!
Run, damn it!
Run!
I am!
Come on!
All right?
Watch, watch, watch!
Let's go!
Aah!
How's he doing?
I'm shot
in the leg.
How you think
I'm doing?
He's going
to be just fine.
And you?
Fine.
You get Ricky
out of there?
Yeah, they found him.
You going to be
all right?
Got a bad headache.
Think they're mad at me?
I wouldn't worry about them.
They'll get to you
eventually.
They're busy with this
salvage operation.
No. Dredges!
Dredges!
There's no gold
out there.
What do you mean?
He took it.
He beat me.
He beat all of us.
He wasn't playing
against you.
Fuck that, McClane!
You're still alive,
aren't you?
Well, aren't you?
Yeah.
So he lost.
Lambert,
would you give him a quarter?
Asshole.
Yeah, it's collect from John.
Uh, Carmen,just tell them
you'll accept the charges.
Son of a bitch had aspirin.
Yeah, it's John.
I'm hanging in there.
Holly there?
I'll hold on.
Zeus, hold up!
Hold up!
John?
John? Goddamn it!
[ Cheering ]
Yesterday...
Yesterday we were
an army with no country.
Tomorrow...
we have to decide
which country
we want to buy!
And remember...
this is all due
to the g-g-g-gullibility
of the New York
Police Department!
To the police department!
Yeah!
[ Speaking German ]
Kamerad!
Deitman, take over.
All right, listen up!
First squad,
you muster out
in half an hour
in the school bus!
You'll be
the lacrosse team!
No rush.
Jurgens, you'll be the padre!
Padre?
[ Unzips Pants ]
[ Helicopter]
Lights! Douse those lights.
[ McClane ]
Hey, dickhead,
did I come at a bad time?
Aah!
Wow! I think she's pissed
at you, McClane.
[ Blowing Whistle ]
[ Shouting ]
Go!
He's under us now.
Come back around.
Zeus, what's on your side?
Look like roaches
in the lights.
I'll be going
to Nova Scotia.
You go with the trucks.
I have something
personal to finish.
Let's go to work.
That's right, run,
motherfuckers!
The exterminators
are here!
Whoo!
What the fuck?
[ Gunfire ]
We got a chopper behind us!
Got a gun on board?
What is this?
Hold it still.
I can't see a thing.
[ Gunshots ]
[ Gunfire ]
Oh, shit!
What do you mean,
"Oh, shit" ?
Hang on. Hang on.
We're going down.
Cease fire!
Hey, McClane,
what the fuck?
Hey, we got smoke!
We got fucking smoke
and shit flying on me!
[ Horn Honks ]
Truck! Truck!
Hold on.
We got to get
out of here!
They'll start
shooting any second.
Oh, shit!
I can't get it off!
Look out!
Here he comes!
Can't get out, McClane.
Get him out of here.
Where you going?
I'll get his attention.
Shit.
This keeps getting
better and better.
I had no idea
Canada could be
this much fun.
Just give me something
to shoot at.
Come on, hotshot.
Show me that smiling face.
Say hello to your brother.
Get out of here!
Yippee-ki-yay,
motherfucker.
Looks like you got
his attention.
Yeah, looks like it.
Think we should call
a fire truck?
Fuck them.
Let him cook.
Oh, shit!
What?
I left Holly
hanging on hold.
Aw, call her back.
I don't know.
She's going to be pissed.
She'll get over it.
I don't know, Zeus.
Like I said,
she's a very stubborn woman.
She'd have to be
to stay married to you.
Ha ha ha!