♪ Hmmm ♪
♪ hmmm ♪
♪ Whoahh ♪
♪ Ohohhum ♪
♪ Mm mm mm
mm mm mm mm ♪
♪ mm mm mm mm
mm mm mm ♪
mm mm mm mm ♪
♪ mm mm mm mm
♪ mm mm mm
mm mm mm mm ♪
♪ little bitty pretty one ♪
♪ come on
and talk to me ♪
♪ lovey dovey lovey one ♪
♪ come sit down
on my knee ♪
♪ ooh ooh ooh ooh
ooh ooh ooh ooh ♪
♪ oh oh oh oh
oh oh oh oh ♪
♪ oh oh oh oh oh
oh oh ♪
♪ tell you a story ♪
♪ it happened
long time ago ♪
♪ my little bitty
pretty one ♪
♪ I been a-watchin'
you grow ♪
[Honk honk]
Oh,
Maggie's here!
Oh, my gosh.
Hi!
Mags!
Guess who got
Joe Don Holly's pin
over spring break
in Florida?
Who?
Maggie,
play the game!
Who?
Me!
Ah!
How was your
spring break?
Great!
Maggie!
Long time no see.
I cleaned your room.
You're kidding!
That's great!
Know what he said then?
"Baby, it get even bigger
when you blow it up."
Ha ha ha ha!
Did I miss
something funny?
No, honey.
Nothing you
ought to hear.
Come on over here
and give me a hug.
Mmm.
Mmm! You smell
good, keefi.
That's not
the coffee.
My boy give it to me
Sunday easter.
It's
glory-o-the-snow.
Smell that.
That's heaven!
That's like nothing
I ever smelled before.
Honey,
it's a head-Turner.
Little bit of heaven
with some smiling
old devil girl for spice.
Glory-o-the-snow.
Honey, the snows
is pretty blue flowers.
They is early bloomers...
Like you, Maggie.
Aw!
I missed you, keefi.
Ahem.
You too, Clarice.
You just missed
my fried catfish
and my hushpuppies.
Now, that's
what you missed.
You run along, girl.
Me and Clarice got
a world to put in order.
Glory-o-the-snow.
That's good!
♪ Hold me close,
hold me tight ♪
♪ make me thrill... ♪
Oh, Maggie!
I'm having a visit
from my friend.
Be sweet to me,
ok?
Come here.
♪ I want you, I need you,
I love you... ♪
Come on.
Hey, y'all!
What do you think?
My sweater!
I got 3
for my birthday.
I can't decide
which is my color.
What are
the other colors?
Periwinkle blue--
a lovely
peachy coral.
They're all
cashmere.
Black is just
sort of you, m.A.
I think so.
It's sophisticated.
Come on, Jean.
T.t.f.n!
Ta ta for now!
I'm going to get
a coke.
You want a coke?
I don't think so.
Oh, no!
Prepare yourself,
Maggie.
Here she is with her
all-new look for 1957...
Miss Kim novak!
[Whistle]
I've just got this mad thing
for Mr. Elvis Aron Presley.
Do you think
I'll ever find anyone
who can help me
with my thing?
♪ ...time we're apart ♪
♪ I want you... ♪
I am so glad
to see you.
Don't you hate
these long breaks?
I came in early.
What with mama and daddy
bugging me
about watching
my ps and qs,
I was bored
out of my mind.
I don't even know
what ps and qs are.
Come watch! You asked for it
is about to begin.
I can't.
I got plans.
Tell me something
I don't already know.
Delia, do you ever
get the feeling
you're really ready
for something,
but you don't know
what it is?
I am so ready.
Good heavens, darling.
Ready for what?
I don't know.
Something.
Anything.
Well, I think
some evil character,
some black knight
upon his black steed,
has cast a warm, cozy,
magical spell on you.
Now.
Hey, Maggie!
Well, if it isn't
our notorious gdi.
Hey, aiken.
For a minute I thought,
"is Maggie praying?"
Maybe I was,
sort of.
Is that Delia?
Hey!
I didn't know you
were still friends.
Don't be
such a stranger!
Close your eyes
again, Maggie.
Maybe you'll see a sign.
Hell, maybe your prayers
will come true.
I wasn't praying, really.
I was only kidding.
Life's too short
not to try everything once.
Close your eyes.
Trust me.
You'll see a sign.
I knew it!
A sign!
Whoo!
You're crazy,
aiken Reed!
Nope. Not yet.
Still looking forward
to that.
Bye.
You know, I'd watch out
for that one if I were you.
Never trust
a goddamn independent.
That's right.
Tell you what...
Tuck invited me
to go to Phoenix city
with him tonight.
Come go. No one
need be the wiser.
I don't know. I got
an 8:00 class in the morning.
Well, so?
Come on, Maggie.
It's our last night
to howl.
And tonight,
I feel hot.
Besides, tuck says at
ma beechie's there's this woman
who can pick up a Dixie cup
with her you-know-what.
All right!
Let's have a big
round of applause
for miss cherry delight
and all the girls.
Boys, give it up!
More! More! More!
Maggie, darling.
The monster has risen.
Oh.
You ok, mags?
She just gets Scarlet
letters across her chest
when Mr. Emotion
has his way with her.
♪ Oh, the night time ♪
♪ is the right time ♪
♪ to be with
the one you love ♪
♪ I said
the night time ♪
I want to dance.
♪ Is the right time ♪
♪ to be with
the one you love ♪
♪ you know, the night time
is the right time ♪
♪ to be
with the one you love ♪
Woo hoo!
♪ Baby ♪
♪ take my hand ♪
♪ baby ♪
♪ understand ♪
♪ oh, that the night time
is the right time ♪
♪ to be
with the one you love ♪
♪ well, the night time
is the right time ♪
♪ to be
with the one you love ♪
She's waiting for you.
She's all yours.
Do it, virg!
Come on, virg!
It's time
to take some action.
Just stay here.
She's waiting
for you, virg!
She's calling
your name, virg!
She's all yours,
virg, come on!
Get him out
of there, virg!
Yeah, virg.
Mind if I cut in?
Hey, you
son of a bitch!
Hey, Maggie!
Oh!
Come on!
♪ ...'cause the night time
is the right time... ♪
Come on, man!
[Whistle]
Hey, ma's
calling the mps!
Ma called the mps!
You want to spend
30 days in the stockade?
You got 3 minutes,
soldier! Move out!
Let's go!
Let's move!
Come on!
Please get US
out of here.
My car's out back.
Come on!
Tuck,
do something.
Pardon
the etiquette.
Oh, you!
Let's go!
I'm going!
[Siren]
It's the yellow one
right there.
Get in!
Oh!
Hey!
[Honk]
Y'all go to
Randolph?
Yes. This is
Delia June curry,
and i'm
Margaret deloach.
I don't believe
we've officially met,
but i'm
Charles Payton Tucker--tuck.
Pleased to meet you,
tuck.
Hoyt Cunningham.
You are nothing
but a hero.
I thought they were
going to kill me.
I never thought
that boy--
yes, you did.
That boy just
asked me to dance.
I watched you
all night.
You're lucky
tuck isn't dead.
I would like to thank you
for your kind assistance.
Think nothing
of it, tuck.
What in god's name
were you doing
in that place?
I don't think that's
any of your business.
You haven't got
any spirit for adventure.
You've got a real spirit
for adventure,
don't you, hoyt?
You're not from
around here.
Matter of fact,
I am.
Greenville,
Mississippi.
Greenville?
That's where Maggie's
boyfriend comes from.
My boyfriend's name
is boots claibourne.
I coached
that little shit
in pop Warner
football.
How is he?
He's perfectly
charming.
He's Maggie's
fiance.
Yeah. She's pinned
to old boots.
Gonna marry that
pretty boy,
aren't you, mags?
You going to
marry boots?
That's for US to know
and you to find out.
You hungry?
No, not really.
I'm getting some coffee.
You coming?
I am definitely
not eating here.
See you later.
Well, all right,
but I am not eating.
Oh!
So what were you
doing at ma's?
Working.
Let me guess.
Woman's lingerie salesman
working ma's
strip joint, right?
Close.
I'm a photographer
for the ap.
I'm covering racial
trouble at fort benning.
Maggie wrote on the negro
situation for the school paper
about that girl who tried to
register for classes at 'bama.
Autherine Lucy.
Wasn't much of a piece.
There's talk of
integration at Randolph.
What do you
make of that?
There will be no negroes
at Randolph in our time.
Well, that's good
to know.
We don't have to worry about
that Montgomery boycott.
Are you talking about
that preacher--what's his name?
Martin Luther King.
They don't do anything but
sing and not ride the buses.
Is that what
you really think?
That's what
my daddy thinks.
He says they'll get tired
and go home.
Your daddy's in
for a big surprise.
It's going to get
very ugly out there.
Before it's over, a lot
of people will get killed.
You sound like
you like the idea.
It doesn't matter
whether I do or don't.
Just is.
Are you a communist?
Ha ha ha ha!
Sweet god.
Come on!
Let's go!
Let's get tuck
a coffee.
Come on, Dee.
Coming!
I'd like coffee
to go, please.
Pack of winstons.
I saw that look.
Watch out
for old Mr. Emotion.
♪ Alpha chi bourbon ♪
♪ our hearts belong to you ♪
Ha ha ha!
Come on, tuck.
I don't believe
I live here.
My car's out back.
I'll drive you home.
And if you're
a good boy,
I'll help get your car back
in the morning.
Never turn down
an offer like that
from a beautiful woman,
right, hoyt?
Never.
Say good night,
tuck.
Good night.
Tell boots
if I get a chance
I'll stop by
and see him.
Thank you
for your help.
Does he still
take his ball home
when he doesn't
get his way?
Look, it was nice of you
to get US out of that bar--
we owe you for that--
but I don't have to listen
to you knock my fiance
and my mind for the way
I think about things.
US simpletons must have
bored you to death tonight.
Hey, Maggie...
Did you know when you get
all hot and bothered,
your chest just
turns bright red?
"...and bending down
beside the glowing bars,
"murmur, a little sadly,
how love fled,
"paced upon the mountains
overhead
and hid his face
amid a crowd of stars."
Miss Reed...
Since you insist
upon polluting
the rarified atmosphere
of my classroom
with that noxious weed,
I insist that you
hand me that pack
so I may do the same.
[Laughter]
As miss Reed
is no doubt aware,
all is not passion
and sea mist
and leering god
with the Irish.
William Butler yeats--
a Mick jerk.
[Laughter]
Mr. Foley...
Yes, sir?
Is there something
about Mr. Yeats' poem
that you appreciated
and would like to share
with the rest of the class?
No, sir, Mr. Flournoy,
nothing in particular.
No. No, sir.
Hmm.
Mr. Claibourne? Boots?
How about you?
There's a lot of charm
in the sentimental
description.
It's romantic
melodrama, really.
If you cut
through that,
you get to
something else,
something deeper,
less romantic.
Truth is, no one wants
to be alone without love,
whether you're old
or young.
What do you think,
Mr. Flournoy?
♪ Come on, baby,
let the good times roll ♪
♪ come on, baby,
let me thrill your soul ♪
let the good times roll... ♪
You could do
a damn sight better
than that
beautiful boots.
Aiken, don't start
this again.
He is
rather gorgeous.
I've thought about
how good he'd be in bed.
Aiken!
Let's get some fries
and a shake.
Looks like Delia's
going after tuck.
If jenks knew...
If jenks knew, nothing.
The guy is
a cheerleader.
What does that tell you
about his mind?
Jenks and Delia,
they're everybody's ideal--
Randolph's
Romeo and Juliet.
If that's true, then
Romeo probably has the IQ
of an argyle sock.
And Juliet
could pull a train
longer than the population
of fort benning
and come back
begging for more.
Oh!
I know.
The pot calling
the kettle black, right?
Difference is,
I'm honest.
I don't tease.
Anyway,
I've often thought
that tuck was
interesting.
I wonder
if a real woman
would scare
the pants off him.
Hi, Maggie!
Hey.
Want a gum ball?
What if we go
to New York,
right after graduation--
greenwich village.
My sister says it's
the most exciting place.
Think about it.
I got to go.
Where does tuck
usually hang out?
The senator
newspaper office,
but, aiken...
Nothing wrong with a little
competition, is there?
You be careful.
Careful? Of what?
Ha ha!
Mind if I have
a fry?
♪ Standing
on the front porch ♪
♪ I grabbed her
and kissed her ♪
♪ boy, was I surprised
when I saw her little sister ♪
♪ lights out ♪
♪ I'm glad now
that the lights were out ♪
♪ her sister knows
more about ♪
♪ what to do
when the lights go out ♪
♪ her mama looked at me ♪
♪ she was peepin'
through the window ♪
♪ the way
she looked at me ♪
♪ you would have thought
I was a sinner ♪
♪ lights out ♪
♪ lights out... ♪
The other night
I met someone you know.
Who's that, baby?
Hoyt Cunningham.
Why don't you go
play someplace else?
Where'd you see him?
Delia talked me into
going to ma beechie's.
There was a fight,
and hoyt broke it up.
Why are you going
without me?
I'm a big girl.
Not big enough.
Nothing happened
anyways.
He bird-dog you?
He wanted to make sure
we knew how stupid we are
at the university
for the ignorant.
He wouldn't
bird-dog you
if he knew
you were mine.
He didn't know
you were mine?
I told him
you were my boyfriend.
What did he have to say
for himself about that?
He said he might just stop by
and see you sometime.
Let him.
It's
a free country.
♪ Lovin'
on the front porch ♪
♪ sittin' on a swing ♪
♪ I could almost hear
those wedding bells ring ♪
♪ lights out ♪
♪ I'm glad now
that the lights were out ♪
♪ her sister knows
more about ♪
♪ what to do
when the lights go out ♪
Jenksie!
All right, y'all!
Rebecca, you want to
sing one for US?
Whoo!
♪ The wayward wind ♪
♪ is a restless wind ♪
♪ a restless wind ♪
♪ that yearns to wander ♪
♪ and he was born
the next of kin ♪
♪ the next of kin
to the wayward wind ♪
♪ the wayward wind ♪
♪ is a restless wind ♪
♪ a restless wind ♪
♪ that yearns to wander ♪
♪ and he was born
the next of kin... ♪
Let's you and me go down
to the lake, Maggie.
Boots.
♪ ...to the wayward wind ♪
♪ in a lonely shack
by a railroad track... ♪
I want you bad,
Maggie.
I can't.
♪ ...i guess that sound
of the outward bound ♪
♪ made him a slave
to his wanderin' ways... ♪
Jenks, don't you think
it would be nice
if you treated me the same way
in front of your friends
as you did
when we were alone?
I suppose that would be
a pretty good idea.
Boots, please!
What the hell's
wrong with you?
Take a lock,
mister!
Oops!
Well, I'll just be
right back.
I love you, Dee.
I love you,
jenks.
Hey!
What the hell's
wrong with you?
Come on,
let's go party!
Brothers
in the bond, boots!
Hi, Maggie, darling.
Hey, mama kidd.
Hi, Delia.
You two have a fight
or something?
Oh, he just thinks
he's god's gift.
You'd think
his precious groveland
was a holy kingdom
or something.
Honey, it is.
Jenks went home with
boots over Christmas.
He said it was straight
out of gone with the wind.
Racehorses
and everything.
♪ Oh, doo-dah, doo-dah ♪
Maggie deloach...
Sometimes I think
you are really crazy.
I'd give my heart and soul
to get married
and live
in a place like that.
You just act
like it's nothing.
In the first place,
I haven't seen his Tara,
so I don't know
what it looks like.
Second, I haven't
mentioned marriage.
Third,
if we got married,
we wouldn't live with his
mama and the infamous judge.
Honey, they're
going to die.
I mean,
sooner or later.
Then you will be
the mistress of groveland.
All those servants.
Boots'
beautiful children.
Sure seems like a fairy tale
come true to me.
Is that really
what you think, Dee?
Yes, ma'am.
I mean, it's
just right out there,
and if you
closed your eyes
and just reached out,
you could get it,
just like that gold ring
on the merry-go-round.
I mean,
can you really imagine
wanting anything else?
Now you think
about that, Maggie.
You're an Alpha chi delta,
boots says.
Oh, that's nice.
So many
of our delta girls
affiliate
with that sorority.
You're housed in such
a lovely old mansion.
But nothing to compare
with groveland.
You and the judge have
the most beautiful home.
This is nothing but
a big old pink elephant.
Come on, coralee.
Groveland is the best
plantation in the delta,
a regular shangri-la,
right, judge?
Shangri-la, huh?
Don't you wish.
Whatever's
going to happen
to this
shangri-la
after I'm gone,
Maggie,
is anybody's
guess.
Courtney, what are
you talking about?
This
is boots' place.
With the proper help,
he'll rule the roost.
Isn't that right,
judge?
Hell, yeah.
I guess so, honey.
Maggie, think you
can keep this slug
from pissing it away
after I'm gone?
Ha ha ha ha!
Hey, judge.
Guess who's back?
Who?
Hoyt Cunningham.
Can you believe it?
He ran into Maggie
the other night.
How is old hoyt?
What's he up to,
Maggie?
I'm not sure.
I ran into him in the--
place where
he was working.
He's a photographer for
one of the wire services.
Boots told me
all about him.
As I recall, you did
most of the telling.
What exactly
did hoyt say?
I guess we did talk
for a time.
I found him
fascinating, really.
Did you know
that he believes
the negroes are planning
to enroll at Randolph,
trying to integrate?
I wouldn't worry
my pretty little head
about that, darling.
He's still
talking about
the next
great revolution?
Another civil war
fought on the delta?
Is he still
talking crap?
Courtney claibourne...
Revolution,
my busted butt.
Courtney, I won't have you
talk like that.
Don't talk like that
in front of Cleveland.
I don't give a damn.
Hey, Cleveland?
Yes, sir.
You hear talk
about riots
among the hands?
No, sir.
You thinking
about revolting?
Oh, no, sir.
That boy
better not come here
spreading
those lies.
'Cause ain't nobody
treats his niggers
better than I do.
Right, Cleveland?
Yes, sir.
You turned on me and
made me look like a fool.
Oh, Maggie--
all that stuff
about hoyt Cunningham.
You led me
right into that.
Did the trick, too.
Got the old man
off my young ass.
I didn't say that
to help you.
Why'd you say it then?
You're no nigger lover,
are you?
You don't have any idea
who I am really.
What am I going
to do with you?
You're back early.
Thought y'all were
going to Birmingham
for dinner
and a show.
Dinner and a show,
my foot.
What happened?
We never even went anywhere
near Birmingham.
Instead, we went
to this cruddy hole,
an apartment one of his
fraternity brothers has.
Said there was going to be
this party there.
Nobody showed up but me
and Mr. Fastest-hands-
in-Alabama.
He said he had
something important to ask me
and he wanted
to be alone.
What did he
want to ask?
Jesus, Maggie!
He asked me
to go all the way.
What did you say?
What did I say, Maggie?
I'm honors,
4.0 every goddamn semester.
I said...
Just who in the goddamn
bluebelly hell
did he think he was?
And what kind of girl
did he think I was?
And just take me home.
And?
He jumped me.
What did you do?
I drilled him hard
right in the teeth
and yelled "rape."
Do you know what
he said then?
He said, "it ain't rape
when it's willing."
You don't know, Maggie.
See, you already
have your pin.
These guys out there,
they're just--
well, he simply forced
bourbon down my throat.
I'm sure I smell like
my da-da on Friday night.
On a Friday night.
I'll talk
to Dean Howard.
We'll have that boy
out on probation.
No.
I can't do that.
Why on earth not?
Sister...
[Sniffling]
You didn't.
You haven't.
When he said
he had something
he wanted to ask me,
I thought he was
going to ask me
to wear his pin.
I need a pin, Maggie.
I'm a senior.
Oh, sister.
[Crying]
Shh.
Whoo!
Ha ha ha!
Owww!
♪ I know a cat
named way out Willie ♪
♪ he's got a cool little chick
named rockin' Millie ♪
Owww!
♪ She just walk and stroll
and Suzie-q... ♪
Is aiken Reed
prettier than me?
You're both luscious,
and you know it.
I hate her.
Oh, Dee.
You do not.
You don't understand her,
that's all.
Hey, Maggie! My sovereign
kappa rho brothers and me
did not request
the pleasure of your company
at our purple passion
weekend
so you could bake
your buns in the sun.
You got to mingle.
You, too, Delia.
They got laws
here in Alabama
against young things
staying in one place too long.
You become
open territory, honey.
Any good old boy
can just have you.
I sure wouldn't want
something of mine
stole
from underneath me.
Mmm.
Oh, my gallant knight,
I'm sure.
Here's to the judge's
code, jenksie.
Honor bound to keep
our women barefoot,
beautiful,
and mute! And mute!
Brothers brothers
in the bond! In the bond!
Owww!
Come on, boots!
I got to piss purple.
Did I ever tell you
I'm thinking about moving
to New York after graduation,
share an apartment with aiken
in greenwich village?
New York, darling?
Have you completely
lost your mind?
You'd throw away
a chance
to marry
the best-looking,
sexiest, richest boy
at Randolph
for New York City
and aiken Reed?
Come on, Maggie.
Dee, I'm not going
to New York.
I'm not going anywhere.
Aiken's going to have
some fabulous career, though.
Career?
Work is for people
like aiken,
not for you and me.
Why not you and me?
Simple.
We don't have to.
You're going to
marry boots in June
with 12 bridesmaids,
and I'm going to
marry jenks.
End of story.
♪ Since I met you,
baby... ♪
All right.
You don't think so.
You got any money
behind that?
Right there.
♪ Since I met you,
baby ♪
♪ my whole life... ♪
I want to dance.
Spud, you betting
on boots?
You getting dumb.
Where's
that money?
Right there.
Spud,
you betting on boots?
I got $5.00 says
you don't make that shot.
Come on, jenksie.
Let's dance.
Honey, I'm about to
take boots' money.
I want to dance now,
and I want
to do it slow.
Why don't we wait
for a fast one?
I'll dance your
pretty behind off.
Come on, gentlemen!
♪ Since I met you,
baby ♪
♪ all I need is you ♪
♪ oh, baby ♪
Oh!
Oh, I was
distracted on that.
Let's go, boots.
Come on.
[Thunder]
God's talking
to US, boys.
God's talking to US.
♪ Since I met you,
baby... ♪
Better go get her,
jenksie.
Look like she's doing
just fine from here.
If that's
my woman out there--
hell,
I'll go get her.
I can take care of this
just fine.
Give her hell, jenksie.
♪ I'm a happy man... ♪
Hey, Delia.
Would you like to
come back to the table?
Why don't you
just finish your game?
Dee.
♪ Any way I can ♪
Hee hee!
♪ Oh, yes,
I'm the great pretender ♪
♪ ooh-ooh ♪
♪ pretending that i'm... ♪
Maggie!
Come on!
You want some more?
Come on! Come on!
You son of a bitch!
Come here!
♪ I'm lonely,
but no one can tell ♪
You want more?
Come on!
♪ Oh, yes,
I'm the great pretender... ♪
You got him.
♪ In a world
of my own... ♪
Go take care
of your woman now.
Come on!
Now!
You move!
You move,
god damn it!
Don't you ever
do that to me!
Stupid bastard.
Poor dumb stupid bastard.
♪ I'm the great pretender ♪
♪ ooh-ooh... ♪
Delia's just
too strong for jenks.
I don't give a damn
what she is.
She's going to lose
that kappa rho pin.
Damn! If she
had my pin--
you could control her?
You pushed jenks
into it.
[Sirens]
Oh, god.
Hold it there, please.
Maggie.
Maggie! Maggie!
Oh, Maggie.
Delia,
where's jenks?
God damn it, Delia!
Where is he?
[Siren]
"Yea, though I walk
through the valley
"of the shadow of death,
"I will fear no evil,
for thou art with me.
"Thy rod and thy staff,
they comfort me.
"Thou preparest
a table before me
"in the presence
of mine enemies.
"Thou annointest
my head with oil.
"My cup runneth over.
"Surely
goodness and mercy
"shall follow me
all the days of my life,
and I will dwell in the house
of the lord forever."
Amen.
Brothers in the bond,
jenksie.
This has been a terrible tragedy
for all of US,
but we can't let
our standards slip.
The chi delts
have always had
a sense
of deep southern pride
and iron integrity
with which we face adversity.
And Delia June curry
needs US now more than ever.
With this thought in mind,
it is with
much sorrow and regret
that I propose
placing a one-year moratorium
on the chi delt involvement
of the honeysuckle queen
pageant this year.
[All talking at once]
Girls...
I honestly believe
that Delia June
would want it that way.
I second that.
All those in favor...
Ok, girls.
I need a hand count.
Would you all cooperate
and raise your hands?
Wait a minute!
We have a legacy
to uphold.
Honeysuckle queen
is a chi delt tradition.
I know that,
sue Ellen!
If the thetas win, m.A.,
we'll never live it down.
Next year during rush,
we'll pay for this.
Delia is
a beautiful girl,
but she's not
the only beauty
in this sorority.
The nominee
has to be a senior.
Listen, I'm not saying
I'm Ava gardner,
but, y'all--
sit down, corney.
Hey,
what about Maggie?
She's a senior.
No...
I don't want to.
Yes! She was
centennial queen
in lytton
over easter, right?
I don't want to.
Maggie,
you're perfect.
You've got
charm, poise,
even beauty.
Thank you.
You have more honors
than anybody else.
And boots claibourne's pin
won't exactly hurt.
Oh, it's perfect!
Excuse me...
Did I miss something?
I mean, forgive me,
but we are talking about
honeysuckle queen, am I right?
I believe
I was elected unanimously
to be the chi delt nominee
for honeysuckle queen.
I see no reason
to change that.
Ooh! Ooh!
♪ Alpha chi delta ♪
♪ sisters for
our whole life through ♪
♪ pledging
friendship and affection ♪
♪ with feelings
strong and true ♪
♪ sharing dreams together ♪
♪ standing tall
when days seem blue ♪
♪ Alpha chi delta ♪
♪ our hearts
belong to you ♪
Well, afternoon, mags.
This stranger
just wandered in here
asking for the article you wrote
about autherine Lucy.
Awfully accommodating
of you, tuck.
Thanks for handing
my article out
to anybody who
walks in off the street.
The senator circulates
to the public,
remember, mags?
Thank you.
What did
you think of it?
You got talent,
but it reads like smalltime
college girl emotion.
My journalism professor
called it "significant."
Good afternoon,
Maggie.
You definitely had something
important to write about,
but you trivialized it
until it became as
newsworthy as a bake sale.
Glad I asked.
Have you ever really
laid it on the line, Maggie?
Have you?
You don't get good
unless you get close.
I lay it on the line
by getting close.
Jean...
We have papers
to deliver.
Jean!
I'm coming.
Bye-bye, Maggie.
It was so nice
to meet you.
You, too.
I think
he likes you.
Hoyt,
see you later.
How would you like to go
to the Presley homecoming
show in tupelo tonight?
I got 2 tickets.
I can't.
Why not?
I just can't.
Why?
Too dangerous?
Too bad.
Hoyt.
This better not
be trivial.
♪ Well, it's a-one
for the money ♪
♪ two for the show ♪
♪ three to get ready,
now go, cat, go ♪
♪ but don't you
step on my blue suede shoes ♪
♪ well,
you can do anything ♪
♪ but lay off-a
my blue suede shoes ♪
♪ well, you can
knock me down ♪
♪ step on my face ♪
♪ slander my name
all over the place ♪
♪ well, do anything
that you want to do ♪
♪ but, uh-uh, honey,
lay off them shoes ♪
♪ and don't you
step on my blue suede shoes ♪
♪ well,
you can do anything ♪
♪ but lay off-a
my blue suede shoes ♪
Let's go!
♪ Well,
you can burn my house ♪
♪ steal my car ♪
♪ drink my liquor
from an old fruit jar ♪
♪ well, do anything
that you want to do ♪
♪ but, uh-uh, honey,
lay off-a them shoes ♪
♪ and don't you
step on my blue suede shoes ♪
♪ well,
you can do anything ♪
♪ but just stay off-a
my blue suede shoes ♪
Rock it!
♪ Well, it's a-one
for the money ♪
♪ two for the show ♪
♪ three to get ready,
now, go, go, go ♪
♪ but don't you
step on my blue suede shoes ♪
♪ well,
you can do anything ♪
♪ but just lay off-a
my blue suede shoes... ♪
Hey!
Get back
with your kind, boy!
♪ ...blue suede shoes ♪
We're going to teach you
a lesson now, boy.
♪ Well, you can
do anything ♪
♪ but lay off-a
my blue suede shoes ♪
No!
You don't belong!
Break it up!
Get out of here!
No!
No! He didn't
do anything!
♪ Well, it's a-one
for the money ♪
♪ two for the show ♪
♪ three to get ready... ♪
He didn't do anything!
♪ ...my blue suede shoes ♪
♪ well,
you can do anything ♪
♪ but just stay off-a
my blue suede shoes ♪
Get that nigger!
Get him!
Uh!
No! You can't do that!
Get him!
Ah!
No!
Everybody back!
You're going home
now, baby.
They can't do this.
Keefi, he wasn't
doing anything.
You listen
to me, girl.
You're going home
now, you hear?
He was just dancing.
Go home.
[Siren]
Let's go.
Go home.
I--
it doesn't
concern you.
Hoyt!
[Crying]
[Cheering]
I see your three,
and I raise you one.
I'm out.
Maggie.
Honey, you lost?
Can I talk
to you?
Well...
Sure.
Just playing cards
with the girls.
These are
my friends, Maggie.
We share the same
day off--poker day.
This is Maggie.
She's one
of my girls.
Hi.
Oh.
Well, this ain't no
set-and-chat visit.
Things a little too
black and white for that.
Come on into
my elbow room, sugar.
Go on in.
Girl, what
about your hand?
Just sit tight.
[Train]
It's about last night,
isn't it?
Honey, what's
really eating you?
That man,
I want to know
what happened to him.
You here about
a negro boy
you don't even know?
You telling me
that, baby?
It doesn't matter
whether I know him or not.
What happened was wrong,
and I want to do
something about it.
Now, you listen
here, girl.
There's business,
and then
there's business,
and this
ain't yours.
I shouldn't
feel anything
when something
like that happens?
What I'm saying is,
this ain't
your business.
Come here.
Disappear boys.
It's their business,
only theirs.
Disappear boys?
Boys like last night.
Sometimes we...
Their mamas
never find out
what happened
to them.
And I don't mean
they go away
like magic.
You're saying,
just ignore it?
Do nothing?
Honey, I prays...
Him...
And him
point the way.
Take care of
all of them
that been
vanished to death.
Keefi...
I still can't believe
that's enough.
Because you still believe
in Santa claus, baby.
I believe in
doing what's right.
Maggie, look here.
Look at these two.
They were boys,
my lights.
Ain't nobody
like them know more
about the pumping
of pain
or how to take it.
They's all I got.
I still want
to do something.
I know, girl.
Just a second.
Can I come in?
Yeah, come on in.
I tried to call you,
but they said
you weren't there.
Well,
excuse the mess.
Mama said there would
be days like this.
How about
years like this?
Would you like
to sit down?
Hoyt.
Last night when
everything was happening,
you were just standing there
taking pictures.
You didn't do anything
to try and help.
Why?
Well, that's my job.
That's what I do.
I understand
that's what you do.
Don't you care?
Come on, I want to
show you something.
It's him.
Hoyt...
I better go.
Maggie?
I want you
to have these.
[Talking and laughing]
Oh, Maggie.
Maggie!
Maggie, she did it.
Sister did it!
Ah!
I thought we'd never
get her pinned.
Maggie!
Maggie, I did it.
I finally did it.
I got pinned.
Oh!
Yeah!
Oh, sister.
Oh, Maggie,
I finally did it.
I'm safe, Maggie.
Hey, y'all,
the boys are here!
♪ Her lips are sweet
and Ruby red ♪
♪ her eyes shine
like southern skies ♪
♪ I'm proud to hold
her hand in mine ♪
♪ for she's the girl
of my dreams ♪
♪ and I will love her
till I die ♪
♪ my theta pi lambda
queen ♪
Great!
♪ Deep within
the heart of Dixie ♪
♪ southern breezes
whisper low ♪
♪ Alabama's sun
beams brightly ♪
♪ over Randolph's
red and gold ♪
♪ other memories
fade and perish ♪
♪ yours alone will shine ♪
♪ Randolph,
o sweet Alma mater ♪
♪ our loyalties
are thine ♪
What are you doing here
at this hour?
I needed some quiet.
You ok?
Let's just say
that I had a long night.
I'm fine.
There you are.
Morning, tuck.
I came for you
this morning,
but you weren't there.
I was here.
Oh, right.
Of course.
Aren't you going
to read it?
Maggie,
not only do I have
my own editorial
to write,
I've got about 10 pounds
of galleys to proof.
I'm sure yours is good.
I wouldn't dare rewrite you.
I know better.
I think you better
read it, tuck.
Y'all want some nestle's
and a glazed doughnut?
No, thanks.
Suit yourself.
I can't run it.
Why not?
You know why not.
The board of directors
will lose their minds.
This isn't the newspaper
speaking out. It's me.
Maggie, I got
my young ass in a ringer
over that simple piece
that you wrote
about autherine Lucy!
This will drive every Dean,
regent, plus the president
straight up
the goddamn wall!
Are you going
to run it or not?
Well, we're going to get
booted out of here,
right off the senator
staff, maybe the school.
Y'all sure
you don't want anything?
Jean!
What?
Maggie, you've thought
about the consequences,
I take it?
The chi delts,
your parents, boots,
your degree.
I want to run
this column.
Well,
I'll tell you what.
I'll take this before
the board of publications
on Monday night.
That's the best
I can do.
Dean Howard's
on the board, right?
Yes, he is.
Will you stand up
for me, tuck?
Honest?
I don't know.
I just don't know.
Maggie.
This here
is really good.
I wish
I'd written it.
Thanks.
Hey, sister said
you've been trying
to reach me
all morning.
Are you ok?
Comme ci, comme ca.
Well, what's going on?
I'm pregnant.
I thought you said
you were using something.
I was.
Well, what happened?
Maggie, diaphragms
don't always work.
Sometimes
they just don't work.
Sad but true.
You pays your money, and
you takes your chances.
What are you
going to do?
That's why
I wanted to see you.
I'm leaving Randolph.
I wanted
to say good-bye.
I'm going to miss you
very much, Maggie.
No. You can't leave.
You don't have
to leave.
Listen. I'm going
to New York.
My sister's got this cute
apartment and a terrific job
with an interior
design firm in the city.
She thinks she can
get me a job with her.
But without a husband,
without a father
for the baby?
I never wanted
to be married, Maggie.
Maybe what I'm looking
for really is a man,
but not any I met
up till now.
And I don't think
it's a man anyway,
more like something
I'll do myself.
Something sort of great!
You know me, Maggie.
I've always
wanted to think
I'll be a great woman
someday.
I'll write you
when I get settled.
Ok?
Can you believe it,
Maggie?
I'm going to be living
in greenwich village.
Come on.
Help me get packed.
"X" marks the spot.
Life starts here.
Now.
Good afternoon.
Come in. Come in.
Won't you please
be seated?
Now,
on Monday evening past
the publication board met,
but you already knew that.
I knew they met,
yes, Dean Howard.
I might add
that your editor-in-chief
placed your opus
before the board
with considerable passion.
He said yours was a sane
and eloquent voice on campus
that deserved to be heard,
and rightly so.
Fine sentiments,
miss deloach.
Of course
there have been,
shall we say,
racial inequities.
I applaud
your sensitivity.
Thank you.
But here at Randolph
we depend
on the generous wisdom
of our board of regents
and on the gracious pocketbooks
of our dedicated alumni.
Shall we get to
the point, Dean Howard?
The point is...
That because of the volatile
political atmosphere
in Alabama today,
we cannot allow you
to publish this column.
Would you mind
elaborating
just a little, sir?
I'm not quite sure
what you're getting at.
We're dealing with
a very sensitive issue here,
things that go beyond
your awareness
and understanding.
You'll just have to trust US
as educators
to know what's right.
But can you be more
specific, Dean Howard?
I could be, but
I choose not to be.
And if we choose
not to trust you
and publish it
anyway?
Now you listen to me,
young lady.
I don't want to burst
your little bubble.
I don't even want to be
the one to call your daddy
and tell him
I'm sending you home.
But you know what?
I won't just
make you resign,
I'll expel your behind so fast,
your head will swim!
You, too, son!
Well...
I'm sure that in time,
miss deloach,
you'll not only see
what's at stake
for you personally,
but you'll see the wisdom
of our position as well.
Am I clear?
I regret this unpleasantness
had to happen.
And I apologize for
my choice of language
and for being so brief.
The junior chamber of commerce
is expecting me for lunch.
If you'll excuse me, then.
You can take Rhett Butler.
I'm going to marry
Ashley wilkes
as soon as
Olivia de havilland dies.
Frankly, m.A.,
I don't give a damn.
I don't know nothing
about birthing no babies!
I don't know what
to do with my hair.
I see curls,
lots of curls.
Good god,
where have you been?
Working.
The newspaper.
Are you crazy?
The ball starts
in 2 hours,
and you're still
working?
Dee,
I'm not going.
Did you and boots
have a fight again?
It's not about that.
Don't be ridiculous.
Of course you're going.
Maggie, this is the biggest,
most important night
of my life.
You've got to go.
I want you
to read something.
Later.
I'll read it later.
Now, Dee, please.
Well, all right.
Go on! Get in the tub!
Read it, ok?
I'm reading.
Come on, girls!
Let's get beautiful.
Keefi, save me.
I know. Curls.
Lots and lots of curls.
Hi.
Hi. Hi.
There are traditions,
and there are traditions,
but the coronation
of the honeysuckle queen
here at Randolph
is a tradition of renewal.
Rebirth, you might say,
of a history
and heritage
we Cherish.
Like the song says,
"old times here
are not forgotten.
"Look away,
"look away,
look away, dixieland."
All the fraternities
have voted.
Your honeysuckle queen--
your honeysuckle queen
for 1957
is miss Delia June curry!
Yay, Delia!
Thank you,
especially to my sisters
at Alpha chi delta.
When I was hurting,
you were there for me.
You know,
when you mix 100 years
of tradition,
gentility, and
good old southern honor...
With friendship,
you get a way of life
you know in your heart
you could never
turn your back on,
because if you betray
that which you say you love,
you only betray yourself.
♪ In dixieland,
I'll take my stand ♪
♪ to live and die
in Dixie ♪
♪ away ♪
♪ away down south
in Dixie ♪
Whoo!
Whoo-hoo!
"Our eyes met,
and I looked into his,
"but through them really
into another country.
"It was the country
of the human heart,
"and I knew
I lived there with him,
and so do you."
Now listen to this part.
"By all the rules
of southern womanhood,
"I should have remained
polite and uninvolved,
"but his look riveted me,
"and I ran out of excuses.
"Perhaps the time has come
for all of US
"to see more clearly, to witness
our common humanity..."
She's here.
"And to turn to equality."
I should have talked
to you about it
before it was printed.
I'm sorry.
Then why don't we have
a talk right now?
It seems to me like she's taking
a stand for integration.
Let me see that thing.
How could you do
something like this?
This isn't some
kind of joke, is it?
What am I supposed
to tell these people?
They're our friends.
I knew you would be
hurt by this.
Don't you see?
I had no choice.
I needed--
you needed, Maggie?
For god's sakes!
What about me?
What about US?
I'm sorry.
I've been looking
for you.
I came here
to give you this.
Maggie,
wait a minute.
Maggie.
We can fix this,
sugar.
♪ The wayward wind ♪
I don't think so.
There's nothing left
to fix.
Come on, Maggie.
You don't mean that.
You know, Maggie,
I'd have been over
at the chi delt house tonight
looking for my pin anyway!
That's right! I'd have been
right over there!
I've been planning on it!
♪ The next of kin ♪
I've been planning
on it, Maggie!
♪ To the wayward wind ♪
♪ the next of kin ♪
I didn't mean it,
Maggie.
♪ To the wayward wind ♪
♪ at the corner
of magnolia and julep street ♪
♪ is Eleanor's body shop ♪
Ok, we are playing--
tomorrow morning at 9:00 A.M.,
the first negro
to register for classes
in the state college
educational system of Alabama
will enroll
at Randolph university.
Officials say that this is
a violation of state law
and are prepared to defend
Alabama's constitution.
The prospective student
will be accompanied
by federal marshals
to help enforce
this nation's new
civil rights laws.
Well, god bless the south
and long live Alabama.
This has been
Charles Payton Tucker,
the voice
of Randolph university.
Bye.
I got something
for you.
It's a glory-o-the-snow.
Keefi...
You're my light.
Any moment now,
Randolph university...
Here she comes!
[Horn honking]
Go home!
We don't need
your kind here!
Go home!
Go back
where you came from!
You ain't got no right
coming down here!
Go home!
Nigger!
You get out of here!
You trash!
Young lady,
I have been ordered
by the government
of the United States
to allow you entry
to this institution
of higher learning.
I do so reluctantly,
under duress.
However...
May I submit to you
that when I was
inaugurated governor,
I took an oath
to uphold and perpetuate
the laws of this great state,
and I also intend
to fulfill that oath
to keep this state free
and sovereign.
Yeah!
Governor!
Who's running
this state anyway?
Please, please.
People, go home!
Please! Go home!
Let's go!
You can't do this!
It's not right!
It's not!
You want
to go say good-bye?
Yeah.
Ok. I'll wait here.
Maggie.
I heard
you were leaving.
I refused to apologize
to Dean Howard,
so I have no choice.
I'm sorry
to hear that.
Say good-bye
to boots for me.
I will.
Take good care of him.
I promise.
Take care
of yourself, Dee.
I'll never
forget you, Maggie.
I swear
I never will.
Bye.
Well...
Well, I'll be
seeing you.
Hoyt.
You pull out
all the stops, Maggie.
You go get 'em.
♪ One fine morning ♪
♪ when my search
is over ♪
♪ I will fly away ♪
♪ Restless heart,
a change is coming ♪
♪ I may never feel
the same ♪
♪ all I had
is gone forever ♪
♪ hear me calling out
your name ♪
♪ take my hand,
we'll walk together ♪
♪ heading for
the higher ground ♪
♪ many tears will
line the highway ♪
♪ I'll never
let you down ♪
♪ dreams of faith,
hope, and glory ♪
♪ shelter me
beneath your wing ♪
♪ you're my light,
my love, my longing ♪
♪ the heart of everything ♪
♪ dreams of faith,
hope, and glory ♪
♪ shelter me
beneath your wing ♪
♪ you're my light,
my love, my longing ♪
♪ the heart of everything ♪
♪ take my hand,
I'll walk beside you ♪
♪ I'll never
let you go ♪
♪ oh, in the end
we'll be together ♪
♪ and find our way
back home ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ dreams of faith,
hope, and glory ♪
♪ shelter me
beneath your wing ♪
♪ you're my light,
my love, my longing ♪
♪ the heart of everything ♪
♪ dreams of faith,
hope, and glory ♪
♪ shelter me
beneath your wing ♪
♪ you're my light,
my love, my longing ♪
♪ the heart of everything ♪
♪ dreams of faith,
hope, and glory ♪
♪ shelter me
beneath your wing ♪
♪ you're my light,
my love, my longing ♪
♪ the heart of everything ♪
Captioning made possible by
mgm home entertainment
captioned by the national
captioning institute
--www.Ncicap.Org--
Watch Movies, TV Series & Live Sports
www.admitme.app