Ladies and gentlemen...
The overture
to "Duel In The Sun."
"Duel In The Sun,"
two years in the making...
is a saga of Texas
in the 1880's...
when primitive passions
rode the raw frontier...
of an expanding nation.
Here, the forces of evil
were in constant conflict...
with the deeper morality
of the hearty pioneers...
and here,
as in this story we tell...
a grim fate lay waiting
for the transgressor...
upon the laws of God and man.
The characters
in "Duel In The Sun"...
are builded out of the legends
of a colorful era...
when a million acres
were one man's estate...
and another man's life was held
as lightly as a woman's virtue.
The character
of the sinkiller...
is based upon those bogus
unordained evangelists...
who preyed upon the hungry need
for spiritual guidance...
and who are recognized
as charlatans...
by the intelligent
and God-fearing.
"Duel In The Sun."
Deep among the lonely
sun-baked hills of Texas...
the great and weather-beaten
stone still stands.
The Comanches called it
Squaw's Head Rock.
Time cannot change
its impassive face...
nor dim the legend
of the wild young lovers...
who found heaven and hell
in the shadows of the rock.
For when the sun is low...
and the cold wind blows
across the desert...
there are those
of Indian blood...
who still speak
of Pearl Chavez...
the half-breed girl
from down along the border...
and of the laughing outlaw...
with whom she here kept
a final rendezvous...
never to be seen again.
And this is
what the legend says...
A flower known nowhere else...
grows from out
of the desperate crags...
where Pearl vanished...
Pearl, who was herself
a wild flower...
sprung from the hard clay,
quick to blossom...
and early to die.
Pearl.
Where's your ma?
She's in there, dancing.
Like mother, like daughter.
I'm commencing to think
I like the daughter better.
Let go!
You go away from me,
or I'll call my pa.
That renegade creole squaw-man?
That's a rich one.
I'll just raise you
fifty, Mr. Chavez.
Would you mind?
Mind what?
That weed.
I find it rather repulsive.
Pretty fancy gentleman,
ain't you, Mr. Chavez?
He's not so fancy
about his wife, if you ask me.
Look at her.
Quitting? Broke again?
Yes, gentlemen...
but there are
greater tragedies...
that I'm sure
you wouldn't understand.
Pa!
Pa, will you take me
in the Presidio?
I ain't never
been in there and...
And you never should be.
What are you doing out here
at this hour anyway?
I was just dancing.
I've told your mother
repeatedly...
this street is no place
for a girl your age.
I didn't mean no harm.
It's my fault, child, not yours.
The sins of the fathers.
Go home now, dear.
I'll be back in a little while.
Don't! Stop!
No, Chavez! Don't!
Don't! Don't! I beg you! Don't!
Pa!
I plead no mitigating
circumstances.
They deserved to die,
as I deserve to die.
For I long since
killed a person...
much superior
to either of them... myself.
I killed that person the day
I gave my family's name...
to the woman
who became my wife.
And since I believe...
the punishment
should fit the crime...
I suggest that you hang me
by the neck until I am dead.
It's from Laura Belle.
Did I ever tell you about her?
She's my second cousin.
Yes, Laura Belle
is my second cousin...
but she was
more than that to me.
You see, once upon a time,
in a different age...
in a different age
and such a different world...
I was in love.
And wonderful to believe,
the lady was in love with me.
You mustn't look at me
as though that were impossible.
I was quite the looker
in my day and very dashing.
Perhaps a bit too dashing.
And that's why
this very wonderful girl...
who might have been your mother,
decided on security...
and gave herself in wedlock
to a wealthy yankee.
Better make it fast, Chavez.
You've only got
five minutes left.
No! No!
They can't.
They can't. I won't let them.
Better that it end.
Really it is.
Your mother and I
can't hurt you any longer.
Laura Belle wants
my little girl to go to her.
Yes, just a few more weeks...
and at last,
you'll have a home...
the mother you should have had.
No, you mustn't leave me.
You mustn't.
You've been a good child.
Through some miracle,
you're good...
and you're decent,
and you're strong.
And now you must prove
that you are strong.
You will do that for me,
won't you, darling?
No tears, no grief...
now or later.
Here. Keep this scarf.
Wear it sometimes.
Get her out of here, Chavez.
Listen to me, darling.
We've very little time.
I want you to lean
on Laura Belle...
make her your inspiration
and your guide.
And then one day,
you'll be the great lady...
I've always wanted you to be.
Promise me that.
I promise.
Cross your heart?
Cross my heart.
She'll love you.
I know she will.
And you must give her
all the love you've had for me.
Smile for me.
Now, now. Head high.
Strong.
Very strong.
All threats of hell
and hopes of paradise...
one thing at least
is certain...
this life flies.
One thing is certain,
and the rest is lies.
The flower that once
has bloomed forever dies.
Ready, Chavez?
Quite ready, sheriff.
Whoa!
I beg your pardon.
You can't be...
What's your name?
None of your business.
Sorry.
I really am sorry.
I wonder if I could...
I don't talk to no strangers.
That's a good rule generally,
I grant you, but...
in this case, it...
Come on.
Won't you answer
just one question?
What is it?
Did you see
a little southern tot...
on the Guadalupe coach?
No.
Are you sure?
She was traveling alone.
You said "one question."
I know, but it doesn't
seem unreasonable if you...
Now you go away
and leave me alone.
I know all about men like you.
Well...
Good morning.
Why couldn't they have been
a little more explicit...
about just which coach
they were sending her on?
Don't worry, Jesse.
I'll drive her out to the ranch
whenever she shows up.
Thanks, Lem.
You can't miss her.
She's one of those...
well-brought-up
southern children.
Probably be hungry
and crying her eyes out.
I'll give her some milk
and blow her nose for her.
Thanks again.
And... so long!
So long.
Give my regards to the old man.
I will.
Say hello to Laura Belle for me.
Wait!
Wait! Do you know
somebody named Laura Belle?
I said, do you know
None of your business.
It is my business.
I don't talk to no strangers.
You can answer
one question, can't you?
That won't hurt you none.
All right, one question.
But remember, just one.
I know all about girls like you.
Don't you dare say that.
Pearl.
How'd you know my name?
If you hadn't been so uppity...
I'd have known who you were
a long time ago.
Now come on. Get in.
Who are you?
My mother couldn't come
to meet you...
so I came in her place.
I'm Laura Belle's son...
the older one, Jesse.
There.
I'm sorry about
not recognizing you.
I guess your clothes
sort of fooled me.
Don't misunderstand me.
I think they're beautiful.
You do?
Yes, and very unusual.
But you know...
I think I'd like to see you
in brighter colors.
Like green?
I have a green blouse.
- Green, blue, yellow maybe.
- Yellow?
I have a real pretty
yellow one right here.
- I'll put it on now.
- Not now.
Save it for tomorrow.
Here's where the ranch starts.
There's the marker...
the Spanish Bit...
a million acres
of McCanles empire.
Empire? Isn't this still Texas?
Yes, but the Senator doesn't
always acknowledge that. Look.
He puts his seal
of ownership on everything.
It's on his sons, too,
I suppose.
In fact, I'm sure
my brother Lewt and I...
are the Senator's
favorite property.
Is your brother as nice
as you are?
Girls in town think he's nicer.
- Hiya, Jesse.
- Howdy, Jake.
Fine foals.
Is that your house?
That is the residence
of Jackson Tilt McCanles
and family.
And on to the fortress...
and happiness.
Jesse! Pearl!
Here you are.
Prettiest girl ever to set foot
on Spanish Bit.
Pearl, dear.
I'm so glad you've
come to us, darling.
Here, let me look at you.
Yes, you're Scott's daughter.
And now you're ours.
You're just like he said.
I'm afraid I'm somewhat
different than he remembered.
But come, dear.
Did you take good care
of her, Jesse?
I showed her all
the points of interest.
- He did. He's nice.
- I think so, too.
You southern belles
are all alike.
Where in holleration
you been all day?
I just went down
to Paradise Flats.
- Senator, this is Pearl.
- Who?
Pearl Chavez, our cousin.
You remember. We invited her
to come and stay with us.
Don't be scared.
You're not a trespasser.
She's no cousin of mine.
She's Scott Chavez's
daughter, ain't she?
Yes, of course she is.
Why don't you say so?
Girl, what are you doing
in that getup?
Is that the latest fashion...
with them aristocratic
cousins of yours?
Or is it what they're
wearing this season in wigwams?
Come on, boy.
We got to talk business.
See you later, Pearl.
Come, dear.
I'll take you to your room.
He don't want me here.
You mustn't mind the Senator.
He doesn't mean anything by it.
It's his way ever since...
ever since his accident.
Accident?
It's a long story...
and, I'm afraid,
not a very pleasant one.
I wish we had
a better room for you...
but later on,
we'll speak to the Senator.
Lewton, dear.
This is Pearl.
My youngest son... Lewton.
Pleased to meet you, Lewton.
Pleased to meet you...
Pearl.
Come, Pearl.
You and Lewton will have
plenty of time later on...
to get to know one another.
I'm sure we will.
Yay... boy.
Sounds of the rude world
Heard in the day
Lulled by the moonlight
Have all passed away
Beautiful dreamer
Queen of my song
List' while I woo thee...
Where will I put
your medicine, Mrs. McCanles?
Leave it on the table.
Mrs. McCanles,
can I get married?
But, Vashti, whom do
you want to marry?
Nobody in particular, ma'am.
I just thought I'd kind of
like to get married.
Of course, Vashti.
You may marry
whenever you wish.
Thank you, ma'am.
Do you know anybody...
who would be nice
for me to marry?
No, I don't,
but I'll think about it.
Thank you, ma'am.
There's no particular hurry.
That Vashti.
I'm afraid I'll never be able
to train her properly.
And as to marriage...
Sit down.
I'm glad your father
sent you to me.
All you have to do
is behave like a lady.
Not that
Scott Chavez's daughter...
could ever be anything
but a lady.
I'm a good girl, ma'am.
Of course you are, dear,
but you see...
you'll be the only young girl
at Spanish Bit.
No one could blame you...
if your head
were turned a little.
You take Lewton, for instance.
He's such an attractive boy.
I think Jesse's much nicer.
But you scarcely know Lewton.
Of course, he's
a bit undisciplined...
but perhaps that's what gives
westerners their charm.
The Senator was like that.
That's why, when your father...
Jesse always chides me
for talking about the past.
I hope Jesse likes me.
We're going to lose him someday.
I've known that ever since
he came back from law school.
I've been so selfish.
He'd have gone long ago
if it weren't for me.
My firstborn... he's so good.
He's made such
a difference in my life.
- Ma'am?
- Yes, Pearl?
I'll be a good girl.
I promise I will.
I want to be like you.
That's what my father wanted.
I'm afraid neither
your father nor I...
found happiness, child.
I hope you will.
Come, child.
This is no way to begin.
Do you know this waltz?
Will you stop
that infernal instrument!
King me, Senator.
I always figured when I moved
into my own quarters...
I'd be rid of that noise.
I guess that's it, Senator.
I think I'll take me
a little stroll.
Now we got that papoose
to put up with.
I don't know.
She looks like
a pretty cute tamale to me.
You think so?
Wouldn't appeal to me none.
Of course, I always
liked my women more...
Say, Senator.
Yeah, Lewt?
You know that last trip
I took up to Abilene?
Yeah.
I was driving the herd all day
and kind of tired...
and felt like getting
some relaxation.
Yeah. Didn't happen
to drop into a place...
called the Last Chance, did you?
How did you find that out?
Sent them a check
for 1,600 just yesterday.
That's how I found out.
I guess I had
a few drinks too many.
That's all right.
A fella's got to sow
some wild oats sometime.
What's the money for?
Senator...
I hope someday I'll be like you.
The only thing
I don't like about you...
is the miserable way
you play poker.
Trying to fill inside straights
is a sucker's game.
Go on, boy. Go on. Run along.
What a boy.
How'd they come
to name you Pearl?
I don't know, sir.
Couldn't have had
much eye for color, could they?
They might better have called
you Pocahontas or Minnehaha.
Ain't that right?
I guess so.
All right, Minne, on your way.
Good night, sir.
Minne... ha ha.
Ha ha.
Hello, Pearl. What's the matter?
Are you unhappy?
Don't you like Spanish Bit?
If everybody was like you.
If everybody was like me,
the world would be...
a terribly frustrated
sort of place.
What do you mean?
Nothing for you to worry
your pretty little head about.
I want to learn.
Will you learn me?
Your ma says you're a lawyer.
I want to be a lady
and know everything, like her.
I wonder if learning
ever made mother any happier.
- I wish I could do that.
- What?
Make rings like that.
Can I try? Let me try.
No, Pearl. Now whoa.
Ladies aren't supposed to smoke.
Now you won't want
to learn me things, will you?
You don't like me
no more, do you?
Of course I do.
I'm afraid a lot of men
will want to learn you things.
I think you better go to bed...
like a good little girl.
We'll discuss your education
another time.
All right.
Good night, Pearl.
Good night, Jesse.
Good night.
What do you want?
I hate you!
Don't you pretend
nobody ever did that before.
They didn't. Nobody did.
Nobody's going to.
You little...
You leave that alone!
I reckon he must be
the white half.
I forgot to say
good night, ma'am.
Sometimes I feel like
a motherless child
That ain't no ham, Miss Pearl.
That's a pig.
Same thing.
But Mrs. McCanles,
she's very particular...
and she don't want no big pig
listed like no little ham.
Here. Maybe you better
make the list, Vashti.
No, ma'am. I can't write.
Mrs. McCanles says to me once,
"Vashti, can you write?"
And I says, "Mrs. McCanles..."
Vashti.
Mrs. McCanles says to me once,
"Vashti, can you write?"
And I says, "Mrs. McCanles..."
Vashti!
Mrs. McCanles says...
That's Mr. Lewt.
I think he wants to see me.
Vashti, where are you?
I'm scared of that Mr. Lewt.
He says to me once,
"Vashti, you're empty-headed."
Vashti!
Tell Miss Pearl
to come out here.
Miss Pearl...
I heard him. Tell him I'm busy.
Why don't you tell him...
and I'll just run along
up to the house?
All right, I'll tell him.
What do you want?
Thought you might like
to see some tricks.
Watch this.
That's a good boy.
Hey, Lewt.
What do you want?
I thought you were supposed to
be on the round-up today.
And suppose you tend
to your mortgages...
and stop sticking your nose
in my business.
Just as one civilized man
to another, l...
if that isn't insulting you...
I have a little
suggestion to make.
All right. Let's have it.
Why don't you
leave this one alone?
She may do very nicely
if given half a chance.
What's the matter, judge?
You got her earmarked
for yourself?
Hey, Pearl.
Come on, Dice. Push.
Whoa.
Give me a good push.
Whoa, boy.
I want you to meet a lady.
Now bow for the lady, Dice.
He's right smart.
What do you think
of my new girl, Dice?
Oh? Maybe not.
Did you teach him all that?
All that and lots more.
He'll turn on a dime
and give you change.
- Do you want to try him?
- Me ride him?
You're just having fun with me.
Or can't you ride bareback?
- Of course I can.
- Let me see you.
I could show you,
but I got work to do.
Of course, if you don't dare,
I don't give a doggone.
Yeah?
Get off him.
Sure enough. He won't throw you.
He's smooth as cream.
Come on!
Now git!
Open the gate!
You all right?
That was a fool thing to say.
You never rode bareback
before in your life.
I never said I had.
Is she hurt, Lewt?
No. Get out of here.
Can we do anything?
Go on and mosey, will you?
Sure.
You got gumption,
but you ain't got no sense.
If you'd only let me
start him right...
instead of scaring him that way.
It wasn't him that was scared.
He won't throw me next time.
You better stick
to buggy-riding.
Maybe him and me
ain't your style.
Ain't no maybe about you.
I wish you'd let me
ride him some more.
Sure.
How'd you like me
to give him to you?
You mean for keeps?
You're not just teasing?
No. I guess you'd
rather have Jesse...
pick you out a riding horse...
even if he don't know
the difference...
between a pinto
and a strawberry roan.
I like this one.
And you like me,
don't you, honey?
You won't throw me no more.
All right. He's yours.
Let's you and me ride down
to the sump after supper, huh?
Where's that?
A shady place
over by Hidden Canyon.
The water's good and deep now,
almost over your head.
You mean go swimming... together?
I'll bring along my guitar,
play us some music.
You got a nerve.
The moon will be
pretty near full.
You didn't buy me,
just giving me a horse.
I'll be waiting for you
after supper out by the bell.
I won't go.
I won't!
Listen to this for poppycock.
"And the benefits
to be derived...
"by the small ranchers
from the new railroad...
"are too numerous
to need recounting here."
"Small ranchers."
Ignorant, nasty,
spoiling the open range...
with their measly fences.
And say, Jesse.
I should have told you before.
Them surveyors had the gall...
to come traipsing
over Spanish Bit...
with them infernal
spyglasses of theirs.
I almost fired
that new foreman Ken...
for letting them on the place.
Shouldn't have
done that, Senator.
Why not?
Because it wasn't Ken
who let them on the place.
Nobody else would
have had the nerve.
I was the one that told them
they could do it.
- Have you gone plumb crazy?
- I don't think so.
I thought it might be
a good idea to cooperate...
and have the tracks where
they'd do the most good.
Good? What do you mean good?
It's getting rather cool,
don't you think?
For one thing...
the railroad will bring
new people, a school.
Paradise Flats will become
a real town instead of...
And that same railway
will ship...
a lot of emigrants
from up north down here...
and they'll start in voting
and putting in taxes.
It's your ranch.
I was just trying to be helpful.
Spanish Bit's going to
belong to you someday...
you and Lewt.
So I don't see why you don't...
Senator, I know
you mean well for me.
You've always been
generous to us.
Maybe Lewt and I would be closer
to what you wanted us to be...
if you hadn't been so generous.
What's wrong with Lewt?
Nothing at all
that you'd object to.
That's not the point.
I'm the one who's the maverick.
I don't know
what you're talking about.
I'd like one McCanles to give
something to this state...
and not just take from it.
Good night, sir.
Your son, ma'am?
Yes, Senator.
Who's there?
Is that you, Jesse?
Hello, Pearl. Nice night.
Want to take a little walk?
It's kind of late.
I think I'd better go...
Where were you going when l...
Got to get me
somebody to love
I...
I guess that's Lewt.
Certainly is Lewt.
He's the best serenader...
this side of the Rio Grande.
I don't care if he is.
Him and his old guitar.
Just because he gave me a horse.
I know why, too.
He can't fool me none.
That's a horse
on Lewt, isn't it?
I didn't really
want to meet him.
Honest, I didn't.
It was just that
I was kind of lonesome and...
I know.
Do you still want me
to take that walk with you?
I don't know why not.
Lewt can supply the charming
musical background.
Got to get me
somebody to love
I'll be...
Thanks, Lewt.
You're a better wrangler
than all of them.
Sid, see that chestnut
over there?
She looks lame.
Take her out to pasture.
Sure.
It's hotter than a stove lid.
Sure wish we was over
at the sump right now.
And somebody else figures
the same way, I reckon.
Looks like she's heading
for a cool-off.
- I'll see you later.
- Where are you going, boss?
- I got business.
- That lucky stiff.
I wish I was a McCanles.
Good afternoon.
How's that water?
As cool as it looks?
You go away from here.
- Care for a swimming lesson?
- No.
What if I just stay around,
keep you company?
Don't you dare.
I'm sorry, honey.
I can't hear a word you say.
Move over.
You can't come in here.
Just act like I'm not even here.
Act like we never even met.
You disappointed?
If you ain't the lowest,
dirtiest, meanest...
Come on out.
I ain't stopping you.
I can't, with you there.
Wait till it's plumb dark,
for all I care.
Let go! Let me down!
Making me late for supper
just to be mean!
What will your ma think?
If you hadn't been so doggone
scared I'd see something...
you'd have been home
a long time ago.
Little tiger cat.
Evening, Pearl.
Have a good swim?
Let me through!
Am I too late for supper?
I mean, is everybody finished?
Mrs. McCanles say anything?
Yes, ma'am.
She said, "Where's Miss Pearl?"
And I said, "I don't know,
Mrs. McCanles."
And she said,
"Where's Mr. Lewton?"
And I said,
"I don't know, ma'am."
And she said, "Well..."
Pearl, dearest.
I was so worried about you.
Sorry, ma'am.
What happened?
I went riding.
With Lewton?
Vashti, get Miss Pearl
some supper.
Yes, ma'am.
The Senator's
got rules about supper.
He says to me,
"Don't you ever..."
- Vashti.
- Yes, ma'am.
Did you go riding with Lewton?
No, ma'am...
I didn't go riding with Lewton.
He wasn't here
for supper either.
He's coming.
But he wasn't with you?
We just happened to meet up.
I see.
But why is your hair wet?
I was down to the sump.
You went in swimming?
Yes, ma'am.
With Lewton?
No, ma'am.
I didn't, ma'am.
Honest, I didn't.
All right, Pearl. L...
Evening, ma.
Good evening, Lewton.
Sorry to be late.
We were down to the sump.
I think I'll take a ride
over to El Paso tomorrow...
and get me a little fun
and relaxation.
Anything I can bring you, ma?
No, thank you.
Pearl, I think
I'll try to get you one...
of them newfangled
bathing suits.
She swims real well, ma.
Where'd you learn?
Oh, my dear!
You... you varmint!
What you getting
your bristles up about?
Giddy!
Miss Pearl, wake up.
What is it?
What's the matter?
Well...
What time is it?
It must have been about 9:00...
when Mrs. McCanles
says to me, "Vashti...
"when Mr. Jubal Crabby
gets here..."
What is it? Who's Mr. Crabby?
Why did you wake me up?
I almost forgot.
Mrs. McCanles wants to see you
up in the sitting room.
Maybe you better hurry.
She's been a-waiting.
I didn't know where you was...
so I said,
"I'll go see Mr. Lewton."
And he said...
Why are you so slow?
I don't rightly know...
exceptin' I always have
so much to remember.
This is the child, Jubal.
Of course, she isn't dressed
quite properly, but...
Close the door, Pearl.
This is Mr. Crabby.
We have no minister
in these parts, but...
A man doesn't have to wear
the cloth to be a sinkiller.
I know that.
That's why I was so anxious...
to have you talk to the child.
Come here, girl.
You call her a child?
Under that heathen blanket...
there's
a full-blossomed woman...
built by the devil
to drive men crazy!
You mustn't frighten her.
I'm sure she only needs
a little guidance.
Guidance she needs,
and guidance she'll get...
or I ain't been the sinkiller...
from here to El Paso
for thirty years.
Sit down, girl.
You could be a woman of sin
or a woman of God.
Which is it to be?
I want to be a good girl.
Then remember that the devil's
always able to hog-tie you.
Sometimes he comes
ghosting over the plains...
in the shape
of a sneaking rustler...
and sometimes... begging
your pardon, Laura Belle...
he stakes out the home...
to the worthy
and the God-fearing.
You're curved
in the flesh of temptation.
Resisting is gonna be
a darn sight harder for you...
than for females protected
by the shape of sows.
Yes, sirree, bob, you've got to
sweeten yourself with prayer.
Pray till you sweat...
and you'll save yourself
eternal hellfire.
- Do you understand me, girl?
- Yes, sir.
Then on your knees.
Now I'm gonna start you
toward salvation.
O Lord, look upon this,
thy creature.
She's a weak vessel
and a pauper, as thou knowest.
But she wants to be
thy handmaiden.
Give her the horse sense
not to go wandering off...
in the tulies
with worthless cowpokes.
Amen.
Rise, girl.
Here. I want you to take this.
It's a hallowed medal,
and a good one.
I took it off
a thieving card sharper...
but first I shrived him...
and sent him
to the pearly gates...
as nice and pretty as any from
his own faith could have done.
You wear it, girl.
Thank you, sir.
Part Indian, ain't you?
Those ancestors of yours
will be spinning like tops...
when they know you got this on.
Just the same, it'll keep you...
sweet and clean
as the first milking.
Won't get you into heaven...
but it will comfort you
on the way there.
That is, if you use it right.
Laura Belle, don't you think...
we ought to be saying
a few words of prayer...
for them worthless cowpokes?
I got a feeling
they'll be needing...
consolation.
On your knees again, girl.
O Lord, have mercy on all men,
young and old alike...
who gaze upon this,
thy regained servant.
Amen.
Senator! Where's the Senator?
What's up?
- Senator McCanles!
- What's the stampede?
There's a great big railway gang
down close to the east fence.
How close?
They say they're coming across
Spanish Bit line this afternoon.
- What will we do?
- Get ahold of Lewt and Jesse.
Lewt's not back from El Paso.
Holleration.
I guess Jesse and me...
can handle it all right.
- Sid.
- Yes, Senator?
Listen carefully now.
Sound every bell
from here to Blue Hills ranch.
I want every wrangler,
every cowhand...
every man and boy
on Spanish Bit...
down there at the east fence,
and I want them there fast.
- Yes, sir.
- And Sid.
- Yes, sir?
- I want them there armed.
You betcha.
I don't like this, Mr. Langford.
It's your railroad,
and it's your headache...
but I still don't like it.
What do you mean,
you don't like it?
You told me we were legally
in the clear, didn't you?
Yeah, and I know you asked
the army for help, too.
And I hope they don't come.
And I hope we don't need them.
What do you mean?
I mean Jackson McCanles
don't scare so easy.
We roamed the plains together.
We fought at Vicksburg together.
And if he gives up
in this fight...
he ain't the man
I've known for fifty years.
I wish you wouldn't
try to ride, father.
You think I'm going
to sit in this house...
like some old woman?
Lift me on that horse.
If they want war,
they can have it.
- Ken.
- Yes, sir?
Strap me on here.
Come on.
I aim to defend
Spanish Bit with lead.
If there's any yellow-bellies
among you, get out now.
Are you with me?
All right, then.
Spread out in a line...
from the west marker
to Pinto Point.
Come on!
Kind of thought he wouldn't
take this lying down.
Looks like they mean business.
Smoot!
Lem Smoot, I thought you had
more sense than this.
Yeah? Since when did you
ever know me to dodge a fight?
You know I'm lawyer
for the railroad...
Never mind that stuff.
Who's the dude?
Langford is the high
mucky-muck on the railway.
Heard a lot about you, Senator.
Glad to make your acquaintance.
Can't say the same,
thank you kindly.
You better tell those
hired thieves of yours...
to pick up their tools...
and fast, if you know
what's good for you.
We have the law on our side.
If you had come into court
when I asked you to...
this land might not have been...
Never mind
that fancy legal talk.
There's my law right there.
Have you a copy
of the writ with you, Smoot?
What's the sense of...
All right. Are you our lawyer,
or aren't you?
- Now read it to him.
- Save your breath.
"From the people of
the sovereign state of Texas...
"to Jackson Tilt McCanles,
greetings."
"Greetings." Ain't that nice?
Jackson.
You and I fought to build
this state of Texas...
and I aim to see these men
perform their duties...
peacefully and as authorized.
Is that so?
I'm gonna shoot any trespasser
that comes on my property.
If you don't like that,
you can lump it...
you and the state of Texas.
Just a minute.
May I speak to you privately?
Say what you got to say
right here and now.
I'm sorry, father...
but I'm afraid
you're in the wrong.
I ain't aiming
to let you settle that.
You mean to shoot down
unarmed men?
Just like they was rattlesnakes
if they cross this line.
In that case, Senator...
Get me a pair of wire cutters.
Ferguson.
So that's where you stand.
Think I'd rather be
on the side...
of the victims
than of the murderers.
Jesse, I'm warning you.
We're going to fire
on those coolies...
the moment you cut those wires.
Their blood will be
on your hands.
Jesse, I'm asking you
for the last time.
Column left. Ho!
Thank God.
Right front into lines. Ho!
I once fought for that flag.
I'll not fire on it.
Sid, tell those men
to get back to their work.
Yes, sir.
Father, l...
Get out of my sight...
and stay away from Spanish Bit
as long as I live.
Watch Movies, TV Series & Live Sports
www.admitme.app