Thank you.
What do you feel like,
fish, chicken, steak?
- I know this terrific little...
- Pizza.
...Pizza place.
- You really live here?
- Yeah.
It used to be a warehouse
before I moved in.
It's different. Very different.
A whole lot different
than where I'm from.
Where is that?
Altoona, Pennsylvania.
Altoona.
I was thinking
more along the lines of Jupiter.
Actually, they're very close.
It's just the next lifeless planet over.
Really, it was boring.
Except for maybe music.
- They have music in Altoona?
- Well, my father, he loves music.
This one time, he took us all
to the symphony, my whole family.
It was supposed to be
this really big deal.
At first I didn't like it very much.
There is nothing to do with your feet
and there's nothing to look at.
It's boring.
I was ready to nod out,
or something.
He said, "If you close your eyes,
you can see the music."
You can, too.
Did you ever try?
See the music?
Come on, try.
Close your eyes.
Well?
Well...
I had a great time.
It was a terrific evening.
Don't you want some pizza?
Hey!
A little late, aren't you?
# Frightened by a dream
# You're not the only one
# Running like the wind
# Thoughts can come undone
# Dancing behind masks
Just subtle pantomime
# Lady, lady, lady
# I know it's in your heart to stay
# When will I ever hear you say
I love you... #
What was that for?
I wanted to see how fast
you could run.
- How did I do?
- Fair.
# Lady, lady, lady
# Don't walk this lonely avenue
# Let me touch that part of you.
You want me to... #
Do that again.
- What?
- That dance step you just did.
I can't, I was just fooling around.
I'm not a dancer like that.
- What do you mean?
- I've never studied before.
I mean, I read books and stuff
and I watch.
But I've never taken dance classes.
There's all those dancers
in one room
watching each other
and watching you.
But you dance in front of an audience
at the club every night.
It's different.
I never see them.
You go out there, the music starts
and you begin to feel it.
And your body just starts to move.
I know it sounds really silly.
But something inside of you
just clicks.
You just take off
and you're gone.
It's like you're somebody else
for a second.
Some nights, I...
Some nights I just can't wait
to get out there...
Just so I can disappear.
# Lady, lady, lady
# Don't walk this lonely avenue
# Let me touch that part of you
You want me to #
"lmagination)
# He says that he can read my mind
# The power to turn iron into gold
# She says she's seen the other side
# And knows the place
The fire burns all night
# There is an answer to the question
# So long ago down below
# Once you have it,
It never goes away
# It's in the pocket,
When you're really really lucky
# When your fantasy becomes reality
# Living inside your imagination
# It's in your pocket,
When you're really really lucky
# When your fantasy becomes reality... #
How come you don't go up there
and dance?
You look like
you could dance real good.
I'm practising.
Yeah? You know how to do
the horizontal mambo?
Jeanie, I just kid around.
I don't mean nothing. Keep that.
That's $100.
I can't take this.
Keep it.
It's my way of saying I'm sorry.
Thanks.
# It will not burn you
# And the once you may love
Only life won't make it, or just burn away #
Hanna!
Darling, here you are.
Bravo! Bravo!
At the end of every performance, does
the lead dancer always get flowers?
- Always.
- Did you get flowers like that?
- Not always.
- But once, right? At least once?
- How does that make you feel?
- You will let me know.
- Now, sleep well.
- You too.
You son of a bitch!
Was that you
or the radiator, Grunt?
Oh, shit.
Shut up, Grunt.
- Hey, it's Richie!
- Hi.
The stupid radiator broke.
- I just wanted to say goodbye.
- Where are you going?
L.A.
- L.A.?
- Got my car all packed.
I'm just going to get on the turnpike.
That's it. I'm gone.
What about Jeanie?
Look, I love Jeanie. But I don't
have it to give to her right now.
She's going to be all right.
She'll be fine.
Don't go yet. I'll make
some coffee, we can talk.
What am I going to do here?
Cook hamburgers
and pretend I'm a comedian?
I'll miss you.
Can't forget my hat.
Good luck.
Give me a turkey sandwich
and a diet 7-U)p.
- I've got that.
- Save your money.
- I was buying you lunch.
- I don't want you buying me anything.
- I don't want you buying me, period.
- What's the matter?
- I've got eyes.
- What are you talking about?
I didn't know you were a ballet fan,
I thought you liked it private.
What?
How quickly they forget.
At the dance benefit.
The blonde in the white dress.
Who's the goddamn blonde?
Blonde?
Wait a minute.
Will you wait a minute?
Wait a minute! What's going on?
Is everybody crazy?
Last night, some idiot throws
a rock through my window...
- I broke your fucking window!
- You what?
You heard me.
I smashed your stupid window.
Are you crazy?
Are you out of your mind?
Maybe.
It cost me a $170.
I had to special order it.
You've got the money!
Go fuck the blonde!
She's my ex-wife.
We have friends on the Arts Council.
I see her once a year
to take her to the stupid benefit!
Why am I explaining myself?
You didn't have to break my window.
I did it because... you pissed me off.
When I was a kid all I wanted was
to afford to eat in restaurants like this.
Were you poor?
I was so poor
I had hand-me-down lunches.
It was rough in the old days.
I used to steal
hubcaps with Johnny C.
You did?
How's the lobster?
It sucks.
Want some of mine?
I'm not hungry, thanks.
Whatever turns you on.
What turns you on?
You like phone booths?
Phone booths?
You probably just like
doing it in bed, right?
- You two look cosy.
- Alex, this is Katie.
Hello.
Nick has told me all about you.
Hi.
- You're not really a welder, are you?
- Yes, I really am.
And you really take your
clothes off at night?
- I don't really take them off.
- I was under the impression that you did.
You look great.
You didn't look this good
when we were married.
- It was the company I was keeping.
- That was good. That's funny.
Has he taken you to the steel mill?
He likes to go there on his first date.
- That was your first date, wasn't it?
- Yeah, it was.
As a matter of fact...
I fucked his brains out.
Obviously, you did.
Charmed, dear.
You loved her once, didn't you?
I thought I did in the beginning.
She was different from anyone
I had gone out with before, she was...
Well educated.
Came from a real good family.
I figured that I had really made it.
And one day, I realised that...
I'd just taken the safe route.
When I realised that, it made it easier
for me to do what I had to do.
What was that?
Let go. Start over again.
Figure out what it was
I wanted to do and go after it.
You got it, didn't you?
How did you do it?
I took a deep breath and jumped.
Hello.
I'd like to apply for admission
to the Repertory Company.
When you fill out this application,
write down all your years
of previous dance training.
Starting with the last school
you attended.
I know that part.
Auditions are by invitation only
and are performed
before the committee
and select members
of the Repertory Company.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Good morning.
May I help you?
Yes. There was a young woman here
a short time ago, wearing an army jacket.
She was here.
I was talking to her...
about admission
to the Repertory Company.
Mr Bradley, please.
Nick Hurley.
Larry! Hey.
Great. Great.
Listen, are you still
on the Arts Council?
I need a favour for a special friend.
# My baby wears his heart on his sleeves
# He wears a look on his face
That says please, please, please, love it
# Everything he wants, love it,
Everything he wants
# I just can't hesitate
When he wants what he wants
# Oh, chaka... #
He called.
# Oh chaka, oh chaka,
Oh chaka, oh chaka
# Last night he called on the telephone
# And though at two in the morning... #
- Trick or treat?
- Hey, throw that bum out!
I told you they didn't like
short people down there.
Richie!
- Did you check out the clubs there?
- Yeah.
- Come on, what happened?
- One of them offered me a job.
That's great.
As a waiter. I said,
"Me, a waiter? You got to be crazy.
"I can't take a job as a waiter.
I'm a cook."
Hi, Richie.
Hi, Jeanie.
- I missed you.
- All those giris out there?
There were no giris out there.
That's why you called me every night?
Hey, it's the cook!
Or is it the comedian?
Nice suit, Richie.
- Let's go, Jeanie.
- See you later, Richie.
See you around.
The audition!
I got it! I got it!
Nick, wait up!
- Look! Wait!
- What's going on?
- Read it.
- What?
I got the audition, look.
I applied for the Repertory Company.
You have to be invited before
you can audition and they invited me.
That's wonderful.
We have to do something about it.
When?
- How about tonight?
- Yes.
Hanna?
Well... I did it.
I knew you would.
Congratulations.
I'm so excited I can't stop shaking.
But what if I don't make it?
You will.
I know you will.
What would I do without you?
I loved the dinner.
And I loved the way
they sat us right away.
I loved that there were 50 people
waiting and we just whizzed in.
I called the restaurant last night...
and told them it was
a very special occasion.
What do you mean
you called them last night?
- Stop the car.
- Why?
Stop the goddamn car!
You called them last night
but I didn't tell you
I got the audition until this morning.
So how the hell did you know?
- Listen.
- Friends on the committee?
Asshole! Stop the car!
- Alex!
- Let me go.
You have no right to help me!
I don't want you to help me!
You're going to get yourself killed!
All I did was make a phone call.
I got you the audition,
the rest is up to you.
The whole thing has to be up to me!
I'm not going to the audition!
Good evening, Mawby's.
- Is Jeanie there?
- Alex, where have you been all week?
Come on, Jake, I don't want to hear it.
Is she there?
She doesn't work for me any more.
She's over at the Zanzibar.
- What?
- You heard me.
# Living on the edge
# Sliding downhill to where
The good giris don't but the bad giris will
# Bad giris will
# Don't wanna know your name
You can tell me lies
# Show me all the secrets
Hidden in your thighs, in your thighs
# Seduce me tonight
# I'll play acts at the stage
Dim the lights
# And baby, seduce me tonight
# I wanna be your slave
Set me in scene
# Take me all the places... #
Come on, Jeanie.
We're getting out of here.
No!
Alex! Alex!
Jesus Christ!
Alex! What the fuck!
What are you doing?
You want to make a living
rolling around on your back?
I make good money.
I thought you wanted to be a dancer.
You call that dancing?
- What's this shit?
- Stop it, that's mine.
Why did you come here?
Because you're my friend. Jerk!
- I'm cold.
- So am I.
- You don't say hello?
- No.
You didn't show up at work,
I was worried about you.
- You look like shit.
- Thanks a lot.
You're welcome.
Listen, I didn't come here to fight,
I came to see if you were OK.
Forget it, it doesn't matter.
- What doesn't matter?
- The audition. I don't care.
- You do care.
- I don't care.
If you can't be honest with yourself,
you can't with me.
I don't need you telling me what to do.
I don't need to hear your shit.
I'm not a baby!
Get out of here!
Go play with your fucking Porsche.
What you need is a kick in the ass.
You're not grown-up enough
to smoke.
The truth is, you're scared shitless
of going to that place, aren't you?
- I am not.
- Yes, you are.
You're using me
as an excuse not to go.
Get out.
You're just going to piss it
all away, Alex.
Don't you understand?
When you give up your dream, you die.
See you.
Hanna?
She died.
Yesterday.
"I'll be where the heart is)
# It's a song that just keeps playing
On the radio
# And you know
I haven't seen you for a while
# I lie awake at night
And wonder how you are
# And I wish that I could see you again
# Is it fate
Or is it luck that brings us back
# Or is it just a common point of view
# Time has put a spell on you
You never seem to change
# And I wish that I could see you again
# I'll be here where the heart is... #
- Where have you been?
- No place.
- What are you doing?
- Getting my stuff.
What are you getting your stuff for?
If it's that bad, why don't you
slit your wrists and get it over with?
I thought nothing ever got you down.
You know, when I started out,
I was 17.
I used to work
in these old movie theatres.
Every cent I had,
I spent on costumes.
I had more fancy costumes
and dresses than you do.
When I went on that stage
I was looking so good.
One day I just stopped buying them.
I don't even know what happened.
I thought about it a lot.
I just can't seem to pin it down.
The dresses got old
and I just stopped wearing them.
I got some in a trunk.
I'll show you sometime.
OK.
What the hell.
It's show time.
May the Lord be in your heart
and mind that you confess your sins
in the name of the father,
the son and the holy spirit.
Bless me father for I have sinned.
It's been a long time
since my last confession.
I want...
I want so much.
# First, when there's nothing... #
Can I start again?
# First, when there's nothing
# But a slow, glowing dream
# That your fears
# Seems to hide
# Deep inside
# Your mind
# All alone
# I have cried
# Silent tears
# Full of pride
# In a worid
# Made of steel
# Made of stone
# What a feeling
# Being's believing
# I can have it all
# Now I'm dancing for my life
# Take your passion
# And make it happen
# Pictures coming alive
# Now I'm dancing through my life
# What a feeling
# Being is believing
# I can have it all
# Now I'm dancing for my life
# Take your passion
# And make it happen
# Pictures come alive
# You can dance right through your life
# What a feeling
# Being's believing
# I can have it all
# Now I'm dancing for my life
# Take your passion
# Make it happen
# Pictures come alive
# You can dance
# Right through your life
# What a feeling
# I can have it all
# Now I'm dancing for my life
# Come on, come on
# Take it now
# Make it happen
# I can have it all
# Now I'm dancing for my life #
Manhunt)
# I'm going on a manhunt
# Turn it around
# Women have been hunted
# Now we hunt around
# Manhunt
# We all got the need
# The one who's been waiting
# Has taken the lead
# I'm going on a manhunt
# I'm out for the kill #
# He says that he can read my mind
# The power to turn iron into gold
# She says she's seen the other side
# And knows the place
The fire burns all night
# You've got to walk right through the fire
# It will not burn you
# The once you may love
# Only life won't make it
Or just burn away #
# Just a still town girl on a Saturday night
# Looking for the fight of her life
# In the real time worid
No one sees her at all
# They all say she's crazy
# Locking rhythms to the beat of her heart
# Changing woman into life
# She has danced into the danger zone
# When the dancer becomes the dance
# It can cut you like a knife
If the gift becomes the fire
# On a wire between will and what will be
# She's a maniac, maniac
On the floor
# And she's dancing
Like she's never danced before
# She's a maniac, maniac
On the floor
# And she's dancing
Like she's never danced before
# It can cut you like a knife
# If the gift becomes the fire
# On a wire between will
And what will be
# She's a maniac, maniac,
I sure know
# And she's dancing
Like she's never danced before #
English