MAN 1: Stay a couple more
days and then go. You've gotta see him.
WOMAN: There are
more than yesterday. They must be...
MAN 2: He will be saying prayers
in the garden. Just follow the others.
He will be saying prayers
Just follow the others.
He will be saying prayers in the garden.
Brother, Bapu is already
late for prayers.
Oh, God!
[PEOPLE SINGING
IN DISTANCE]
[MAN PRAYS IN
FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
The object of
this massive tribute
died as he had
always lived:
A private man
without wealth,
without property,
without official title or office.
Mahatma Gandhi
was not the commander
of armies,
nor a ruler of vast lands.
He could not boast
any scientific achievement
or artistic gift.
Yet men...
governments, dignitaries
from all over the world
have joined hands today
to pay homage
to this little brown man
in the loincloth
who led his country
to freedom.
In the words of
General George C. Marshall,
the American
secretary of state:
"Mahatma Gandhi has
become the spokesman
for the conscience of all mankind.
He was a man
who made humility
and simple truth
more powerful than empires."
And Albert Einstein added:
"Generations to come will scarce
believe that such a one as this
ever in flesh and blood...
walked upon this earth."
[TRAIN WHISTLE
BLOWING]
Tell me...
do you think about hell?
No, neither do I.
But-- But this man here
is a Christian, and he's written
that in order to believe--
[MEN CHATTERING
INDISTINCTLY]
Excuse me, sir.
How long have you been
in South Africa?
Uh, a week.
I don't know how you got a ticket.
Just what are you doing
in this car, coolie?
Why, I have a ticket.
A first-class ticket.
How did you get hold of it?
I sent for it in the post.
I'm an attorney.
And I didn't have time--
MAN: There are no
coloured attorneys in South Africa.
Go and sit where
you belong!
I'll take your luggage back, sir.
GANDHI: No, no, no.
Just a moment, please.
You see?
Mohandas K. Gandhi,
attorney at law.
I'm on my way to Pretoria
to conduct a case for an Indian trading firm.
Didn't you hear me? There
are no coloured attorneys in South Africa.
Sir, I was called
to the bar in London...
and enrolled at
the High Court of Chancery.
I am, therefore, an attorney.
And since I am,
in your eyes, coloured,
I think we can deduce that there
is at least one coloured attorney in South Africa.
Smart bloody Kaffir.
Throw him out.
Just move your black ass
back to third class
or I'll have you thrown off
at the next station.
But I always go first class!
I've travelled all--
But you're a rich man.
Why do you put up with it?
Yes, I am rich.
But I am Indian.
I, therefore, do not
expect to travel first class.
In England,
I was a poor student.
Oh, that was England.
This is part of England's Empire.
Mr. Gandhi, you look at Mr.
Khan and you see a successful Muslim trader,
while most South Africans
see him simply as an Indian.
And the vast majority of Indians,
mostly Hindus, like yourself,
were brought here to work
the mines and harvest the crops.
Most Europeans don't want
them doing anything else.
But that is very unchristian. I--
MOHAMMED: Mr. Gandhi,
in this country Indians are not allowed
to walk along the pavement with a Christian.
You mean you employ
Mr. Baker as your attorney,
but you can't walk
down the street with him?
KHAN:
Well, I can.
But I risk being kicked
into the gutter by someone
less holy than Mr. Baker.
Well, then it
must be fought.
We are children of God
like everyone else.
Allah be praised! And
what battalions will you call upon?
I...
I will write to the press,
here and in England.
And I will use the courts.
You'll cause a great deal
of trouble. Our position is--
We are members
of the Empire.
And we come from
an ancient civilisation.
Why should we not walk on
the pavements like other men?
KHAN: I rather like the idea
of an Indian barrister in South Africa.
I'm sure our community could
keep you in work for some time, Mr. Gandhi,
even if you caused
a good deal of trouble.
Especially if you caused
There's the English reporter.
I told you he'd come.
You also said your
article would draw a thousand people.
At least some of the Hindus
brought their wives.
No, I asked my wife
to organise that.
Some of them are leaving.
GANDHI:
"Ladies and gentlemen...
we have asked you to gather
here to help us proclaim our right
to be treated as equal
citizens of the Empire.
We do not seek conflict.
We know the strength of
the forces arrayed against us...
know that because of them,
we can only use peaceful means.
But we are determined
that justice will be done.
The symbol of our status
is embodied in this pass,
which we must carry
at all times,
but which no European
even has to have.
The first step towards
changing our status
is to eliminate this
difference between us."
Now?
You write brilliantly, but
you have much to learn about handling men.
"We do not want to ignite...
the fear or hatred
of anyone.
But we ask you,
Hindu, Muslim and Sikh,
to help us light up the sky...
and the minds of
the British authorities
with our defiance
of this injustice."
We will now burn the passes of
our committee and its supporters.
We ask you to put
your passes on the fire--
You bloody dog!
OFFICER:
Those passes
are government property!
And I will arrest
the first man who tries to burn one!
Take him away.
You little...
Sammy...
bastard!
Now! Are there any more?
If you want this kind
of trouble, you can have it.
Oh!
[GASPS]
Let me go!
Oh!
Stop.
[GRUNTS]
[SCREAMS]
The London papers have
arrived from the Cape, sire.
Yes.
The worst was the Daily Mail, sire.
They said the burning
of passes by Mr. Gandhi--
Ask Mr. Herzog
to see me.
The burning of passes by
Mr. Gandhi was the most significant act
in colonial affairs
since the Declaration of Independence.
Did they? Well, they'll find
we're a little better prepared this time.
Mr. Gandhi will find
he's on a long hiding to nothing.
GANDHI:
Hmm.
"A High Court judge has
confirmed that Mr. Gandhi
would've been within his rights
to prosecute for assault
since neither he nor
Mr. Khan resisted arrest."
I told you about English law.
As I told you about
English policemen.
GANDHI:
Yes?
HARILAL: We're very
pleased to have you back, Papa.
And I am glad to be back.
Come.
Mind your face.
Tomorrow I'll tell you about
my days in a police hospital.
AYAH:
Come, come.
Just like proper English
gentlemen. I'm proud of them.
They're boys
and they're Indian.
Will you take this off?
It pinches every time I speak.
I've got it.
[CHILD SPEAKS
INDISTINCTLY]
You'd be Gandhi.
I thought you'd be bigger.
Oh, I'm sorry.
No, that's all right.
My name is Charlie Andrews, sir.
I've come from India.
I've read a great deal
about you.
Some of it good, I hope.
Would you care
to walk?
Uh--
You're a clergyman?
Yes, uh...
I met some remarkable
people in India.
And when I read what you were doing here,
I, um-- I wanted to help.
Does that surprise you?
Not anymore.
At first, I was amazed,
but when you're fighting
in a just cause,
people seem to pop up,
like you, right out of the pavement.
Even when it's
dangerous or...
[PEOPLE CHATTERING
INDISTINCTLY]
MAN 1:
Hey, look what's coming!
MAN 2: A white
shepherd leading a brown Sammy!
Uh, perhaps we
should, um...
Doesn't the New
Testament say:
"If your enemy strikes you
on the right cheek, offer him the left"?
Well, I think perhaps the phrase
was used metaphorically. I don't think our Lord--
I'm not so sure. I--
I have thought about it a great deal.
I suspect he meant
you must show courage...
be willing to take a blow,
several blows, to show
you will not strike back,
nor will you be turned aside.
And when you do that,
it calls on something in human nature,
something that makes his hatred
for you decrease and his respect increase.
I think Christ grasped that,
and I have seen it work.
Good morning.
Get off the pavement,
you bloody coon.
MAN: Yeah, get off.
COLIN: Kaffir!
WOMAN: Colin, what you doing?
Nothing.
WOMAN:
Come out where I can see you!
I said, what you doing?
We were just trying
to clean up the neighbourhood a little.
WOMAN: You're late for work
already. I thought you'd gone 10 minutes ago.
Get on!
You'll find
there's room for us all.
That was lucky.
I thought you were a man of God.
Well, I am, but I'm not
so egotistical as to think
he plans his day
around my dilemmas.
MAN:
Kaffir!
GANDHI: Yes, you could
call it a communal farm, I suppose.
But you've all come
to the same conclusions.
Our Gita, the Muslim's
Koran, your Bible.
It's always the simple things
that catch your breath.
"Love thy neighbour
as thyself."
Huh.
Not always practised...
but it's something we Hindus
could learn a lot from.
And that's the kind of
thing you'll be seeking on this farm, huh?
Well, we shall try.
SONJA:
Bad news, I'm afraid.
They're going to
change the pass laws.
SMUTS: It's taken time,
but it needed to be done fairly.
We didn't want to create
an injustice simply because Mr. Gandhi
was abusing our
existing legislation.
Just one moment,
sir, please.
I beg your pardon.
But on a short trip...
I wouldn't spend too much
time on the Indian question, Mr. Walker.
It's a tiny factor in
South African life.
Well, it is news at the moment.
Of course, I do plan to report on
the condition of the mines here
as well as the economy.
Good.
But, uh, I would like to meet
this Mr. Gand-eye.
Gandhi.
Of course. We Westerners
have a weakness
for these spiritually inclined
men of India.
But as an old lawyer,
let me warn you.
Mr. Gandhi is as shrewd a man
as you will ever meet,
however otherworldly
he may seem.
But I'm sure you're enough
of a reporter to see that.
I hope so. Thank you
for your time, sir.
So it's not spiritualism
or nationalism.
We're not resisting anything
but the idea that people can't live together.
You see?
Hindus, Muslims,
Sikhs, Jews...
even Christians.
Mr. Walker of
The New York Times.
WALKER:
How you doing?
Without a paper,
a journal of some kind,
you cannot unite
a community.
You belong to a
very important profession.
Hmm.
And, uh, what do you think
an important professional should write
about your response
to General Smuts' newest legislation?
I don't know.
I'm still searching
for a response.
You will respect the law?
There are unjust laws
as there are unjust men.
You're an awful small minority
to take on the South African government,
not to mention the British Empire.
If you are a minority of one...
the truth is the truth.
Ah, Herman Kallenbach.
He's our chief carpenter,
also our chief benefactor.
Hello.
WALKER:
Vince Walker, New York Times.
Well, this is quite a place
you've got here.
And you, uh,
call it an ashram?
That's right.
The word only means "community."
But it could stand for
"village" or "the world."
You're an ambitious
man, Mr. Gandhi.
I hope not.
[MEN CHATTERING
IN DISTANCE]
Uh, I hear that you also participate
in preparing the meals and cleaning the toilets.
Is that part of the experiment?
Ba!
We will need another place set
for Mr. Walker's driver.
I will tell Tara.
Yes, it's, uh, one way to learn
that each man's labour
is as important as another's.
In fact, while you're doing it,
cleaning the toilet
seems far more important
than the law.
Please, come and join us.
You'll need something
before your journey back.
Uh, would you excuse me, please?
Yeah, sure.
What is it?
Sora was sent
to tell me I must...
rake and cover the latrine.
That's right.
Everyone takes their turn.
It is the work
of untouchables!
In this place, there are
no untouchables,
and no work is
beneath any of us.
I'm your wife!
All the more reason.
As you command.
The others may follow you,
but you forget...
I knew you when
you were a boy.
It's not me.
It's the principle.
And you will do it with joy
or not do it at all.
Not at all, then.
All right then, go.
You don't belong here!
Go and leave the ashram
altogether. We don't want you!
[BA SHOUTS INDISTINCTLY]
Have you no shame?
I'm your wife!
Where do you
expect me to go?
What's the matter with me?
You're human.
Only human.
And it's even harder
for those of us
who do not even want
to be as good as you do.
I apologise.
I must get back
to that reporter.
And I must...
rake and cover the latrine.
GANDHI:
I want to welcome you all.
Every one of you.
We have no secrets.
Let us begin by being clear
about General Smuts' new law.
All Indians must now
be fingerprinted...
Like criminals.
Men and women.
No marriage other than
a Christian marriage is considered valid.
Under this act...
our wives and mothers
are whores.
[PEOPLE SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY]
And every man here
is a bastard.
[PEOPLE SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY]
He has become
quite good at this.
And a policeman...
passing an Indian dwelling--
I will not call them homes.
--May enter and demand the
card of any Indian woman whose dwelling it is.
MAN 1:
Goddamn them!
[PEOPLE SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY]
GANDHI:
Understand...
he does not have to
stand at the door.
He may enter.
MAN 2:
I will not allow it!
I swear to Allah.
I'll kill the man who offers
that insult to my home and my wife...
and let them hang me!
I say talk means nothing!
Kill a few officials
before they disgrace one Indian woman.
Then they might think twice
about such laws.
In that cause,
I would be willing to die!
I praise such courage.
I need such courage
because, in this cause,
I too am prepared to die.
But, my friend...
there is no cause for which
I am prepared to kill.
Whatever they do to us,
we will attack no one,
kill no one.
But we will not give
our fingerprints, not one of us.
They will imprison us. They
will fine us. They will seize our possessions.
But they cannot take away
our self-respect
if we do not give it to them.
MAN 3:
Have you been to prison?
They beat us and torture us.
I say that we should--
I am asking you
to fight.
To fight against their anger,
not to provoke it.
We will not strike a blow.
But we will receive them.
And through our pain...
we will make them see
their injustice.
And it will hurt...
as all fighting hurts.
But we cannot lose.
We cannot.
They may torture my body...
break my bones...
even kill me. Then...
they will have my dead body...
not my obedience.
We are Hindu and Muslim...
children of God,
each one of us.
Let us take a solemn oath
in his name...
that, come what may...
we will not submit to this law.
ALL [SINGING]:
♪ God save our gracious King ♪
♪ God save our noble King ♪
♪ God save our King ♪♪
These men are
contracted labourers.
They belong in the mines.
You put their comrades in jail.
When you free them,
they will go back to work.
I've warned you.
We've warned each other.
I don't think
that's very good.
Steady, steady.
Stop!
Hyah.
At the canter, charge!
We should lie down.
Down! Down!
The horses won't
trample on us. Lie down!
[HORSES WHINNYING]
[SOLDIERS GRUNTING
AND SHOUTING]
Come on, you!
All right, give it up.
Follow me! Follow me!
Now what the hell
do we do?
MAN:
Let them march.
In our own sweet time,
in our own sweet way...
we'll get them.
MINERS: One law!
GANDHI: One king!
Some of you may be rejoicing that
Mr. Gandhi has at last been put into prison.
But I would ask you,
assembled here in this house of God...
to recognise that we are
witnessing something new,
something so
unexpected, so unusual,
that it is not surprising
the government is at a loss.
What Mr. Gandhi
has forced us to do
is ask questions
about ourselves.
As Christians, those
are difficult questions to answer.
How do we treat men
who defy an unjust law...
Who will not fight...
but will not comply?
As Christians, or as people
who have not heard the word--
They're sparing
no one, I see.
Ah.
No, you were
the surprise.
It has been
all over the prison.
We thought they would
be too afraid of the English press.
So did I.
Hyah!
DRIVER:
Whoa.
I don't know who they have
left out there to do the work.
Have they touched
the women?
GANDHI: My
wife publicly defied the law.
They've arrested
her and four others.
It split the government.
Well, that's one victory.
If we hold firm,
it won't be the last.
Don't worry.
I've never seen
men so determined.
You have given them
a way to fight.
Gandhi!
I want Gandhi!
Which Sammy is it?
SMUTS:
Ah...
Mr. Gandhi.
I thought we might
have a little talk.
Thank you, Daniels.
Will you have
a glass of sherry?
Thank you, no.
Perhaps some tea?
I dined at the prison.
Please, do come and sit down.
Mr. Gandhi.
I've more or less decided to ask
the House to repeal the act
that you have taken
such exception to.
Well, if you asked, General Smuts,
I'm sure it will be done.
It's not quite that simple.
Somehow, I expected not.
I thought of calling for
a royal commission
to investigate
the new legislation.
I think I could guarantee
they would recommend the act be repealed.
I congratulate them.
But they might
also recommend...
that all future Indian
immigration be severely restricted...
even stopped.
Immigration was not an issue
on which we fought.
It would be wrong of us
to make it one, now that we...
We are in a position of advantage.
I'm ordering the release
of all prisoners within the next 24 hours.
You yourself are free
as from this moment.
Assuming we are in agreement.
Yes, yes.
Um, it's just that in these clothes,
I would prefer to go by taxi.
All right. Fine.
And, um...
I'm afraid I have no money.
Oh, uh...
Neither have I.
Oh.
I'm awfully sorry.
Huh.
Daniels...
would you lend Mr. Gandhi
a shilling for a taxi?
I beg your pardon, sir?
How far will you
be going, Gandhi?
Well, now that this is settled,
I had thought seriously of going back to India.
But a shilling will do
splendidly for the moment.
Thank you.
I'm obliged, Mr. Daniels...
but I can find
my own way out.
[STEAM WHISTLE BLOWING]
GENERAL:
Guard of honour!
Attention!
Present arms!
My God, he loves it!
I'm sure he hates it.
Generals' reputations are
being made in France today,
fighting on the
Western front.
Not as military
governors in India.
What the devil's
going on back there?
MAN 1: Must be that Indian
who made all that fuss back in Africa.
My cabin boy told
me he was on board.
There he is.
MAN 2: God,
he's dressed like a coolie!
I thought he was a lawyer.
Mr. Gandhi, have you
refused to wear European clothes?
No, I haven't refused.
I simply wanted to dress the way
my comrades in prison dress.
Mr. Gandhi, will you
support the war effort?
If, as a citizen, I wish to enjoy
the benefits and protection of the British Empire,
it would be wrong of me
not to help in its defence.
Thank you.
Now that you're back in India,
what are you gonna do?
I don't know.
Mr. Gandhi--
Mr. Gandhi, one more question.
As an Indian woman, how
could you accept the indignity of prison?
My dignity comes
from following my husband.
Thank you very much.
Just a few words, and
then we'll get you to civilisation.
May I?
I'm glad to be home...
And, uh...
I thank you for your greeting.
I'll follow with your
wife. Don't worry. Everything's arranged.
Um, I, um...
GANDHI: Who was that young man?
That's young Nehru.
He's got his father's intellect,
his mother's good looks...
and the devil's own charm.
If they don't ruin
him at Cambridge-- Wave, wave!
--He might amount to something.
I must say, when I first
saw you as a bumbling lawyer here in Bombay,
I never thought I'd
be greeting you as a national hero.
I'm hardly that, Mr. Patel.
PATEL:
Oh, yes, you are.
It's been 200 years
since an Indian has cocked a snook
at the British Empire
and got away with it.
And stop calling me Mr.
Patel. You're not a junior clerk anymore.
The new military governor of the
Northwest Frontier Province was on that ship.
Too bad you came
back third class.
He might have
been impressed
by a successful barrister
who had outmanoeuvred General Smuts.
Yes, I'm sure.
MAN:
Are you involved too, Mrs. Nehru?
No, no, no. I leave practical
matters to my husband...
and revolution to my son.
Mr. Gandhi, I'd like
you to meet Mr. Jinnah, our joint host,
member of congress
and leader of the Muslim League.
JINNAH:
How do you do?
And Mr. Prakash, who, I fear
is awaiting trial for sedition
and inducement to murder.
I have not actually pulled
the trigger, Mr. Gandhi.
I have simply written
that if an Englishman kills
an Indian for disobeying his law,
then it is an Indian's duty
to kill an Englishman
for enforcing his law
in a land that is not his.
It's a clever argument. I'm
not sure it will produce the end you desire.
We hope you're going to join
us in our struggle for home rule, Mr. Gandhi.
Well--
Uh, excuse me.
Uh, may I, Mohan?
Uh, there's someone
I would like him to meet.
Oh, excuse me.
ANDREWS:
Sorry to rush you.
He told the press
he'd support the British in the war.
That's nonviolence
for you.
ANDREWS:
You know, Mohan...
now I have a
confession to make.
I didn't decide to come
to South Africa.
Professor
Gokhale sent me.
We are trying
to make a nation, Gandhi.
But the British keep
trying to break us up
into religions,
principalities, provinces.
What you were writing
in South Africa,
that's what we need here.
I have so much
to learn about India.
And I have to begin
my practise again.
One needs money
to run a journal.
Nonsense. Go on, Charlie.
This is Indian talk.
We want none of you
imperialists here.
All right, then, I'll
go and write my report to the viceroy.
You go and find
a pretty Hindu woman
and convert her
to Christianity.
That's as much mischief
as you are allowed.
Come, let's find
a quiet corner.
Now, you-- You
forget about your practise.
You have other
things to do.
India has many men
with too much wealth.
And it's their privilege
to nourish the effort of the few
who can raise India
from servitude and apathy.
I'll see to it.
You begin your journal.
I have little to say.
Come, come, come.
Let's sit down.
India is an alien
country to me.
Change that.
Go and find India.
Not what you see here,
but the real India.
You will see what
needs to be said...
what we need to hear.
When I saw you
in that tunic, I knew.
I knew I could
die in peace.
Make India proud of herself.
Charlie, please.
You're both being foolish.
But the air is lovely. Anyway,
there's no room in there.
Please! Come in.
Come in.
No violence, please.
Let me hang on
with two hands or I will fall.
Englishman, sahib!
Come, there is room up here!
Put your foot on
the window. Come!
What are you doing?
I'm going nearer to God.
Charlie! Be careful!
Let go!
Let go. Let go!
Oh, dear!
Hello.
You see?
It is most comfortable.
MAN:
Sahib?
Are you a Christian?
Yes. Yes, I'm a Christian.
MAN 1: I know a Christian.
Oh.
MAN 1:
She drinks blood.
Blood of Christ.
Every Sunday.
Charlie!
MAN 2: It's all right,
sahib. It's very safe.
[CHUCKLING]
Bend!
Pray to God, sahib.
Now is when it is best to be Hindu.
PATEL:
I agree with Jinnah.
Now that the Americans are in,
the war will be over soon.
The Germans are
worn out as it is.
And our first act
should be...
to convene a congress
party convention...
and demand independence.
And we will speak
with one voice, united.
And we should invite Gandhi.
What the devil's
happened to him anyway?
He's discovering India.
Which is a lot better than
making trouble where it matters.
Invite him, let him say his
piece about South Africa...
and then let him
slip into oblivion.
GANDHI:
Insurgents.
They've derailed
a troop train.
MAN:
Keep clear!
Come on.
ANDREWS: They've
killed an English soldier.
JINNAH:
We were asked for toleration.
We were asked for patience.
Some of us gave it...
and some did not.
Well, their war is over.
And those of us who supported it...
and those of us
who refused...
must forget
our differences.
And there can be no excuses
from the British now.
India wants...
home rule.
India...
demands home rule!
Congratulations.
And let no one question
that Mr. Jinnah speaks
not just for the Muslims...
but for all India!
And now...
I'm going to introduce to you
a man whose writings
we are all becoming
familiar with.
A man who stood in high esteem
with our own beloved Gokhale.
A man whose
accomplishments in South Africa
will always be remembered.
Mr. Mohandas Gandhi.
Your journal has
made great impact.
I'm flattered by Mr. Patel.
I would be even more flattered
if what he said were true.
But it is true.
I read it. Often!
Since I returned
from South Africa...
I have travelled
over much of India.
And I know that I could travel
for many more years
and still only see
a small part of her.
And yet, I already know...
that what we say here...
means nothing to
the masses of our country.
And those English liberal
magazines that may grant us a few lines.
But the people of India...
are...
untouched.
Their politics are
confined to bread...
and salt.
Illiterate they may be,
but they're not blind.
They see no reason to give
their loyalty to rich and powerful men
who simply want to take over
the role of the British...
in the name of freedom.
This congress tells the world...
it represents India.
My brothers,
India is 700,000 villages...
not a few hundred
lawyers in Delhi
and Bombay.
Until we stand in the fields...
with the millions that toil
each day under the hot sun...
we will not represent India.
Nor will we ever be able
to challenge the British...
as one nation.
Have you read
his magazine?
No.
But I think I'm going to.
[PEOPLE CHATTERING
INDISTINCTLY]
Pull over.
MAN:
This can't be the way.
Yes, I'm sure this is
the direction India is taking.
To think I almost got
excited by Mr. Jinnah...
when all this
was awaiting me.
[MAN SINGING IN DISTANCE]
[AUTOMOBILE APPROACHING]
NEHRU: We're
looking for Mr. Gandhi.
Ah, well, uh...
I think you'll find him
under that tree over there.
NEHRU: Thank you.
MAN: Come on.
I'm anxious to
meet this new force.
GANDHI: I try to
live like an Indian, as you see.
It's stupid, of course.
Because in our country...
it is the British who decide
how an Indian lives...
what he may buy,
what he may sell.
And from their luxury,
in the midst
of our terrible poverty...
they instruct us on what is justice,
what is sedition.
So it's only natural
that our best young minds
assume an air
of Eastern dignity
while greedily assimilating
every Western weakness
as quickly as they can acquire it.
If we have home rule...
that'll change.
Hmm.
Would you, please?
GANDHI: Why should
the British grant us home rule?
Here, we must take
the peelings to the goats.
We only make wild speeches
or perform even wilder acts of terrorism.
We've bred an army
of anarchists,
but not one single group
that can really fight the British anywhere.
[GOATS BRAYING]
Hello! Hello!
But I thought you were
against fighting.
Now just spread it around.
There you are.
They like the new peelings
mixed in with the rotting ones.
Where there's injustice,
I always believed in fighting.
The question is, do you fight
to change things or to punish?
Oh, myself, I've found
we're all such sinners,
we should leave
punishment to God.
And if we really want
to change things...
there are better ways
of doing it
than derailing trains
or slashing someone with a sword.
BA:
The fire is ready.
You see, even here...
we live under tyranny.
What did I tell you?
Look at him!
I can see the
British shaking now.
Hello!
I'm looking
for Mr. Gandhi.
I've been trying to speak
to you for a long time.
Our crops.
We cannot sell them.
We have no money.
But the landlords still
demand the same rent.
We have nothing left.
Hmm.
Mr. Taylor, sir. Up here!
Jesus!
What the hell is going on?
MAN:
I don't know, sir.
The agent
got a telegram.
And it just said,
"He is coming,"
and gave the time
of the train.
Who the hell is "he"?
I don't know, sir.
MAN:
Make way for the officer.
Get back here.
Come back here.
Get out of the way.
Out of the way.
Come on, you!
Who the devil are you?
My name is Gandhi.
Mohandas K. Gandhi.
Well, whoever you are,
we don't want you here.
I suggest you get back on
that train before it leaves.
They seem to want me.
Now, look here. I'll
put you under arrest if you'd prefer.
On what charge?
I don't want any trouble.
I'm an Indian travelling in
my own country. I see no reason for trouble.
Well, there had better not be.
Stand back! Move!
Make way
for the officer.
For years...
the landlords have ordered us
to grow indigo
for dyeing cloth.
Always, they took part
of the crop as rent.
But now...
everyone buys their
cloth from England.
So no one wants...
our indigo.
The landlords...
say we must pay our rent
in cash.
What we could...
we sold.
The police have
taken the rest.
There is no food.
I understand.
The landlords
are British?
What we can do,
we will try to do.
GANDHI:
Shukla...
is all Champaran like this?
SHUKLA:
Yes, Bapu.
The whole region.
Hundreds.
Thousands.
Some landlords
have tried to help.
But what
can they do?
Mohan?
Are you Mr. M.K. Gandhi?
Yes.
I'm sorry,
you're under arrest.
I'm not sorry at all.
Who did you
say would be buying the drinks?
MAN 1:
Oh, no.
Wouldn't you know, that's
the best innings I've had since Oxford.
India's full of grief, old man.
MAN 2: I've got no idea.
All I know is there's a
riot or something at Motihari in Champaran.
The whole company's
ordered out.
[CROWD SHOUTING
INDISTINCTLY]
I would like to see
the prisoner, please.
GUARD:
On the left, sir.
Charlie.
Shades of South Africa.
Not quite.
They're only holding me
until the magistrate's
hearing.
Then it will be prison.
Did they take
your clothes?
These are my
clothes now.
You always had
a puritanical streak, Mohan.
If I want to be one with them...
I have to live like them.
Yes, I think you do.
But, uh...
Thank God we all don't.
My puritanism runs
in a different way.
I'm far too modest
for such a display.
Couldn't I be let in
with the prisoner? I am a clergyman.
They're calling you "Bapu."
I thought it meant "father."
It does.
We must be
getting old, Charlie.
Well, what do you
want me to do?
I think, Charlie,
that you can help us most
by taking that assignment
you've been offered in Fiji.
I have to be sure--
They have to be sure
that what we do...
can be done by Indians alone.
But you know the strategy.
The world is full of people
who will despise what's happening here.
It is their strength
that we need.
Before you go...
you could start us
in the right direction.
Uh... I must leave
from Calcutta...
and soon now.
You're to say
goodbye to Ba for me.
Well, I...
There are no goodbyes
for us, Charlie.
Wherever you are,
you will always be in my heart.
[PEOPLE SHOUTING
INDISTINCTLY]
I'm going to clear the courtroom.
I'm not sure we'd be able to, sir.
It is a first hearing.
It's supposed to be public.
And he's a lawyer.
I don't know where
they found the nerve for all this.
I'm sure I don't either, sir,
but the troops won't be here till tomorrow.
How did the press get here
before the military?
That English clergyman sent
a number of telegrams yesterday afternoon.
I understand one of them
even went to the viceroy.
You have been ordered
out of the province
on the grounds of
disturbing the peace.
[PEOPLE SHOUTING
INDISTINCTLY]
With respect,
I refuse to go.
JUDGE:
Do you want to go to jail?
As you wish.
[THUNDER RUMBLING
IN DISTANCE]
All right.
I will release
you on bail
of 100 rupees
until I reach a sentence.
I refuse to pay 100 rupees.
Then I will grant
release on bail
without payment
until I reach a decision.
PEOPLE [CHANTING]:
Gandhiji! Gandhiji!
MAN:
Gandhiji.
We are from Bihar.
We received a cable
this morning from an old friend
who was at
Cambridge with us.
His name is Nehru.
I believe you know him.
Indeed.
He tells us you need help,
and we have come to give it.
I want to document coldly,
rationally, what is being done here.
It may take months.
We have no pressing
engagements.
You will have to live
with the peasants.
There will be risks.
I don't know what
this country's coming to.
EDWARD:
But good God, man!
You yourself raised the rent
simply to finance a hunting expedition.
And some of these others:
beatings, illegal seizures,
demanding
services without pay.
Even refusing them water.
In India!
Nobody knows what it is to try
to get these people to work.
EDWARD: Well, you've
made this half-naked whatever-he-is
into an international hero.
"One lone man, marching dusty
roads, armed only with honesty
and a bamboo staff,
doing battle with the British Empire."
At home, children are
writing essays about him.
What do they want?
EDWARD:
Gareth!
Yes, sir.
There's a rebate
on rents paid.
They're to be free
to grow crops of their own choice.
And a commission,
part Indian, to hear grievances.
Hmm.
That would satisfy him?
And His Majesty's
government.
It only needs your signature
for the landlords.
It'll be worth it
to see the back of him.
GARETH:
Thank you, sir.
We're too damned liberal.
EDWARD: Perhaps.
But at least all this has made
the government see some sense about what men
like Mr. Gandhi should be allowed,
and what they should be denied.
Where is Mr. Gandhi?
He said he
preferred to walk, sir.
I followed him most of the way.
He's just turned the corner.
He came third class.
God, give me patience.
My house is honoured.
Ah, the honour is ours.
Uh, I'd like you to meet Dr. Kallenbach,
he's an old friend.
And he's interested in flowers.
How do you do?
I presumed to tell him
he could wander your garden while we talk.
I'll send for my gardener.
I'm sure you'll have plenty to discuss.
Mm-hmm.
Thank you.
Gentlemen, the
hero of Champaran.
Oh. Only the stubborn
man of Champaran.
Mr. Patel you know.
Maulana Azad, my
colleague and a fellow Muslim...
and just recently
released from prison.
Salaam.
Mr. Kripalani.
And of course,
you know Mr. Nehru.
I'm beginning
to know Mr. Nehru.
Please sit down.
Do sit down.
Well, gentlemen, I've asked you
to come here through Mr. Jinnah's kindness...
because I've had the chance
to see the legislation.
And it is exactly
as was rumoured.
Arrest without warrant,
and automatic imprisonment
for possession of materials
considered seditious.
And your writings
are specifically listed.
So much for helping them
in the Great War.
There is only one answer
to that. Direct action on a scale
they can never handle.
NEHRU:
I don't think so.
Terrorism would only justify
their repression.
And what kind of leaders
would it throw up?
Are they likely to be the
men we would want at the head of our country?
JINNAH: I, too,
have read Mr. Gandhi's writings.
But I would rather be ruled
by an Indian terrorist than an English one.
And I don't intend to submit
to that kind of law.
PATEL: I must say,
it seems to me
that it's gone beyond
remedies like passive resistance.
If I may...
I, for one, have never
advocated passive anything.
I'm with Mr. Jinnah.
We must never submit to such laws...
ever.
And I think our resistance
must be active and provocative.
May I?
I want to embarrass all
those who wish to treat us as slaves.
Thank you.
All of them.
Forgive my stupid illustration.
Allow me.
No, please.
But I want to change
their minds...
not kill them
for weaknesses we all possess.
And what resistance
would you offer?
The law is due to take
effect from April, the 6.
I want to call
upon the nation
to make that a day of
prayer and fasting.
You mean a general strike?
I mean a day of prayer
and fasting.
Of course, no work
could be done. No buses.
No trains.
No factories.
No administration.
The country would stop.
My God, it would terrify them!
AZAD: 350
million people at prayer?
Even the English newspapers
would have to report that...
and explain why.
But could we get people to do it?
NEHRU: Why not?
No, thank you.
Champaran stirred
the whole country.
Oh, thank you.
They're calling
you "Mahatma."
"Great Soul."
Fortunately, such news comes
very slowly to where I live.
I think if we all worked
to publicise it...
all of congress...
every avenue we know...
I could get articles printed
in most of the papers in Delhi and Bombay.
[MEN CHATTERING INDISTINCTLY]
[CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYS]
MAN 1: Only civilians will
visit. Don't you think so, Your Highness?
MAN 2: Of course,
the army will always be loyal.
MAN 3: I'll have you know,
we've got 500 troops.
MAN 4: They'll be damn
hungry by morning, I'll tell you that.
Excuse me, Your Excellency.
Mr. Kinnoch.
Sir?
I'm afraid it's confirmed, sir.
Nothing's working, sir.
The buses, the trains,
the markets.
There's not even any ordinary
civilian staff here, sir.
Is it simply Delhi and Bombay?
No, sir. Karachi, Calcutta,
Madras, Bangalore. It's-- It's total.
The army had to take
over the telegraph so...
Or we'd be cut off from the world.
I can't believe it.
He's going to sell
his own paper tomorrow in Bombay, sir.
They've called for a parade
on Victoria Road.
Arrest him.
GUARD: He's
to go to the visitors' room.
Bapu.
You too?
It seems less
formal than Mahatma.
Since your arrest,
the riots have hardly stopped.
Not big, but they
keep breaking out.
I want to stop them.
And Patel and Kripalani,
they're never at rest.
But some English civilians
have been killed.
And the army is attacking
crowds with clubs.
Sometimes worse.
Maybe I'm wrong.
Maybe we're not ready yet.
In South Africa,
our numbers were small.
The government's afraid.
They don't know what to do.
They're more afraid
of terrorism than of you.
The viceroy has agreed to your
release if you will speak for nonviolence.
I've never spoken
for anything else.
[MAN SINGING PRAYER]
England...
is so powerful.
Its army...
and its navy...
all its modern weapons.
But when a great
power like that...
strikes defenceless people...
it shows its brutality,
its own weakness.
Especially when those people
do not strike back.
MAN 1:
Fighting back will not work.
And that is why the Mahatma...
begs us to take
the course of nonviolence.
[MAN 1 SHOUTING
INDISTINCTLY]
Back away! Back away!
MAN 1:
But if we riot...
[DYER SHOUTING
INDISTINCTLY]
MAN 1:
if we fight back...
we become the vandals...
and they become the law.
If we bear their blows,
they are the vandals.
God and his law
are on our--
[DYER SHOUTING
INDISTINCTLY]
DYER: Front rank,
kneel in position!
We...
must have the courage...
to take their anger.
[DYER SHOUTING
INDISTINCTLY]
[PEOPLE SHOUTING
Should we issue
a warning, sir?
They've had their warning:
No meetings.
Fire!
Take your time!
Corporal!
To your left.
MAN:
General Dyer...
is it correct that you ordered
your troops to fire
at the thickest
part of the crowd?
That is so.
1516 casualties with...
1650 bullets.
My intention was
to inflict a lesson
that would have an impact
throughout all India.
General...
had you been able to
take in the armoured car...
would you have opened fire
with the machine gun?
I think, probably, yes.
General, did you realise
there were children and women in the crowd?
I did.
But that was irrelevant
to the point you were making?
That is correct.
Could I ask you what
provision you made for the wounded?
I was ready to help
any who applied.
General, how does a child...
shot with a .303 Lee-Enfield...
apply for help?
CHELMSFORD: Forgive me,
gentlemen, but you must understand...
that His Majesty's government
and the British people repudiate...
both the massacre
and the philosophy that prompted it.
Now...
what I would like to do...
is to come to some
compromise over the new--
GANDHI: If you will excuse me,
Your Excellency,
it is our view that matters
have gone beyond legislation.
We think it is time
you recognised
that you are masters
in someone else's home.
Despite the best intentions
of the best of you,
you must, in the nature of things,
humiliate us to control us.
General Dyer is but
an extreme example of the principle.
It is time you left.
With respect,
Mr. Gandhi...
without British
administration,
this country would be
reduced to chaos.
Mr. Kinnoch...
I beg you to accept that
there is no people on Earth
who would not prefer
their own bad government
to the good government
of an alien power.
BRIGADIER: My dear sir,
India is British.
We're hardly an alien power.
Mr. Gandhi,
even if His Majesty could
waive all other considerations, uh,
he has a duty to the millions
of his Muslim subjects,
who are a minority
in this realm.
And experience suggests
that his troops
and his administration
are essential
in order to secure the peace.
All nations contain
religious minorities.
Like other countries,
ours will have its problems.
But they will be ours...
not yours.
GENERAL: How do
you propose to make them yours?
You don't think we're just
going to walk out of India.
Yes.
In the end,
you will walk out...
because 100,000 Englishmen
simply cannot control
350 million Indians
if those Indians refuse to cooperate.
And that is what
we intend to achieve.
Peaceful, nonviolent
noncooperation...
till you yourself
see the wisdom of leaving...
Your Excellency.
GENERAL: So I said to him,
"You don't expect us just to walk out."
And he said, "Yes."
BRIGADIER: What an
extraordinary little man, isn't he?
"Nonviolence,
noncooperation."
For a moment, I was afraid
they were actually gonna do something.
Yes, but I think it would
be wise to be very cautious for a time.
The Antiterrorist Act
will remain on the statutes,
but on no account
is Gandhi to be arrested.
Whatever mischief
he causes...
I have no intention
of making a martyr of him.
BA [OVER P.A.]: But
now something worse is happening.
When Gandhiji
and I were growing up...
women wove
their own cloth.
But now there are millions
who have no work...
because those who
can buy all they need from England.
I say with Gandhiji:
There is no beauty
in the finest cloth
if it makes hunger
and unhappiness.
[PEOPLE CHEERING
WILDLY]
PEOPLE [CHANTING]:
Gandhiji! Gandhiji!
GANDHI:
My message to you...
is the message I have given
to your brothers everywhere.
To gain independence...
we must prove worthy of it.
There must be
Hindu-Muslim unity always.
Second:
No Indian must be treated
as the English treat us.
We must remove
untouchability...
from our hearts
and from our lives.
Third:
We must defy the British.
[PEOPLE CHEERING WILDLY]
Not with violence
that will inflame their will...
but with a firmness
that will open their eyes.
English factories
make the cloth...
that makes our poverty.
All those who wish to
make the English see...
bring me the cloth from Manchester
and Leeds that you wear today...
and we will light a fire
that will be seen in Delhi...
and in London.
And if...
like me...
you are left with only
one piece of homespun...
wear it with dignity.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
No, no, no.
Thank you, I can manage.
[LAUGHING]
Herman.
Don't destroy my good intentions.
I'm already feeling guilty
about travelling second class.
You've earned a few indulgences.
Well, perhaps, but Maulana's
made of sterner stuff.
Our trains met in Bombay.
And there he is, back there in
that lot, the model disciple.
KALLENBACH: Ah,
there's another passenger.
A Miss Slade from London.
She's been writing to Gandhiji for years.
She's the daughter
of an English admiral.
Ah, Maulana, what do you
think the daughter of an English admiral
proposes to do
in our ashram? Sink us?
AZAD: From
the looks of the luggage, yes.
She wants to make her
home with us. And Gandhiji has agreed.
Miss Slade!
You'd be Mr. Kallenbach.
Oh. And you--
You would be Miss Slade?
I prefer the name
Gandhiji has given me:
Mirabehn.
BA: Don't pull
it so fast. You'll break it again.
Leave it. Leave it.
God gave you 10 thumbs.
Eleven.
Sardar!
Mirabehn.
Come, come, come.
You will be my daughter.
AZAD:
But then...
some rioting broke out
between Hindus and Muslims.
Violent, terrible.
Whether it was provoked...
I don't know.
But it gave them an excuse
to impose martial law throughout Bengal.
Some of the things
the military have done...
Is the campaign
weakening?
The marches and protests
are bigger, if anything.
But with the censorship here...
they know more in England
than we do.
And it saps the courage
to think you may be suffering alone.
They are not alone.
And martial law only shows
how desperate the British are.
Is that homespun?
I sent for it from here.
I dyed it myself.
What do the workers in England
make of what we're doing?
It must have
produced hardship.
It has...
but you'd be surprised.
They understand. They really do.
Good.
Ba will have to teach you
to spin too.
I'd rather march.
First, spin!
Let the others march
for a time.
I'll teach you all
our foolishness.
And you must
teach me yours.
[PEOPLE SHOUTING
INDISTINCTLY]
PEOPLE [CHANTING]: We burn
British cloth! We burn British cloth!
We burn British cloth!
Long live Gandhiji!
British rule must go!
I'll stuff it down
your damn throat!
MAN:
Hey, help us!
Leave us alone!
We are not harming you.
Go on your way.
On your way!
Come back!
[SCREAMING IN PAIN]
Help us! Help us!
Help! Help!
[MAN MOANING]
[POLICEMEN SCREAMING]
PATEL: That's one
bit of news they haven't censored.
Now it's all over the world.
India's "nonviolence."
NEHRU:
What can we do?
GANDHI:
We must end the campaign.
After what they did at
the massacre? It's only an eye for an eye.
An eye for an eye only
ends up making the whole world blind.
Gandhiji, do you know
the sacrifices people have made?
We'd never get
the same commitment again, ever.
The whole of India
is on the move!
Yes, but in what direction?
If we obtain our freedom by
murder and bloodshed, I want no part of it.
Bapu...
you are the father
of the nation.
Today, I see no ground
in that for anything but shame.
This was one incident.
Tell that to the families of
the policemen who died.
Bapu...
the whole nation is marching.
They wouldn't stop,
even if we asked them to.
I will ask.
And I will fast as a penance
for my part in arousing such emotions.
And I will not stop
until they stop.
But...
God! You can be sure
the British won't censor that.
They'll put it on
every street corner.
Gandhiji, people are aroused.
They won't stop!
If I die, perhaps
they will stop.
[GANDHI COUGHING]
I must get ready
for morning prayers.
Mirabehn is here.
I've brought your
drinking water.
There's a little lemon
juice in it. That's all.
Herman has gone
to meet Pandit Nehru.
There was a telegram.
Almost everywhere,
it has stopped.
When it is everywhere...
then my prayers
will be answered.
Do you find me stubborn?
I don't know.
I know that you are right.
I don't know
that this is right.
May I turn you?
When I despair...
I remember that
all through history...
the way of truth and love
has always won.
There have been tyrants
and murderers
and, for a time,
they can seem invincible.
But in the end,
they always fall.
Think of it.
Always.
Whenever you are in doubt
that that is God's way,
the way the world
is meant to be,
think of that...
and then try
to do it his way.
And now, could I have
another feast of lemon juice?
Panditji!
Jinnah, Patel...
all of congress has called
for the end of noncooperation.
There's not been
one demonstration.
All over India, people
are praying that you will end the fast.
They're walking
in the streets...
offering garlands
to the police...
and British soldiers.
Perhaps I have overdone it.
[GOAT BRAYING]
Good morning, Bapu.
Good morning.
Don't let him go. If he bumps me,
I'm done for.
BOY: Don't worry,
I won't let him go.
I'm sorry,
Mr. Gandhi, sir...
but you're under arrest.
On what charge?
Sedition.
You can't be serious.
This man has just stopped
a revolution.
POLICEMAN:
That's as may be.
I only know what
I am charged to perform.
I don't believe it.
Even the British
can't be that stupid.
GANDHI:
Panditji.
Help me, please.
Mira, you must
look after Ba.
If there is one protest, one riot,
a disgrace of any kind,
I will fast again.
Herman.
Yeah.
I have been on many trips.
Monda.
This is just another trip.
I'm at your command.
I know we are not ready
for my kind of independence.
If I'm sent to jail,
perhaps that is the best protest
our country can make
at this time.
And if it helps India, I've
never refused His Majesty's hospitality.
Call the prisoner to the bar.
"Noncooperation has one aim:
The overthrow
of the government.
Sedition must become our creed.
We must give no quarter...
nor can we expect any."
Do you deny writing it?
GANDHI: Not at all.
And I will save
the court's time...
my lord, by stating under oath
that, to this day,
I believe noncooperation with evil
is a duty
and that British rule
of India is evil.
PROSECUTOR:
The prosecution rests, my lord.
I presume you are conducting
your own defence, Mr. Gandhi.
I have no defence, my lord.
I am guilty as charged.
And if you truly believe in
the system of law you administer in my country,
you must inflict on me
the severest penalty possible.
It is impossible for me to
ignore that you are in a different category
from any person
I have ever tried...
or am likely to try.
Nevertheless, it is my duty
to sentence you
to six years' imprisonment.
[PEOPLE SHOUTING
INDISTINCTLY]
If, however, His Majesty's
government should, at some later date...
see fit to reduce the term...
no one will be
better pleased than I.
Yes, I'm sure that's exactly
what they hoped.
Put him in prison a few years.
With luck, he'd be forgotten.
Maybe they could
even subdue him.
Well, he certainly
wasn't forgotten.
And as soon as he got out,
he was back tramping the countryside,
preaching nonviolence
and demanding a free India.
Everyone knows
another showdown's coming.
Well, how does an American
journalist in Central America
learn that Gandhi was born
in Porbandar anyway?
I've been aware of him
for a long time.
He certainly makes good copy.
The other day, Winston Churchill
called him a half-naked Indian fakir.
Yeah.
I met him once.
What, you mean Gandhi?
Yeah.
South Africa,
a long time ago.
I wonder if he'll
recognise me.
What was he like?
Well, he had a full
head of hair then.
We were a bit like college students,
trying to figure everything out.
Well, he must have found
some of the answers.
BA: In every worthy wish of yours,
I shall be your helpmate.
GANDHI:
Helpmate.
Take the fourth step,
that we may be ever full of joy.
BA: I will
ever live devoted to you...
speaking words of
love and praying for your happiness.
Take the fifth step...
the walking
around a fire...
that we may serve
the people.
I will follow close
behind you...
and help to serve
the people.
Hmm.
Take the sixth step...
that we may follow
our vows in life.
I will follow you
in all our vows and duties.
Take the seventh step...
that we may ever
live as friends.
You are my best friend...
my highest guru...
and my sovereign lord.
And then I put a sweetened
wheat cake in her mouth.
And I put a sweetened
wheat cake in his mouth.
And with that,
we were pronounced...
man and wife.
We were both 13.
BOY:
Bapu! Bapu!
It's beautiful.
Even as a boy...
I thought so.
Thank you.
Trying to keep up with you
is like chasing a jackrabbit.
And you've come all this way
because you think something is going to happen.
Is it?
Perhaps.
I've come here
to think about it.
Do you remember much
of South Africa?
Oh, yes. A great deal.
I've travelled so far...
and thought so much.
As you can see,
my city is a sea city.
Always full of Hindus...
Muslims...
Sikhs, Jews, Persians.
My family's sect
was the Pranami.
Hindu, of course.
But in our temple,
the priest used to read
from the Muslim Koran
and the Hindu Gita,
moving from one to the other
as if it mattered not
which book was being read
as long as God
was being worshipped.
Hmm.
When I was a boy...
I used to sing a song
in the temple.
Hmm.
[SINGING] ♪ A true
disciple Knows another's woes ♪
♪ As his own ♪♪
He bows to all...
and despises none.
Like all other boys,
I sang the words...
not thinking what they
meant or how they might be influencing me.
I've travelled so far.
And all I've done
is come back...
home.
Wait a minute.
You know what you're
gonna do, don't you?
It would have been
very uncivil of me
to let you make such
a long trip for nothing.
Where are you going?
Come.
WALKER: Where are we going?
I'm going back to the ashram.
And I'm going to prove
to the new viceroy
that the king's writ
no longer runs in India.
Salt?
Yes, sir. He's going to march
to the sea and make salt.
OFFICER: There's a royal
monopoly on the manufacture of salt, sir.
It is illegal to make it or sell it
without a government licence.
All right, he's
breaking the law.
What's that going to
deprive us of? Two rupees of salt tax?
It's not a serious attack
on the revenue, sir.
Its primary importance
is symbolic.
Don't patronize me,
Charles.
No, sir. I...
In this climate, sir,
nothing lives without water or salt.
Our absolute control of it is
a control on the pulse of India.
And that's the basis
of this declaration of independence?
Yes, sir.
The day he sets off,
everyone is supposed to
raise the flag of "Free India."
And then he walks some
240 miles to the sea and makes salt.
EDGAR:
I say ignore it.
Let them raise
their damned flags.
Let him make his salt.
It's only symbolic
if we choose to make it so.
He's going to arrive
at the sea...
on the anniversary
of the Massacre of Amritsar.
General Edgar is right.
Ignore it.
Mr. Gandhi will find
it takes a great deal more
than a pinch of salt
to bring down the British Empire.
Bapu.
[SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
Namaste, Bapu.
Namaste.
Uh-huh.
MAN:
Bapu, namaste.
Namaste, Bapu.
Namaste.
You've done me
a great service.
Not at all, sir.
It would be uncivil for us
to let you make such a long trip for nothing.
We'll go.
PEOPLE [CHANTING]: Long
live Gandhiji! Long live Gandhiji!
Long live Gandhiji!
Is it all over if they
arrest you now?
Not if they arrest me
or 1000 or 10,000.
It's not only generals
who know how to plan campaigns.
What if they don't arrest you?
What if they don't react at all?
Something for your notebook:
The function of a civil resister
is to provoke response.
And we will
continue to provoke
until they respond
or they change the law.
Mm-hmm.
They are not in control.
We are.
That is the strength
of civil resistance.
COLLINS:
Vince!
What did he say?
He said he's in control.
GANDHI: Do you
intend to walk all the way?
WALKER: It's the
only way I can get the story.
Besides, my
name is Walker.
"My name is Walker."
[PEOPLE CHATTERING
IN DISTANCE]
[PEOPLE SINGING]
My dear Mrs. Nehru!
Bapu.
GANDHI:
Man needs salt...
as he needs air and water.
This salt comes
from the Indian Ocean.
Let every Indian claim it
as his right.
MAN [ON NEWSREEL]: And so,
once more, the man of nonviolence
has challenged the might
of the British Empire.
[MUSIC PLAYING
ON NEWSREEL]
They're making it everywhere,
sir. Mobs of them.
Publicly.
Congress leaders are
selling it on the streets of Delhi.
We're being made fools of,
sir, around the world.
EDGAR: Isn't there
any instruction from London?
We're required to stop it.
And stop it we will!
I don't care if we
fill the jails. Stop it!
Arrest anyone, any rank,
except Gandhi.
We'll cut the strength
from under him.
And then we'll deal
with the Mahatma.
All right. Jump to it!
Clear this beach!
Ahh!
Zia, don't hit back!
No violence!
FIELDS: There must be ninety,
100,000 under arrest.
And it still goes on.
Who's leading them?
I don't know.
Nehru, Patel,
almost every congress
official is in jail.
And their wives
and their children.
We've even arrested
Nehru's mother.
Has there been
any violence?
Oh, in Peshawar,
the deputy police commissioner
lost his head and,
uh, opened fire with a machine gun.
Uh... But he's, uh,
facing disciplinary court.
You can't expect things
like that not to happen. I mean--
I believe the question
was intended to discover
whether there was
any violence on their side.
Eh... Uh, no, sir.
No. No, I'm afraid not.
Perhaps if we arrested
Gandhi, it might, um...
He's addressed this letter
directly to you, has he?
Yes, sir, he has. The usual thing:
"India's salt belongs to India."
Then he says flatly
that he personally is going to
lead a raid tomorrow on the Dharasana Salt Works.
Thank him for his letter...
and put him in jail.
FIELDS:
Yes, sir.
Yes, sir. It'll be
my pleasure.
And Fields?
Sir?
Keep that salt works open.
Yes, sir.
OFFICER:
I'm sorry, sir.
But my orders are
to allow regular staff
and regular staff only
through these gates.
AZAD:
Very well.
WOMAN: We will
receive them in his name.
And for his sake,
we will not raise a hand.
Long live Mahatma Gandhi!
PEOPLE:
MAN: Long live...
PEOPLE: Gandhiji!
Mm-hmm.
PEOPLE: Long live Gandhiji!
AZAD:
We are ready!
I want firmness
and discipline.
OFFICER: All right,
take up your positions.
Yes, sir.
OFFICER:
To your mark. Forward!
Last night at midnight...
they took Gandhiji from us.
They expect us
to lose heart
or to fight back.
We will do neither!
OFFICER:
On your guard!
[WOMEN CHATTERING
INDISTINCTLY]
No, sir.
The gate is closed!
[WOMEN GASPING AND
CHATTERING]
[WOMAN SPEAKING
INDISTINCTLY]
[MEN MOANING]
WALKER:
"They walked,
both Hindu and Muslim alike...
with heads held high...
without any hope of escape...
from injury or death.
It went on and on
into the night."
Stop.
"Women carried the wounded
and broken bodies from the road
until they dropped
from exhaustion."
Stop. "But still, it went
on and on." Stop.
"Whatever moral ascendancy
the West held...
was lost here today.
India is free...
for she has taken all
that steel and cruelty can give...
and she has neither cringed
nor retreated. " Stop.
I am aware that I must
have given you much cause for irritation,
Your Excellency.
I hope it will not stand
between us as men.
Mr. Gandhi...
I am instructed to request
your attendance
at an all-government
conference in London...
to discuss the possible
independence
of India.
[MUSIC PLAYING ON NEWSREEL]
[STEAM WHISTLE BLOWS]
MAN [ON NEWSREEL]:
Only recently released from prison,
Mahatma Gandhi
leaves Bombay on the SS Rajputana
to attend the roundtable conference
on Indian independence
called by Prime Minister
Ramsay MacDonald.
Mr. Gandhi, the sole
Indian Congress Party delegate,
is staying at Kingsley Hall
in the East End of London
for the duration of the talks.
And he's seen here
amongst local cockneys
who have taken him
to their hearts.
Besides attending the conference,
he has found time to meet
political and religious leaders,
like Mr. Lloyd George and
the Archbishop of Canterbury,
as well as Mr. George Bernard Shaw
and Mr. Charlie Chaplin.
[MUSIC PLAYING ON NEWSREEL]
He journeyed last week
from Kingsley Hall
to accept an invitation to tea
from their majesties King George and Queen Mary
at Buckingham Palace
before attending the conference.
MACDONALD: And I would
emphasise that I think our first duty
is to recognise
that there is not one India...
but several.
A Hindu India...
a Muslim India...
and an India
of princely states.
And all these
must be respected...
and cared for.
Not just one.
[MUSIC PLAYING ON NEWSREEL]
MAN [ON NEWSREEL]: Mr. Gandhi,
who has been attending
the London Round Table
Conference on Indian Independence,
journeyed north
to visit a cotton mill.
Although not dressed
for the Lancashire climate,
Mr. Gandhi received a warm
welcome from cheering mill workers...
before heading back south
for a final meeting
with Mr. MacDonald.
The prime minister said later
that the talks were both constructive and frank.
[MUSIC PLAYING ON NEWSREEL]
So farewell, Mr. Gandhi.
And bon voyage!
JINNAH: So the truth is,
after all your travels,
after all your efforts,
they've stopped the campaign
and sent you back empty-handed.
They're only clinging
to old dreams...
and trying to split us
in the old way.
But the will has gone.
Independence will fall
like a ripe apple.
The only question is,
when and how.
Well, I say,
when is now!
And we will determine how.
Precisely.
CHILD:
Bapu, she is limping again.
GANDHI:
It's only a sprain.
Take her to the river.
We'll make a mud pack for her.
Go. I won't be a moment.
Huh.
[GOAT BRAYING]
GANDHI:
They are preparing for war.
I will not support it.
But I do not intend to take
advantage of their danger.
That's when you
take advantage.
No, that is just
another way of hitting back.
We've come a long way
together with the British.
When they leave,
we want to see them off as friends.
Now, if you'll excuse me,
there is something I must attend to.
Mud packs.
Mr. Gandhi, sir.
I have been instructed to enquire
as to the subject of your speech tonight.
The value of goat's milk
in daily diet.
But you can be sure that
I will also speak against war.
Sorry, sir.
That can't be permitted.
Corporal!
Sir!
[CORPORAL SPEAKS
INDISTINCTLY]
It's all right,
Mrs. Gandhi.
I have orders to return with
you and your companion to the Mahatma's ashram.
If you take my husband,
I intend to speak in his place.
MARGARET:
Hold it a second, will you?
It was the Aga Khan's palace
before they turned it into a prison.
They're holding Gandhi and a number
of the leading congress politicians in there.
Pandit Nehru and the others
are up at Ahmednagar Fort.
Not bad for a prison, eh?
Well, I guess no place
is good if you're locked in.
Your timing's pretty lucky.
They had him cut off
from the press.
But last month his personal secretary died,
so they let up on restrictions.
Yes, I have heard
of LIFE magazine.
I've even heard of
Margaret Bourke-White.
But I don't know why either
should be interested in an old man
sitting alone in prison
while the rest of the world
is blowing itself to pieces.
Well, you're the only
man I know who makes his own clothes.
Ah, but for me, that's
not much of an accomplishment.
No, prison is rather
agreeable to me.
And there is no doubt
that after the war...
independence will come.
My only worry...
is what shape it will take.
Jinnah has--
Stop!
I'm sorry, but, uh--
Could you come forward, please?
Ah, come, come.
Just up to the railing.
Thank you very much.
Thank you.
Uh-huh.
Now, sorry.
Go on just as you were.
"What shape it will take..."
Jinnah has what?
Ah. Jinnah has cooperated
with the British.
It has given him power
and the freedom to speak.
And he's filled
the Muslims with fears
of what will happen to them
in a country that
is predominantly Hindu.
Hmm. And that I
find hard to bear...
even in prison.
Mr. Gandhi?
It's very hard for me
to see this as a solution
to the 20th century's
problems.
I have friends
who keep telling me
how much it costs them
to keep me in poverty.
But I know happiness
does not come with things,
even 20th-century things.
It can come from work
and pride in what you do.
India lives in her villages
and the terrible poverty there
can only be removed
if their local skills
can be revived.
Poverty is the worst form
of violence.
And a constructive programme
is the only...
nonviolent solution
to India's agony.
It will not necessarily be
progress for India
if she simply imports
the unhappiness of the West.
But do you really believe you could
use nonviolence against someone like Hitler?
Not without defeats
and great pain.
But are there no defeats
in this war?
No pain?
What you cannot do...
is accept injustice
from Hitler or anyone.
You must make
the injustice visible.
Be prepared to die
like a soldier to do so.
Is this what I'm meant
to end up with here?
No. That's what you get
for distracting me.
What do you expect
when you talk like that?
I expect you to
show as much patience as I am now.
Turn slowly
and pull it gently.
And that includes
the life of women.
Bapu has always said...
there were two kinds
of slavery in India:
One for women,
one for the untouchables.
And he has always
fought against both.
Does it rankle, being
separated in this way?
In Hindu philosophy...
the way to God...
is to free yourself
of possessions...
and of passions.
Bapu has always struggled
to find the way to God.
Do you mean that
he gave up married life?
Four times he tried...
and failed.
But then he took
a solemn vow.
And he's never broken it?
Not yet.
I've got permission
to move her. He can go too.
I'm very sorry, sir.
She's had a massive thrombosis.
It's a very serious heart attack.
She'll never survive the trip.
I think it's better if we just
keep her here and hope.
It's time for my walk.
I won't be long.
[OFFICER SHOUTING
ORDERS INDISTINCTLY]
Guard...
present arms!
[BAND PLAYING
"GOD SAVE THE KING"]
We have come to
crown victory with friendship.
To assist at the birth of
an independent India...
and to welcome her
as an equal member
in the British Commonwealth
of Nations.
I am here to see that I am
the last British viceroy
ever to have the honour
of such a reception.
Gandhiji, I am not concerned
about the independence of India.
I am concerned about
the slavery of the Muslims.
Please, please, Mr. Jinnah.
I will not stand by to see
the mastery of the British
replaced by the mastery
of the Hindus.
Sardarji, Panditji!
Muslim and Hindu
are the right and left eye of India.
No one will be master,
no one slave.
The world is not made of
Mahatma Gandhis.
I'm talking about
the real world.
How the--
NEHRU: The real India has
Muslims and Hindus
in every village and every city.
How do you propose
to separate them?
Where there is
a Muslim majority,
that will be Pakistan.
The rest is your India.
PATEL:
My dear Jinnah...
the Muslims are in a majority
on two different sides of the country.
Let us worry about Pakistan.
You worry about India.
MOUNTBATTEN: Gentlemen,
I think perhaps we should recommence.
PEOPLE [CHANTING]:
Death to Jinnah! Death to Jinnah!
Death to Jinnah!
Death--
GANDHI: Thank God,
they've stopped.
MIRABEHN:
Manu. Abha.
I'm your granduncle,
but I can still walk
either of you into the ground.
And I don't need to be
pampered in this way.
Finish your quota
of spinning.
Hmm.
Bapu.
Bapu, please don't do it.
What do you want
me not to do?
Not to meet with Mr. Jinnah?
I am a Muslim
and a Hindu...
and a Christian and a Jew.
And so are all of you.
When you wave
those flags and shout...
you send fear
into the hearts of your brothers.
That is not
the India I want. Stop it!
For God's sake, stop it.
JINNAH: If you've
finished your prayers, gentlemen,
perhaps we could begin
our business.
My dear Jinnah...
you and I are brothers
born of the same mother India.
If you have fears,
I want to put them at rest.
Begging the understanding
of my friends...
I am asking Panditji
to stand down.
I want you to be the first
prime minister of India...
to name your entire cabinet...
to make the head of
every government department a Muslim.
Bapu...
For me and the rest...
if that is what you want,
we will accept it.
But out there...
already there is rioting
because Hindus fear you are
going to give too much away.
PATEL:
If you did this...
no one would control it.
No one.
It is your choice.
Do you want an independent India
and an independent Pakistan...
or do you want civil war?
[BAND PLAYS]
CROWD [CHANTING]:
Jinnah! Jinnah! Jinnah!
Jinnah! Jinnah!
[PEOPLE SHOUTING]
NEHRU: What you did in Noakhali,
Bapu, was a miracle.
Miracle.
But millions are
on the move...
and no one can
count the dead.
In Calcutta,
it's like civil war.
The Muslims rose
and there was a bloodbath.
Now the Hindus
are taking revenge.
If we can't stop it...
there'll be no hope
for the Hindus left in Pakistan.
An eye for an eye,
making the whole world blind.
AZAD: Aren't
there any troops to spare?
Nothing.
The divisions in Bombay
and Delhi can hardly keep the peace now.
And each fresh bit of
news creates another wave of madness.
We could cut all news off.
Bapu, please,
where are you going?
I don't want to hear more.
PATEL:
We need your help.
There is nothing I can give.
Where are you going?
Calcutta.
GANDHI: If I
had shunned death or feared it,
I would not be here now,
nor would you be concerned for me.
OFFICER:
But, sir, please.
I don't have the
men to protect you...
not in a Muslim house,
not this quarter.
I'm staying with the friend
of a friend and--
PEOPLE [CHANTING]:
Death to Muslims! Death to Muslims!
Why are you staying
at the home of a Muslim?
They are murderers!
They killed my family!
MAN:
Get out of Calcutta, Gandhi!
PEOPLE [CHANTING]:
Death to Muslims! Death to Muslims!
Death to Muslims!
Prime Minister.
Why must I read news
like this in the paper?
Inform Sardar Patel.
Arrange a plane.
We will go Friday.
Four days, sir?
[CROWD SHOUTING
IN DISTANCE]
Bapu.
Panditji.
Sardar, you have
gained weight.
You must join
me in the fast.
If I fast, I die.
If you fast, people go
to all sorts of trouble
to keep you alive.
NEHRU: Bapu,
forgive me, I've cheated.
I could have come earlier...
but your fast has helped.
These last days, people's
minds have begun to turn to this bed...
and away from the atrocities.
But now...
it is enough.
All that has happened is that
I've grown a little thinner.
Tomorrow, 5000
Muslim students of all ages
are marching here,
in Calcutta, for peace.
And 5000 Hindu students
are marching with them.
I'm glad.
But it will not be enough.
Bapu...
you are not so
young anymore.
Don't worry for me.
I cannot watch the destruction
of all that I've lived for.
[CROWD CHANTING
INDISTINCTLY]
MAN:
Death to Gandhi!
Who dares say such things?!
Who?!
You kill me first!
Come!
Where are you?!
Kill me first!
Where are you?
His pulse is very irregular.
The kidneys aren't functioning.
NEHRU:
Bapu.
I have brought
Mr. Suhrawardy.
It was he who called
on the Muslims to rise.
He is now telling them...
to go back to their homes...
to lay down their arms.
Think what you can do by living...
that you cannot
do by dying.
What do you want?
That the fighting will stop.
That you make me believe...
that it will never start again.
NEHRU [OVER P.A.]:
Sometimes...
it is when you are
quite without hope...
and in utter darkness...
that God comes
to the rescue.
Gandhiji...
is dying...
because of our madness.
Put away your revenge.
What good will
come of more killing?
Have the courage to do...
what you know is right.
For God's sake...
let us embrace like brothers.
[WEAPONS CLINKING
ON GROUND]
It's our promise.
We stop.
Hindu swords.
It's a promise.
GANDHI:
Go.
God be with you.
Here, eat!
Eat!
I'm going to hell...
but not with your death
on my soul.
Only God decides
who goes to hell.
I killed a child.
I smashed his head
against a wall.
Why?
They killed my son.
My boy.
The Muslims killed my son!
I know a way out of hell.
Find a child.
A child whose mother
and father have been killed.
A little boy about this high...
and raise him as your own.
Only be sure that
he is a Muslim...
and that you raise
him as one.
Go.
God bless you.
MIRABEHN:
Bapu?
There's been no fighting...
anywhere.
It's stopped.
The madness has stopped.
It's foolish...
if it's just to save
the life of an old man.
No. In every temple
and mosque...
they have pledged to die...
before they lift a hand
against each other.
AZAD:
It is true, Bapu.
Everywhere.
Maulana, my friend...
could I have some orange juice?
Then you and I...
will take a piece
of bread together.
Hmm.
[PEOPLE CHATTERING
INDISTINCTLY]
He will be saying prayers
in the garden.
That is how you eat muli.
I'm not sure that I want
to be remembered that way.
Well, don't worry.
With luck, you may not be.
PATEL: No, he will
be remembered for tempting fate.
[ABHA GIGGLING]
ABHA:
Mickey Mouse!
So you really are going
to Pakistan, then?
You are a stubborn man.
Hmm.
I'm simply going to prove...
to Hindus here and Muslims there...
that the only devils
in the world are those...
running around
in our own hearts.
And that is where
all our battles ought to be fought.
Bapu.
Oh.
So, what kind of warrior
have you been in that warfare?
Oh, not a very good one.
That's why I have
so much tolerance...
for the other scoundrels
of the world.
Sardar?
Ask Panditji to consider
what we've discussed.
Enough!
One more.
You're a temptress!
Just an admirer.
Nothing's more
dangerous...
especially for an old man.
There's a sadness about him.
He thinks he's failed.
Why?
My God, if anything's proven him right,
it's what happened these last months.
I may be blinded
by my love for him...
but I believe...
when we most needed it...
he offered the world
a way out of madness.
But he doesn't see it.
Neither does the world.
Namaste.
Hmm.
Brother, Bapu is already
late for prayers.
GANDHI:
Oh, God!
Oh, God.
GANDHI:
When I despair...
I remember
that all through history,
the way of truth and love
has always won.
There have been tyrants
and murderers,
and for a time,
they can seem invincible,
but in the end, they always fall.
Think of it.
Always.