But Father Fitzgibbon, why
do you want a new furnace?
Because, Mr. Haines, last winter,
in the month of November alone, four of me
perishiners took to
the bed with pneumonia.
Well that's too bad.
It's only by a miracle
that I meself pulled through.
And it'll only cost $632.50,
complete with an automatic damper.
But Father Fitzgibbon, I didn't
come here to put in a new furnace.
I think you oughta give
him his furnace, dad.
It would warm people's hearts and
maybe his collections would be bigger.
No son.
Improvements are out.
Now Father...
That was good, what
he said, that was good.
Oh, well he's new to our business.
Now Father...
No furnace huh?
No furnace.
Now Father, here's my business.
You owe the Knickerbocker
Savings and Loan Company
five payments on this
mortgage, and if they're
not taken care of, I'm afraid the
Knickerbocker Savings and Loan Company
will have to take the necessary action.
Huh?
Why don't you make that the subject
of your sermon next Sunday?
Tell it to your people.
The Lord loveth the cheerful giver?
Oh I can imagine meself
saying that in Mass next Sunday.
What a sermon that would be, Mr. Haines.
The text of me sermon this morning
is taken from the mortgage.
According to Mr. Haines.
From the first to the 23rd clause.
If they'd only know.
Oh but that's your business.
Keep it bright, huh?
No, but seriously Father, we've made
a bad loan and we want our money back.
Well you'll get it somehow.
Ah, well that's all I wanted to know.
Well good day, Father.
Come on son.
Dad.
You can't foreclose, why
it just hasn't been done.
I read up on it, and there's never been
a Catholic Church foreclosure
in the history of New York.
Well there's always a
first time isn't there?
Don't you think you're
being a little harsh with him?
You've got to be.
Son, never loan money to a church.
As soon as you start to close in on them,
everybody thinks you're a heel.
Well aren't you?
Yes.
Good morning!
Excuse me, but could you tell me
where I'd find St. Dominic's Church?
Eh?
I'm looking
for St. Dominic's Church.
Why?
I'm gonna work there.
The new assistant eh?
And you can't even find the church.
Well all I can say is, young man,
you're off to a mighty bad start.
What's your name?
Father O'Malley.
Charles Francis Patrick O'Malley.
What's yours?
Her name is Quimp!
Hattie Quimp!
You'll see a lot of her, you will.
At St. Dominic's she's
a regular two-dayer.
Very religious.
Burns candles.
I could tell you plenty about them too.
And if I did, they'd have
to leave the neighborhood!
If you're looking for
St. Dominic's, Father,
it's a block up and then to your left.
Thank you.
Hello.
How's things going?
Aw terrible.
They never hit one to me.
Watch right field for me
a minute, will you Father?
Sure.
I gotta run in the house.
Okay.
Hey fellas, the Father's
gonna take my place!
Okay Father!
I got it!
Got it!
Thanks.
What do you think you're doing?
I'm a substitute right fielder.
You oughta be ashamed of yourself.
Playing around with a lot of kids,
smashing people's windows.
A big grown up man.
And a priest besides.
Oh hello.
Still looking for St. Dominic's?
You just wait 'til I
tell Father Fitzgibbon.
Look, you keep out of this will you?
Go on, go on.
This is between him and me.
Honestly, I'm sorry about the window.
Yeah, but being sorry don't fix it.
Well I intend to pay for it.
When?
Priests never have any money.
That window...
Now wait a minute, my good man.
I said I'd pay for it
and I told you I'm sorry.
What else can I say after I say I'm sorry?
Well that ain't the idea,
it's the principle of the thing.
A priest didn't oughta go around
breaking people's windows.
It sets a bad example for the children.
You got me stymied there,
I'm contrite and I'm penitent.
I told you I'm sorry.
Yeah, you told me that
twice, but that don't...
That doesn't fix the broken
window, I know, I know.
I think you're just plain
hard to get along with.
Maybe a little security might help.
Huh?
These were given to me.
Why don't you keep them
until I've made good?
Maybe they'll make you feel better.
They're mother of pearl, you see?
If that'll satisfy you, I'll run along.
Hey you.
Here.
I got no use for this.
First place, I don't believe in it.
As a matter of fact, I
don't believe in anything.
I can believe that.
I'm an atheist.
Besides, I'm superstitious.
All right then, I'm sorry about
the window, I'll have it fixed.
Can I have the ball back?
You even throw like an atheist.
Mrs. Carmody, did the
young priest come yet?
He's here.
But he insisted on changing
his clothes before seeing you.
Ah, that's nice.
Tidying himself up a bit.
Hello Father.
I'm your new curate, Father.
If you'll excuse my appearance.
I know it's not possible.
The bishop may have a grudge against me.
He may think I've a mouth full of clover
and can't preach, but even the bishop
wouldn't do a thing like this to me.
I see what you mean.
Young man, may I ask is that
the official garb of the
priests in St. Louis?
No, something happened
to me on the way over.
I guess this just isn't my day, Father.
Do you mind if I...
Nah.
Eh.
Young man, as a matter of curiosity,
what made you become a priest?
Why I...
Hello?
Well you don't say.
You don't say.
Oh yes, I can well believe it.
Mrs. Quimp?
Oh yes, yes indeed, Miss Quimp.
Yes indeed, I appreciate
your good intentions.
Yes yes yes.
Goodbye, yes, goodbye, goodbye, goodbye.
I guess she told you about me huh?
Yeah, the girl is all bitty.
Young man, I'm afraid you're
off to a very bad start.
That's what she said.
I'm sorry, Father.
Smashing people's windows, such conduct.
Oh yes, that reminds me, I
wanted to ask you something.
Tell me young man, how did
you happen to become a priest?
Well I...
Yeah?
Chuck?
Chuck who?
Father Chuck?
That's me.
Here, I'll take it over here.
Hello?
Timmy!
Well how are you Timmy?
Oh I just got in.
Well what do you know.
That's Father O'Dowd,
an old friend of mine.
We used to go to school together.
♪ Hail alma mater, thy
time honored halls ♪
♪ Shall echo with our praise 'til we die ♪
♪ And round our hearts are
the ivy-covered walls ♪
♪ Of East St. Louis High ♪
Oh ho, good Chuck, good, good.
Can you talk?
Well no.
All right, then I'll do the talking.
How does your new pastor impress you?
You're a big help.
Well it's a little early to say.
Time will tell.
Uh-uh.
No, I think it'd be better
if I told you when I saw you.
Yes, it'd be much better.
All right Timmy, make it soon huh?
So long.
Oh he's a great little man.
Yeah, yeah.
Well what were we talking about?
I was going to ask you something...
You were gonna ask me if
I wanted to see the church.
Yes, that's right.
I like this.
It's beautiful.
Thank you.
How long you been here Father?
45 years.
46 in October.
The church?
The same.
I built it.
Can only hope someday I
can say I built as much.
This is nice.
Yeah, the birds like it.
They're good company.
Listen.
Yes, I've taken a great deal
of pleasure in me garden.
It's been hard work,
but it's been worth it.
I think you'll find this a very
pleasant place in which to meditate.
You do meditate don't you?
Oh yeah, sure.
Now I'll show you the church.
What we really need is
a loudspeaker system.
For a minute I thought I
found a four leaf clover.
Guess it just isn't my day.
Would you like to see the...
Oh yes!
Oh Mrs. Carmody!
Just a minute.
Where's Father O'Malley?
He left early this morning.
The young man doesn't sleep
as late as you do, you know.
Huh?
Oh, oh.
What's this?
His luggage.
Just arrived.
Golf, tennis.
Now where may I ask is his fish pole?
It's here.
Good morning, Father!
Been to market huh?
Mrs. Carmody could attend to that.
You should've been making parish calls.
I have.
Mrs. McGonagall, you know, the one
with the big house and rheumatism?
She sent you a present.
Oh she did huh?
How very generous of her, I must say.
A fine Christian woman in Mrs. McGonagall.
I wonder what it is.
Something to eat, I dare say.
Jam!
No, pickled pigs feet.
Possibly some brandy peaches.
Oh if there's one thing I'm partial to,
it's a nice big jar of brandy peaches.
A nice basket too.
Yeah, she wants it back.
They're too young, O'Malley.
Much too young to be
separated from the mother.
That's what she said.
So here's the mother.
Ain't she cute?
Hello baby.
The joy of giving is indeed a pleasure.
Especially when you get rid
of something you don't want.
Oh Mrs. McGonagall is
famous for these tricks.
When her husband died
she sent me his umbrella,
his long flannel underwear,
and his mustache coat.
♪ Hail alma mater, thy
time honored halls ♪
♪ Shall echo with our praise 'til we die ♪
♪ And 'round our hearts
are the ivy-covered walls ♪
♪ Of East St. Louis High ♪
Timmy how are you?
Hiya Chuck, I'm glad to see you.
Glad to see you.
How long is it
since we've seen each other?
Four years.
Oh five anyway.
Has it been that long?
Yes.
Pardon me.
Father Fitzgibbon, this is
my old friend Father O'Dowd.
How are you, Father Fitzgibbon?
We've been friends since we
were knee high to a nibbly.
He was our local Huckleberry Finn.
Laugh and the world laughs
with you, he used to say.
Cry and you cry all by yourself.
How are you, Father Fitzgibbon?
I just dropped by to
see if Father O'Malley
could play a little golf this afternoon.
Oh you did?
Where's your parish?
Right over here, St. Francis.
Well now, about your golf.
'Course I can't answer for you, but at
St. Dominic's we've very little time
for games of golf and sunshine.
And if you're working
for me, all I can say
is that you wouldn't have time for either.
It's lucky for me then
that I'm at St. Francis.
It's my hope St.
Francis can say the same.
Uh-oh, he's got you there Timmy.
Good Father, very good.
Say Father, why don't you
come around with us sometime?
It's a grand game.
Sure Father, we'll teach you.
A man is never too old to learn.
A lot of nice fresh
air out on the golf course.
And profanity too.
No.
A golf course is nothing but
a pool room moved outdoors.
You mind if I use that
one sometime Father?
Young man, would you mind?
How did he ever become a priest?
Well I don't...
Father Fitzgibbon.
Excuse me.
Who is it?
Mrs. Quimp.
Oh gosh.
Does he know?
Does he know what?
That you're in charge.
How'd you know?
I didn't.
Ha.
I gathered as much when
I heard you were here.
Everybody knows that St.
Dominic's is in a bad way.
Father Fitzgibbon is
getting to be an old man.
This needs a young Father...
Timmy, look.
Don't mention it to anybody.
Oh no, no.
You see, when I had
my talk with the bishop
it was our understanding
that Father Fitzgibbon
was to remain here as pastor and I was
to try and straighten out St. Dominic's
without hurting his feelings.
I see.
You're in charge but you're not.
I don't think I'd like
an assignment like that.
But the bishop couldn't very well
put him out to pasture could he?
Pasture?
What's this I hear about a pasture?
I was just saying to him, Father.
The next time I come "past your" church
I'm going to drop in and see you.
Good day, Father.
So long, Chuck.
I was going to ask you something.
Oh yes, the telephone.
Mrs. Quimp just telephoned, her landlord
has thrown her out again, she'll want
somebody to go down and
see her, you better go...
I'll go right along, Father.
Will you mind the puppies?
Yeah.
Thank you.
I'll bet you're the new
assistant, the one who's
going to get St. Dominic's
out of all its trouble?
And I'll bet you're all the trouble.
I'll wager you're the
man with the mortgage.
Oh you've heard about the mortgage?
All churches have mortgages.
It isn't respectable for
a church not to have one.
My name's O'Malley.
Mine's Haines.
Nice meeting you.
We may have to touch you for
a little more a little later on.
Eh?
Yeah, we're gonna need a new
paint job here pretty soon.
But I must run along.
You look like a man it'll be a
pleasure to do business with.
Yes.
Get out!
Get out, you're not throwing me out!
And I'll pay you me rent when I get it!
Good morning, Father.
Morning.
Hello, Father.
Mrs. Quimp and I were just discussing you.
Oh you were?
As you know, I represent the
Knickerbocker Savings and Loan Company.
And in as much as Mrs. Quimp declines
to pay her rent, the Knickerbocker
Savings and Loan Company refuses
to offer her any further hospitality.
Is she very far in her rears?
Mrs. Quimp has paid
us nothing for six months.
Well it's certainly very nice
of you to show her so much leniency.
Supposing the poor old
woman has no place to go.
Well the Knickerbocker
Savings and Loan Company
is not a charitable institution,
Father, like St. Dominic's.
With us it's just a matter
of cold-blooded business.
Well with you it's different.
You haven't got anything
and you don't want anything.
That's your business, and
people respect you for it.
But I'm not in your business, see?
If I haven't got anything and
don't want anything, I'm a bum.
Surely there must be
something we can do about it.
Well I don't know what
you're gonna do about it,
but I'm going to throw
her right out on her ear.
Now why don't you give her a break?
Give her a month to make good in.
St. Dominic's will guarantee it.
St. Dominic's?
Yeah.
I can see you haven't
been around long, Father.
Why St. Dominic's is in
worse shape than Mrs. Quimp.
My old man happens to own
the mortgage and he says...
Oh your father holds the mortgage eh?
You're darn right he does.
And confidentially, I think he'd
like to find a way to foreclose.
He wants to tear down the church
and making a parking lot out of it.
Can you imagine?
Oh he's a very disliked man.
I'm sorta following in his footsteps.
Junior eh?
Yeah.
Let's cut through the churchyard.
Good afternoon boys.
Oh hello, Father.
That's a fine fat bird you have there.
Oh, well we were sorta
bringing it over for you.
It's sorta a present ain't it Herman?
Yeah!
Well now that's very generous of you.
Such a fine bird and all.
Now where, may I ask, did you get it?
We got...
We won it in a raffle
over at the theater.
We were lucky.
Why isn't that great huh?
But surely your mother...
Well except on Christmas,
ma don't like turkey.
She don't huh?
Honest.
Well now that's most fortunate for me,
for there's nothing I'm
more partial to than
a nice Tom turkey,
roasted all with dressing.
Well I appreciate your kindness, boys.
Aw it ain't nothing, Father.
Oh on the contrary, I
appreciate the thought behind it.
Small luxuries, like small sacrifices,
are oftentimes the most godly.
Well bless you both.
Thank you.
Take it in, inside the
kitchen's the housekeeper.
Okay Father, we'll see you later.
So you guaranteed
Mrs. Quimp's rent did you?
Of course I did.
St. Dominic's can't afford it.
I expected you to counsel
Mrs. Quimp, not to adopt her.
Ah, hot turkey.
Hot?
Of course it's hot.
That's what I said.
Bless us, oh Lord, for these
thy gifts we are about receive
in the name of amen.
Amen.
Say Father, you know a youngster
around here named Tony Scaponi?
Mmmhm, what about him?
Well this afternoon...
Tony belongs to a fine,
upstanding Catholic family.
11 children.
Oh sure I know Tony.
As fine a lad as there is in the parish.
Police don't think so.
Oh they don't huh?
No.
If something isn't done about Tony
and his pals, I'm afraid they're
gonna wind up in a reform school.
Who told you that?
The police.
Oh you've been listening
to Patrick McCarthy no doubt.
Let me tell you that that...
That man hasn't been to
Mass in the last 10 years.
That may be, but I think
McCarthy's right about those kids.
They're terrorizing the
whole neighborhood, Father.
Always talking like that.
To hear the police talk, you'd think that
every lad in the parish was a criminal.
I'll have you know that
the very food there
before us is brought to us by two
of those very lads that the police
are so maliciously slandering.
Is that so?
Tony Scaponi was one of them.
I gave them both my blessing.
And they gave you the bird.
Yeah.
I'll get it.
Hello, McCarthy.
Oh good evening, Father.
Well I brought 'em.
Tony Scaponi, Herman Langerhanke.
Hi fellas.
I don't think you have to wait, McCarthy.
Well okay, Father.
Say, I understand that you fellas
like baseball pretty well huh?
Yeah.
I was thinking Saturday
the Yanks are playing
the St. Louis Browns, a double header.
Would you like to go out
and see the games with me?
St. Louis my old hometown, you know.
I get all the passes I want.
What do you say?
Well I guess so.
Yeah, yeah sure, I guess
the fellas would like that.
That's a date then.
I'll meet you here Saturday at noon?
Yeah, that'd be good.
You run along and have your dinner.
I'll go finish my turkey.
Let me see, now where was I?
Oh yeah, I know.
I was going to ask you something.
Oh yeah, what made me become a priest?
No no no no.
About young Tony.
What was it the police accused him of?
Stealing.
Stealing?
Stealing what?
Turkeys.
Seems the boys hijacked a
poultry truck down the street
here and there was quite
a bit of excitement.
The driver reported them to the police.
And did that poor man
get his turkeys back?
All but one, Father.
Thank you.
Hello McCarthy, how are you?
Good morning, Father.
You open for business?
Always open for business, McCarthy.
Come on in.
You just wait here.
Come right in, Pat.
I got a problem, Father.
Yeah?
Seems like it's more yours than mine.
Mmmhm.
It's her.
Well Father, it's this way.
Last night I'm walking my beat, see?
And who do you think I run into?
Her?
Mrs. Quimp.
Ah.
"Officer McCaddy" she says.
You know how the old stool pigeon talks.
Yes I do.
"If you'll go around the
corner you'll find a girl.
"I've been watching her and
she ain't up to no good."
Well Father, I go around the corner
and there, like the
Quimp says, I find her.
You follow me, Father?
Yes I am.
Well I look at her and size her up.
One of those things, I think.
And I'm just about to say to her
no sister, not on my beat.
When she turns, and right
away I see another line.
You follow me Father?
Mmmhm, yup.
Well to get down to her, Father,
I find she's broke and run away from home.
There's no soul in town.
So instead of booking
her, I take her home.
It's all right with the Mrs for one night,
but if she stays any longer, well I guess
Mrs. McCarthy, good woman that she is,
is no different from any other woman.
You follow me, Father?
Yeah, I follow you.
So anyway, she tells us that she's
run away from home on account
of her folks don't understand her.
We tried arguing with her,
Father, but she's a tough one.
She thinks honor thy father and
thy mother is a belly laugh.
Well Father, guess I'll let
you pick it up from here.
Says her name's Carol James.
All right, McCarthy.
So long, Father.
Goodbye.
All right, you can go in now.
Come right in.
Would you sit down over here?
Carol.
Suppose you give us
your version of it huh?
I guess it's just about like he said.
You don't get along with your parents.
No.
So you're going to leave home?
Oh I've left.
How you fixed for funds?
I haven't any.
That's how I met Officer McCarthy.
Oh but I'll get by.
How about you go back home.
I tell you, at home
my life is intolerable.
Parents?
We don't agree on anything.
Don't like the way I do my hair,
my eyebrows, too much lipstick.
Something or other.
Too long, too short.
Do you think it's too short?
Well I...
I don't know.
They even object to my boyfriends.
And if they do let me go out
they say "where are you going?
"Come home early!
"Come right home after the show!"
"No drive-in."
And no matter how early
I get in, it's too late.
And if I say we ran out of
gas, they say I'm lying.
Are you?
Sometimes.
Did you ever think of maybe having
the boyfriends over to the house?
Now you talk like they do.
I tell you why I can't have
them over to the house,
because grandma sleeps in the living room.
She does huh?
By 9 o'clock we have
to be off the couch.
She needs it for a bed.
Can you imagine?
Course you know, there
might be two sides to it.
Maybe you're being a little unreasonable.
I'm 18.
18 huh?
As old as that?
You know, when I was 18 I thought
my father was pretty dumb.
After a while when I got
to be 21 I was amazed
to find out how much he
learned in three years.
Oh well.
Now that you're in New York,
what do you propose to do?
I'm going to get a job.
I'm a singer.
A singer huh?
You any good?
Well of course I'm good.
What makes you think so?
Well I'm just good, that's all.
Well would you sing something for me?
Maybe I can help you.
I'm supposed to be a pretty good judge.
You wouldn't know the
kind of songs I know.
How do you know?
Do you happen to know Day After Forever?
What key?
Would you mind dropping
it just a little?
♪ All day tomorrow ♪
♪ I'll be whispering your name ♪
♪ And the day after forever ♪
♪ I know I'll do the same ♪
♪ Maytime or winter ♪
♪ I won't let you out of sight ♪
♪ And the day after forever ♪
♪ We'll talk about tonight ♪
♪ Your laughter is a melody ♪
♪ That I'll remember long ♪
♪ It plays upon my heartstrings ♪
♪ It's my favorite song ♪
♪ All through a lifetime ♪
♪ I'll be loving you and then ♪
♪ On the day after forever ♪
♪ I'll just begin again ♪
Well what do you think?
Well you got a pretty nice voice,
but instead of so much of this, you oughta
think about putting a little
feeling into the words.
For instance, Father?
♪ All day tomorrow ♪
♪ I'll be whispering your name ♪
♪ And the day after forever ♪
♪ I know I'll do the same ♪
♪ Maytime or winter ♪
♪ I won't let you out of sight ♪
♪ And the day after forever ♪
♪ We'll talk about tonight ♪
I see what you mean, Father.
Supposing you try it then huh?
Just speak the words.
Your laughter is a melody.
That I'll remember long.
That's it.
It plays upon my heartstrings.
Now sing it.
♪ It's my favorite song ♪
♪ All through a lifetime ♪
♪ I'll be loving you ♪
♪ And then on the day ♪
♪ After forever ♪
♪ I'll just ♪
♪ Begin ♪
♪ Again ♪
What's that, again?
I was imitating you Father.
Did I do that?
Oh definitely.
Maybe, but I didn't do that
♪ And the day after forever ♪
♪ You're my favorite song ♪
There's no thought behind that at all.
♪ We'll talk about ♪
What has that got to do with the song?
Hello, Father.
This young lady came to us for some help.
So it's work you're wanting.
Yes, Father.
Well I think maybe I can place you.
You can?
What would you think of
a little general housework?
Mrs. Scaponi with all those children.
11, no 12, 12 in October.
I think maybe she could use you.
Oh no.
I'm not looking for that kind of work.
I don't think you understand
Father, she's a singer.
Aren't you?
Well now.
And where, may I ask, are you
expecting to find employment?
In some nice cool airy
nightclub I suppose.
Any prospects?
Well no.
Not exactly.
And you're willing to starve
rather than push a broom.
You have a home, I presume.
Oh she just left it, Father.
Then go right back to your parents.
A fine little girl like you singing
in some place like the
Blue Goose or something.
Well you've got to
start someplace, Father.
Nonsense, being a good wife and a mother
is a good enough start for you.
Like your own mother.
Well goodbye, Father.
Goodbye.
Hey.
Young lady.
You go home and stay home
until the right man comes around.
The right man will
never come near our house.
But don't worry.
I'll get by.
Carol!
Wait just a minute.
Father.
Do you think you may have 10, Father?
Of what?
$10?
She's all alone, she hasn't a thing.
Open up our hearts, huh?
$10.
Just a minute.
How about five eh?
Five?
No no, 10.
Carol, I didn't like the way
you said that "I'll get by."
Here's a little something
to tide you over.
Oh, it's fine...
It's all right, it's not charity.
It's a loan.
Thanks.
I can use it.
I appreciate it.
Carol, I guess there's a lot of things
I should have said to you, advice for
one thing or another, but you
wouldn't have paid any attention.
After all, you are 18 aren't you?
Don't worry.
I'll be all right.
Of course you will, Carol.
I'll get by.
Oh don't say that.
Now let's hear from you, huh?
All right, Father.
Bye.
Bye Carol.
Hey fellas!
What are we doing hanging around here for?
'Cause I promised
O'Malley, that's what for.
Why?
'Cause I said so, see?
Hey fellas, look.
Waist petticoats.
First thing you know, he'll be
charming us into these things.
Yeah, making
altar boys out of us.
First guy up, I kick his teeth in see?
Now look yous, O'Malley's
a right guy, see?
Pick him up.
Now look yous, O'Malley's
a right guy, see?
He didn't rat on us
about the turkeys did he?
No.
Took us to a
baseball game didn't he?
Yeah.
Bought us hot dogs didn't he?
He's gonna take us
to a picture show ain't he?
How do we know?
Hello Father.
Say hello to the Father.
Hi fellas.
Hey Father, where'd you get the outfit?
That's the St. Louis Browns.
I told you I used to work out with them.
They thought I brought them luck.
When I left town they
made me a present of it.
Oh that's just the
outfit to wear in a cellar.
Oh you, knocking my team.
Well I guess you fellas wonder
why I asked you down here huh?
Well hey Father, I wanna
talk to you a minute.
Can I?
Wanna see me?
Yeah, just a minute.
Pardon me boys.
Tony, what's on your mind?
Well Father, so you
won't have no beef coming,
I'm laying it on the line okay?
Okay.
Well he's here, Father.
Like I promised, only you
should've heard him squawk.
Worse than that turkey.
Oh the turkey, they did huh?
Yeah, they figured that being a priest
you was gonna slip them the old routine.
Oh yeah.
Personally, I'm for giving you a break,
and what I says is what the gang goes.
Swell of ya, Tony.
Aw it ain't nothing, Father.
Only the way it is now Father,
I'm on a hook for you, see?
I'm responsible for you, get me?
I won't let you down Tony.
Well maybe you won't,
but I'm telling you,
you step out of line just once and me and
the gang will drop ya
like you was a hot potato.
Okay?
Okay, can I talk to them now?
Oh sure.
Go ahead.
Boys, I'm not gonna do much talking.
Like Tony says, I'm gonna
lay it right on the line.
I asked you down here to do me a favor.
St. Dominic's needs a choir
and I wanna start one.
I know, I know what you're thinking,
but it's not gonna be that way at all.
It's gonna be fun.
Believe me, I like fun as much as anybody.
If it doesn't turn out
that way, if you think
I'm trying to slip something
over on you, well like
Tony says you can "drop
me like a hot potato."
What do you say?
You gonna give me a break?
Well Father, that depends.
What is it?
Well how many of you
here know Three Blind Mice?
I know it.
One.
Two, any more?
Three.
Oh come on, you all know it.
Everybody knows it?
Fine.
What's the matter with him over there?
Oh Herman?
He's pouting.
Hey Herman!
He's got a good bass voice.
You want him?
Well certainly, Tony.
You've got him, Father.
Now let's see, we gotta
divide this up some way.
Hey Herman, wait a minute.
The Father wants to see you.
Well I don't wanna see the Father!
Shhhh.
What is...
Keep quiet, will ya please?
Don't hit me on the
head, you make me dopey!
You are dopey.
Now keep quiet.
But I...
Come here.
Now look, he wants a bass singer...
I ain't a bass singer!
You are a bass singer!
Why am I a bass singer?
Oooh that burns me up!
My head, my head!
Shhh.
He wants a bass singer.
I don't know how to...
Will you go down please?
Will you go down?
Now keep quiet, okay?
Let's go.
Okay.
♪ Three blind mice ♪
♪ See how they run ♪
♪ They all ran after the farmer's wife ♪
♪ She cut off their tails
with a carving knife ♪
♪ Did you ever see such
a sight in your life ♪
♪ As three blind mice ♪
♪ Three blind mice ♪
♪ See how they run ♪
♪ They all ran after the farmer's wife ♪
♪ She cut off their tails
with a carving knife ♪
♪ Did you ever see such
a sight in your life ♪
♪ As three blind mice ♪
It's no business of mine Father,
but sometimes the things you do
in haste are the things we most regret.
Think it over a while.
Then if you really feel
you must see the bishop...
That I do.
But the boys are much better off here
than running the streets, I'm sure
that was Father O'Malley's idea.
I'm a charmed man, Mrs. Carmody.
But there's some things that get under
my skin and Three Blind
Mice is one of them.
But he's young, Father.
Eh?
I admit, maybe a wee bit impulsive.
But I know he means well.
And after all, it was the bishop
himself did put him here.
Yeah, and the bishop himself
will put him someplace else.
I'm going to ask to have
Father O'Malley transferred.
Don't worry.
It's not a bad report I'll be making.
I'll just tell the bishop that this
young man and I, that
we don't see eye to eye,
and I'd be happier if he
was sent some other place.
It's a long hard road
you've come, Father.
45 years and most of the time
carrying other people's burdens.
The time has come when you
should rest on your oars.
Take things a might
easier, enjoy your life.
Let somebody else carry the load for you.
Surely Father O'Malley's got
a strong pair of shoulders.
♪ Three blind mice ♪
♪ See how they run ♪
♪ They all ran after the farmer's wife ♪
See what I mean?
♪ She cut off their tails
with a carving knife ♪
♪ Did you ever see such
a sight in your life ♪
♪ As three blind mind ♪
No, I've got to see the bishop.
♪ Three blind mice ♪
♪ See how they run ♪
Now we got our sections down,
I'm gonna give each section a note.
And we'll put them all together
and we'll have a chord.
Take this section first, here's your note.
♪ Baaaa ♪
Got that?
Let me hear it now.
♪ Baaaa ♪
I thought we had some singers here.
I wanna hear everybody in this section.
Big, now let me hear it.
♪ Baaaa ♪
That's good.
Second section, here's your note.
♪ Baa baa, baaaa ♪
You got that?
Let me hear it.
♪ Baaaa ♪
Oh we got a crawler in there somewhere.
Who is that?
You?
What's your name?
My name's Elmer.
Elmer?
Your voice is changing or something is it?
Yeah, I guess so, Father.
Think we'll have to
drop you down a bracket.
You get over here in the third section.
Elmer's a switch hitter it seems.
Let me hear that second section again.
♪ Baa baa ♪
♪ Baaaa ♪
Oh that's great, now the
third section, here's your note.
♪ Ba-ba baaaa ♪
Got that?
♪ Baaaa ♪
Tell me you sing like you
were made for this section.
Now we're gonna drop way down in the bass.
Watch this now, this is
tricky, everybody take it tall.
♪ Ba-ba-ba baaaa ♪
That's your note, baaaa.
Let me hear it.
♪ Baaaa ♪
There's a pink one in there somewhere.
That wasn't me.
What did you sing?
Ba-ba!
Sit down, Tony.
Okay, everybody together now.
You got your notes?
♪ Ba-ba-ba baaaa ♪
Now we hit them all together
and we got a nice chord.
Ready?
Everybody take a deep breath now.
Let's hear it.
Now you got chord number one,
chord number two, chord number three.
Put those three chords together
and we can sing a song.
I'll hold up the fingers,
those will be your signals.
Watch the signals now.
Make out I'm the catcher,
I'm giving you the signals.
One, two, three.
Ready?
Here's your note now.
♪ Baaaa ♪
♪ Silent night ♪
♪ Holy night ♪
♪ All is calm ♪
♪ All is bright ♪
♪ Round yon virgin ♪
♪ Mother and child ♪
♪ Holy infant ♪
♪ So tender and mild ♪
♪ Sleep in heavenly peace ♪
Oh that's fine boys.
Thanks very much.
Wanna call it a day?
There's still enough light
outside for some baseball.
Let's sing some more, Father.
Yeah, let's go ahead.
You saw the bishop, Father?
Yeah, yeah.
Would you ask Father O'Malley if
he'd mind stepping into me study?
You wanted to see me, Father?
Yeah, yes I did, I did.
Sit down, sit down.
Father O'Malley, I've
been to see the bishop.
Oh you have?
And I want to be frank with you.
I must admit that my purpose in going
to see the bishop was
to have you transferred.
I'm sorry you don't like me, Father.
I don't dislike anyone.
It's just that I disagree with you.
What did the bishop say?
After a little talk, he congratulated me
on my 45 years at St. Dominic's.
He has a remarkable memory.
He said it was a monument to
the fact that I had built it.
Coming from the bishop,
that's certainly a fine compliment.
Then I told him I'd
come to talk about you.
That seemed to disturb him.
Then he started telling me about
what a fine young man you are.
Capable, progressive, how
much confidence he had in you.
He even told me that he had a nice talk
with you before you reported to me.
Course he didn't tell me
what you two talked about.
He didn't have to.
I could see it in the good man's eyes.
When you get to my age you
can tell that, you know?
Then after a little more telling me how
progressive you were, he
asked me why I'd come.
Unknown what was on his
mind, and to save him
the embarrassment of having to tell me.
The bishop wouldn't hurt anyone.
I put him at his ease.
Bishop, I said, the very thing that's
on your mind is on mine, it's the
very thing I've come to see you about.
I want you to put young Father O'Malley
in charge of St. Dominic's.
The bishop seemed much relieved.
He congratulated me on my ability
to see so clearly at my age.
On my ability to face the inevitable.
Then what happened?
That was all.
Oh Father.
Why can't we go along
just as we have been?
No no, you're in charge now.
Sit down.
No Father.
Sit down, I'll familiarize you with...
There's no hurry, we can
do that anytime, Father.
Well is there anything
you'd like me to do?
I mean now.
Nothing.
Well then.
If you don't mind, I'll lie
down a while before dinner.
All right, Father.
When you and the bishop
had your little talk,
it was more or less along
those lines wasn't it?
Yes.
I think you better start without him.
Looks like he's not
coming down for dinner.
Well he said he wanted
to take a little nap.
He didn't look well did he?
When he came in this evening.
Go see if he's awake.
If he's coming down, I'll wait for him.
Father O'Malley!
Father!
He's gone.
He's packed his things.
Everything.
He's gone.
Where would he go?
I can't imagine.
Okay, sure.
But keep at it, will ya?
No, you can't miss him.
A little guy.
Old.
Got a grip and an umbrella.
Okay.
Nothing yet, Father.
They're gonna check the
subways, the hospitals.
Look Father, take it easy will you?
And you better go home.
No use the two of us getting drowned.
All right, but you call me
the minute you hear anything.
I will.
I don't care what time it is.
I will, Father.
Shall I make some coffee?
Wha, hmm?
Oh, no thank you.
Come on.
Now what's the matter?
If you don't mind, I'd
rather go in by myself.
If you don't mind, I found you
and I'm going to deliver you personally.
That's not necessary.
There's no reward you know.
It's going to be a little difficult
and I'd rather explain to Father O'Malley
in me own way, and I can do that
better when you're not around.
Okay.
But if you want my
advice, you just tell him
you've been a bad boy, you ran away
from home, and you're sorry.
And if you want my
advice, you'll go to church
on Sunday, say you haven't been to Mass
in 10 years, and that you're sorry.
Hello.
If you don't mind, I've come back.
But only temporarily.
Until me plans are more formulated.
Maybe you wouldn't mind letting me stay.
I'll be no bother to you.
Here Father, let's get out of these
wet clothes and get you up to bed huh?
But I don't expect me
old room, that's yours now.
Oh I haven't moved in there yet.
No no, I insist, that's your room.
I'll sleep on the cot, anywhere.
I'll not even be
bothering you for me food.
I'll eat out.
We'll talk about that later.
Mrs. Carmody will bring
you something on a tray.
No no no no, I'm not a bit hungry, I...
Come on now Father, just a wee snack.
I've been keeping it for you on the stove.
Nice juicy cut of roast
beef, Yorkshire pudding,
and there were some
creamed onions too huh?
And some asparagus with
buttered breadcrumbs.
Golden brown potatoes
and a nice cup of coffee.
Well if you insist, just a
small portion of everything.
I hope it wasn't too much
trouble for you, Mrs. Carmody.
No trouble at all, Father.
I feel I ought to help
you with the dishes.
Don't worry about the dishes.
Isn't much washing they'll be needing.
Say, you're still a little cold Father,
you were drenched to the skin.
You oughta take a little
something to warm you up.
Do you have a wee drop
of the creature about?
Matter of fact, I might
have a little one with you.
I was out myself tonight.
I went out for a paper.
Ah, well in that case.
I'll ask Mrs. Carmody
where she keeps it.
No no no no, look
yonder in the bookcase.
Oh.
No no, other side.
No down, down.
You'll find it behind The
Life of General Grant.
Bit of ol' Ireland huh?
Every Christmas since I left,
my old mother sends me one of these.
With a degree of abstinence
it becomes me calendar.
I get a little behind during Lent,
but it comes out even at Christmas.
That's me mother.
She's very beautiful.
Of course that was taken some time ago.
She's 90 now.
Let's drink to your mother.
Hope you'll be seeing her soon, Father.
What about your mother?
Well I don't remember much about her.
She died when I was quite young.
Well.
Let's drink to the two of them anyway.
Thank you, Father.
You know, Father O'Malley?
I always planned that as soon as I got
a few dollars ahead, I'll go back
to the old country and see my mother.
Would you believe it?
That was 45 years ago.
And every time I get
a few dollars ahead...
There's always somebody that
seems to need it more than you do.
Aye, you'd like her.
She'd like you too.
She always had a song in her heart.
I can almost hear her now.
Me boy, do you know too-ra-loo-ra-loo?
♪ Too-ra-loo-ra-loo-ral ♪
♪ Too-ra-loo-ra-li ♪
♪ Hush now, don't you cry ♪
♪ Too-ra-loo-ra-loo-ral ♪
♪ Too-ra-loo-ra-Li ♪
♪ That's an Irish lullaby ♪
♪ Too-ra-loo-ra-loo-ral ♪
♪ La, da-de, da-da ♪
Take it easy, boys.
Here Tony, here's the fare.
Everybody right home and to bed!
Get a lot of rest!
I'm responsible for ya.
Don't forget we got a
rehearsal in the morning huh?
Oh gee Father, ain't you coming with us?
No, I think I'll walk home alone.
I wanna think about my sermon for Sunday.
Has to be an extra special
one for your parents.
Oh good.
On how to bring up children.
Oh Father, good luck to you!
Good luck Father!
Chuck.
Gennie.
Chuck, it's good to see you.
Well it's good to see you too.
Where were you going Gennie?
To work, and I'm late.
Come along.
What are you doing here?
This is the Metropolitan.
This is where I work!
Wait a minute, isn't that Carmen?
Huh?
What do you play?
One of the spectators at the bullfight?
Believe it or not, I'm Carmen.
Gennie Tuffle, Carmen?
Oh I've changed that.
It's Genevieve Linden.
I was singing Carmen in Rio and they
heard me and said would you sing it here.
Here, can you imagine?
Gennie Tuffle at the Metropolitan.
Imagine that.
Well Chuck, make yourself comfortable.
I have to be getting on.
Oh it's good to see you Chuck.
Come on Effie, I'm terribly late.
I don't know why I'm even talking to you!
No?
Why didn't you write?
I did write.
I know you did, but why did you stop?
Didn't I tell you?
No you didn't.
But you're going to.
Gennie.
Please, I want to ask
you just a small favor.
Hello Tommy, what is it?
Tonight, would you be so good as to
glance occasionally at my baton?
Tonight, let's not race, let's try
just for once to finish together huh?
All right Tommy, I promise.
And Tommy, do me a favor.
Meet Chuck O'Malley.
He's a very old friend of mine.
Chuck, Senor Tomaso Bozanni.
Father.
Chuck?
She always calls me that.
You haven't told me yet Chuck.
Why did you stop writing?
I did tell you in my last letter.
Which letter was that?
Guess that must've been
the letter you didn't get.
You wrote to me in Rome, in Florence.
Naples, Vienna, Budapest.
Then I went to Switzerland and I found
one of your letters
waiting for me in Luzzone.
Oh you should've been there, Chuck.
It was a week before Christmas.
There was a quaint little post office.
I walked up to it in the snow.
The moon was so bright that I read
your letter on the way home.
And I answered it that night.
But that letter in Luzzone
was the last one I got.
From there I went to South America.
There were no more letters.
What happened Chuck?
Chuck, what hap...
Father Chuck.
It'll take me a little
while to get used to that.
Where's your parish, Father?
I'm over here at St. Dominic's.
About 10 blocks from here.
Remember Timmy?
Tim O'Dowd?
Yes, of course I do.
He's at St. Francis
now, he's a priest too.
Dear ol' Timmy.
Can you imagine that?
Well I'll have to be running along.
Oh please, please don't go.
Tommy, he can stand in the wings can't he?
It would be a privilege.
Please.
You know, Tommy?
Father O'Malley was the first one
to tell me I could sing.
Maybe one day I'll
tell her the same thing.
If she listens to you
Father, maybe you could
persuade her to listen just once to me.
Watch the baton.
Good luck, Miss Tuffle.
You wanted to see me Father?
Yeah, yeah.
Mrs. Quimp here, good woman that she is,
has come here with a bit
of disturbing information.
I think it should more properly
be brought to your attention.
That's nice work Mrs. Quimp, what is it?
Suppose you tell Father
O'Malley in your own words.
You better tell him, Father.
Huh?
Well your little songbird who was
without funds, but not a
bit interested in general
housework, is fitting a
nest in her own manner.
And if Mrs. Quimp's observations
are correct, a very fine manor it is.
It seems, Father O'Malley, that the
young lady in question has an apartment
directly across the street.
Opposite Mrs. Quimp's bedroom.
And according to Mrs.
Quimp, young Ted Haines
comes early and stays so late that...
Mrs. Quimp is losing a lot of sleep.
It's queer isn't it, Father?
Young Haines was ready to throw me out
without so much as a how do you do.
But when it comes to this young "lady,"
and mark you, there are other words
I could call her, he acts quite different.
Don't you think it's strange?
That's a question.
People do funny things you know.
Father O'Malley.
It's as plain as the nose on your face.
The nose on whose father Father?
Well it doesn't matter
whose face it's on.
You and I have got to face it.
Excuse us.
This is very suspicious, Father O'Malley.
As you're more familiar with the case,
I think you should handle it.
I handle the little sins.
♪ All through a lifetime ♪
♪ I'll be loving you ♪
♪ And then on the ♪
♪ Day after forever ♪
♪ I'll just begin ♪
♪ Again ♪
Come in!
Hello Father.
Hello Carol.
Hi Father.
Hello.
I heard you.
That's more like it.
Thank you, Father.
Maybe it's because I'm putting
more meaning into the words.
Very nice here isn't it?
Very nice.
Now before you go any further Father...
You mean it's all in my mind?
That's right.
Yes, I'm sure Father is just
dying to hear more of the details.
Huh?
Yes.
Won't you sit down?
Mmmhm.
Well I was going down the street,
and minding my own business too,
when who do you think just happened by,
purely by accident of course,
and pulled up alongside of the curb?
Ted Haines Jr.
Right.
And what do you think his approach was?
You tell him.
I prefer not to remember.
Well being a woman, I do.
His exact words were "Hey
good looking, what's cooking?"
Aw now wait a minute.
What I really said was "Who
do you know that I know?"
You know that's worse?
Well...
Well that was that, and
with practically no more
of a buildup than that,
he asked me to lunch.
Who knows, it might have worked.
It's been known to.
So after I'd cooled him off I came
back here, no job, no money,
expecting to be thrown out any minute.
There was a knock on the door and I said
to myself the landlord, here it comes.
And who do you think was there?
Junior?
Right.
I was so surprised.
So was I.
Well up to here we're all surprised.
Naturally before throwing me out
he had to know a little about me.
So in a few well chosen
sentences I gave him the details.
Sorta like I told you.
And you found a landlord
with a heart of gold.
Well not exactly a heart of gold Father,
but well we had the apartment vacant
and it seemed a shame to throw her out.
Well anyway, what's wrong with that?
Nothing that I know of up to here.
Well as I was saying, it
was a shame to throw her out.
Like Mrs. Quimp?
Yeah.
No!
Well that's different.
I can see that obviously.
Look Father, she told me about coming
to see you and that
you wanted to help her.
You don't have a corner
on helping people do you?
And besides, I've practically
got her lined up in a job.
Yes, and soon as I get it
I'm going to pay him back.
Every nickel of it.
And you too, Father.
Don't worry about me.
Rather a nice looking piano you have here.
Well she needs one doesn't she?
She's gotta practice, she's a singer.
That's very thoughtful.
Course pianos are a little
expensive these days.
Well I asked her first
if she can play a ukulele.
Well then naturally.
Yeah, naturally.
Carol tells me you can play, Father.
How about trying this one out
and see if I got a good buy.
Yes, play something for us, Father.
Would you mind us asking
you a few questions, Father?
No.
Where'd you get that wicked left hand?
Well I've always been
interested in music.
Used to write a bit of it at school.
Had a little band, I used to
play for the school dances.
O'Malley's Orioles.
You know, at one time I had
quite a decision to make.
Whether to write the
nation's songs or go my way.
Any regrets, Father?
Regrets?
No.
I get a great happiness
out of helping people
realize that religion
doesn't have to be this.
Taking all the fun out of everything.
Can be bright.
Bring you closer to happiness.
You go to church Ted?
Well...
Would you rather I change the subject?
If I could just express
musically what I have
in my mind, it would
be much more eloquent.
Sound simpler than be remembered.
Sometimes the spoken
word can be pretty dull.
You mean sing your sermons, Father?
Yeah, sorta.
Have you ever
had anything published?
No, no.
Will you play us one
of your unpublished ones?
♪ This road leads to Rainbowville ♪
♪ Going my way ♪
♪ Up ahead is bluebird hill ♪
♪ Just pack a basket full of wishes ♪
♪ And off you start ♪
♪ With Sunday morning in your heart ♪
♪ 'Round the bend, you'll see a sign ♪
♪ Dreamer's highway ♪
♪ Happiness is down the line ♪
♪ Going my way ♪
♪ The smiles you gathered ♪
♪ Will look well ♪
♪ On you ♪
♪ Oh I hope you're ♪
♪ Going my way ♪
♪ Too ♪
Well I think I'll leave you on that.
Goodbye Carol.
Goodbye Ted.
Bye Father.
Nice thought.
Going my way.
Isn't it Ted?
He's quite a fella.
Good morning, Father.
I'd like to present Miss Genevieve Linden.
Gennie, this is Father Fitzgibbon.
Good morning, Father.
How do you do?
She's a singer.
Huh?
Ah.
Looking for work?
Oh no, no, Father.
She sings at the Metropolitan Opera House.
Well now, it's a great privilege
to meet you, Miss Linden.
You've come quite a ways in the world huh?
Well I...
Travel extensively?
Yes, quite a bit.
Ah, well where's your home?
Well I just bought
a home in Long Island.
Well, a nice home?
Very lovely.
In that care undoubtedly
you'd be interested
in a crazy quilt, we're raffling it off.
Again?
We're trying to raise a
little money, Father O'Dowd.
I see.
How many?
I'll take them all.
How much are they?
Be $10.
Thank you.
And I hope you win this one.
And I hope you win it too, Gennie.
Then perhaps you'll
donate it to our church.
And we can raffle it off
over there all over again.
Oh I'd hate to see that
crazy quilt leaving the parish.
Where's the Pied Piper
and his merry little men?
Down in the basement.
Thank you, Father.
Come Gennie.
Goodbye Father.
Goodbye, thank you.
Congratulations on
selling all your tickets.
Like some more?
Mmmhm.
You're our first audience you know.
Ready boys?
That's the best.
Course we have our more serious side.
Would you like to hear the
boys sing something nice?
Something with a little more beauty?
Yes, very much.
That was very well done boys.
That's all.
Thank you so much.
See you all tomorrow huh?
They're angels.
They've got something you
lose when you get older.
What's the matter Timmy?
Nothing, nothing.
That was beautiful, Chuck.
Beautiful.
Of course we don't get
Miss Genevieve Linden
of the Metropolitan down here every day.
Nor deems O'Dowd either.
Oh now wait a minute, wait a minute.
I'm glad to see you kept up
your interest in music, Father.
Are you writing anything anymore?
Oh yes.
I have a little song here now that
Timmy's gonna take to a publisher.
A very good friend of
his, and if he likes it
that might be the answer
to all our trouble.
I have bad news for ya.
I've been to the publisher, Chuck.
He wasn't interested.
Wouldn't even look at it.
Said they were loaded up.
May I see it?
So you're still in trouble.
Wouldn't even look at it huh?
Oh he glanced at it.
What'd he have to say?
"Schmaltz isn't selling this season."
Schmaltz?
And what are they buying?
Bafola.
No, I think they call it vafola.
Ah, vafola.
- Vafola.
Boy I heard some of their song hits.
It was Hut-Sut Time on the Rillerah.
And then there was another one,
I couldn't even understand the words.
This fella lost his
girl in Salt Lake City.
Then he goes on to say the
altitude is 5,400 feet.
Interesting.
The average temperature 73.
The section is noted for gold, silver,
copper grade, but that doesn't
make any difference to this fella
because he's lost his sugar.
Vafola.
Oh I know what vafola is.
It's...
What's the matter with that?
Not for me.
Can you imagine Beat Me Eight
to the Bar by Daddy O'Malley?
Oh no.
I like this.
She's buying schmaltz.
Going My Way.
Will you autograph it for me?
All right.
Thank you.
Well I have to go now.
Father Tim, can I drop you off?
You can, thank you.
There you are.
Thank you.
Goodbye.
My pen, Father.
Oh, oh yes.
Good day.
Oh.
Yes?
Uh-huh.
Mmmhm.
Well who are you?
I want to have a talk
with you, that's who I am.
Ooooh.
You must be his father.
How old are you?
I'm 18.
Well that's good.
Well.
Oh Ted!
Be right with you darling!
What?
Hello dad.
Where have you been
for the past two weeks?
Well dad.
I've been in a blue Heaven
dancing on a pink cloud.
She came in on a moonbeam.
That's a lie, I had you followed.
That wasn't cricket, dad.
When you were my age I
didn't follow you around.
Everything I say kills her.
It kills me too.
Do you realize this is
one of my apartments?
Oh yes, I had it redecorated.
And that's one of my robes.
Yes, I had it altered.
I'm going to like him.
Do you know I could have
you thrown out of town?
Maybe I know something
about her you don't know.
She was picked up on the
street by the police.
Oh I know that.
Maybe we know something
that you don't know.
We're married.
Married?
Oooh I'll have that annulled.
Uh-uh.
You can only get them annulled when
they aren't right in the first place.
Ours was right.
We said something about
'til death do us part.
Remember?
Where were you married?
St. Dominic's, Father O'Malley.
O'Malley?
A secret marriage eh?
Well he's put his foot in it this time.
It wasn't a secret marriage dad,
it was in all the papers.
I didn't see it.
Well you never get past
the financial column.
Don't be impertinent.
Young woman, do you know how
he's planning to support you?
You know he's quit his job.
That's all right.
I'll support him.
Sure, she's working.
You...
You'd live off your wife?
Well mother was a big
help to you wasn't she?
Until you got on your feet.
That was entirely different.
I made something of myself.
Yes dad, you certainly have.
Look son.
My boy.
Have you no family pride?
Uh-uh.
No shame?
Nope.
You certainly slipped, my boy.
You've lost everything.
I don't think so dad.
I think I found something.
Mmmhm.
Well darling, I guess
I'd better get dressed.
I think I'm a failure as a father.
I don't think so.
Darling!
Where's my hat?
I'll get it.
You'll have to forgive the way
we've been acting today, dad.
We were a little hysterical.
I guess we were both a little mad.
Well I'm mad too.
Quitting his job like that.
Running off and getting married.
I don't know, this younger generation
doesn't seem to have any sense.
So long, sweetie.
God bless you.
Goodbye dad.
That plane you gave me did the trick.
When they found out about
my 600 hours in the air
they said okay bud, we want you in.
Well.
Be nice to her dad.
She'll grow on you.
Goodbye boy.
Well.
He's gone.
Dad.
Look Max.
Max.
Max, you just have to do this for me
and I don't want any arguments about it.
I'm afraid we got all
the songs we need, Father.
Our catalog is full.
Oh now, now, now wait a minute.
I've been through a lot of trouble
to arrange this, so grab your hat,
and a taxi, and get right over here.
Yes now!
This very minute!
If you don't, I'll put
the Irish curse on you.
Goodbye Father.
That's Father O'Dowd, a friend of mine.
What did he want, a donation?
No.
Pal of his has got a song
and he's plugging it.
And what a plug.
He's grabbed off the Metropolitan
Opera House with the full orchestra
conducted by this fellow Tomaso...
Whatever his name is, the star
Genevieve Linden, and
a choir of 30 voices.
All this fuss to put over a
song written by a pal of his.
And they're waiting right
now for us at the Met.
At the Metropolitan?
Can you imagine such a thing?
♪ This road leads to Rainbowville ♪
♪ Going my way ♪
♪ Up ahead is bluebird hill ♪
♪ Just pack a basket full of wishes ♪
♪ And off you'll start ♪
♪ With Sunday morning in your heart ♪
♪ 'Round the bend, you'll see a sign ♪
♪ Dreamer's highway ♪
♪ Happiness is down the line ♪
♪ Going my way ♪
♪ The smiles you gathered will look well ♪
♪ On you ♪
♪ Oh I hope you're going my way ♪
♪ Too ♪
♪ 'Round the bend, you'll see a sign ♪
♪ Dreamer's highway ♪
♪ Happiness is down the line ♪
♪ Going my way ♪
♪ The smiles you gathered will look well ♪
♪ On you ♪
♪ Oh I hope ♪
♪ You're going my way ♪
♪ Too ♪
Well that's very good.
Wonderful.
You sang it great, Miss Linden.
Thank you.
That's a pretty good
song you got there, Father.
Thank you.
I guess you oughta know.
You bet he does.
They say he's the sharpest
little man in town.
Well now I'm embarrassed.
You mean to talk business?
The money?
Oh don't let that embarrass you.
We love it.
Well what I wanted to say is that
although it's great, it's just as
I told you, Father, it's too good for us.
It's way over our head.
You see, it's not just the type of song
that a guy would, pardon me Father,
that a gentleman would croon
to his babe, if you know what I mean.
It doesn't say enough,
it hasn't got that...
Well it's just not for me.
I think you oughta try it out on
someone who publishes higher class stuff.
Thanks.
Well I guess we better
get back to the office.
You know Father, I could be wrong.
I hope I am.
Goodbye.
Oh I'm sorry.
Well we tried.
You sang it beautifully, Gennie.
Boys, you did fine.
Not a single mistake.
Thank you, Father.
If that isn't good, I'll go
in the real estate business.
I was going to ask you and the boys
to sing a little more, but maybe
you don't feel like it now.
They sing divinely.
And they look like Botticelli's angels.
Maybe a little something huh?
What do you think
they'd like to hear boys?
The Mule.
Hmm?
The Mule?
Yeah.
That all right with you?
♪ Oh would you like to swing on a star ♪
♪ Carry moonbeams home in a jar ♪
♪ And eat better off than you are ♪
♪ Or would you rather be a mule ♪
♪ A mule is an animal
with long funny ears ♪
♪ Who kicks up at anything he hears ♪
♪ His back is brawny
and his brain is weak ♪
♪ He's just plain stupid
with a stubborn streak ♪
♪ And by the way, if you
hate to go to school ♪
♪ You may grow up to be a mule ♪
♪ Oh would you like to swing on a star ♪
♪ Carry moonbeams home in a jar ♪
♪ And be better off than you are ♪
♪ Or would you rather be a pig ♪
♪ A pig is an animal
with dirt on his face ♪
♪ His shoes are a terrible disgrace ♪
♪ He has no manners
when he eats his food ♪
♪ And he's fat and lazy
and extremely rude ♪
♪ But if you don't care
a feather or a fig ♪
♪ You may grow up to be a pig ♪
♪ Oh would you like to swing on a star ♪
♪ Carry moonbeams home in a jar ♪
♪ And be better off than you are ♪
♪ Or would you rather be a fish ♪
♪ A fish won't do anything
but swim in a brook ♪
♪ He can't write his name or read a book ♪
♪ To full the people is his only thought ♪
♪ Yeah, but even though he's
slippery, he still gets caught ♪
♪ But then if that sort
of life is what you wish ♪
♪ You may grow up to be a fish ♪
♪ And all the monkeys are in the zoo ♪
♪ Every day you meet quite a few ♪
♪ So you see, it's all up to you ♪
♪ You can be better than you are ♪
♪ You could be swinging on a star ♪
Was that your song, Father?
Yes.
Well we'll take a flyer on that.
Did you hear that Timmy?
Max!
You're a grand lad.
I knew your name wasn't
golden for nothing.
Fellas, if you'll come to St. Dominic's
tomorrow morning at 10:30...
Church?
Oh now Max, a day in church
isn't gonna hurt you that much.
Be there and bring the cash with you.
Father O'Malley will tell
you how he wants it paid.
An old man, very dear friend of
Father O'Malley's, is involved in this.
Father Fitzgibbon.
It would make Father
O'Malley very happy if you
fellas would, you know,
just do this his way.
Church.
As you know, I've
been here for 45 years.
46 in October.
And during that time, I've
always asked you to be generous.
Which you have.
And now I have to ask you again.
You all know how I feel
about St. Dominic's.
Well we're in dire financial straits.
So give what you can.
And I know, I know that whatever
you give, whether it's large or small,
the good Lord will bless you for it.
In the name of the Father,
Son, the Holy Ghost.
Amen.
Gratifying.
Very gratifying.
And the bishop thought I couldn't preach.
Thought I had a mouthful of clover.
I wish he'd been here.
Father, now that you're practically
wallowing in wealth, you suppose
I could have a half a dollar?
What for, what for?
Well Father O'Dowd
and I thought, with your
permission, we'd play
a little golf tomorrow.
I need a new gold ball.
If I lose it I'll swear off, I'll quit.
Take 50 cents.
No no no, take it out of the.
They never keep any books.
Suppose I could buy
Father O'Dowd one too?
Must we?
I can get two nice
repaints for 50 cents.
Give him 50 cents.
You oughta come along with us, Father.
You don't have to play.
Just go around.
The fresh air will do you good.
You can be our.
Your what?
What's...
Sorta an over the shoulder quarterback.
Will you come?
Well a little fresh
air might do me good.
We'll get a ball for you too.
Of course.
Plenty
mushrooms around here.
Well now where did that go?
Right there.
Now let me understand.
If you get the ball in the hole
in this hit, then Father O'Dowd...
I win.
So you've gotta count
the number of blows.
That's right Father.
Step aside, he's gonna play now.
Careful.
How many did you have?
Three huh?
How many?
Well that's remarkable.
Remarkable.
Can you do that every time?
Oh I've been known to miss, Father.
A strong crosswind or something.
Here, give me a hold of that.
You wanna try it?
Yeah.
Better throw a ball in there for you.
There you are.
Keep your head down now, Father.
Watch your language.
Father, you holed out!
Not bad for a beginner huh?
Oh you've played before.
Oh no no, believe me, that's the
first time I ever had a caddy in me hand.
Well you better play
in our watch then huh?
Well I guess I better be going.
Let that be a lesson to you, Father.
Don't trust anyone.
What an extraordinary person.
Isn't he?
Well I'll sleep well tonight anyway.
It must be that golf.
you know, I
feel 10 years younger.
You know I was thinking Father,
now that everything is going so right,
before something goes wrong,
you oughta take a little time off.
To do what for instance?
Well like for instance take
a trip home and see your mother.
Interest is all paid up to date.
If something goes wrong, I have plans
that'll take care of the next payment.
You really think it would be all right?
I mean it would yeah?
Father Fitzgibbon,
Chuck, the church is afire!
Don't worry, Father.
We'll build again.
Can I help you Father?
No, it's all right, I can manage.
This is for the birds.
They're used to coming here.
I don't want them to go away.
No.
Oh you see Father?
They're not leaving.
Nobody's leaving here.
And when your church is
rebuilt, they'll all be back.
Everyone will be back.
In the meantime you can send
your congregation over to my parish.
I'll split the collection with you 50/50.
Take it, Father.
What makes you all so hopeful
that the church will ever be rebuilt?
Here, you're supposed to take this.
No, no I cannot.
Come on, please Father, take it.
I tell you what, if you'll
take it I'll take some too.
There, now that wasn't so bad.
Don't you try it.
Doctors, medicine, feh.
What I need is to be up and about.
Being up and about
is what's got you down,
tramping all over the parish trying
to raise funds, and how
much did you collect?
There's no need for you to rub it in.
$35.85.
Yeah.
How much is the doctor's bill?
40.
Says here to take two now, we wanna
get our money's worth, here.
Now listen, there's nothing in that
bottle that's going to do me any good.
Oh Father, now you're not
gonna lose hope are you?
Hope?
You know Chuck, when
you're young it's easy
to keep the fires of hope burning bright.
But at my age you're lucky if
the pilot light doesn't go out.
I know, Father.
45 years of your efforts in ashes.
Here, take this.
That'll keep the pilot light burning.
Yes, it ought to.
Tastes like it had kerosene in it.
Well did you make your parish calls?
Oh yes.
Mrs. McGonagall's rheumatism
is kicking up again.
I told her to bury a
potato out in the backyard.
That's for warts.
That's what she said.
And I heard Mrs. Quimp's new gossip.
Oh what else?
And then I went to see
Carol and Mr. Haines.
Oh, did they hear from young Ted?
Young Ted has been wounded in Africa.
Ah, too bad.
They're shipping him home.
Find upstanding young fella.
Maybe they'll decorate him.
No, I doubt it.
Some friend of his ran over him in a jeep.
But I got some good news.
I have a letter from Miss Linden.
Miss Linden, well now, that's very nice.
Where is she?
She's in St. Louis.
And here it comes Father, I gave you
that medicine to quiet your nerves.
Tony and the boys are with her.
They're on a concert tour.
They're on a what?
Now I had their parents' consent
and they'll be back in time for school.
But you...
Besides, travel's a great education.
If they make enough money it's
gonna build you a new church.
Not much of one maybe, but
something to go on with.
Miss Linden sent you a check.
With her love.
$3,500.
How's the pilot light burning now?
It's burning brighter, Chuck.
It's a long road back,
but we've started huh?
You know, I have a feeling
the dawn may rise again.
Sure it'll rise again.
You know, I think I'll get up meself.
No no, now you better stay
there and get some rest.
Rest, you're well, but not that good.
You don't feel near that good.
Hey now boys, boys, boys!
Go on, go on home, go
on away with you now,
your dinner's ready, go on go on go on.
Bye Father.
Goodnight.
Fine girl, Miss Linden.
Very thoughtful, very generous.
Close this up, keep the sawdust out hmm?
That will lend beauty to the dedication.
And at Christmas you and
the choir will be able to...
Father, I won't be here at Christmas.
Huh?
Well I was with the
bishop this afternoon.
He's transferring me to another parish.
You're leaving me.
Well now it never occurred
to me that someday you might.
But me boy, what am I
going to do without you?
You didn't ask to?
Oh no Father, as a matter of fact
I asked to stay with you, but the bishop
asked me to help him out and I...
St. Dominic's, what's going to happen?
Well you'll be all right, Father.
I wish you could've heard some of
the things the bishop said about you.
Would've done you good.
Says you're looking 10 years younger.
He has all the confidence
in the world in you.
And don't worry, you'll
have a new assistant
Well now I want you
wish you all the success
in the world, which I know you'll have.
Is it a perish of your own?
Well no, not exactly Father,
you see this church, St. Charles,
well the pastor's getting along
in years and things aren't...
You mean they're in trouble.
Yes, and I'm supposed to go
in there and try and help...
You mean without both of their knowing.
Uh-huh.
Well now that's a difficult assignment.
But it'll work out.
You may have trouble with
the old man at first.
He may be running off to the
bishop every few minutes.
But don't let that bother you.
You'll bring him around
to your way of thinking.
Well there's dinner.
You'll know how to manage
these old fuss buckets.
Take them out in the golf course.
Bring them out in the fresh air.
Yeah.
We'll get along just so he...
Knows enough to come in out of the rain.
That's it.
That's it Father, that's it exactly.
Come in, Tony.
Hi Father.
So you're really leaving us huh?
Yes, I've got my orders Tony.
I guess when the bishop says
you gotta go, you gotta go.
That ain't hay huh?
That's right Tony.
You know, sometimes I
think I don't like bishops.
Well Tony, bishops are like umpires.
You have to have them to
call the close decisions.
Really?
Say, I got a little
Christmas present here for you.
I want you to take my
place with the choir.
From now on, you're in charge.
That's swell of you, Father.
It's a great present.
I always had my eye on it.
I thought you did.
Say, when you gonna give
Father Fitzgibbon his surprise?
Shhh, not so loud.
Later on in the church.
Those boys haven't told anyone?
Not a word Father, not a word,
and if they did I'd kick, er,
I mean I'd be disappointed in them.
Well I guess I'll get going, Father.
I know there's a lot on your mind,
you wanted to tell me about taking
your place with the gang and everything.
But I'll make it easy for you.
I'll be everything you want me to be.
Just as if you were
here checking up on me.
And if you don't, I'm gonna
drop you like you was a hot potato.
Okay Father, it's a deal.
Good luck to you.
So long, Father.
So long.
Pretty near Christmas.
Yeah.
I'm sure that the way to say what I'd like
to say will occur to me after you've gone.
We're separated by many
years, Father O'Malley.
Which could be the reason why we haven't
seen eye to eye in many instances.
But though we've had many differences,
we never differed in fundamentals.
It was only in method.
But never in our hearts.
Good stuff huh?
Oh yes.
Bye Ted.
Bye Father.
Bye Carol.
Right man did come along.
Yes, but not past our house.
Stubborn huh?
Goodbye, Mr. Haines.
Father.
Pardon me, Mr. Haines.
I've just left the bishop.
He told me to report to Father Fitzgibbon.
I'm taking your place.
I'm the new curate.
Come on, come on,
you've very little time.
They're waiting in the
church to say goodbye.
All right Father, I've been
doing you a lot of good here.
You're gonna have a new
church after the war.
Yes, but we didn't raise enough money.
That's just it.
Mr. Haines is gonna give us a mortgage.
Take care of the difference.
That's right, Father.
He convinced me I have a heart.
And after all, it wouldn't be
a church without a mortgage.
That's right, that's right.
He's a wonder.
I don't know what I'm
going to do without him.
I don't know who the bishop is going
to send in his place, but whoever he is...
Father.
Right behind
you, Father O'Dowd.
Congratulations to you, Father.
The bishop wouldn't do that to me again.
Yes he's done it.
Mr. Haines.
Nice of you to give that
mortgage to the church.
Oh not a problem.
Can't tell you how
much we appreciate it.
As you know, we're all
going to miss Father O'Malley.
He was a fine man.
This is Father O'Malley.
The man who sent for you.
How do you do, Mrs. Fitzgibbon?
I've heard so much about you.
Now it's good to see you.
I think you'll agree with me that we're
all a little better for having known him.
He was always thinking of others.
And that, you know, can
make life very beautiful.
Believe me, it's what
we do for others that...
♪ Too-ra-loo-ra-loo-ral ♪
♪ Too-ra-loo-ra-li ♪
♪ Hush now, don't you cry ♪
♪ Too-ra-loo-ra-loo-ral ♪
♪ Too-ra-loo-ra-li ♪
♪ That's an Irish lullaby ♪
♪ Too-ra-loo-ra-loo-ral ♪
♪ Too-ra-loo-ra-li ♪
♪ Hush now, don't you cry ♪
♪ Too-ra-loo-ra-loo-ral ♪
♪ Too-ra-loo-ra-li ♪
♪ That's an Irish lullaby ♪
Watch Movies, TV Series & Live Sports
www.admitme.app