In the previous section contents:
- Already in the new waitress arrived? - Julio Espinosa, has just arrived.
- What the hell are you doing? - Finding my sister.
My sister is not left on their own feet. I think something happened to him.
Something happened that night and threaten to figure out.
Jimena was with you last time.
- What happened to him? - They were found dead this morning. They were stabbed.
I guess you're the detective ...
Detective Ayala, the Supervisory Body.
It appears this fiercely ... made of gold.
The only places where gold can knife.
Alicia's mother asked from her hand.
I could not right hands of my daughter's life. And the family business.
Anyone else in the family, my mother.
I will not let anyone come Vergara Markijan set aside.
You want to be a manager?
You get used to it, and be hard to take anything for victory.
I wish you would say a toast. Wedding.
Alicia Señorita another world, Julio. Beat in as much that will help you
find out what happened to your sister, and do not think about it any more.
I can not.
What are you doing here?
Are you afraid that your fiancee gets to know the real face?
- Can you feel? - The child already extends with.
I know that the child is not from me, but no one would like the way I'm going.
- Is there a problem? - One of the maid, Belénnel.
- What happened to him? - Pregnant.
What is it?
I will not let you ruin this kid put it in my life, you hear?
You need your help to stop Ángel. If not, we both fail.
Don Diego, as the hotel manager, believes you could use a helping hand.
You made a mistake, Belén.
Now that my vicinity or, in real life a living hell can I change.
Yesterday, when I weighed the helper himself, I noticed the tattoo on his arm.
This is typical of the prison.
- It was a minor theft. - You do not have to explain.
I know what you did and who you are, Julio Espinosa.
Or I should call him ... Julio Olmedónak?
I do not know whether you know my daughter, Eugenia.
And what can you do to this end?
Eugenia, my dear ...
We do not have to get married if you do not want.
But I want to Javier.
My dear sister, Mercedes. Javier Alarcón, the groom.
Why was not you? Why do not you recognize you before?
Eugenia, no! Put it down, please.
Do not move!
The availability of translator: oseynara@gmail.com
Lektorálta: Witch
Watch Movies, TV Series & Live Sports
www.admitme.app
GRAN HOTEL Part 5: Blood Red Moon
- Calm down! We can fix! - There's nothing to fix.
Eugenia! If you really love me, put the gun down.
And you say nothing?
No, please, Eugenia.
- It was not his fault, it's mine. - Do not come near!
Eugenia. Eugenia, listen to me. That does not mean anything. I love you.
- You're lying. - No, Eugenia.
- I love you. - You're lying.
No no. Only I truly love.
Eugenia, please.
I love you.
Javier! Javier! Javier!
- Kérlek! Javier! Ne! Javier! - Megõrültél, Eugenia? Megõrültél?
There are matters of honor, which are to be solved by man-to-man.
I've come to ask her to give it over to his son.
Please, General, I want to do is barbaric.
It would not solve anything.
And you know as well as I do, that the law prohibits the duel.
The son of disgraced both my daughter.
The desecration ... a little overkill, do not you think?
Nobody wants to know if you do not stick to a stupid duel.
Be discreet.
And the daughters of honor will remain intact.
You're wrong, Doña Teresa.
It will only be intact if you do something for the restoration.
He hands me his son or myself have to do?
You will not believe my mother, but almost Eugenia Lelo ...
- What are you doing, mom? - I will save your life.
Sleep with a soldier, both daughters. How can you be so stupid?
If he did not kill Eugenia and her father do.
I travel to. Within a few months only hang-up about it.
You do not care about your family's honor?
Your father is rotating in his grave.
Because of me or because of you, my mother?
You stay here. And fulfill spousal duties.
I think rather get married than to die.
I do not take away a woman who nailed a gun at me.
On this we agree. The girl is not in his right mind. The sister, Mercedes lost.
You can not be serious.
If you doubt, you do not know me. In AGREED with his father.
And do not be wanting for lunch. Because announcing your engagement.
Doña Teresa, arriving at the hotel, who was waiting for.
Try another galibába not get involved in the next hours,
if it is not too much to ask.
No one can take forth, while I can not say.
Especially not a general Herrera and her daughters.
Igen, Dona Teresa.
Mateo saw the general's gun was in the safe.
Are you sure you don Javier has made trouble again.
Fat takes longer, but the other one.
He found them in bed together.
The sister of the võlegényével, think about it.
Don Javierrõl not hard to imagine.
Perhaps the walls do not have ears, but I did.
If you ever hear such rumors and comments,
Doña Teresa is going to know about it.
Do they understand?
Igen, Don Benjamin.
Cernuda. Espinosa did not see?
This dish should be had to the 15 room.
I think even the breakfast is taking off, but do not worry, I'll take.
And do not forget that must be prepared for lunch.
The main events will be, and no one is missing.
Yes, sir.
Sit down.
Lift up your sleeves.
I suppose you know that on arrest
All the accused are recorded anthropometric data.
What are you talking about?
- They do not measure it? Height, arm. - But, but, but.
And they were bathing.
These measurements, which were removed, the anthropometric measurements.
One way of identifying convicts. They took me down too.
When I saw the rough tattoo idea that was in prison,
so I sent all the dimensions of the authority.
And as I expected, I received answers to arrest authority.
Julio did not match any of the data Espinosával.
But Julio agreed to a certain Olmedóval.
Who has been convicted of a minor robbery.
- And if they were the wrong size? - One size may be incorrect. The logic is not.
The last name Olmedo, reminded me of Cristina Olmedo. The maid was gone.
And it explained to you the constant presence of my investigations locations.
Or you're wrong?
In my business of silence means yes.
I sat down in the penalty and released.
Señor ... Olmedo clamps are the hands? No.
This means that I would not arrest him.
I just want you to tell me why you're here.
Someone killed my sister.
And I will know it.
Whether you like it or not.
Imagine ...
please.
The same questions we are looking for answers.
And since you are an employee of the hotel, perhaps others knew what I did not.
So please, tell me everything you found out.
Pascual ...
The receptionist, who was gunned down Murquía Don Diego.
Igen. Megzsarolta don Diegót.
- The murder of her sister? - No, I do not think so.
Before he died, he said that Don Diego did not kill my sister.
So he is blackmailing something else.
- Do you think that Pascual had killed her sister? - I do not.
They were engaged. And she loved him.
This is a common motive bûntényeknél.
But go on. What else can you Pascualról?
She gathered her belongings and took her sister's house.
There, we could not find anything.
- You are wearing them? - I do not.
They knocked down and taken away from me.
What has brought to the nõvérérõl?
The murder ...
Lake of the garden.
The body of the disappeared.
Until now.
What do you mean?
Mr. Olmedo.
I'm sorry to have to tell you this, but ...
a young woman's body was found in the woods. At least two months dead.
And I think that one is ...
his own sister.
I thought about the dates of the wedding.
Barely a month ago, we engaged.
But things are starting to go well.
And I think that would be a perfect day on November 4.
Feast of St. Charles. So your father could somehow present. What do you think?
Dear idea Diego.
But by then it is not already too Sofía delivery, and it would be awkward for him.
Maybe you should look for another visit, is not it?
What do you think of the beginning of March it?
The sisters will be by then a mother.
Of course.
When we announce lunch.
Don Bernardo! We have not been already used.
It's that seized the hotels that ours have not visited?
Unfortunately, all my time. But I could not refuse the invitation to the hunt.
Tell me the truth, my father. I insisted to come.
Ignacio! The last time I saw you, did you get any of the knobs.
You are just as beautiful and charming as it always has been.
They will not regret coming.
And I organized a banquet in your honor.
Ignacio?
- Alicia! - Ignacio!
Look at you! Beautiful woman've become!
Don Diego Murquía.
Welcome to you. I am the director of the hotel. And the groom.
The current fiancé, you understand.
Alicia was my fiancee.
- How long are we? Six-year-olds? - Seven.
- Seven. - Low In our time we were good friends.
And we loved to play together.
We could continue the conversation with a tea?
Interference?
Why bother?
See you later.
Diego humiliated you in front of everyone.
Before my mother.
I do not understand how can you be so calm.
We must be patient, and I do like him.
Wait for mistakes and to take advantage of it.
Wait?
Ez a whole?
Good plan for aging. But the hotel management of the acquisition are not.
You know Diego is the way I am. Are you sure that more and more messy transaction.
These things leave their mark.
- We have to go into his study. - Do not be naive, Sofía.
Do you really think that Diego is compromising anything there?
Everyone nose before?
If you would eldugnia before thee, leave it in the middle of the foreground kellõs.
If you want to hide something important, I would use the hotel vault.
We know where preserves the key?
Sofía, I will not scan Diego's room.
- You're a coward. - I do not. I am careful.
The server must be careful and have the room for girls.
You or Marquis.
That's why I'm not going to walk the halls like a common thief.
Forget Diego.
It may be that he was the manager, but we will soon be our brand.
And our child is born.
It is no longer just a job, Alfredo.
Diego humiliated you in front of my family, and it can not stay like this.
Why are not these kivasalva tablecloths?
New, so I think you do not have to iron them.
Who gave you this?
- I'm your assistant. - Belén. The decisions are mine to make.
It is your responsibility to elvégeztesd them.
As early as the first day you're making mistakes.
It was impossible to kill them in time.
A good housekeeper is able to do the impossible.
Take them and learn from his lesson.
Or another, more suitable helper to look for, and it would not take long.
Köszönöm, Dona Angela.
I will not forget these lessons when you replaced the honeycombs. Once.
That should take place within 5 months.
No frowned upon, if you are breast-feeding a housekeeper leave her job.
Angela.
Someone needs replacement, bed linen Senor Murquía room.
Azonnal, Miss Sophia.
Belén, go.
And if you are ready, the table cloths are ironed out.
What are you waiting for? Open up.
- Once you're done, clean up the room. - Yes, ma'am.
- Are you done? - No, ma'am.
You can do your job.
We found him in the river. Already overgrown with weeds.
At least two months dead.
It will be very unpleasant sight.
Are you sure you're ready?
Again.
Please.
I'm sorry.
It is not.
He had dark hair.
And it was not so stout.
It did not Cristina, that's for sure.
- Senor Olmedo, a lot of time has passed. - I do not know who it is, but not my sister.
Hernando, please.
Check the archive if there are such, that seemed to be
Young girl in recent months.
If it's not your sister, the situation is complicated, Senor Olmedo.
So far, only Jimena, the girl's body was found in the street, maybe he remembers.
And we assume that your sister died.
I have not two woman.
But from three.
Here, the best coffee I could find. Awful. It's not like the hotel.
I'm not used to their server.
To this girl died?
They were stabbed.
A scar is the same as the murdered prostitutes.
Do you think that your sister is so dead?
The judging from his clothes found bloodstains, very likely.
- Do you know who this woman? - No, no, no, sir.
- Nobody disappeared? - On the contrary. Several people also.
During the past four months it disappeared Cantaloából and környékérõl.
A street girl Jimena. August 24th
A maid Cristina Olmedo. July 25th
A peasant girl Dorotea Prieto. June 25th
The description corresponds to the miserable,
who lies in our makeshift ravatalozónkban. But proceed.
A sewing girl Adela Gómez. May 27th
Another peasant girl Irene Castaño. April 27th
And a beggar, whom he called 'Swallow'
and whose disappearance is the most difficult to define. It was in March.
All they killed during the night or disappeared Cantaloából.
- And it was all young. - Do you think that one person did it?
The opposite would be strange coincidence.
Olmedo Señor, I am afraid that his sister was a victim of obsessive compulsive,
that psychiatry 'lack of moral health as' recognized
and who commit ritual murders.
I soon learned that this Jimena stabbed with a knife,
Dorotea and that wound was perfectly match it.
I fear that the other woman also died the same way.
But let's see the dates.
Roughly one victim a month.
Or a month.
I do not know much about the moral similar things.
But I come from peasant families.
Sowing and harvesting, and the moon align.
It is possible.
Perhaps the art dates from the moon are aligned. It would not be the first case.
Jimena day after the arrival of the hotel was killed. And there was a full moon. I remember.
And when will the next?
But ...
Do you think he's going to kill again?
Yes. But it will be a problem.
We have the weapons.
It is a pity that our families were so far away from each other so much time.
The years spent here were really happy ....
We were children. The kids are always happy.
Yes. And I thought it was all still remain,
and the game becomes a reality, remember?
- Ignacio, I'm the bride. - I know I know.
And what you want?
Yes. So the best for me and my family.
Would I believe if you had answered yes.
Because if you really love someone, there is no need for arguments.
Ignacio, if you'll excuse me for a moment.
- I'll start with lunch. - Just be a minute.
July!
I was worried.
Ayalával Why did you leave?
He realized who I was.
How did you know it?
I do not know, but it does not matter.
He realized he was looking for the same thing. How many things have happened.
He unearthed another dead woman.
And he believes the killer will try again today.
He thinks the same way. Gold is one of the knife.
The detective and his men to watch all the exits.
I do not have to verify that no knife is missing or not.
And why is not he doing it?
According to Ayala mother she did not really want to help him.
It is open.
That can not be.
July, my ez to ruha rajtad? Miss Alarcon.
Andrés, do not know where the gold dinnerware?
In the dining room. Don Bernardo Alonso honor for lunch.
And do Benjamín up there waiting for us. So get dressed and come up as soon as possible.
Anyone can take it away with a golden knife.
- This complicates the situation. - What situation?
Andrés, you have to help us.
The lunch will be four tables.
Each of them will have a golden knife dinner services.
Which one for you, Andres? Andres?
- Is something wrong, Andrés? - No, no, Señorita Alarcón.
If there is the entrance, it's mine.
Fõasztalnál I will be with my family.
- It will be mine. - He will sit in the general's daughters.
Barreda's table and left without a Biro felügylet. With what?
Investigation ... what are you doing here?
Do not worry, Doña Teresa. I'm not here as an investigator.
Even a man like me, you need to relax.
This is understandable. But as I recall, we were not invited to this lunch.
Barreda referee was kind to invite me to his table.
And stop you to try the legendary cuisine, it would be a sin.
Mr. Ayala,
I do not want you to think, to feel any resentment towards you.
Due to my work I'm so used to such treatment,
I would feel strange if my presence does not bother anyone.
Well, I'm sorry, but I need to feel the ill effects corpse to you.
And I hope you do not mind having Barreda.
But it would be an honor to know you at your table.
And I accept it.
- Senor Murquía. - I'm busy.
I can not think about that Doña Sofía opened its me your room.
And you did it?
What could I do?
Doña Teresa's daughter ... and said I need to peel off your bedding, but ...
- It was not the reason. - And what were you doing in my room?
I do not know. But körbeszaglászott everywhere.
Why did you tell me?
They had problems with Diego, but I want you to know that I'm on your side.
I'm glad to hear that.
With kerestetek?
- I do not know what you mean. - You were in my room, right?
- You can play the fool on, Sofía ... - Diego, do not ...
Do not you dare!
What were you doing, Sofía?
I know that you did not find anything, because I'm not hiding anything.
Does not occur anymore, understand?
I told you.
Look at what happened.
What happened to Alfredo?
Diego raised his voice slightly.
Or a boy, or a grown-up man?
Diego knows what you did. And did not you do anything with it.
We are worse off than before.
It is impossible to be self-realized.
An ally told him.
There is a maid who can not afford to lose sight Belén.
Doña Angela segédje.
Can you come in?
Ángela, please.
I guess you know why called you.
Sir, while you are a guest in the hotel, whatever you want, I'm available.
The perfect answer to the perfect házvezetõnõtõl.
Angela, megduplázom to fizetésedet has átjössz to madridi hotelembe.
What do you say?
My place is here.
A talented housekeeper essential for proper functioning of any hotel.
Don Bernardo, ha megbocsátja
merészségemet...
Sure.
Perhaps from acquiring a good housekeeper.
I'm listening.
A segítõm. Bethlehem Martin.
It has végeztek Enrique szobájával, tisztítsátok ki szõnyegeket.
- Bethlehem Martin? - Igen?
You are the helper housekeeper, right?
- Yes. Did something happen? - I do not.
But do you know the people looking into my hotel in Madrid.
Here is a good job and a good salary. And my quarters.
Maid is no longer needed. Just a housekeeper.
Would you like your housekeeper would I be?
A luxury hotel. Almost like it.
You would have your own room, and earn twice as much.
Here you go some allowance I do not think that you can provide.
But in my hotel should not jump whim of others.
I spend a little time there, near the affairs of my employees trust.
It would be superior, and the decisions could bring to your liking.
I do not know whether the bonus is comparable with those you mentioned,
but I assure you that my hotel were to live better and more relaxed.
Sorry I'm late.
You look beautiful.
Thank you.
Are we going? My mother is already waiting for us sure.
We have a problem.
General Herrera's table to sit to calm him;
and supervise your brother. I would appreciate if you sit next to me.
A menyasszonyomként.
I do not think that would be wrong. To us another table as a family.
The etiquette permits, Alicia.
I want to sit with my family, Diego.
Of course.
Espinosa. Why was delayed so much?
One of the guests poured my shoes and went to clean up, sir.
Try. The others have been working for quite some time.
I do not see what you are looking for Ayala Alarcón table.
Who will supervise so Barreda judge's table?
What do you think? Let Exchangeable table. If Lady recognizable, you're done.
I do not know how you do it, but you're still having problems become my gondjaimmá.
Espinosa, why Cernudával changed?
I do not know. He asked.
- Cernuda? - Igen.
Why Espinosával changed?
Well ... you know how generous the Lady borravalóval.
And I wanted to buy presents for my mom. The birthday.
What will be five months from now?
Very expensive gift.
Well okay. Espinosának thank the favor.
Alicia. Alicia?
My father asked me a question.
Sorry.
I asked how many server must serve so many tables?
As you need.
Serving one more, one less dissatisfied guests - as my father said.
Barreda judge. Sorry but you can not make it.
Ayala, I hope you did not miss by much.
Such a glamorous woman in the company of a man would miss indecency.
How gallant. And what about the number of waiters? Considers it enough?
I assure you that if the number of security forces
It would be as big as your hotel, and directed them as well,
They liquidated within a week of the crime kingdom.
You really generous.
It is a pity that the waiters are not good investigators.
A waitress, a good waiter, and always pay attention to every detail
It goes one step further. Both also feature a good detective.
My father always wanted the best of the hotel.
Therefore so happy when I married Alfredóhoz.
The correct position can provide fame to the hotel.
The mere presence of your husband's reputation for providing it. True, my dear?
I'm flattered that you think so, Doña Teresa.
But our son will Alarcón Vergara and The Count, who unites the two families.
Brother worried about the delay.
While it does not arrive, not to announce her engagement.
You know how Javier.
That's why I'm worried.
Tell your partner,
You must be within two cuts of the knife perfectly clean.
Yes, sir.
If carried out with the meat, leaving the blade in the system tray.
It will be easier to keep an eye on them.
For now, all is well.
The knife must not be from here on out.
July July mehetsz the nem.
Espinosa, why did you take his place?
Sorry, Benjamín do. Someone brought this knife from the tray and looked.
One such piece is not to kallódhat.
Place back in the dining room.
Can we expect the presence of the hunt, Don Diego?
Sure. Even though I was seated next to the secretary of the minister of defense.
I am grateful for it.
You do not know how much longer I want to use my gun.
My dear, if you do not like it, let me know. The kitchen prepare anything for you.
Last year, I do not know how they did it, but it brought me strawberries in mid-January!
My appetite.
- I do not want this engagement. - Yeah.
- Because you did not do anything, right? - Eugenia behave.
- They took me to my fiancée, because of you! - Daughter! Daughter!
- You leave this to my father! - Eugenia, come back!
Javier.
Please. I can supply.
We could start again.
You know I love you.
I think a little late.
Instead of such an entry you would be allowed to stay in your room as well.
I'm notification of new engagements, mother.
Well, we drink to this!
As you ideállítottál,
not to announce her engagement, but it's still getting married.
Put down the glass.
Go to the bride's table, they wear you out.
In such a state, I do not think we get the point.
And I do not want to marry this woman.
And none of the others did not, he rámerõszakol you, mother.
I remind the generals can kill you. I will leave you with nothing.
The decision is up to you.
- I hope you enjoyed your lunch. - Very well.
Although not as much as your company, Doña Teresa.
I'm beginning to understand why choose this place is so relaxing.
Let's be honest, Detective. It really was just to relax?
It's hard to believe that your research megpihennének eyes for a moment.
As I see your eyes no rest ever, Doña Teresa.
In alike.
Good afternoon.
- Nyomozó. - Miss Alarcon ...
You are amazing.
When Julio said that two people in this hotel, in whom blindly
trust, I did not think that you are one of them.
Not too familiar,
that a lady as you cultivate a friendship with someone like Senor ...
Espinosa.
I know all the employees of the hotel.
And I like to get along well with them.
I did not say it because serving ...
but because of the criminal elõélete.
I knew as soon as I saw the tattoo on his arm.
Then they helped me to find out that he Cristina Olmedo's younger brother.
The knives are in place.
- We'll take turns guarding. - Thank you very much.
My people will pay attention to the two gates: the main entrance and the staff.
If you need me, I'll be outside.
We must stand ready for this evening.
What does the tattoo on your arm?
- Just a nonsense. What does it matter ... - Where did it?
What does it matter?
- In my village, Blancaróban ... - First titkolózol, now you're lying.
Ayala told me everything. I know you were in prison.
- Alicia, I can explain ... - Of course. But I do not want to hear it.
Alicia!
- Is there a problem, Señorita Alarcón? - No, no.
- Put away the last one, Espinosa. - Yes, Benjamín do.
- Everything went well. It's over, is not it? - Not yet. Shall be supervised in the cabinet.
- Me? - Something is not checked.
Ayala will speak to you.
As soon as possible leváltalak.
You monitors the main entrance.
Motozzon everyone whose appearance or behavior of the suspect.
Hernando, you have the rear. I will help if need be.
Yes, sir.
- I see what you bring in? - Yes, sir.
You can go.
"I look forward to the festival of light. When the power is inaugurated.
From then on everything will be easier for me.
You can not imagine how hard it
megtiszítani the candlesticks around the dripping wax.
Always everything must be unimpeachable. Perfect.
As if it were new.
But this is only the appearance, Julio.
As in humans.
We must always smile and flawless be.
And because of this, which is in fact, hurt even more.
Here, everyone is hiding something, and nothing is as it seems.
Therefore, I want you to see. "
July!
Don Benjamín ask whether the waste is exported.
Tell him you did.
I have given orders to clean up the first-floor carpets.
You can now polish out of the bathrooms have copper.
I am your helper. That's not my job.
But I trusted you.
- Don Bernardo spoke to me. - You will polish the brass?
Work recommended the hotel. Házvezetõnõit.
And paying a lot more than yours.
- If you go with me, I will just win. - I am very happy, ma'am.
Because I said yes.
You do not have to endure any more of your excesses.
From now on they will obey.
And my son to accept?
A fia?
Andrew?
Speaking ...
What happened with you?
The bad news is difficult to tell. So I'll be straight.
I'll leave.
Why?
- If, due to my mother ... - No, that's not it.
I was offered a job in another hotel.
- Don Bernardo volt?
- Igen.
You will pay more and housekeeper.
I do not know. I could go with you. You did not ask whether there is a waitress?
Your mother needs you. But he would not leave the hotel.
- But I love you. - I love you too.
But this is no longer the future.
Your place is here, not mine. I'm so sorry.
Ne, Bethlehem!
- Do not do it even more difficult! - No, you make it even more difficult!
Women always túlbonyolítanak everything!
Miss. Hey, Miss. Miss.
What happened? They stabbed?
No. Leeshetett.
Quick! Call me a doctor!
Miss. Hey. Breathe. Breathe.
Miss, come on.
- You listen. The details. - Investigation.
Something happened to the rear gate.
Stay here.
How's the woman who lost?
They are taken to the room. The doctor will perform immediately.
How many of you went out so that it does not researched into them?
I do not know. Four or five.
- They went to the village. - For God's sake, Hernando!
The étkezõszekrény!
Andrew! Andrew!
Are you okay?
They forced open.
And a missing knife.
What is it, young man?
I do not know. I am sitting in here and all of a sudden I heard a noise and then a mighty blow,
and I do not remember anything else.
Gentlemen, you already have the killer weapon.
And it may be headed toward the village.
The doctor has not lost hope. You do not lose it, Eugenia.
Your sister needs your prayers more than your tears.
I was mad at her father.
But I know that what happened does not matter.
How are you?
Do not move! Stay calm, son.
A jég, Dona Angela.
Hogy van Mecedes Miss Herrera?
It's stable. Which means that they do not know better will be.
My mother, I can not work with this tomorrow, and you know, the hotel's image ...
Squeeze it here. Tomorrow lelappad swelling, and the detachable bond.
Let only.
Feel better?
- So. - Yes.
The hotel can not afford an incapacitated
and a waiter taking care of her.
As you wish, Doña Ángela.
Get well soon.
You were lucky, my son, it could have been fatal.
Yes. But there are shocks that hurt more than anything.
Belén abandoned.
He goes to the hotel.
I know you did not like him, but ... I loved it.
Andrés is not good for a mother to see her son suffer.
- But over time you realize it's for the best. - I do not.
It's never going to happen, my mother.
I can not find anything like him.
- Where are you going? - I walk in the garden, my father.
Miss Aliciával, nem?
They got engaged. And he Alarcón.
Take care, son. I do not want you to suffer.
Good friend.
It always has.
You are responsible for the level of it?
Continue your work, Antonio.
I'll talk to Senor Alonso.
Maybe I can help you. What do you want?
Ask for a cup of tea.
You do not need to come into the hall. Csengethetsz your room as well.
Do not look for another excuse Bernardo.
Quite annoying that you want to steal the munkásaimat,
and even worse, when you look foolish.
You talk to the employees, as if they were property.
I'm just a better job and salary offered to them.
Behind me.
Some people come here to have the letters not recognized.
And I learned a profession.
And now that I picked this fruit, you want to marry you.
I took from you a couple of employees. Carlos stole from me this hotel.
- Well, this is all about. Revenge. - Business.
One lesson you taught your husband.
- That the friendship does not mean anything. - I will not insult you more.
- Carlos was a gentleman. - And what are you doing? It offers're throwing away?
Of course not.
It would not be too smart move my part. As your part even if you stay here.
I'm not going to discharge.
The cabinet assigns tonight, Don Diego.
I started to be checked by an rooms but
may have been the thief took from the hotel.
The same lock mount.
But confirm. I do not want any repetition of that.
- Exterminator me then? - Of course.
Good luck, you!
- You're going to really miss him. - You too me.
We need more towels and cold water Señorita Mercedes room.
Immediately, Don Diego.
- Are you leaving? - Don Bernard is included.
This solves every problem, is not it?
For my part, the problems have been resolved, Belén.
I'm going to miss?
Many things will be missing.
One thing will be missing here.
This is not the appropriate moment.
Others will no longer be.
You have to be satisfied with what it was.
Don Bernardo, I'm here.
I'm sorry, but my offer to be involved.
Why?
I found out you're pregnant.
I can not let my housekeeper
In the first months of the hotel to go to give birth.
- Who told you? - I was.
Did you really think that I do not know who goes and who stays in the hotel, you?
Now I should say that if you have already packed up, then leave.
The traitors deserve.
But I do not do it.
Due to the child?
Deal. And five more months to complete a part of you.
Hold.
But that's a lot of money.
Who gets the child?
I do not want money in exchange for the questions.
Yes, ma'am.
This changeover will take effect after five months.
That left the szülésedig.
Until then, you can not get to it, but it's yours.
To remind you that you owe me.
- And then? - You leave the hotel.
In the meantime, do your old job.
- Szintfelelõsként? - As a Maid.
And can thank. I am very generous with you.
Yes, ma'am.
Can I go now?
It'll have to continue to tolerate.
- I'm not leaving. - I know.
I spoke to Doña Teresa.
If you leave now, my son will suffer, and do not forget. It'd be a martyr for.
But if you stay, I'll show him what you truly are. And then you're done.
You were you, right? You pushed him off.
Now we have no one to stand between us.
How could you do with your sister?
And that he would have taken it, I liked best?
Come here, Javier.
I'll tell everyone what you've done.
And I tell you, it was you.
And who would believe it?
An upper-class girl ... or a drunken fall.
If you're not mine, nobody will, Javier.
We have time until tomorrow to ask my father to renew our engagement.
Or I'll tell everyone you're my sister pushed him out.
No. No no no ...
- What happened? - No, my father.
Javier scared me, but I do not think it was intentional.
Of course not.
Stay away from the lányaimtól.
The Cernuda has been mild shock. So you can get back to work tomorrow.
I am glad that Andrés fine. And Señorita Herrera?
Serious condition. But fortunately there are still among us.
All right. Thank you, Benjamín.
The reason I wanted to come to my father, to restore family relationships,
and what he did, excuse me, is despicable.
- It's business, Ignacio. - I do not.
It ruined the family's reputation.
Alicia, forgive me. I did not know what my father made.
If I had not I make every effort to come.
Although I would not see you again.
I do not know what happened, Ignacio. But ... whatever it is, I know I can trust you.
A message for you, Señorita Alarcón.
"I need to see you. I do not want what happened ruin our relationship.
We need to talk. I will be the first-floor corridor. "
Thank you.
See you tomorrow before I leave?
Again.
Then it does not bother you further.
- Where are you going? - In my room. Relax.
- Felkísérlek. - It is not necessary, thank you.
We should not meet here.
They stole one gold knife. Ayala tries to find the culprit.
- You've come to tell me that? - To ask you, take care.
And to explain things.
Cecilia.
This is what the "C" which is tattooed on my arm.
Blancaróban I fell in love.
Because of him I got to prison.
And why you were carried out in prison?
He spoke to a woman who has been very valuable jewels and ...
- ... And made me steal them away. - And you robbed?
Again.
I gave Cecilia, take care of them.
The next day, the police arrested.
No I owed to him and the prison tattooed myself in my first letter.
A little later I learned that Cecilia betrayed to save himself.
He fled with jewels, and I did not hear from him again.
And I did not want you to think that's why I came to the hotel.
Therefore, I do not tell.
Well, that's the story.
I always had a talent for it ... They fell in love, whom he should not.
And trust the wrong man.
Alicia.
Diego, what happened?
Who is it?
I do not know what you're talking about.
Do not lie to me.
"I need to see you. I do not want what happened ruin our relationship."
What happened?
What's between you and the person from this?
It was me.
I sent the message.
Ignacio! No, no, no, no! No, stop! Stand down, please!
- Do not! No! Stop! - What happened between you, Alicia?
- Nothing, nothing, nothing happened. - Stop!
I sent a message to apologize for the crime of my father.
I do not want to ruin our friendship, that's it.
That's right. Just wanted to ask for forgiveness.
Free.
I'm sorry about what happened, Diego.
You do not have to explain, it was all a misunderstanding.
You can too. Ignacio was not supposed to strike.
Especially not in front of the guests.
It was not a big deal. Neither shocks nor humiliation.
Therefore I do not feel bad.
I always control myself.
Very well.
But most of us are,
I feel for you,
it is too much.
It was right. This behavior only farther away.
And I'm really sorry.
I apologize.
For having doubted you.
The reason why I thought I'd be able to lie to ...
To see you with someone while you're planning to come to me.
No, Diego.
If there is something that needs to be made, it is forgiven.
Javier?
Where are you going?
To find this Ayala detective to justice.
Drunk in the middle of the night? What are you saying?
You know what happened to Mercedes-winds, the general's daughter?
Accident.
Accident? You think you are, but I know the truth.
And once in my life I'm going to do the right thing. Look out of the way!
- You can not go so Cantaloába! - Tomorrow will be even worse!
Javier!
Motozza that man.
Ma'am, please go home immediately. Keep up to.
July! Segítened kell to bátyámnak!
- What are you doing? - Cantaloába go, he drank a lot and ...
teeming with police and did not want to come to harm.
Do not worry.
Thank you.
Is anyone there?
Who's there?
Alicia.
Alicia, are you there?
Diego?
Alicia, I am, open the door.
I saw you in the hallway and run scared me, or I'm wrong?
Someone was in the hallway with a knife and chased.
- He had a knife with him. - Calm.
Relax, I'm here with you, everything will be all right, calm down.
He is overheard and left.
Or maybe he went to another woman.
Already Cantaloában others killed.
I'm going to disappear selfish, but I'm worried about you only.
Now lie down and rest.
Do not cry!
I'm not leaving. I'll be up all night on the other side of the door.
All right?
I'm not going to get hurt.
Thank you.
I'll be outside.
If you need anything, be anything ...
just let me know.
Miss, return home immediately.
Hernando!
Do not touch
And if he's still alive?
Clear sting.
The ribs 6 and 7 between.
Believe me: dead.
You leave without a farewell?
Yesterday something happened at the hotel, and you have to go to the village.
But you're right. I'm sorry.
I wanted to thank the messaging thing.
- I want to explain everything ... - I'm your friend, Alicia.
The friends are not waiting for an explanation.
- Too bad you have to go already. - Yeah, too bad.
I came with the hope to win back his childhood love.
- But I know it is impossible. - I'm engaged to Diego.
No I mean it.
Good luck!
Decided?
Again.
Namely?
Last night Cantaloába I went to talk to the police.
- What did you tell them? - The truth.
They do not believe you, and I say it was you.
Witness, too. One man who rushed to help your sister, she saw me.
- You can not do this to me, Javier. - Leave me alone and I'm not saying anything.
I did it because I love you.
You own it.
We can be happy, Javier.
"Dear Father! The former fiance, Javier changed my life a nightmare.
First he cheated my sister,
then he pushed from the balcony to get rid of him.
I'm afraid of my father.
Javier sworn to kill me if I tell you what he did Mercedes-Nations. "
Detective Ayala ...
Miss Alarcon.
You do not know how much paperwork associated with a murder.
As I am now in relation to the crime.
Do you know something that we can help the sinner?
Last night someone chased me into the hotel hallway.
A golden knife.
- He recognized the levy? - I do not.
So while the village guarded ... ... the killer was in the hotel.
Investigation.
Outside, waiting for the murdered girl's parents yesterday.
I do not want them megváratni such circumstances.
It has megbocsát, Miss Alarcon.
- Of course. - Arrived in the mail.
Investigation.
Circling OLMEDO JULIO AND warrant
I-Blancard Stewards
"Circling and arrest warrant against Julio Olmedo, for murder.
Immediately they should be arrested and handed over to the judiciary. "
The Continued ...
Alicia! You do not think I'm a murderer?
I do not know Julio.
Julio Espinosa stole my savings and ran away with it.
By the time I got back to the room, he was not there.
One daughter is dead, the other is unconscious, and all because of you!
With mûvel?
What has been the beginning should have done. You will duel with me.
What happened in Sofia?
My mother, I know the kid who wants to give me, that of the maid.
- I do not want that kid. - This is the time to visit?
- That child is Diego. - I no longer need the child.
- But you said ... - Do not ever interrupt me.
It's called the Ruta plant.
Two spoonfuls is enough to get rid of the kid.
Sofía, is not found in this image, neither of these.
But why would he do that? To kill a maid?
So you terminate the engagement.
You do not have to stay any side, whom you do not trust.
Because you do not feel anything for him.
You slept with a whore. What else are you hiding from me yet?
When you call, I will return tomorrow along with the fõállamügyésszel, and the press writes,
by rotating upside for the hotel in search of a killer.
Watch Movies, TV Series & Live Sports
www.admitme.app