A hundred years ago - the island of
St. Pierre in the English Channel.
This came for you,
Reverend Mother.
Thank you.
Reverend Mother and Friend.
A bad penny always turns up and -
- this useless aging one
returns home today.
If my beloved Sophie is still living
after all this time -
- please tell her I have not
forgotten the great love we -
He needn't wait.
- respectfully, a voice from the past
Edmond Ozanne
Thank you, you needn't wait.
Open the gate, sister Angelique.
Forgive me, Reverend Mother -
If you're going to St. Pierre,
the tide is due to rise.
And if you should get caught!
Child!
The matter of this letter may ruin the
happiness of a family we all respect!
Of course, I could stay here
and pray to the good Lord.
Yes, you could that, Reverend Mother!
You're not so young any more!
But I think the good Lord would
prefer me to do something about it!
And my age is my
own business.
And you could come with me!
Sophie.
Reverend Mother, how nice to see you!
Do sit down!
No, no, I haven't time for that.
- But I haven't seen you for years!
- Sophie!
Is something wrong?
Edmond Ozanne,
has returned to St Pierre.
Edmond!
Naturally,
he doesn't know you'r Mrs. Patourel.
And he wants to see you!
There is my answer!
My two daughters.
You don't mention Octavius?
Don't you love him?
Octavius, of course!
He is my husband.
You didn't love him when your parents
forced the marriage on you.
Octavius is kind and devoted!
He has been a loving father to his children,
he has carried on the family business beautifully!
But Edmond is still the
man you love!
And always will.
My parents forbade me to marry Edmond.
Because he drank too much.
And talked to much!
Because they considered
the marriage unsuitable.
Don't lie to me, Sophie Patourel!
You would have thrown yourself
over the cliff that night!
If I hadn't stopped you!
Help me! Help me,
Reverend Mother!
Octavius think I scarcely
knew Edmond.
He and my children must
never know the truth!
You must go and see
Edmond today.
Tell him about your marriage.
Your daughters.
Let him know unmistakenly that
the past is buried forever!
And he will say nothing to jeopardize
your family's happiness.
Yes, I'll see him!
I'll go today!
Good!
Now I must hurry. The tide may
not wait, even for Mother Superior!
There's Edmond now.
Oh, Mrs Metivier, you flatter me.
He has changed.
Shockingly.
Cabby, let's have
this bag first, eh?
Who is the young man?
That is his son.
Edmond married in England
his wife died when the boy was born.
Come, sister.
Goodbye, my child.
Goodbye, Reverend Mother.
Mama, help me get
my bonnet on properly!
Naturally, darling.
Marianne, Marianne!
I won't be long, I'm with papa.
I wrote to London this morning -
- and told them not to send you
the plans for the steam boat.
Marianne, why don't you get married?
And I signed your name to the letter.
You what?
I said, I signed your name to the letter!
Marianne, it is most unseemingly!
Oh nonsens, Papa,
these are modern times!
I have made up my mind.
You must marry!
Sir Charles, that's our man.
You must know that he loves you.
Don't think Mama and I didn't notice
that you spent three hours with him
in the conservatory last night!
Yes.
Yes, it took me three solid hours to
coax sir Charles to give me this report.
You see it is marked "confidential".
Here it is.
Your new glasses.
These figures prove that
at present cost of operations -
- the steam boat will eat upp
all its profits.
I still say it is most unseemingly for a young woman
to know so much about the shipping business.
Papa!
You'll be using steam
ships in eight or ten years.
By that time you will be retired
and I will be running the business.
By that time you'll be married to some
smart young fellow who carry on in my place.
If I ever marry -
- it won't be because the bride
groom is a good business man!
Marianne my dear,
sometimes you shock me!
Of course I do.
I'm bold and scheming.
And sometimes I think
I'm not quite nice!
Marianne, Marguerite
is waiting.
Oh, be an angel and run
down and tell Mama -
- that in exactly five minutes -
- I shall descend upon the
staircase so elegantly -
- I'll frighten myself!
You're incorrigible!
Marguerite.
Marianne, you're beautiful!
Simply beautiful!
I am not beautiful!
I'm immensly chique!
Smell.
It's a new perfume from Paris.
I think it's a little
indecent, don't you?
Marianne, the neckline of that
dress, do you think it modest?
Mama, it's the very
latest style!
Papa my angel, what do you think?
Is it all too bold?
Not on you, my dear.
God has given you that quality.
Oh no, it's all
my own doing!
Now, now, Marianne,
don't be rude to your father!
Go where you're going
before I lose my patience!
We're going shopping,
come on!
Shopping? In that dress?
But Mama, this dress is
only to prove -
that even if we are the richest people
on the island we are not snobs!
- At least I'm not!
- As a matter of fact I feel particularly common!
What are we going shopping for?
We are not going shopping.
We are calling on our new neighbours.
Both of them.
Look alive you,
young whipper-snapper!
Come in, come in!
Well, bless my soul -
- if you aren't a pretty pair!
William, come and see
what I've got!
A pink one and a green one.
Are there any more of you
outside? A yellow one or a blue one?
William, make your manners.
Bow to thelittle dears.
This is my son William.
And your name is?
- Marianne, and you are sweet.
- Well, thank you!
And yours?
Marguerite.
Marianne and Marguerite.
Two pretty names for
two pretty little dears!
Holy Moses, I don't know I've
ever heard two prettier names.
Did you, William?
I don't like them. Too fancy
and too much alike!
He's a viscious little brute, isn't he?
Now, sit down, ladies!
I've been trying to save him from the likes
of you ever since the day he was born!
I've never saw them until this minute.
Oh, he doesn't mean saving you from us!
He means from good manners,
respectability, sobriety.
Please don't be angry with her,
she talks like that to everybody.
- Angry with her, why, if I were a young man I'd ...
- You'd what?
I'd run away as if you were
the devil himself!
And a fine job you'd made of
yourself and your son.
If it is impossible you can be your son?
Impossible?
What's wrong?
Well, you can start making yourself civilized.
By tying your shoe laces.
I wouldn't give a penny for all
the civilized shoe laces in London!
A revolutionary? And just what would be
your idea of a satisfactory existence?
If I were running this world
I would pass a law that -
- everyone could do exactly as he pleased!
Convincing rascal, isn't he?
Ladies, I am Ozanne,
doctor Edmond Ozanne.
And you are Marianne and
Marguerite what?
- Excuse me, please!
I'm afraid my daughters
are rather unconventional.
Naturally one calls on a new neighbour
but not without warning of course.
I am Mrs Patourel, you remember me?
And you are Edmond Ozanne.
- Yes, Mam.
And you are Sophie.
- We used to know each
other when we were -
- Yes, I was just about to tell your
daughters that I didn't know you very well.
My father being a shop keeper -
- on a lower social level -
- than your mother's family.
- Oh, Edmond, that make us
sound like snobs!
- Oh, but you are Mama! You are
sweet, but you are a snob.
- Pay no attention to her.
My husband ...
I don't think you ever knew him.
His name is Octavius Patourel.
- And he's a bit of snob too!
- Close your mouth,
young woman!
Your mother is a gracious lady.
Merely trying to be kind to a -
- good for nothing who drinks more
than is good for him.
- Oh, Edmond!
- Yes, I ...
The only times I ever really
got away from this island ...
What I left behind here ...
Is through a bottle of ...
But I won't presume on
boyhood acquaintanceship.
Ah, I forgot! My son!
Salute the lady, William!
You are very like your
father as a boy.
Let's go now.
Come girls!
Good bye, doctor Ozanne.
I'm coming again, soon.
An honour, young lady!
- Goodbye.
- Goodbye, William!
- Goodbye, William.
You would look much more like a
human being if you combed your hair!
- Thank you Edmond for
helping me out!
They mustn't ever know that
you and I once ...
- Once loved each other
beyond all else.
Don't worry, Sophie.
No one will ever hear it from these -
- aging lips.
And which of the two young
ladies put that comb in your hand?
- It was Marianne.
Or is her name Marguerite?
It was the nice one!
- Why, thank you!
Who sent them?
- Oh, this is nice.
- There are two of them.
- Well, shouldn't Miss Marianne Patourel be told
the name of her secret admirer who sent her flowers?
- She doesn't even know I exist
and she never will.
- I'll go and tell her!
- You keep your mouth shut, Corinne,
and mind you own business!
Since when has Timothy Haslam
not been my business?
What is over is over -
- I have told you that a thousand times,
now, can't you understand it?
- I can understand.
But will my brother understand?
You know he can use a knife too!
That statue of the Madonna up
there, how tall is it?
No one has ever seen it close.
Except for the Sisters of Saint Peter.
William, I've been thinking over very seriously
what you said about shoe laces the other day.
Can you get up there from here?
Well, they say that many years ago -
- before the convent was built -
- smugglers used to climb up through
a tunnel inside the cave!
- Smugglers, huh?
Well, I can do anything
a smuggler can do!
- William!
- Pretty smart of those old smugglers.
You know, at high tide the
whole cave is hidden under water.
And at low tide it is perfect for ...
- Sit down, William!
Now, what are you going to
do about your future?
- My future?
I think I'll be a smuggler!
- Please be serious!
A man must have some
sort of career.
- I will have to think that over,
it may take years and years.
In the meantime -
- I think I'll just
lie back here.
And think of all the exciting places on
the other side of that ocean.
The Pacific Ocean and all the others.
- Good morning, Emily.
- Good morning, Miss Marianne!
- Good morning, Dolly.
- Good morning, Miss.
- Marianne.
- Pleasant dreams?
- Very!
Marianne?
It is possible to fall in love with a man -
- that you've only known for five days?
And seen three times?
- Yes, I think it is!
- That means you're in love with him too?
- No I'm not, but I could be in love
with the man he could be.
- Whichever of us?
Oh Marianne, it must
never make any difference between us!
- Nothing ever could
or ever will!
- How can William not
fall in love with you?
You're so striking.
And you have a brain.
- William.
- Yes, father?
- There you are!
William, did you drink as much
as I did last night?
- I did, old fellow, but
I'm young.
- You ungrateful young cub!
- Father, Marguerite
is coming.
- The sign says "Doctor Ozanne".
- Come this way, please.
Sit there.
Hey, here's a patient for you!
- What's the matter, getting a little trouble?
Holy Moses, that's bad!
You've lost a lot of blood.
It's a knife wound, eh?
It's a matter for the police.
I'll have to report it.
- No!
- I always have to report knife wounds.
- I don't need you to.
- Well, give me one good
reason why I shouldn't.
- Because it's a private matter.
- A woman, huh? And the man
who carved you up was her husband?
- Her brother.
- Brother?
Very dull and uninteresting.
Well.
Nothing better for the morning
after than a little surgery.
- What's the matter, do
I fright you that much?
Yes. You are so blasted clever,
you scare me to death!
- Good. Perhaps I can
scare some sense into you!
Come down to the harbour,
I want to show you something.
- A beautiful ship!
What is she, Marianne?
- One of the new clippers. The finest,
fastest kind of merchant ship.
You see, William? You
see the name? The Green Dolphin.
And you live on the corner of
Green Dolphin Street. That's a sign!
Look how high those masts are!
I wonder how
many sails she carries?
Well, there's a fore-topmast , staysail, inner jib, outer or flying jib,
foursail, mainsail and mizzen, fitted with topsail, topgallants and royals.
What would you be doing here?
Where can one get the first
good sleep I've had in a week!
Do you know what a storm it was
that drew me here last night?
Where are you from
and what cargo?
From New Zealand,
a cargo of timber.
Well, you've got the most
perfect ship I've ever seen!
Captain Dennis O'Hara at your service!
Come aboard and have
a bite of breakfast!
That's the mark of a shark!
Caught it in the Tasman Sea
with a boat hook!
Yes, New Zealand is a
beautiful country.
With forests, half of them grand swell.
And the top of trees are
a 150 feet above your head.
And giant ferns below, ferns
reaching above your shoulders.
- Giant ferns?
- Go on, captain O'Hara!
It's the first I've ever seen William -
- interested in anything worthwhile!
- Yes, a grand land!
With birds bigger than an ostrich!
But not able to fly for the reason of the heavy stomach they have on them.
And mountains with the snow
always on their crests.
Slipped ashore last night, did you?
Stole the eggs off the natives?
It's meself, I'm proud of you for that!
Doesn't your servant talk English?
Not, he don't talk sense at all!
Some cannibals in New Zealand
tied with his tongue.
That's why.
Cannibals?
Chopped off his leg too!
A grand country, New Zealand!
With timber and flax, and
wonderful pasture land!
All virgin soil, and don't
belong to no one!
There are places like that in this world,
and I have to live and die here on this little ...?
You don't have to do anyting you don't want to!
Here, my dear, for you!
They are made of a New
Zealand stone called tangiway.
And green is your colour, I can see.
And for you, son!
The maoris of New Zealand -
- use a knife like this.
For cutting up human flesh.
Captain O'Hara, they are beautiful!
I've gotta be going, there's
trouble on deck.
Finish your breakfast.
Answer, what's going on here?
Sneaked aboard, eh?
A stow-away! Who are ye?
Who are ye?
What difference does it make?
Toss him overboard!
Let me go!
My name is Timothy Haslam.
You wouldn't be hiding
from the police?
It was a fair fight.
And it's plain you
killed the other fella.
I won't lie to you,
I did kill him.
But I didn't lift a hand at him until he came at me with a knife.
I believe you.
It is well and fairly spoken.
And I'll help you.
Besides, I'm a man short in me crew.
Take him below.
Hide him in the fox hole.
Come along.
The English law can't reach
you in New Zealand.
- Now look.
Just look at her!
I know what I'm gonna do.
I have made up my mind.
- What?
- I gonna be a sailor on
a clipper ship, like that one.
- No, not on a clipper ship. Your
going into the navy.
- The navy?
- To be an officer and a gentleman!
- Well, that takes money.
- Well, suppose somebody
found a way -
- to provide the money and the influence?
- Well, that's just talk, who?
- My father.
- What?
And you suppose my father
would permit that?
- I repeat, Marianne.
How could you go aboard a strange
ship with that uncouth ragamuffin?
How could you indulge in such a
disreputable escapade?
Stop sulking!
- Are those your new glasses?
- Certainly, certainly.
- Well, then you better send
them back. I'm not sulking.
I'm smiling humbly.
I am sorry, I aplogize and my
behaviour was most unladylike.
I ask you to forgive me.
- Well, we'll say no more about it.
- Thank you, Papa.
- The matter is closed.
- Not quite.
What about William?
- William?
- He wants to go in the navy.
- Not my problem.
- Well, you object to William
being around and -
- if he went off to the navy,
he wouldn't be here.
Would he?
And when he does come back -
- why, then he'd be a gentleman.
And he wouldn't be so offensive.
Would he?
- Bright girl, Sophie.
- But of course, it takes
money and influence.
- Not my money, oh no!
- Mama is very fond of William.
Wouldn't you like to treat William
as if he were the son -
- that Mama has always longed for,
but has never had?
Mind you, it's not going to be as
easy as you think.
William's father is very proud.
You may have a little difficulty in getting
him to accept the proposition.
But you're so brilliant, you'll do it!
And mention Mama and her
affection for William.
- I don't need to be told how to
carry out a good idea!
- Then don't go to see doctor Ozanne this evening.
Tomorrow will do.
- I should go tonight!
I should go now!
And take doctor Ozanne
a bottle of brandy.
- I will not!
- Our best brandy. The kind you
smuggle in from France.
Marianne, your father is very good.
He's very easily managed.
Mama.
Emily, put the keys of the
wine cellar back in my desk.
Very well, Sir.
William, you're practically in the navy.
It's Midsummer Festival day.
How slowly the years have passed -
- since William left for England and -
- the Royal Naval College of Portsmouth.
And now at last Her Majesty's
ship arrive -
- sailing majestically into our harbour -
- and William is aboard.
There he is!
Two years without a
letter to his own father!
The young cub!
Hey, hey!
Well, old fellow, you look
younger than I do!
Digestive trouble!
I may even have to take some of that horrible stuff I give to my patients!
Come in!
Come in, my boy, come in!
This note came for
you a while back.
One of the servants brought
it from the Patourel house.
"Dear William."
"I have arranged for you to
come to dinner tonight at 7."
"So that my father -
- may see the results so far of
his investment in your future."
"I know you won't fail me.
Marianne."
Hey, you've gotta go, too!
I wanna go.
I wanna see...
But my ship sails at
high tide tonight.
I know, but we'll have
the whole afternoon together.
What's a few more years?
Time passes.
Soon you'll be
home to stay!
How do you know
about my ship?
The Patourel girl told me.
Came over here not ten minutes
after the Orion had dropped anchor.
Which Patourel girl?
Both of them.
Both of the pretty
little rascals!
They've been popping in
and out of ever here since you left.
Bless their hearts.
Which one is it you're
so anxious to see?
The one I've had on my
mind ever since -
- ever since I
first saw her.
That would be the one who is so much
like her mother when she was a girl.
Son, if you have it in your
heart to speak to this girl -
- remember that fine families are
very particular -
about a son-in-law.
I know, I've been
worrying about it.
About her father.
When you are an
established officer -
- in her Majesty's Navy -
- you'll be a gentleman!
Even to Mr Patourel!
- Good evening, Sir.
- Good evening.
- In the drawing room, Sir.
- Thank you.
- William!
- Marguerite!
- The others will be down in a moment.
- And I shall make use of that moment.
Marguerite.
Ever since I saw you last -
- I've thougt of nothing but you.
I love you.
May I say that?
I love you!
- Keep saying it William because I love you too.
- Listen.
This must be our secret.
But all the time I'm away from you -
- you must keep saying to
yourself that I love you!
- Mama!
- Good evening, William.
It's a pleasure to
welcome you to our home.
You're very handsome
in your uniform.
Thank you, Mrs Patourel.
He's a little thin.
- That's the life of disciplin.
The best thing in the
world for a man.
William.
How are you, Marianne?
Very well pleased with you.
So you're off to China tonight?
Oh, how lucky you are, William!
You know, Mama, The Green Dolphin
trades on the China coast.
And captain O'Hara says that knowledge of
the Orient is most important nowadays.
Yes, I suppose so.
In the future, the commerce of the
world will center on the Pacific.
Yes, I think Papa will be satisfied with
your progress so far.
Excuse me.
What is it, Mrs Metiver?
Doctor Ozanne, he's just had a seizure.
He's very ill!
Mr William must come!
Yes, I'll bring him.
Get my cloak.
William.
Your father just had a sudden attack.
My father?
Margurerite, get Mama's smelling salt.
And then find a doctor. The nearest.
Come William.
Steady William, this might not be serious.
Speak to him, William.
Father?
Can you hear me?
Are you really here, William?
Of course I'm here, of course I'm here!
.
Thank you, thank you for coming, William.
Shows you -
- you really love me.
You won't have to stay very long.
Because I'm not going to last very long.
- William!
- Yes father?
Wouldn't it be a joke now -
- if I didn't die after all?
But I won't play that kind of joke on you.
Because I've always loved you.
Father! Father!
Oh, come William!
- William, William, listen to me!
- You don't know how wonderful he was!
- Yes, I do. I knew and I loved him.
But you must realize tonight he saw you were being wonderful too.
He saw you as you are now, an officer and a gentleman.
- And that's how you should remember him!
- What does that matter now?
It matters a great deal. Cause you
are going to do things that will
make him very proud of you.
Oh, William.
Stay here with him for a little while.
I'll stay with you if you like.
But then we must get you back to your ship
cause it sails at midnight.
I'm not going to the ship!
I won't leave. I can't!
Yes you can!
You're going to sail away with your ship.
And when you come back next year
you come back with your head high!
Full of pride of what you've done with yourself!
With the knowledge that he would've been
as proud of you.
You'll find his grave. We'll bury him
with honour and with kindness.
But when you kneel by his grave -
- you can weep upon a brave heart and
respect yourself as well as him!
William, there will be flowers on
his grave next year.
There will always be flowers on his grave.
"Pier 3"
"Sailing tonight: HMS Orion"
Well, Ozanne, there's China.
- Take it all in.
- Yes, Sir.
But be back on board by midnight!
-  By all means, Sir.
All I'm looking forward to is our return home.
- You wish to buy something?
- Yes. Please, I'd like something
for a young lady.
- Certainly.
- You speak English, perfectly!
- Yes, my father was an Englishman.
This is a Chinese charm necklace.
To be given to the one whom you love.
- Ah, yes, that's just what I wanted!
How much is it?
- Four pieces of silver.
Chinese money.
- I haven't any Chinese money.
Will you take English?
- One English gold sovereign.
- Could I write a letter?
- Of course, over there.
"Dear Marguerite."
"This necklace will say I
have always loved you."
"Wait for me!"
"When I come home I -
- will ask your father for your hand in marriage."
- And when will you be home?
- Not for another two years.
- There is an English clipper
ship in the harbour.
It will be home in six months.
- Thank you very much!
You there?
- Ay ay, Sir?
- There's a clipper ship in
the port sailing for home.
Put this package and letter on board.
Ay ay, Sir!
- I think this should cover the cost.
- Right, Sir.
- You will drink a little rice wine?
- Where is this place?
Where is this place?
- What's the matter, mate?
- Where's the Orion?
The Orion, man, where is she?
- The Orion, mate, she sailed at midnight!
As far as you're concerned
she's halfway to Calcutta!
- Ahoy, a stow-away!
What the devil are ye?
- Don't you remember me, captain O'Hara?
Of St. Pierre?
- Let's have a look at you!
That young fellow!
What are you doing here, son?
What's the trouble?
- I had shore leave.
Something happened.
My ship sailed.
- Women and rum?
- Yes, Sir.
- What ship?
- The Orion.
- The navy?
Young fool!
Alright, lad.
If you had gone straight to
Her Majesty's consul -
- and made a clean brest of it.
But, no.
Instead of that you are now a deserter.
A fine mess you've made of your life!
- Where are we bound, captain O'Hara?
- New Zealand.
And you're lucky!
There you'll be safe from the law.
Fine young muscles like yours will
be at a premium among the settlers!
- William!
Parson and Mrs Kelly.
William Ozanne.
- How do you do?
- Well son, I'm ready to up anchor
and leave Wellington.
Which means you are through
with the Green Dolphin.
But parson Kelly and his
wife will take you in.
You can help in the
mission school.
- I don't like to impose on a parson.
- Who else am I to impose you
on for the parson?
A parson can't refuse you bed and breakfast,
it is expressly provided in the Book of Matthew.
Isn't that so parson?
- Quite so!
- Thank you parson!
Mam!
Give a good heart, son!
Don't fret over past mistakes.
And remember, it is better to
keep away from the liquor today -
- than to waste tomorrow counting
yesterday's empty bottles!
- Thank you for everything,
captain O'Hara!
If you ever get back to St Pierre -
- you won't tell anybody?
- Have no fear of that, son,
and God bless you!
Shove off lads!
- Earthquake?
- That's right, chum,
there's an earthquake.
- That's right!
- Whiskey!
- You're a homie!
- Huh?
- New to this country?
- Oh, just landed, Sir.
- Got a job?
- Yes, I've got a job.
Teaching the kiddies at
the mission school.
- Not your sort of work, huh?
- What do you think?
- Got a place up north in the
backblocks, getting out Caule.
That is big tree timber.
You can pitch in and join
me, if you like.
- But why, you don't know
anything about me?
- I know as much about you as your father
know about me back in St Pierre.
When he patched up this arm
without telling the police.
- I remember, I thought
you looked familiar!
You killed a man and got away!
- Keep your mouth shut!
- And your name's Haslam!
- My name's Tai Haruru.
The Maoris gave it to me.
That's all you need
to know about me.
- And the same applies to me!
- Alright.
I'll work you harder than you've
ever been worked before in your life.
And you'll have to be ready for travel
because there'll be war between the
natives, the Maoris, and the colonials before long.
Make up your mind, if you go with me you
can forget that girl at home.
- Who told you about a girl?
- A mutual friend.
Captain O'Hara.
Tell me something, Ozanne.
Which of the two sisters was it?
- None of your blasted business!
Sir.
- Well, there it is, Ozanne!
- The whole valley?
- Oh, we live...
- You see the lake?
- Aha.
- We live on the banks of the river -
- 10 miles upstream from there.
Without the benefit of clergy or doctors.
- Very comforting.
- The whole valley is a
Maori stronghold.
You'll find our settlement
reasonably comfortable and safe.
- Are those friendly Maoris?
- Well, they're my friends.
Perhaps they'll be yours if you treat
them courteously and keep your word.
Never show fear before them.
But they're a dangerous and strange people.
I've seen some extraordinary exhibitions of
their ability to predict the future.
Have a look at their river, Ozanne!
Perhaps some day that water will travel
halfway around the world and splash
on the beach at St Pierre!
- Marguerite!
I want you to go down to the dressmaker's
and match this silk for me.
Marguerite, I...
What are you hiding
from me, Marguerite?
- It's a secret, Mama.
- Is it a secret that has anything
to do with you not marrying anyone
of those halfdozen young men?
My dear, I would never insist
upon you marrying anyone.
But you have your life to live.
I have a life, mama, -
- in my thoughts and my dreams.
- Marguerite!
- Marianne! Home, Edward.
- Papa?
I believe William Ozanne is dead.
- No, I question that.
Only the good die young!
No, he's dead!
Or that would account for his not writing
once since he sailed away on the Orion.
- Oh, I don't know...
Well, if he were alive -
- nothing would have kept him -
-  writing to... you in common gratitude.
- Oh, true...
- Or to me in friendship.
Or to Marguerite.
Of whom he was once very fond.
In a childish way.
No, papa.
William is dead.
- Sophie, come quick, she's fainted!
- What?
- She's fainted!
- Mrs Metivier, Marguerite's fainted.
Get my smelling
salt, cold water and towels.
- And the dusters.
- Marianne's fainted?
I don't believe it!
- Neither do I.
But your father hasn't lied to me for 30 years.
Let's go and see.
- I have asked your
mother to come down.
- Marianne, what is it?
- Get her some cognac.
- No, no, no, some smelling salts!
- No, cognac would be better, dear.
[moans]
- But who!
- The lady is late.
I was waiting here for Mr Patourel
when the two of them came in.
And all I said was:
"Here's a letter for you, Mr Patourel, which
I bring you from William Ozanne in New Zealand".
And then...
Now look, this one's fainted!
- No, this one hasn't fainted.
This one's praying.
- Then I'll be going.
- But tell me about William,
what is he doing in New Zealand?
Is he still in the navy?
- Due to an unfortunate incident,
the lad severed his connection.
And good day to ye all!
- Marianne, the letter is
addressed to me!
- Suppose I read it aloud, dear?
- I will not be bullied
in my own household!
"Dear Sir"
"It is a long time since I've had
the pleasure of addressing you."
"Much has happened and I now feel that
I have earned the privilege of writing."
- The young blaggard!
Left the navy, and a deserter probably!
After all the money I spent on him!
- Mama, go on with the letter!
"I have been in the lumber business
for over two years."
"And I can say I am becoming a
fairly successful businessman."
"My partner is a man of great ability."
"And we have developed our little
settlement into a garden spot with
comfortable dwellings."
- What's been going on out there?
Has that fortune telling medicine man
been reading tea leaves again?
- He says that a letter you wrote
was delievered today on the
other side of the world.
- How could he know that?
I personally gave it to captain -
- O'Hara myself months ago,
I didn't even...
Hold on, wait a minute!
- It was about a young woman, wasn't it?
That's my own private affair!
- Put down that drink!
The Patourel girl?
Alright!
I was drunk!
I was in Wellington.
Alone and miserable!
Alright, I was drunk!
Never had the courage if I hadn't been drunk.
Asking a wonderful girl like that to
come all the way out here.
- Which girl?
- After all they did for me.
I wrote and offered my hand in marriage.
A life like this!
- Which girl, I said?
- Marguerite of course!
- "I do not know what life has brought
you and your good wife."
"And as for your lovely daughters
they may have married."
"Yet I can not but hope that..."
- Speak up, what does the
young blaggard want?
"Yet I cannot but hope that your
daughter Marianne is still unmarried."
"That you would consider
permitting her to live -
- in such a rough but glorious
country as my wife."
- As his wife?
Marianne?
- The confounded cheat!
The outrageous, overwhelming fool!
Sophie, here, write, my dictation!
Here's pen, ink, paper, sit down, dear!
Now write, Mr William Ozanne.
- Father, you act as though I've been insulted -
-  instead of honoured by a marriage proposal!
- No daughter of mine...
- I am old enought to marry without your consent -
- and that is exactly what I intend do!
- Of course you are!
You are unjust to William!
If he was foolish in the past -
- he has now written you a fine and straight forward letter.
- My daughter going to live among
a lot of man eating savages?
- She always wanted to marry William.
She will never marry anybody else.
Will you, Marianne?
- No!
And I am going to marry William!
- Everyone is insane here except me!
Here, write a letter to
mister William Ozanne.
"Sir, you may return here."
"And if at that time Marianne still desires to marry you."
I will permit the bands to be published.
"And in due course -
- and in the presence of her family,
and in her own church..."
- I don't intend to wait for any letter!
When does the Green Dolphin sail?
- On the 31.
- And I forbid you...
- Then I'm going on the 31!
- I forbid it!
Log of the Green Dolphin.
Sunday. 172nd Day out of St Pierre.
Weather fine.
Lord hear our prayer.
Eternal Lord which alone spreadeth out the heavens -
- and ruleth the raging of the sea.
Receive into thy Almighty protection.
The persons of us.
Thy servants.
And the ship in which we serve.
Amen.
Look alive you buckeyed nincompoop!
Is it land or is it a cloud?
Land ho!
Land at starboard!
Mr Johnsson!
Anchor it with four topsails and yip
Ay ay Sir!
Start the rollers and get up.
Come on you sons of a seacook and get up there!
Now hear me closely!
William Ozanne has no reason
to expect you on this ship.
When we tie up at Wellington -
- you can shut yourself up in your cabin.
And three days later we'll be on our way again.
You don't want me to marry William Ozanne?
The letter I gave your father was handed to me -
- by a bleary-eyed William Ozanne.
Just out of a stinking saloon.
Surely it was written more in whiskey than in ink!
Had I known it was a proposal of marriage to ye -
-  I'd have torn it to bits and flung it to the seven winds!
So help me I would!
If William were a fine strong character -
- what would he need me for?
For the very reason that he sent for me -
- is because he knows I can save him from himself.
Captain O'Hara, I've loved you since the
first day I came aboard the Green Dolphin.
But there isn't anything you can say to change me.
I'll make a fine man of William.
I will.
Drink up lads!
The Green Dolphin's pulling in if you wants to meet her.
That proves no second sight.
The natives could have just sighted the ship -
- rounding The Three Kings and sent word over.
Now, if she brings a letter from Marguerite...
That's different.
Come on, let's see.
Look.
Look there.
It can't be.
She came!
It's Marguerite!
Look again.
Marianne?
You stupid fool!
Did you put the wrong name in that drunken letter?
But even if I did -
- why should Marianne come?
Did Marianne ever show any signs
of being in love with you?
I think -
- perhaps she did.
Go on.
Wave to her
Keep waving.
Wave your arm off.
I can't marry her. I'm not in love with her!
Are you gonna send a girl like that back home -
- turned down by a drunken young jackass too
tipsy to remember the right name of the girl he loved?
No, you won't do that.
I might do it in the name of truth and common sense.
But you haven't got either the strength or the cruelty.
Now listen!
Go to her, put your arms around her.
Make her feel that you want her.
And don't ever let down.
And remember, her name is Marianne.
I hate what I'm gonna do, but I do it!
I'll marry her, just as my father married.
Out of pity.
And don't worry, I'll go through with it.
Good luck, Mam.
Congratulations, Sir.
Mister Morgan!
All hands -
- spice the main braize.
And a double eggnog to all of ye!
Thank you, captain O'Hara.
Thank you for my beautiful wedding.
Now with certain documents to be signed -
- and since we set sail with the sunrise tide -
- would you mind lending me your new husband for a thrice?
Take him captain, with all my worldly goods I hold him in debt.
I seem to recall the best man didn't kiss the bride!
You don't like me, do you?
Please, Mrs Ozanne.
It's not that, I'm ...
I'm anxious about you.
Anxious?
I've been very close to your -
- husband for several years now.
He has changed since you knew him.
Mr Haslam, I'm quite capable
of handling my own family.
I merely suggest for both your sakes that -
- you be patient with him.
Oh, I'll be patient.
I have no idea that my husband
loves me to distraction.
Actually, he's never known what real love is.
And I did not travel halfway -
- around the world expecting any miracle to have improved him.
Belive me, I ...
... I only want to help you.
You can, now.
Is there any reason why we can not leave
for the settlement at once instead of tomorrow?
You see, I refuse to spend my wedding
night anywhere except in the home my
husband has provided for me.
Oh, put it in there!
And as for father, poor darling,
he's as blind as a bat.
Here, in the cupboard.
But of course, that has been coming on for so long.
By now he hardly knows whether he can see anything or not.
And Marguerite, is she well?
A good deal has changed from
the young girl you remember.
And like so many beautiful women -
- she's become spiritually lazy.
She hasn't married?
Well, she has had many offer.
But I don't believe she has been able
to summon the necessary emotion.
Hine-Moa, in the bedroom please.
Mr Haslam?
Who's idea was it shipping your
timber over land on those wagons?
It's the only way to ship timber.
Don't you know that it is always cheaper
to transport bulky goods by water?
Excuse me.
Now look here, Marianne. Tai knows the timber business.
And I know the shipping business.
- Sit down, Mr Haslam.
- Thank you.
Oh, that will be all, Hine-Moa, thank you.
You should build barges. Large ones.
Float your timber to the sea down that river. From
there you can ship it to any place in the world.
Yes, I think that is quite possible.
Well, it will cut your delievery costs by two thirds.
I believe they would.
Now, Mrs Ozanne, I'm sure that you will excuse me.
Yes of course, Mr Haslam.
This is my wedding night.
Miss Marguerite.
This one's in Mr Ozanne's handwriting.
It must be important.
Mrs Metivier, I want you.
My daughter.
Marguerite.
I have something to say.
Mostly Octavius for you.
I want Marguerite to hear it too.
Don't talk, Sophie dear!
When I married you, Octavius -
- I did not love you.
The marriage was forced on me by my parents.
Against my will.
Mama!
I was in love with another man.
I came to you Octavius with a broken heart.
Hating you.
But from the very beginning you were kind to me.
Thoughtful, generous.
And so I began to realize -
- that your love was bigger
than anything I had ever felt.
I was humble.
And frightened in its presence.
But still I did not love you.
Dear, my dear!
There's no need to talk, no need to tell.
And as the years went on -
- something began to grow in my heart.
At first respect.
Then gratitude.
And the dashing young prince I once loved -
- faded from my dreams.
And suddenly -
- before my eyes -
- you Octavius.
Feeble sized without much hair.
No longer young.
But more splendid -
- than any dream lover a girl have ever had.
Do you know what I'm saying?
Do you, Marguerite?
Yes, yes I'm trying to.
I've come to love your father.
With a love so deep.
So great.
- that nothing on Earth can compare.
Mama!
I know what you mean.
Apply it to your own life.
To your own lost love, my dear child!
And now, Octavius.
My dear one, I've always known, all about it.
Octavius!
Yes, even before I married you!
My eyes were quite good then.
Remember?
So it was impossible for me to mistake
the way you looked when his name was mentioned.
Yes, Marguerite.
I've always known your mother's
beautiful and honourable secret.
That's why I always did
what I could for William.
William?
Then ...
I was in love with William's father.
And you?
You knew always?
If I had thought that Edmond
Ozanne would make you happy -
- I would never have married you.
But I did not believe in his love.
But I did believe in mine!
I believed I'd be a better
husband. A better father.
Octavius!
You are wonderful!
Sophie.
I knew!
Even though -
- you never told me before.
Just when.
You began to love me.
Oh, Sophie!
Sophie, Sophie!
I'm so proud!
And happy!
That you did tell me!
At last.
Leave me alone with her, dear.
Leave us together.
Marguerite.
Please, little one!
Come on, read your letter, maybe it will help.
Read it to me, please?
"My dear sister-in-law."
"I hasten to write you -
- that Marianne will go to Wellington soon -
- where she will have the best of care -
- for the arrival of our child."
"Hoping this finds you" ...
My daughter.
May I go to my father now?
Your father does not need you now.
Quietly -
- he has joined your mother.
God rest his soul.
Reverend Mother, Reverend Mother!
Somebody's knocking on the old door.
It must be Saint Peter!
Saint Peter?
Saint Peter! Come, you can hear him yourself!
I hear nothing?
But I heard Saint Peter knocking!
Plese, may I unlock the door?
It is unlocked.
I unlocked it myself 40 years ago.
Open it yourself, if you wish.
Pick her up.
Bring her to my room.
Thank you, Reverend Mother, thank you!
My poor dear child.
Help me, help me, I'm all alone now.
I'll try my child.
There's no one to turn to.
I'm completely lost!
I can't think.
It's my mind.
I can't think. I can't think.
Others have passed through
the same dark way.
There's no way for me to live.
You'll find a way.
Child.
Your tragedy is not unique in human history.
I needed my father and my mother because -
- because the man I loved turned away from me.
And now, because your parents are gone -
- because your earthly lover has failed you -
- you imagine that God has also
withdrawn His presence?
Yes!
The way the in which the human race
perpetuate its scorn of Our The Mighty God -
- is quite deplorable.
Come!
Let's see if you can stand up.
Yes, I can stand, I can walk, I can run.
And if I could fly it wouldn't help.
Let us see if you can pray!
Thank you, Reverend Mother.
Oh, Marguerite?
Marguerite?
I have a little book here.
I read it myself when I was about your age.
Read it!
Then - we may talk again!
That's a nice job of loading, William!
Cleverly planned.
Yeah, my wife's idea.
This was hers idea, not yours I suppose, the
two of you sat up all night arguing about it?
Tai, I promised you I'd stick to my
bargain but I didn't agree to like it.
Yes, Mr Haslam, you've come to
apologize for William again?
No.
I've brought you a gift.
Thank you, Mr Haslam!
Thank you!
Why do you dislike me so much?
Cause you have too much influence with William!
I've only been able to influence
William on only one thing.
Not to give up when he takes on a job.
Alright, I failed in my marriage.
And you think I'm making you
the scapegoat for my failure?
Your marriage is not a failure!
My husband hates me!
If I told you that hatred -
- was only the reverse side of love -
- you'd ridicule me as usual.
It's not true.
You can no more separate love from hatred -
- than you can separate the two sides  of a coin.
To possess one is to possess the other.
But I don't want scientific explanations.
What do you want?
What do I want?
I love my husband to the point of agony.
Yet there's no brightness,
no warmth in our lives.
What do I want?
Tell me, Mr Haslam.
Have I been completly wrong
in my handling of William?
Or isn't it true that he is
infinitely a finer and better person?
That's very true, he has improved!
But you think he would be happier if -
- I was more submissive and helpless.
It would be a strange way to wane
a husband away from his weaknesses.
- by developing weaknesses of my own.
Marianne? Marianne?
William?
About last night ...
I'm sorry, Marianne!
William, have I been a bad influence on you?
No man could have a better wife!
Perhaps ...
Perhaps the boy will help you when he comes?
You sure it's gonna be a boy?
I believe you'd rather have a girl?
It's going to be a boy, I know it!
William.
Please let Mr Haslam take the barges this time.
Stay here with me.
Cutting the timber is Tai's job.
Taking it to market is mine.
You know The Green Dolphin be
waiting at the sea coast for this timber.
Captain O'Hara is expecting me. I can't let him down!
William, William, what's happened to us?
Even when we're in each other's arms -
- there always seem to be a thousand miles between us!
Look, Marianne.
I've been a clumsy fool and I've made you wretched.
If you forgive me, I promise I'll try to do better.
Yes, yes, William!
Goodbye, Marianne.
Forward!
So we're left alone together.
Not for the first time.
As a rule I see very little of you on these occasions.
Perhaps this time I shall see more?
Mr Haslam, will you please make
those natives stop singing?
No, that is the chant of the earthquake God.
The native's believe there
is to be an earthquake.
But William does not believe it.
And I imagine you don't belive it?
But when your house starts shaking -
- stand in the nearest doorway.
And yell for me!
The men have stopped working.
Go and see what's happened.
We should see the coast around the next bend.
Big sea!
Yeah.
Watch out! Watch out!
My son!
I shall lose my son!
You'll have your son.
No, it's too soon!
Tai, get a doctor!
This isn't a country where a doctor lives on the next street.
My son!
- I thought I'd at least ...
- Marianne, listen to me!
You'll have your child, I know what's to be done.
What?
Oh no, no!
You've got to trust me!
Remember this is the sort of thing
that happens to women who chose to
live in the backblocks.
And remember you chose it.
Oh, I trust you!
I will try to give -
- to give as little trouble as possible.
First news from the backblocks.
Horrible disaster.
The Green Dolphin is missing.
Here you are, first
news from the backblocks.
Horrible disaster,
The Green Dolphin is missing.
For three weeks only meager details.
The worst catastrophe
in New Zealand history.
Exquisite!
Now you look a bit more like your old self!
This is no time for compliments, Mr Haslam!
Tell me, is there any definite news of William?
Yes, this time there is definite news.
Your husband is alive, he's quite safe.
The barges were wrecked in the tidal wave
but he was able to make his way into Wellington.
You're not lying?
You swear you are telling the truth -
- William is alright?
I'd give you my word, now be calm!
But I am calm!
I have complete control of myself.
My mental and physical condition is remarkable, Mr Haslam.
It's no good, Marianne.
In this situation we can't go back to where we were!
Why not be friends?
I'm not aware we're not friends!
William!
Marianne, what a terrible time you've had!
- But William, there...
- There were so many days -
- before I knew that anyone here was alive!
I'm in such a filthy state.
I should have washed and changed.
- But I...
- But you were so anxious to see your child.
Well William, there she is!
She?
She! Is it a girl?
Yes, I'm afraid it is.
Why wasn't I told? A girl!
I had no idea your daughter
would mean so much to you!
You can tell she's gonna be fair haired!
Look at those eyes!
Yes, I've named her Marguerite Veronica.
But we'll call her Veronica?
Time baby's bath!
You may take her, Hine-Moa.
What's wrong, William?
Marianne.
Captain O'Hara is dead.
Dead?
Drowned.
And the Green Dolphin?
That's gone too.
Tell me!
The Green Dolphin was wrecked by the tidal wave.
I... I swam out with a rope.
How dared you, you
might have been drowned!
You should have thought
of your wife and your child!
Captain O'Hara insisted
on being the last ashore.
He stood on the quarter
deck bellowing orders.
Then suddenly before you
could say "Jack Robinson".
The Green Dolphin heeled over -
- and was gone.
And him with it.
I swam out again.
I couldn't save him.
But I think he knows I tried!
And you have paid your debt to him.
I'm proud of you William!
Captain O'Hara!
Green Dolphin.
The last tie with -
- home gone.
Everything else is gone too, Marianne.
Years of hard work destroyed in a single day.
We begin again.
We begin again, William.
And we'll do better!
We certainly will!
The several passing years see New Zealand -
- swept by the fierce tides of a raw new world -
- raging in violent ebb and flow.
"MAORI WAR BREAKS OUT AGAIN"
"NATIVES BURN VILLAGE NEAR AUCKLAND"
"TROOPS TO DEFEND WELLINGTON"
"Mr Haslam."
"A native friend of yours sends secret warning" -
- "to expect hostilities in
your neighborhood at any moment."
William?
Tell me, do you think
this is reassuring enough?
"My dear Marguerite, do not
worry about the Maori war."
"True, it still goes on up... north."
"Because the natives who want to
sell their land to the white settlers" -
- "are now killing Maoris who don't want to sell."
"But the new governor expect to
work out a treaty of peace" -
- "which is probably accomplished by now".
Aren't you a bit too optimistic,
even for Marguerite?
Peace can be arranged!
I could do it if I were the governor.
You probably could!
Hello there!
Uncle Tai!
Well, you didn't come in to see me today!
I've got some news for you.
Let's go inside.
Heavy fighting has broken out again.
Marianne and Veronica must
leave for Wellington at once.
Why?
But the peace terms?
The governor has blundered badly.
We have men and guns, we will fight!
You must take Veronica to Wellington!
We'll build a stockade around the house.
And turn this place into a fort?
- Certainly!
- That would -
- be the worst possible mistake.
To show our friendly Maoris we don't trust them.
You argue with your wife.
She never would listen to me.
You must take Veronica to Wellington,
don't you see that?
I see nothing of the sort!
Veronica and I stay here!
Stop and think, Tai, you realize that I'm right!
Veronica and I are far more likely
to be murdered on a long journey to Wellington!
And if we stay here we'll be well protected.
There's something about that, Tai!
As always I bow to your clever reasoning.
May I do anything for you in Wellington?
Are you going to Wellington?
Yes, I am.
William, may I see you outside for a moment, please?
Marianne, please!
What is all this?
Are you trying to get rid of me?
- Good night, daddy!
- Good night, sweetheart!
- Good night, mama!
- Good night, dear!
Good night, Hine-Moa!
Well, pray for the best.
Tai's gone and without him we'd never dare make the trip to Wellington.
Then get out every man you have and start building that stockade!
Come Veronica, your dinner.
Come here.
Veronica! Veronica dear!
Come, you must wake up.
No, no, there...
Marianne!
Can you forgive me, William?
It was all my fault.
I wouldn't go to Wellington.
I made you build that stupid stockade.
No, you didn't make me. You honestly convinced me.
So don't blame yourself only.
We're both guilty.
I'm afraid, daddy!
Shhh!
Well thank heavens you're alright!
- How did you get through?
- Be quite and listen!
When I went to Wellington for help -
- I expected this invasion from the northern tribes.
But our own Maoris turned on us!
And for good reason. Now that's our chance.
Our own Maoris are out there among the others.
And they're still my friends. They were strong enough to get me in here.
Oh William, then everthing ...
Whether they have the influence to get us out I don't know.
They're in council now, that's why it's so quiet.
But what if they won't?
It's a chance we'll have to take!
Chance? But Veronica!
179 pounds 11 shillings 3d.
That's a good account.
Well, how do we stand financially?
I should say we have enough capital in the
bank to start ourselves another future.
No, we can forget that one.
You know, I've been thinking about our future.
The Maori wars are getting worse.
I think it would be best if -
- well, if we were to leave here and go south.
South Island?
I've been thinking I said, I haven't decided!
Let's talk it over.
John Martin...
What are the timber prospects on South Island?
Bad!
But there's a great future for sheep farming.
Sheep?
What exactly have you got in mind, Marianne?
To sell our land and take a ship to the
South Island. Find some good pasture land.
Spend our capital on it, hire expert labour.
Soon there be nothing about sheep we won't know.
Why sheep? I know timber, I love it.
Why can't we stick to timber?
Because there's a bigger future in wool!
How do you know that?
Because I've an instinct for these things.
An instinct for making money.
Personally I can never think of sheep -
- without connecting them with Job in the Bible.
One time Job lost all his sheep; had boils.
That was just one bad year.
How much of this is your business instinct
and how much is the safety of Veronica?
It's mostly for the child's sake.
Ever since the Maori trouble she's
been having dreadful nightmares.
You know that, William.
She has a morbid curiosity now
about fighting and soldiers.
I want to take her where there is no fighting.
Yes Tai, it's uncanny the way you
always bring a hammer down on the nail.
It's really for Veronica's sake!
Well?
Well William?
If it is for Veronica's good
that we should go south -
- we go south!
Here's to the flocks and herds of Job.
And no boils!
We'll go as soon as possible.
There's a great suffering among my
Maori friends caused by the Colonials.
They need help.
I'm going back to them with medical supplies.
Tai, we can not wait indefinitely ...
I will not prevent you from leaving whenever you like!
And all my best wishes will go with you.
But you are our partner!
Surely you'll come with us?
You don't know me very well, Marianne.
I find very little value in life -
- beside from my personal independence.
That you and William should
join me in my lumber business -
- that was one thing.
That I should follow along at the tail end of your -
- biblical migration like a tamed tabby cat -
- that is another.
There you are, darling!
Say goodby to uncle Tai, Veronica.
I'll go aboard and see about the luggage.
Oh, and Marianne, try not to fight with
Tai your last five minutes together!
I'll try!
Come, sweetheart.
Are you really hurt that I'm not coming with you?
Yes, I am.
I thought you had a real affection
for William and Veronica!
I have.
And for you.
Then why not come with us?
The reason I gave.
You spoke of trailing after us.
You'd be what you've always been,
a central figure in the picture.
I thought Marianne Ozanne must always be there.
No, I... I know myself better than I used to.
I'm sure.
I really don't how I should manage without you.
I doubt it.
Don't talking of losing your independence.
A man in love has no independence worth mentioning.
Yes, Marianne, I love you.
I have for years.
You certainly didn't love me when I first came out here.
Long before that.
At home on the island.
When you were a little girl in your teens.
I used to worship you from a distance.
On the island?
William never told me you came from St Pierre!
That's no coincidence.
Captain O'Hara brought us to the same place -
- for similar reasons.
I can never go home there.
I began by loving you as a child.
I love your faults as well as your virtues.
Have I still so many faults?
At least I'm not proud now, am I?
No, you're not.
I love you for that too because -
- I think I had something to do with it.
Yes, you did.
A great deal.
Everything.
And that's why you love me.
Oh, you hated me too!
Remember what I said that you could
no more separate love from hatred
than separate the two sides of a coin?
Well, you hated me because I saw
too much of your real self.
Then I found when you were with me -
- everything was alright.
You learned humility from me.
And you love me, don't you?
Tai, I love William with
every fibre of my being.
But I love you too.
For the qualities you have that
I've tried to develop in him.
Yes, Tai, I love you.
But I belong to William.
You still believe that?
It's true!
William's love is all I ever wanted.
That's why I'm not going with you.
You'll have more chance of getting what you want if -
- he has no one to turn to but you.
But I have his love.
Don't be too sure.
This newfound humility of yours only goes skin deep.
You have made progress, but -
- your battle isn't won yet.
Goodbye, Marianne.
I won't forget you.
Ever.
If I believed in souls -
- I'd say that yours and mine are very long aquaintances.
Veronica is in the cabin.
Goodbye, William.
You're glad to get rid of a
couple of trouble makers, eh?
I'd not have missed these years for anything!
Not always happy.
All those rousing arguments.
I wonder how you stood it?
Well, the adjustments interested me.
You've made a good job with Marianne.
Most people including Marianne would
say she'd made a good job out of me.
Only a fool could have made
that blunder that you did.
But only a very fine man could
have saved her from disaster.
Disaster, Marianne?
If you hadn't turned your life
into a magnificent lie -
- she'd have certainly floundered.
And if you hadn't made that idiotic
mistake in a girl's name I'd never known her.
Ready Mr Ozanne?
We're about to cast off, Sir.
Well.
Reverend Mother?
What is it, sister Angelique?
A lady to see you, Reverend Mother.
She sends you this little book.
Sit down, Marguerite.
It's a long time.
You've read it?
Over and over!
To see if there is some way for me to live.
I seem to have given up
all my girlhood friends.
I've dropped out of all life.
I belong to nothing or nobody.
And yet -
- you do not look so very unhappy?
I'm not unhappy!
I'm only... lost.
But I want to feel once again -
- that I'm following some pattern of life.
Sometime God permits deep
disappointment to enter our lives.
In order to open up our eyes to what He wants us to do.
And so great is His magnanimity -
- that if we come at last to His feet.
- I think he cares little how we came.
Am I good enough, Reverend Mother?
Ask yourself, my daughter.
Keep asking yourself.
- This is the residency of Mrs William Ozanne?
- Yes?
With compliments of Captain Fawcett.
Of Her Majesty's ship Brighton.
What you doing tonight?
What sauce, I wouldn't go out with you!
Besides, we've got a party on!
Thank you, Lucy.
Listen mama, Mr Anderson
is making a speech!
Yes dear.
Gentlemen!
Two years ago this group sponsored the
organization of a steam ship company.
Ay, look what the shares are quoted at today!
Of course the original idea came from Mr William Ozanne.
You know...
I'm thinking he must have
Scottish antecedence!
Gentlemen!
I give you the health of the
most popular man in Dunedin!
Mr William Ozanne.
To William Ozanne!
Thank you, gentlemen!
I think your toast might well be to New Zealand.
Or to the steamship itself,
which Mr Anderson so cannily puts -
- has done so much good for all of us.
But certainly instead of me -
- I think your toast should
have been given to my wife.
Because in New Zealand or Timbuktu -
- with sheep, wool, steam or with timber -
- any man influenced by such a woman -
- must succeed!
It is to her that I owe whatever
small accomplishments I've made.
There, Veronica.
You've heard your father's speech.
Now you must go to bed.
Come along!
How was the party?
Beautiful, weren't you listening?
Yes.
All those things you said about me -
- made me blush!
But they were true!
But you were generous.
Far too generous.
William.
There's something I want to talk to you about.
Let's sell out here and go home!
To our real home, St Pierre!
Back to St Pierre?
Why?
Because of... of Marguerite.
Marguerite?
But, she's going to become a nun!
But she's still a novice.
And we can see her before
she takes her final vows.
But why?
Here we have everything!
The finest house in Dunedin.
But William!
This isn't really our home!
There's that beautiful house in
St Pierre, empty, waiting for us.
Then there's the family business
that you can now run most efficiently.
But I can't go back.
There's the little matter of
desertion from Her Majesty's Navy.
Come here.
There.
It's taken me more than a year to arrange that.
"With due consideration it has been decided -
- that William Ozanne is to be allowed
to resign honourably from the Royal Navy.
And in regard to the charges of desertion
it has instead been officially pronounced
involuntary absence from duty"
Think what home would mean to Veronica!
The opportunities she can have.
But mostly William, it's Marguerite.
My own sister.
You never knew what it
cost me to leave my home.
To come out to this new country to marry you.
I want to go home, William!
I do so want to go home!
May I look now?
No, not yet!
Now?
No, no, no!
Now!
That's where mama was born.
But how will Father Christmas
know we moved from New Zealand?
Oh, he has ways of finding out!
Miss Marianne!
For the love of God!
No, no, Miss Metivier, no!
Do you think you could find a dolly at Grandpa's office?
I wouldn't be at all surprised!
Goodbye sweetheart!
Goodbye.
Four sheets -
- twelve pillow slips, embroidered.
Here Veronica!
See you may help mama.
Take this into your bedroom -
- and put it on the bed, dear.
Four linen sheets.
Oh, there's a tear in this one.
Very well, put it aside.
What about my letter?
The tide was out -
- and the young man is already back.
The young man delievered your letter to the Mother Superior.
And it will reach Miss Marguerite at once.
What is it, dear?
Look mama!
Well, where did you find it?
In this box.
"Dear Marguerite.
This necklace will say I have always loved you.
Wait for me.
When I come home I will ask your father for your hand in marriage.
William."
May I wear it?
May I?
Yes dear.
Look, Mrs Ozanne, I found these
two embroidered pillow cases.
I suppose you used these
when you were children.
This one will come in very well for Veronica.
After all her name is Marguerite.
Good evening, Mrs Metivier!
Where is Mrs Ozanne?
In her room.
She is not feeling well, Sir.
Too much unpacking in
my way of thinking, Sir.
Hello, my dear!
Tired yourself out, did you?
I'm tired too.
Father's business is quite
a terrifying institution.
What's the matter, Marianne?
Is it... is it Marguerite?
Have you heard from her?
Yes, I've heard from Marguerite.
Tomorrow she is to become a nun.
It would seem we arrived just in time.
I found this today.
This was written a long time ago, Marianne.
But you loved Marguerite!
You loved her!
But that's all passed now.
But when you wrote my father you lied.
You asked for my hand in marriage.
I didn't lie.
Listen to me, Marianne, I love you.
Listen to more lies?
You never loved me.
You loved her!
But you sent for me, why?
It wasn't a lie.
Why did you send for me?
I'll tell you, Marianne.
Now I must tell you.
I never wanted you to know, never though you'd find out.
But now.
What did you never want me to find out?
That I accidentally wrote your name instead
of Marguerite's in the letter to your father.
You accidentally wrote my name?
Now our whole marriage has just been -
- a slip of the pen?
Marianne.
Does Marguerite know of -
- of your slip of the pen?
No, absolutely not!
I never even as much as hinted anything.
Please believe me, Marianne.
I never told a living soul.
Oh, that's not quite true.
I told Tai Haruru, I had to tell him.
Tai Haruru knew?
He knew that you hated me?
I thought I had reached the lowest depths of degradation.
But I didn't expect this!
So Tai knew?
Of course he knew.
And now I understand everything.
Why, you would never have married me
if he hadn't forced you into it.
Would you've, William?
Oh William.
William, don't ever ever -
-speak to me again!
Good morning, Mrs Metivier.
Has Mrs Ozanne come downstairs yet?
She left the house an hour ago, Sir.
Miss Marguerite takes her vows
to the church today.
Have you forgotten, Sir?
Thank you.
- Oh, Marianne!
- Marguerite!
My dear, even when you were on
the other side of the world -
- I always felt you near to me!
Marguerite?
Yesterday I found a letter
William sent you with a necklace.
He intended to ask you
to come to New Zealand.
But when he wrote father he put in my name by mistake.
Then when I came instead of you -
- he married me.
Out of pity.
Oh, Marguerite, don't you hear me?
Don't you realise what I'm saying?
I knew you were in love with him.
I knew he had an affection for you.
I made myself believe it was only a childish infatuation.
So I fought you for him.
And I always thought I had won him fairly.
But he's never loved anyone but you.
Was it just an accident that you found the letter?
Just chance, do you think?
Perhaps there is less chance in life than we realise.
Perhaps it was intended to bring out the truth at last.
But when I think of what your life has been.
- Heartbreak.
- Do I look like a heartbroken woman?
But you're becoming a nun because William married me!
At first when you went away to marry him -
- and when your child was born -
- there was nothing left for me but chaos and hopelessness.
Oh, Marguerite!
Marguerite, can you ever forgive me?
There is no question of forgiveness.
Marianne?
Your husband is here in my room
He wants to talk to you.
He loves you.
I'll send him to you.
No!
I ask you to do this for me.
Tell William that I have outgrown the young selfish love of a girl in her teens.
That I found here what I've been searching for all my life.
Tell him this is the way everything was meant to be.
You were destined to accomplish his salvation.
I was destined for this.
I was swept up to thee by thy beauty.
And if I was once unhappy -
- today I am supremely happy!
Not because I have given up something.
But because I have been given everything.
Tell him this.
And then when you hear the chapel bells ringing -
- then bring him to see me.
Marianne, so there is to be no doubt in your mind.
I've come here to see Marguerite.
To tell her that as much as I loved her once -
- my love is now only for my wife.
What kind of love can that be?
Something manufactured out of your sense of duty?
It would be an unhappy world -
- if the only kind of love was the love of you.
Suppose I didn't love you when I married you?
You weren't a very lovable person then!
I didn't want to love you, I didn't try to.
But something great and wonderful was born out of our relationship.
By accomodating ourselves to each other's feelings -
- and learning to know each other's virtues.
This is far more worth having than any other love I can think of.
Marianne, don't you see -
- it was no slip of the pen that brought you to me?
It was something far greater than us!
Something beyond my control.
Why, I do love you, Marianne.
Now that I know how much -
- a whole new life is ahead of us!
Come with me to Marguerite so I can tell the truth.
So that you know that I -
- I only want you!
William!
This love of yours.
This love that grew out of our marriage?
Has it all the warmth and glory?
The passion?
And tenderness?
Everything that you once wanted love to be to you?
More than I ever dreamed of!
And now -
- with absolute truth between us -
- it will be as perfect love as there can be on this Earth.
Oh William!
William, I'm so proud of you.
Go now, my children.
And be investeded in happiness -
- of the congregation of the Sisters of St Peter.
May the blessing of almighty God -
- the Father, the Son and the Holy Ghost
descend upon you and remain forever.
Amen.
THE END
Watch Movies, TV Series & Live Sports
www.admitme.app