When you see a guy
reach for stars in the sky
You can bet that he's doing it
for some doll
When you spot a John
waiting out in the rain
Chances are he's insane
as only a John can be for a Jane
When you meet a gent
paying all kinds of rent
For a flat that could flatten
the Taj Mahal
Call it sad
Call it funny
But it's better than even money
That the guy's only doin' it
for some doll
Your eyes are the eyes
Of a woman in love
And, oh
How they give you away
Why try to deny
You're a woman in love
When I know very well
What I say
I got the horse right here
The name is Paul Revere
And here's a guy that says
if the weather's clear
Can do, can do
This guy says the horse can do
If he says the horse can do
I'm pickin' Valentine
'cause on the mornin' line
The guy has got him figured
at five to nine
But look at Epitaph
He wins it by a half
According to this here
in the Telegraph
For Paul Revere I'll bite
I hear his foot's all right
Of course it all depends
if it rained last night
I know it's Valentine
The morning works look fine
You know, the jockey’s brother's
a friend of mine
Just a minute, boys
I got the feed box noise
It says the great grandfather
was Equipois
I tell you Paul Revere
Now this is no bum steer
It's from a handicapper
that's real sincere
I give you Valentine
'cause on the mornin' line
The guy has got him figured
at five to nine
So make it Epitaph
He wins it by a half
According to this here
in the Telegraph
- Epitaph
- Valentine
Paul Revere
I got the horse
Right here
Follow the fold
and stray no more
Stray no more
Put down the bottle
and we'll say no more
Follow, follow
Before you take another swallow
Follow the fold
and stray no more
Tear up your poker deck
And play no more
Follow, follow the fold
Friends, my name is Sarah Brown.
This is no place to make a speech,
and I'm not going to try.
You don't want to be told
how unhappy you are.
about the emptiness of your lives.
You who drink too much...
you who gamble at cards,
dice and horse racing...
let us help you not to lose
your hard-earned money...
in gambling dens
and bookie joints.
This doll has captured
my attention.
Let us give you the strength
to stop your drinking and gambling.
She has lost me.
Let us welcome you
to the Save-A-Soul Mission.
- Just around the corner.
- Come to me!
- Open all day and night.
- You'll call me a liar.
- A special meeting this Thursday.
- You'll think I ain't telling the truth.
Today I'm giving away solid gold watches
for one dollar each.
That's right, my friends.
A solid gold watch for one buck.
Remember, all that glitters
is not gold.
More to be desired are the judgments
of Heaven. Gold is not enough.
You say it's not enough?
Today only, I include a nail brush
with a solid ivory top.
Then, my friends, a built-in,
genuine magnetic compass.
How often, when you're brushing your
nails, do you wonder where you're going?
Which way is north,
east, south or west?
Which way are you going?
Down, down, down, or up to salvation?
Come to the mission and find out
absolutely free!
Absolutely free!
The nail brush is absolutely free!
Now, don't crowd. Don't push.
There's plenty of room for everybody.
There's room for everybody
in the kingdom of Heaven too.
Let's pack up.
Did you notice a lot of them stayed
till you were halfway through your talk?
If we could only sell them
salvation for a buck...
solid gold with an ivory top
and a built-in compass.
You don't suppose by any chance those
watches could really be solid gold?
Uncle Arvide, don't you dare!
That's right, my friends,
a solid gold watch for one buck!
Harry the Horse!
Benny Southstreet!
Since when do you yell out
a person's name...
in the open air
which is full of police?
It was a friendly impulse.
I lost my head.
If I do not like you so much,
this would now be a fact.
You know Nicely-Nicely Johnson,
of course.
- Of course. How goes everything?
- Nicely-nicely, thank you.
I have been waiting to hear
from Nathan Detroit.
What will be the location
of his crap game?
We don't know yet. Nathan's been
lookin' around, but he's hard to please.
The heat is on very hot around here,
and it is making Nathan sweat.
That's too bad, because I would dislike
to take my trade elsewhere...
but I am loaded
and lookin' for action.
I've just acquired 5,000 fish.
Five thousand?
If it can be told, where did you
take on this fine bundle of lettuce?
I have nothin' to hide.
I collected the reward
on my father.
It is an advantage
to have a successful father.
Nobody ever wanted my old man
for as much as 500.
I've worried about Nathan.
Harry the Horse is not the only one.
There's a lot of loose money around,
and everybody's lookin' for some action.
If Nathan doesn't find a place-
Why, Lieutenant Brannigan.
Mr. Southstreet,
it is Lieutenant Brannigan...
of the New York City
Police Department.
Have either of you seen
Nathan Detroit?
- Which Nathan Detroit is that?
- Your boss, Nathan Detroit!
The Nathan Detroit
who runs a floating crap game.
- Floating crap game?
- On a boat?
A crap game that moves
to a different spot every night...
so the police can't find it
and break it up.
Sounds like
a very difficult thing to do.
You should know,
since it's your job...
to rustle up the customers
and tell them where it is.
Especially with a famous detective
like you putting on the heat.
You can give just that message
to Detroit.
Tell him Brannigan says he's not gonna
find a spot for his crap game...
because everybody knows
Brannigan's put on the heat...
and Brannigan's breathing
down everybody's neck.
Nathan, you're lucky.
You just missed Brannigan.
I'm lucky.
I just missed Brannigan.
He left a message for you.
He said-
I am not going to find a place
for my crap game...
because everybody in town knows
that Brannigan has turned on the heat...
and that Brannigan is breathing
down everybody's neck.
That's what he said.
Have you tried
all the regular places?
Won't any of them take a chance,
seeing it's you?
Seeing it's me, no...
except one-
Joey Biltmore's garage.
Joey said he might take a chance
for 1,000 bucks.
- A thousand?
- In advance, and in cash.
He would not even take my marker.
This I do not believe-
that Joey will not take your marker.
You got no idea what a breath
this Brannigan has got.
After all, a marker's not just
a piece of paper saying...
"I owe you 1,000.
Signed, Nathan Detroit."
A marker is the one pledge
which a guy cannot welch on.
Never. It's like
not saluting the flag.
It does not seem possible-
me without a livelihood.
Why, I've been running the crap game
since I was a juvenile delinquent.
But the situation is desperate.
You have got to think of something.
My only thought
costs 1,000 bucks.
I cannot even afford to think.
I'm broke.
I'm so broke, I couldn't even buy
a present for Adelaide today.
Is it her birthday?
It is mine and Adelaide's
14th anniversary.
We are engaged 14 years today.
Nathan, you must concentrate
on a game.
The town is up to here with
high players. The Greek's in town.
- Brandy Bottle Bates.
- Scranton Slim.
I know, I know!
I could make a fortune...
but to make a fortune I need
a fortune- a thousand bucks!
Where do I get it?
The Biltmore garage wants a grand
But we ain't got a grand on hand
And they now have
a lock on the door
To the gym at Public School 84
There's the stock room
behind McCloskey's Bar
But Mrs. McCloskey
ain't a good scout
And things being how they are
The back of
the police station is out
So the Biltmore garage
is the spot
But the 1,000 bucks
we ain't got
Why, it's good
old reliable Nathan
Nathan, Nathan, Nathan Detroit
If you're lookin' for action
he'll furnish the spot
Even when the heat is on
it's never too hot
Not for good old reliable Nathan
For it's always just a short walk
To the oldest established
Permanent floating crap game
In New York
There are well-heeled shooters
everywhere, everywhere
And an awful lot of lettuce
For the fella
who can get us there
If we only had
a lousy little grand
We could be a millionaire
If the size of your bundle
you want to increase
I'll arrange that you go broke
in quiet and peace
In a hideout provided by Nathan
Where there are
no neighbors to squawk
It's the oldest established
permanent, floating
Crap game in New York
Where's the action
Where's the game
Gotta have the game
or we'll die from shame
Gentlemen, I am deeply touched
by your faith and loyalty.
Gentlemen, do not worry.
Nathan Detroit's crap game
will float again.
Guess who's sittin' in Mindy's
right now eatin' a steak breakfast.
- Hitler.
- Wrong! Sky Masterson.
Sky Masterson's in town.
This should be the greatest crap game
of your career.
Where's it gonna be?
City Hall, the Mayor's office.
- What time?
- We will leave you know, Angie.
Sky Masterson,
the highest player of'em all.
- What a spot I'm in.
- Does he bet higher than the Greek?
Why do you think
they call him Sky?
Once with my own eyes
I saw him bet 5,000 bucks...
that one raindrop would beat
another raindrop down the window.
Another time, he was sick
and would not take penicillin...
because he bet his fever
would go to 104.
- Always makes crazy bets like that.
- Did he win?
Him and his crazy bets.
He got lucky. It went to 106.
So? So why don't I bet him?
Why don't I bet him
1,000 bucks on something?
Max, what's the matter?
No Danish today?
It's a holiday in Denmark.
How do I know?
All these years
you've been bringing me Danish.
So we ain't got Danish today.
Today I'm bringing you cheesecake.
You want strudel instead,
I'll bring you strudel.
- I don't like strudel.
- So eat the cheesecake.
Live it up a little.
I do not understand you.
Everybody's crazy about Mindy's
cheesecake and strudel.
They must sell thousands
of portions every day.
That's just it.
Everybody's on cheesecake and strudel.
It makes me feel like
I'm playing the favorite.
Playing the favorite.
Nicely, Benny, I want you
to go into the kitchen...
and find out exactly how many pieces
of cheesecake they sold yesterday.
Also, how many pieces of strudel.
How much cheesecake?
How much strudel?
What do you want to know for?
I'm investigatin' for the FBI. Go!
Barrigan!
Stop breathin' down my neck!
- Why, Nathan!
- Adelaide! Doll!
Now, how could you think
I was Lieutenant Brannigan?
We don't even use
the same perfume.
I was kinda daydreamin', I guess.
I don't dream about detectives,
even in the daytime.
Do you know what I dream about?
You, and your career as a businessman
in a normal business.
And our career together
as a normal husband and wife.
- Gesundheit.
- Thank you.
Your cold's not getting any better.
It comes and goes, comes and goes.
It's just a chronic condition.
Even if it is, it sure hangs on.
Nathan, speaking
of chronic conditions...
happy anniversary.
Guess what's inside.
- A thousand bucks?
- I only wish it was.
Go on. Open it up.
"Mr. Nathan Detroit,
General Manager."
- General manager of what?
- Whatever you set your mind on.
I have faith.
Adelaide, I do not have
a present for you.
I don't mind if you
don't give me a present.
It makes me feel
like we were married.
Nathan, darling, there isn't anything
I couldn't do without...
just as long as you don't start
running that crap game again.
Crap game?
Adelaide, didn't I promise you?
- 1,200 cheesecake and 1,500 strudel.
- What?
Yesterday Mindy sold
1,200 cheesecake and 1,500 strudel.
More strudel than cheesecake.
Are you sure of this?
- Straight from the baker's mouth.
- What is this all about?
Statistics- things a businessman
has to have at his fingertips.
- Any news yet?
- Not yet. I will leave you know.
I'm gettin' impatient, Detroit.
- And what was that about?
- His wife's having a baby.
But why is he asking you?
He's nervous.
It's his first wife.
Look, I'm expecting a fellow
on an important business conference.
Suddenly I get a suspicion
you are trying to get rid of me.
No, doll. It's just that
this fellow does big business.
- Supermarket.
- Super, super.
With him business is business,
and dolls make him nervous.
Besides, you're late
for your rehearsal.
Nicely, you and Benny take Adelaide
to the Hot Box in a cab.
But it's only a couple of blocks.
The streets are covered with tourists,
and I do not want you molested.
Nathan, darling, you are the most
thoughtful man that ever lived.
- But who's gonna pay for the cab?
- I am, of course.
- Sky Masterson!
- Detroit!
Can I believe my eyes?
Is it really you?
- How goes your percentage of life?
- Not bad.
- And you?
- Healthy at the moment.
Sit for a minute. Relax. Talk.
Or maybe you're in a hurry.
My daddy always said there's only
one time a man should be in a hurry-
when the cops
are comin' up the stairs.
How about a cup of coffee?
Maybe a piece of cheesecake?
Thanks. I'm pleased to hear
things go well with you.
From communiqués
received in Las Vegas...
we understood that Lieutenant Brannigan
was corking up the town.
Who worries about Brannigan?
How was Vegas?
Paradise for two weeks.
For two weeks, I gambled in green
pastures, the dice were my cousins...
and the dolls were agreeable,
with nice teeth and no last names.
You are sure I cannot offer you
a piece of cheesecake or strudel?
No, thanks. I just ate.
How long are you in town?
Only for tonight.
Tomorrow I fly to Havana.
Sky, don't think I am a pest,
but do yourself a favor.
Eat this last little bite of cheesecake.
You will thank me.
Honestly, I couldn't swallow
a mouthful.
How is Adelaide?
Fine, fine.
I suppose one of these days
you'll be getting married.
- We all gotta go sometime.
- But we can fight it.
The companionship of a doll
is a pleasant thing...
even for a period of time
running into months...
but for a relationship that can last
through all the years of our life...
no doll can take the place
of aces back to back.
Still, you will admit that Mindy's
is the greatest cheesecake alive.
Gladly.
Furthermore, I am quite partial
to Mindy's cheesecake.
And yet, although
you might disagree...
many people prefer
Mindy's strudel to cheesecake.
Do you disagree?
It is my understanding that
the Constitution of the United States...
allows everybody the free choice
between cheesecake and strudel.
I would be interested to hear.
Offhand, would you say
that Mindy sells more cheesecake...
or more strudel?
Going strictly
by my own personal preference...
I'd say more cheesecake
than strudel.
For how much?
- What?
- For how much?
Why, Nathan, I never knew you
to lay money on the line.
You always take your bite
off the top.
A thousand bucks says that yesterday
Mindy sold more strudel than cheesecake.
- Let me tell you a story.
- Have we got a bet?
On the day I left home
to make my way in the world...
my daddy took me to one side.
"Son," my daddy says to me...
"I am sorry I'm not able to bankroll you
to a very large start...
but not having the necessary letters
to get you rolling...
instead I'm going to stake you
to some very valuable advice.
One of these days in your travels...
a guy is going to show you
a brand-new deck of cards...
on which the seal
is not yet broken.
Then this guy is going
to offer to bet you...
that he can make the jack of spades
jump out of this new deck of cards...
and squirt cider in your ear.
But, son,
you do not accept this bet...
because as sure
as you stand there...
you're going to wind up
with an ear full of cider."
Now, I do not suggest that you
have been clocking Mindy's cheesecake.
Would I do such a thing?
However, if you are
really looking for some action...
I will bet you the same 1,000 that you
cannot name the color tie you have on.
Have we got a bet?
No bet.
Polka dots!
In the whole world,
nobody but Nathan Detroit...
could blow 1,000 bucks
on polka dots!
- Hi, Sky.
- Nice to see you, Benny.
- How goes it, Sky?
- Healthy at the moment.
- With you, Nicely?
- Nicely-nicely, thanks.
What's the matter?
You look sick.
A temporary disorder.
The cheesecake backed up on him.
Maybe that's why they told us
they sell more strudel than cheesecake.
Adelaide gave us
a message for you.
Pick her up at the Hot Box
after the show, and don't be late.
Yes, dear. I mean, okay.
"Yes, dear"? This is husband talk
if I ever heard it.
You are trapped, because Adelaide is
the kind of a doll...
that is most difficult to unload.
I don't want to unload her.
I love her.
Well, if a guy does not have a doll,
who would holler on him?
A doll is a necessity.
I am not putting
the knock on dolls.
They are just something to have around
only when they come in handy.
The proof that I am right is that dolls
are available all over the place...
as far as the eye can see.
Not dolls like Adelaide.
Nothing personal,
and no offense...
but figuring weight for age
all dolls are the same.
- All dolls are the same, huh?
- As far as the eye can see.
Then it seems the one place
a doll would come in handy...
would be on a trip to Havana.
This being the case,
how come you ain't got one?
- How come you are going alone?
- A matter of choice.
I choose to travel alone, but if I
wish to take a doll to Havana...
the supply is more
than Woolworth has got beads.
- Not high-class dolls.
- There's only one class.
Indivisible and interchangeable.
A doll is a doll-
all dolls, any doll, you name her.
Any doll?
Will you bet on that?
Would you bet a thousand bucks
that if I name a doll...
you can take the same doll
to Havana with you tomorrow?
You've got yourself a bet.
I name her.
- Her?
- Sergeant Sarah Brown.
Daddy, I got cider in my ear.
It is my fault, you know.
It's not the mission.
It's me.
I can't do the job that has to be done.
I'm a failure.
I'd be doing the right thing
if I resigned and went back to Boston.
Sarah, should you be able to bend
a solid gold watch?
- Of course not.
- That's what I thought.
Why do you want to go home? Because
there aren't any sinners in Boston?
What have I accomplished here?
Surrounded by thousands
of depraved characters...
and after months of hard work,
an empty mission.
I'm ashamed of you.
Just because the riffraff of Broadway
didn't break down that door...
the minute they heard
you were in charge of this mission.
These aren't small-town delinquents
who drink too much on Saturday night.
You're up against the devil's
first-string troops...
a whole army of devil's disciples!
Do you take sinners here?
At any time of the day or night, son.
Come right in and sit down.
- Cup of coffee and a donut?
- Just coffee, thanks.
I am not here
because I am poor and hungry.
Not for food, that is.
"Blessed are they which do hunger
after righteousness." Is that it?
"Hunger and thirst after righteousness."
Yes, sir, that's it.
My name's Arvide Abernathy.
The young lady at the desk
is Sergeant Sarah Brown.
To you, we're Brother Arvide
and Sister Sarah.
- Sit down, son.
- How do you do?
Brother Sky.
Hello, Sister Sarah.
Is that your name? Sky?
Sky Masterson.
What is it that troubles you,
Mr. Masterson?
- Brother Sky.
I gather you are not
in need of money.
I'm healthy at the moment.
It can change.
Are only the unhappy poor
welcome here?
What are you unhappy about, son?
Gambling.
Apparently, you're a successful gambler.
Is it wrong to gamble
or only to lose?
I better come back for help
when I'm broke.
Please don't misunderstand.
It's just so unusual for a successful
sinner to be unhappy about sin.
My unhappiness came up very suddenly.
Maybe it'll go away again.
We can keep you unhappy, son.
Give us a chance.
You don't look like a gambler at heart.
What made you take it up?
Evil companions.
Evil companions who are always
offering me sucker bets.
Just what is a sucker bet?
A bet that is reserved for suckers.
For a gambler to get sucked in
on such a bet is most humiliating.
But to lose it means you are marked
for a very long time as a chump.
So you must go all out
to win such a bet.
Is that so terrible,
to be marked as a chump?
Among my people, being a chump
is like losing your citizenship...
because a chump is an outsider...
a yokel who will buy
anything with varnish on it.
- Like a solid gold watch for a dollar?
- This is a real chump.
I think I'll get some rest
before we go out again.
Brother Sky,
I'm glad you found us.
Just stay and talk
to Sister Sarah.
Whatever your problems are,
she'll have the answers.
- I hope so.
- I know so.
If there's one thing
Sister Sarah never fails in...
it's solving
other people's problems.
What did he mean by that?
The way he said it- how you never fail
in solving other people's problems.
Haven't we changed places,
Mr. Masterson-
- Brother Sky.
- Brother Sky, aren't we-
Why do you have trouble
calling me Brother Sky?
Aren't we supposed
to be discussing your problems?
It just struck me that maybe
non-sinners also have problems.
If you are sincerely interested
in giving up gambling...
Mister- Brother Sky...
reading these pamphlets
will help you.
My daddy always said reading pamphlets
never made anybody give up anything.
Now, I had
a more personal help in mind.
We're having a midnight
prayer meeting on Thursday-
Thursday's the day after tomorrow.
Who's going to help me till then?
Well, our doors are always open.
Come in anytime.
You know what I think,
Sister Sarah?
You not only don't want to help me,
but for some reason you're against me.
I'm afraid that is true.
I don't trust you, Mr. Masterson.
- Brother Sky.
- Mr. Masterson.
You don't believe
I'm a sinner, do you?
I'm prepared to believe that you're
the biggest sinner I've ever met.
But you don't believe
I want to repent.
Is that it?
All of a sudden
you want a cup of coffee.
Did it ever occur to you some people
could be all repentance and no sin?
I may start a chain of missions
to help your kind.
Come, all ye repenters, and let us
bring a little sin into your life.
"There is no peace under the wicked.
Proverbs." This is wrong.
Let's say it's
a matter of opinion.
I made a statement of fact.
It's wrong.
How dare you!
Even if this is not a church,
it is a mission! How dare you blaspheme!
How dare you misquote the Bible!
"No peace under the wicked"
is not Proverbs. It's Isaiah.
- Of course it's Proverbs.
- Isaiah.
Chapter 57, verse 20 or 21.
Would you like to bet on it?
Not money. Just a nice sociable bet.
Isaiah?
There's only one thing that's been
in as many hotel rooms as I have-
the Gideon Bible.
Never tangle with me on the Good Book.
I must've read it a dozen times.
- If all that was no help to you-
- Who says it wasn't?
Once, in one of my blackest moments,
I came up with a three-horse parlay-
Shadrach, Meshach and Abednego.
Mr. Masterson,
why did you come in here?
- I told you I'm an unhappy sinner.
- Excuse me, but you're a liar.
Excuse me, but lying's
not one of my sins.
I am not in the market
for a one-dollar solid gold watch.
All right. We'll lay it on the line.
From now on, we'll deal the hand open.
Could you say that in English?
I'm sure you've earned your stripes
courageously, combatting the devil-
There's no need to be sarcastic!
But not on this battlefield
against the devil's first-line troops...
because you can't get
at the enemy.
- This mission is laying an egg.
- You have no way of knowing.
I've got lots of ways of knowing.
You are stuck with a store
full of repentance and no customers.
Without sinners to repent,
what is repentance? It doesn't exist.
So you're stuck with
a store full of nothing.
- Now do I give you a fair rundown?
- I wouldn't know.
I've never had a rundown.
Would you be open to a proposition?
I've had those. No.
Don't flatter yourself.
I'm talking business.
I am in a position
to supply you...
with the raw material you need
for your work- namely, sinners.
- How?
- That's my work.
When is this big midnight meeting?
Thursday, day after tomorrow.
I guarantee to supply that meeting
with at least one dozen genuine sinners.
Whether they repent or not
is up to you.
Thank you very much.
That seems to be a fair rundown.
Now, if you will excuse me.
Just a minute, Sister Sarah.
This is not a charity contribution.
This is a business transaction.
Something you want
for something I want.
And what is that?
Have dinner with me tomorrow night.
Why should that be
something you want?
Well, maybe because I think
I'll be hungry tomorrow night.
- Keep this. It's my marker.
- Your what?
My marker, my IOU for at least one
dozen sinners delivered as described.
I will pick you up here
tomorrow at noon.
- At noon to go to dinner?
- It takes time to get there.
We're going to eat at my favorite
restaurant, El Cafe Cubano.
El Cafe Cubano?
Where's that?
- Havana.
- Havana, Cuba?
- What other Havanas are there?
- You want to take me to dinner in Cuba?
They eat in Cuba, same as we do.
What do you take me for,
Mr. Masterson? A chump?
- Isaiah's on the other side.
- You get out of here!
What are they worth to you?
One dozen sinners ready for salvation.
A chicken salad in the tea room?
One last word, Sergeant.
I don't want you to walk out of this
room thinking the reason you're upset...
is because some blackhearted sinner
made improper advances-
It's none of your business
what I think.
To a virtuous young lady
with a shining white soul.
Any sinful thoughts that may be present
in this room at this time...
come out of you, doll, not me.
You're quite right. I'm nothing
but a repressed, neurotic girl.
I've read two books on the subject-
who is abnormally attracted to sin
and therefore abnormally afraid of it.
You're not the first man
to try that approach, Mr. Masterson.
I am happy to know I'm not the first man
who tried to approach in any way at all.
You're not even close.
I imagine by now you've succeeded
in blocking all possible approaches.
Except for a few that you
wouldn't know about, I'm afraid.
Well, of course, I only know the ones
on the outskirts of society.
What are the approaches like
on the inskirts?
All paved with
honorable intentions?
- I wonder what he'll be like?
- Who?
That upright, downright,
forthright square...
with his close-shaved chin up...
who right now somewhere is marching
along the proper approach to proper you.
- What'll he be like?
- He will not be a gambler for one thing.
I can name better than you can the
things he won't be, but what will he be?
- How will you know when he gets to you?
- Don't worry. I'll know.
For I've imagined
every bit of him
From his strong moral fiber
To the wisdom in his head
To the homey aroma
Of his pipe
You have wished yourself
a small town Galahad
The breakfast-eating
four-button type
And I shall meet him
When the time is right
I'll know
When my love comes along
I won't
Take a chance
For, oh
He'll be just what I need
Not some fly-by-night
Broadway romance
And you'll know at a glance
By the two pair of pants
I'll know
By his calm, steady voice
Those feet on the ground
I'll know
As I run to his arms
That at last
I've come home
Safe and sound
And till then
I shall wait
I'll be strong
For I'll know
When my love
Comes along
Mine will come
As a surprise to me
Mine, I'll leave to chance
And chemistry
- Chemistry?
- Yeah, chemistry.
Suddenly I'll
Know
When my love comes along
I'll know then and there
I'll know
At the sight of her face
How I care, how I care
And I'll stop
And I'll stare
And I'll know
Long before we can speak
I'll know
In my heart
And I won't ever ask
Am I right
Am I wise
Am I smart
But I'll stop
And I'll stare
At that face
In the throng
Yes, I'll know
When my love
Comes
Along
Mm-hmm.
Well, that makes it necessary
for me to drop back again.
Matthew 5:39.
Don't bother looking it up.
It's the bit about the other cheek.
I know, Joey.
But the thousand bucks
is guaranteed.
What? It's a bet I cannot lose.
I bet Sky Masterson he could not take
a certain doll to Havana with him.
Not this doll.
Not this doll!
And now for the grand finale
of our "Round the World" revue...
the Hot Box takes you
out to the alley...
with Miss Adelaide
and her Alley Kittens.
Hello!
One meow, two meow,
three meow, scat.
What's the initial
of my pet tomcat?
Is it A, B, C, D, E, F, G?
Is it H or J or L, M, N, O, P?
Is it L, M, N, O, P,
Q, R, S, T?
No, it's you!
You're the cat for me!
You know you've been mean to me
And you know
when you're mean to me
How it always makes me want to
Roam
And you know there's a danger
That some gentle stranger
Might pick me up
And make me feel
At home
So pet me, Papa
Papa, pet me nice
Pet me, Papa
Papa, melt the ice
And you know how
If you don't want me
out roaming the city
Talk to me pretty
Here, kitty, kitty
And pet me, Papa
Papa, pet me nice
Papa, pet me good
Pet me, Papa, proper
like you should
And you know how
If you care to keep me home
by the fire
Especially when
it's time to retire
Then pet me, Papa
Papa, pet me good
Warm up my saucer of milk
And maybe I'll purr
Lay out my cushion of silk
Don't rumple my fur
Just reach over
and pet me, Papa
- Papa, melt the ice
- Tasty as a mouse
If you don't want me
out roaming the city
Talk to me pretty
Here, kitty, kitty
Pet me, Papa
That's my good advice
Yeah, pet me, Papa
That'll get me
Pet me, Papa
Papa, pet me nice
Look, Joey, I gotta hang up.
Can I at least tell the guys that the
game will be at your garage tomorrow?
I would gladly pay you in advance, but
I won't get the money until tomorrow.
I've got to have time
to spread the word around.
Joey, listen to me.
Yes, Joey.
Drop dead, Joey.
Nathan, darling!
You got here early.
It's so thrilling
to find you waiting for me...
just like we were married
and I was coming home from work.
You wouldn't make me
stop working, would you?
That would be cruel.
A doll like you could earn good money
for another ten years easy.
Sweet. And you
were reading my book too.
See? I told you reading
don't make people go blind.
It's very interesting, isn't it?
What is? Oh, the book. Yeah.
The doctor gave it to me.
He said he thought it might help me
get rid of my cold.
With a book?
The doctor thinks my cold might
possibly be caused by psychology.
How does he know
you got psychology?
Nathan, everybody has got it.
And female psychology
explains why...
certain girls do
certain kinds of things.
It's all in the book.
Must be some book.
Would it, for instance,
tell you what kind of a doll...
would go for a certain kind of guy
which you wouldn't think would do so?
No matter how terrible
a fella seems...
you can never be sure
that some girl won't go for him.
Take us.
Get dressed.
We'll go eat.
Starting with next week...
I will be getting
a raise in salary.
Where does it say
what different kinds of dolls will do?
You're not even listening to me!
I will be making enough
so that we can finally get married.
What do you think?
Of course we'll get married
sooner or later.
After 14 years, it is already
too late to be sooner.
If it gets much later, sooner
will be too late even to be later.
Besides, I don't know
what to do anymore about Mother.
Mother?
What about your mother?
Well, this is something
that I haven't told you before...
but my mother
back in Rhode Island...
well, she thinks
that we are already married.
How could she think such a thing?
Maybe because I wrote her
that we were already married.
That would make her think so.
In Rhode Island, people do not
remain engaged for 14 years.
They get married!
So how come
it's such a small state?
Furthermore,
after about two years-
After about two years, we-
We got a divorce?
We had a baby.
- You wrote your mother we had a baby?
- I had to.
Mother kept after me, and finally
I just ran out of excuses.
And what type baby was it?
It was a boy.
I named it after you, Nathan.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Tell me, what has Nathan, Jr.
Been doing all these years?
Well, right now
he's in boarding school.
As a matter of fact,
I wrote Mother...
that he won the football game
last Saturday.
I wish I had a bet on it.
But, Nathan, I-
That isn't all.
You're not going to tell me
we also have got an Adelaide, Jr?
All these years, Nathan!
Mother believes
in big families...
and we had such an early start.
Just give me the grand total.
Five.
How could you do such a thing
to a nice, old broad like your mother?
Nathan, darling...
let's just us get married,
and I'll handle everything else.
Okay, doll, when we're ready.
Nathan, we are ready now.
We have been ready for 14 years.
All we need now is a license
and a blood test.
- Blood test?
- Don't worry. You've got blood.
What a city.
First I close my crap game,
and then they open my veins.
Nathan, you gave up the crap game.
Of course I did, doll.
And you know why? For you.
Because I love you.
Can I borrow some earrings?
It is customary, Laverne,
to knock...
when entering the private dressing room
of an engaged person.
As far as I'm concerned,
you are in here by yourself.
May I borrow some earrings?
- Diamonds or pearls?
- Diamonds.
In the top drawer of the trunk.
The big box.
Aren't they a little long, dear?
Remember, you've got a short neck.
He's a tall man.
You! I'm all dated up
with Society Max tomorrow night...
and he breaks it on account
of your silly crap game!
Adelaide, look at me.
I'm on my knees.
Oh, get up!
It reminds me of your crap game.
Adelaide, doll!
You're getting yourself upset
about nothin'.
It's a game I set up a long time ago.
I couldn't get out of it.
Understand?
Look, we love each other.
We're gonna get married.
We'll be happy.
Get out of my life,
Nathan Detroit!
I knew you'd understand.
It says here:
The average unmarried female
Basically insecure
Due to some long frustration
May react
With psychosomatic symptoms
Difficult to endure
Affecting the upper
Respiratory tract
In other words
Just from waitin' around
For that plain
little band of gold
A person
Could develop a cold
You could spray her
wherever you figure
The streptococci lurk
You can give her a shot
for whatever she's got
But it just won't work
If she's tired
of gettin' that fish eye
From the hotel clerk
A person
Can develop a cold
It says here:
The female remaining single
Constantly in suspense
Shows a neurotic tendency
See note
"See note"? "Note."
Chronic, organic syndromes
Toxic or hypertense
Involving the eye, the ear
the nose and throat
In other words
Just from wondering
Whether the wedding is on or off
A person
Can develop a cough
You can feed her all day
with a vitamin A
And the bromo fizz
But the medicine
never gets anywhere near
Where the trouble is
If she's getting
a kind of a name for herself
And the name ain't his
A person
Can develop a cough
And furthermore
Just from stalling and stalling
and stalling the wedding trip
A person
Can develop la grippe
When they get on the train
For Niagara
And she can hear
church bells chime
The compartment
is air-conditioned
And the mood
Sublime
Then they get off
at Yonkers racetrack
For the 14th time
A person
Can develop la grippe
La grippe
La postnasal drip
With the wheezes
and the sneezes
And a sinus
that's really a pip
From a lack of community property
And a feeling
she's getting too old
A person
Can develop a bad, bad
Cold
Follow the fold
and stray no more
Stray no more
Put down the bottle
and we'll say no more
Follow
Nathan, if you had arrived
one minute earlier...
you would have witnessed Miss Sarah
give Sky Masterson a 100% brush-off.
So the thousand for Joey Biltmore
is practically in your pocket.
- You should be jumping for joy.
- I'm jumping.
You got work to do,
arrangements to make.
A shave and a hot towel
will fix you up.
For who should I have a shave?
For who should I have a hot towel?
Do you know what is at stake here?
Nathan Detroit's crap game.
Because of a doll.
I cannot believe that
a number-one businessman like you...
could let himself go and fall in love
with his own fiancée.
All right!
So Adelaide is my weakness.
Can you not be tolerant
that I have got a weakness?
Especially since this weakness is a sad
condition that guys are in everywhere?
Look-
What's playing at the Roxy
I'll tell you
what's playing at the Roxy
It's a picture about a Minnesota man
so in love with a Mississippi girl
That he sacrifices everything
and moves all the way to Biloxi
That's what's playing at the Roxy
What's in the Daily News
I'll tell you what's in the Daily News
Story about a guy
who bought his wife a small ruby
With what otherwise
would have been his union dues
That's what's in the Daily News
What's happenin' all over
I'll tell you what's happenin' all over
Guy sitting home by a television set
who used to be something of a rover
That's what's happening all over
Love is the thing
that has licked them
And it looks like
I'm just another victim
Yes, sir.
When you see a guy
reach for stars in the sky
You can bet that he's doing it
for some doll
When you spot a John
waiting out in the rain
Chances are he's insane
as only a John can be for a Jane
When you meet a gent
Payin' all kinds of rent
For a flat
that could flatten the Taj Mahal
Call it sad
Call it funny
But it's better than even money
That the guy's only doin' it
for some doll
When you see a Joe
savin' half of his dough
You can bet there'll be mink in it
for some doll
When a bum buys wine
like a bum can't afford
It's a cinch that the bum
is under the thumb
Of some little broad
When you meet a mug
lately out of the jug
And he's still lifting
platinum folderol
Call it hell
Call it heaven
It's a probable 12 to 7
That the guy's only doin' it
for some doll
When you see a sport
and his cash has run short
You can bet he's been blowin' it
on some doll
When a guy wears tails
with the front gleaming white
Who the heck do you think
he's tickling pink
On Saturday night
When some lazy slob
gets a good, steady job
And he smells
from Vitalis and Barbasol
Call it dumb
Call it clever
Ah, but you can give odds forever
That the guy's only doin' it
for some doll
Some doll, some doll
That guy's only doin' it
for some doll
Well, I think we finally managed
to shake off the Prince of Darkness.
You certainly did your best
to discourage him.
I certainly did.
Arvide.
General Cartwright,
what a pleasant surprise.
- We didn't even know you were in town.
- A flying visit.
Flew in from Boston early this morning.
Important luncheon meeting.
While waiting, thought I'd check
a few of our outposts informally.
I must say, Sarah, I was surprised
to find the mission unattended...
in a neighborhood
as unsavory as this.
Why should you be surprised, General?
You've seen our records.
We don't seem to get anyone in here,
even to rob the place.
Yes.
Well, now that you've
brought it up...
I must confess
I have come for a purpose.
An unhappy one.
I know it doesn't look as if we're
accomplishing anything, but in time-
Time, I'm afraid,
is what we can no longer afford.
My good friends...
after careful deliberation,
National Headquarters has decided...
to close this branch of the mission.
- Close the mission?
- Oh, no, General, please.
Even if I haven't made a success of it,
there must be someone who will.
Sarah Brown, if you can't
attract sinners, nobody can.
There are so many calls on us...
so many other places
where our work is needed.
How do you do?
I don't believe we've met,
Brother-
Brother Sky Masterson,
former sinner.
I am General Cartwright,
Regional Director of Save-A-Soul.
- Why isn't his name on the report?
- What were you doing in there?
I was resting, Sister Sarah.
I was going to ask Brother Arvide
if he might let me carry the drum...
when we go out again
this afternoon.
On behalf of the former sinners
of the future...
I protest the closing
of this mission.
- I think I should explain to you-
- This man has a right to be heard.
Continue, Brother Sky.
General, would you be open
to a proposition?
The general is flying back
to Boston this afternoon.
She will not be available
for dinner tonight.
Sarah, what are you talking about?
- What have you got in mind, young man?
- Faith in Sister Sarah.
I ask you to give her 36 hours
to show you that she...
can make this mission pay off.
Saving souls should not
be referred to as "paying off."
Why 36 hours?
Because he knows that our big meeting
36 hours from now...
- will be a great success.
- Uncle Arvide!
How can you guarantee that,
Brother Sky?
Well, let's just say
I have a feeling about it.
"If sinners entice thee,
consent thou not."
That's the wrong thought.
Where is yesterday's Thought for Today?
Top right-hand drawer.
Excuse me, General.
Before going to the expense
of a big meeting...
I should think it'd require more than
just a feeling that it'll be successful.
Oh, it's a very strong feeling,
General.
"There is no peace to the wicked."
Isaiah 57:21.
That is correct.
General,
my proposition is this:
Why don't you come to the midnight
meeting tomorrow night...
and find out for yourself?
Well, if I thought there was a chance
of finding definite progress...
any sizable turnout.
What do you think, Sister Sarah?
Don't you honestly believe
that this mission could be saved...
within the next 36 hours?
General Cartwright...
I'm in a position
to guarantee you personally...
at least one dozen
genuine sinners.
Hallelujah!
Hallelujah.
Be sure you're wearing
your carnation.
Remember, nobody gets
in a crap game...
without they got a red carnation.
It's like a password.
Nathan's orders.
We got the flowers.
Where is the action?
The minute Nathan arrives,
we're gonna-
He has arrived.
Is it all set?
Can I tell the customers
it's Joey Biltmore's-
Not till I put the thousand in Joey's
hands, and I haven't got it yet.
I sent Nicely to wait
for Sky at his hotel.
The minute Sky gives him the money,
Nicely's gonna bring it to me.
But they won't stick around much longer.
They're gettin' nervous.
I'm not nervous?
Well, Harry the Horse.
How is everything in Brooklyn? The same?
I hope, Detroit, you will not
spoil our evening...
inasmuch as I happen to be entertaining
a very prominent guest tonight.
I would like you to meet
Big Jule from Chicago.
Big Jule,
welcome to our fair city...
in which, as you know,
the heat is on.
However, if you will be patient,
you will be provided with action.
What do you say? Should we
stick around, or should we blow?
I come here to shoot crap.
Let's shoot crap.
Order another milkshake
and relax.
Do not let the fact that Big Jule
drinks milk give you any wrong ideas.
Big Jule does not like
to be displeased.
Why, Harry, did I give the impression
that I was being rude to a guest...
who has such a well-deserved
reputation as Big Jule?
I'm sure that you did not
misunderstand my kidding remarks.
It's just that one look
at your kindly face...
which is so full of fun...
good fellowship-
Could I have a swallow
of your milk?
Well, well, well.
What have we here?
The jails must be empty tonight.
Can anybody be missing?
Harry the Horse...
Liver Lips Louie...
Angie the Ox, Society Max.
And here is a face for which
I cannot supply a name.
May I ask where you come from?
East Cicero, Illinois.
And what is
your occupation there?
I'm a scout master.
Don't ever help my mother
across the street.
Such lovely red carnations.
Is it a funeral?
Did somebody die suddenly
that I don't know about...
yet?
What's on, Nathan? What brings
all these senior delinquents together?
They got lonely.
How do I know?
And why are they all
wearing red carnations?
They are also all wearing pants.
You are up to no good, Detroit!
Is it now a crime to wear flowers?
Is Mindy's a hideout for gangsters?
Lieutenant, I'll confess.
We're smuggling hot cheesecake
into Canada.
This is all I need.
It's complete.
Everybody in the whole world
who hates me...
is now here.
What's the use, Nathan?
Why try to keep it a secret?
- Bite your tongue, Benny!
- All right, Southstreet.
- Let's have it. What's this all about?
- It's a party.
- What kind of a party?
- A dinner.
A bachelor dinner for Nathan Detroit.
He's gettin' married.
For he's a jolly good fellow
Which nobody cannot deny
Oh, Nathan, darling.
I'm so thrilled.
- Why didn't you tell me?
- It was gonna be a surprise wedding.
You certainly had me fooled,
Detroit.
When is the happy occasion?
It's gonna take a little time
to get the blood tests, the license.
Gee, wouldn't it be wonderful
if we could get married tomorrow night?
I mean, right after the opening
of the new show at the Hot Box.
According to the laws under which
we live, it's gonna take a little time.
You could elope.
You are telling me
to violate the law?
It's legal to elope at your age.
And the great state of Maryland will
marry you right away, no blood test.
Ain't that unhealthy?
The lieutenant has come up with a
romantic suggestion of which I approve.
Elope, and for the trip,
I will loan you my getaway car...
that is, my station wagon.
Oh, Nathan, darling.
Let's do it. Please?