Previously on Hannibal...
- How do you know Hannibal is in Florence?
- Botticelli.
You're drawing them to you, aren't you?
I'm not searching for Hannibal.
I know exactly where he is.
I will pay 3 million
dollars for the doctor alive.
I'm inspector Rinaldo Pazzi.
Dr. Lecter is careful. He will strike.
You're going to be caught.
It's already been set into motion.
Jack.
He's wounded...
and he's worried.
No, Hannibal doesn't worry.
Knowing he's in danger
won't rattle him any more
than killing does.
If Rinaldo Pazzi had decided to do his job
as an officer of the law,
he would have determined
very quickly that he was
Hannibal Lecter. Would have
taken less than 30 minutes
- to get a warrant.
- All those resources
were denied to Pazzi.
As soon as he decided to sell Hannibal,
he became a bounty hunter.
Outside the law and alone.
Here we are: outside the law and alone.
Have you told la polizia
they're looking for Hannibal Lecter?
They're motivated to find
Dr. Fell inside the law.
Knowing who he is, what he's worth,
it will just coax them out of bounds.
- That'd be a free-for-all.
- And Hannibal will slip away.
Will you slip away with him?
Part of me will always want to.
You have to cut that part out.
(small chuckle)
No, of course, you found him here,
not because of the exhibit,
but because of the crowd it attracts.
You had him, Jack. He was beaten.
Why didn't you kill him?
(Jack sighs.)
Maybe I need you to.
I want to be able to draw
these streets from memory.
the Palazzo Vecchio
and the Duomo.
You won't be coming back here
for a very long time.
Memories of Florence will be all I have.
Florence is where I became a man.
I see my end in my beginning.
All of our endings can be
found in our beginnings.
History repeats itself,
and there is no escape.
You've packed lightly.
I packed for you.
This is where I leave you.
Or more accurately,
where you leave me.
This isn't how I intended to say goodbye.
I imagined it differently.
I didn't.
I knew that you intended to eat me,
and I knew that you had
no intention of eating me hastily.
Would be a shame not to savour you.
I have not marinated
long enough for your tastes.
When they come for you...
And they will come...
what will you say of me?
I will help you tell the version
of events you want to be told.
I will help you because you asked me to.
You may make a meal of me yet, Hannibal...
but not today.
(theme music)
Synced and corrected by oykubuyuk
www.addic7ed.com
(chopping sounds)
Pig tails cut into sections to give
the aesthetic of fingers cut at the joint.
Finger food. Ha!
Hands are how we touch the world.
They're tactile... sensual.
Remove an arm and your patient
will still feel phantom digits.
Imagine how Dr. Lecter will feel
when he watches you nibble on his fingers.
Oh, poetry, Cordell. Poetry.
In a ginger-black vinegar sauce.
Mmmm. It's mostly skin and bone.
- Oh!
- The actual fingers
will have more meat.
Then, there's the marrow.
Here it is in a fermented
bean sauce.
Ah, I prefer the ginger.
No, no.
Spit.
- (spitting)
- (Ding!)
- (Cordell laughing)
- A Buddhist singing bowl.
The gong represents the start of a new day.
- Buddhists don't eat meat.
- This isn't meat...
this is man.
Papa always used to say
meat was a people business.
He was a pioneer in livestock production;
I'm sure he's eaten someone.
I must admit a tremble
at the notion myself.
I find there's something reassuring
about you eating Dr. Lecter.
It makes you the apex predator.
I like that. "Apex predator."
We could... Peking duck him.
Oh?
You have to torture a duck to prepare it.
Pump its skin up with air,
then glaze it with a hot honey
and hang it by its neck until it dries.
And then roast until crispy.
(classical music playing)
(sizzle)
Transubstantiation.
(phone ringing)
I'm here. Tell me.
(woman on TV speaking Italian)
I feel like I just paid a lot
of money for a dead dago.
The feces will fly about Pazzi.
Better get it out that Pazzi was dirty.
They'll take it better
if he was dirty. Was he dirty?
Except for this, I don't know.
What if they trace Pazzi
back to you?
(disfigured man): Oh, I can
take care of that.
You took care of Pazzi.
I have little interest
in the expensive piece of meat
twitching on the end of that
electrical cord, Dr. Bloom.
Might wanna get interested.
Hannibal could disappear too well
and you'd be left with nothing.
(seated woman): Better buy another cop.
Better buy the whole department.
(tapping her arm)
You must be looking for Hannibal Lecter.
One of his patients?
No, not a patient.
Where is he?
Seeing how you let yourself in,
forgive me if it's forward for me to ask,
who the hell are you?
Family.
And you've come all the way from home.
Who are you?
I'm his psychiatrist.
Medicinal purposes.
You're like his bird.
I'm his bird, too.
He puts us in cages
- to see what we'll do.
- Fly away
or dash ourselves dead against the bars.
You haven't flown away.
You are flying right
towards him. How does he
inspire such devotion?
You're his psychiatrist.
You could add into what I've learned
from my experience with him
and from the mute postures of the dead.
Were you there?
Did you watch
as the wild beast within him
turned from the teat
and entered the world?
I met the beast...
and I saw him grow.
Someone wants to kill him.
More than one someone, I'd say.
What do you want?
I want to cage him.
I thought Will Graham was
Hannibal's biggest mistake...
wonder if it isn't you.
Now, if you'll excuse me,
I have to take my medicine.
Mrs. Fell I presume?
My husband is a doctor.
He's been treating my condition.
And what condition is that... Mrs. Fell?
I get confused.
Oh, please. You need to get
over yourself, whatever self
that is, Bedelia.
My name is Lydia Fell.
You expect us to believe that you somehow
lost yourself in
the hot darkness of Hannibal Lecter's mind?
That Lydia Fell is some construct?
It's you, isn't it?
Well, now I'm really confused.
I... don't...
believe you.
You...
are not confused...
Bedelia.
- That is not my name.
- Oh, you know
who you are and what you've
done, and you know exactly
how you're going to wiggle
out of it. What is this?
Sedatives? Hypnotics?
Ethanol? Scopolamine?
- Midazolam?
- Same cocktail
Dr. Lecter served Miriam Lass.
You've been freebasing your alibi.
And I'm not even mad at you.
To tell the truth, I'm fairly impressed.
Mostly because you're still alive.
When this fog of yours clears...
- I'd love to hear how you managed that.
- You say my husband
murdered a chief investigator.
Where is the polizia?
Shouldn't they be questioning?
Don't worry. They will.
They sure are taking their time.
What could possibly be the delay?
Oh, I have an idea.
Do you?
They're being bought
by the same people
that bought Rinaldo Pazzi.
Interest in my husband is
certainly getting competitive.
Will?
I wonder who'll catch him first.
I've made new friends in Italy.
They're cleaning up and
starting over, so all you need
to concern yourself with now
is what will happen
once Dr. Lecter is in your hands.
You've worked so hard
to give me what I want.
It's only fair to talk
about what Margot wants.
Come sit on Santa's lap, huh?
You know what I want.
The biggest regret of my life
is taking away your ability
- to create it.
- Adoption
is a nice thing to do.
No pedigree in buying
a Chinese baby.
They're cheaper than shoats.
I wish I could give you a Verger baby,
our own baby. Yours and mine.
We could raise it together.
The last time you said
you wanted to have a baby,
- you removed my uterus.
- In my defense,
you weaponized your uterus.
You shouldn't have been
waving it around like a loaded pistol.
I brought it on myself.
As you so often do, Margot.
But there's a possibility
that I'm still packing
loads of viable sperm.
Stumbled across
any viable uteruses lately, hm?
What are you up to, Mason?
I want us to have a baby, Margot.
I could be really good to a child.
I could take parenting classes.
Let's find a way, Margot.
Let's find a way to be a family again, hmm?
(Will groans.)
(Will sighs.)
If I saw you every day,
forever, Will,
I would remember this time.
Strange seeing you here in front of me.
Been staring at afterimages
of you in places you haven't
been in years.
"To market, to market, to buy a fat pig.
Home again, home again, jiggity-jig."
I wanted to understand you
before I laid eyes on you again.
I needed it to be clear...
what I was seeing.
Where does the difference between the past
and the future come from?
Mine?
Before you and after you.
Yours?
It's all starting to blur.
Mischa.
Abigail.
Chiyoh.
How is Chiyoh?
She pushed me off a train.
Atta girl.
You and I
have begun to blur.
(Will sighs.)
Isn't that how you found me?
Every crime of yours...
feels like one I am guilty of.
Not just Abigail's murder, every murder...
stretching backward and forward in time.
Freeing yourself from me and...
me freeing myself from you,
they are the same.
We're conjoined.
I'm curious
whether either of us can
survive separation.
Now is the hardest test:
not letting rage and frustration...
nor forgiveness keep you from thinking.
Shall we?
(Will groans.)
After you.
(gunshot with silencer)
Mason's ahead of the FBI
in the pursuit of Hannibal Lecter.
Mason has no intention of ever
sharing his lead with the FBI.
I do...
once he has Hannibal.
There is something I need to get from Mason
before he goes to prison.
Any experience harvesting sperm?
(with Italian accent):
We cannot locate Dr. Fell.
Close attention has been
brought to bear on him.
We have eyewitness accounts
of a bloody figure,
matching his description,
running from the scene.
The Italian public has already decided
il Mostro has killed Rinaldo Pazzi.
A 20-year-old debt finally paid.
The Italian public is right.
Il Mostro died in prison.
Il Commandator Pazzi
had been assigned to investigate
the disappearance of two men
from the Palazzo Capponi.
My husband knew Professor Sogliato.
We were at his home many times.
We believe your husband was
responsible for the disappearances
and murdered Pazzi when he came
to the same conclusion.
If you haven't already,
access the ViCAP database at Quantico.
You'll find Dr. Fell
on the Most-Wanted page,
under the name of Hannibal Lecter.
The fingerprints
you'll pull from Pazzi's noose
- will be his.
- If you knew
Dr. Fell to be Hannibal Lecter,
why didn't you bring it to
the attention of the Questura?
He had a price on his head. Pazzi
knew about it, tried to sell him.
For that kind of money, I can't blame him.
Can you?
(amused exclamation)
You've already been questioned
regarding Rinaldo Pazzi's
murder, Signor Crawford.
Since you're not in Florence
on official FBI business,
that will be all.
Not you, Signora Fell.
You stay right where you are.
(sigh)
(Will panting)
This is gonna hurt.
The bullet is still inside you.
(Will panting)
(Will grunting in pain and panting)
Chiyoh has always been
very protective of me.
(Will laughing)
Did she kill her tenant,
or did you?
She did.
Excellent.
You dropped your forgiveness, Will.
You forgive how God forgives.
Would you have done it quickly?
Or would you have stopped to gloat?
Does God gloat?
Often.
No, no. No, no, no, no, no.
Ugh!
(Will panting)
(Will breathing easier)
Give that a moment.
I can almost taste the butter.
Taste and smell are the oldest senses
and the closest to the center of the mind.
(Will): Parts that precede
pity and morality.
They play in the dome of our skulls,
like miracles illuminated
on a church ceiling.
The ceremonies and sights
and exchanges of dinner
can be far more engaging than theater.
What's for dinner?
Never ask.
Spoils the surprise.
No, no.
I don't indulge much in regret, but...
I am sorry to be leaving Italy.
There were things in the Palazzo Capponi
I would have liked to read.
I would have liked to play the clavier...
and perhaps compose.
I would have liked
to show you Florence, Will.
Soup isn't very good.
It's a parsley and thyme infusion,
and more for my sake than yours.
Have another sip.
Let that circulate.
Are we expecting company?
Wrong floor.
(muffled Italian song playing)
- (tick-tock)
- (something sizzling)
(Italian song playing)
- (louder sizzling)
- (Italian song still playing)
Will.
He is under the table, Jack.
Argh!
Your husband left you behind.
I had no reason to run.
I've done nothing wrong.
I hold in my hands
the photographs
taken for Dr. Fell's State work permit.
Oh. I also have his French
work papers.
Looks different with a beard, no?
- That is not my husband.
- This is Roman Fell.
And this is Lydia Fell.
I am Lydia Fell.
Did you murder her with your husband?
Or did you just watch?
I... am Lydia Fell.
I don't care who you are.
I don't care if you're in your right mind
or your wrong mind. Understand?
Those things are inconsequential.
I understand. In this moment,
you do not work for the Questura.
Hmm...
That's a good thing to understand.
I do not want to be seen
as... uncooperative.
How you're seen is entirely up to you.
Rescued by the brave Questura or...
apprehended.
I've never considered myself
in need of being...
rescued, until now.
Is your husband still in the city?
My husband was hoping to meet a friend
before he left Florence.
Where?
The nature of the meeting required privacy.
They will be somewhere
no one is supposed to be.
I've taken the liberty of giving you
something to help you relax.
Won't be able to do much more than chew,
but that's all you'll need to do.
I didn't have
an opportunity to ask you
during our last encounter,
but did you enjoy the exhibition?
A different kind of evil minds museum...
Not that different.
We were supposed to sit down together
at your house in Baltimore,
just the three of us.
You were to be the guest of honour.
But the menu was all wrong.
Yes, it was.
Jack was the first to suggest
getting inside your head.
Now, we both have the opportunity
to chew quite literally...
what we've only chewed figuratively.
(saw buzzing)
Hannibal...
stop.
Stop!
(silent screaming)
Gentlemen,
welcome to Muskrat Farm.