It's beautiful here.
It was our aunt's.
We used to come here
as kids.
The Order uses it now
as a safe house.
What's left of us, at least.
Muggles think these keep
evil away,
but they're wrong.
I need to talk
to the goblin.
How are you?
Alive.
You probably don't remember...
That I showed you
to your vault
the first time
you came to Gringotts?
Even amongst goblins
you're famous, Harry Potter.
You buried the elf.
Yes.
GRIPHOOK: And brought me
here.
You are...
..a very unusual wizard.
How did you come
by this sword?
It's complicated.
Why did Bellatrix Lestrange
think
it should be in her
vault at Gringotts?
It's complicated.
The sword presented itself
to us
in a moment of need.
We didn't steal it.
There is a sword
in Madam Lestrange's vault
identical to this one...
..but it is a fake.
It was placed there
this past summer.
And she never suspected
it was a fake?
The replica is
very convincing.
Only a goblin would
recognize that
this is the true sword
of Gryffindor.
Who is the acquaintance?
A Hogwarts professor.
As I understand it,
he's now headmaster.
Snape?
He put a fake sword
in Bellatrix's vault?
Why?
There are more than
a few
curious things in the vaults
at Gringotts.
And in Madam Lestrange's vault
as well?
Perhaps.
I need to get into Gringotts.
Into one of the vaults.
This is impossible.
Alone, yes.
But with you,
no.
GRIPHOOK: Why should I
help you?
I have gold.
Lots of it.
- I have no interest in gold.
- HARRY: Then what?
That.
That is my price.
HERMIONE: Are you thinking
there's a Horcrux in Bellatrix's vault?
HARRY: She was terrified
when she thought we'd been in there.
She kept asking you
what else we'd taken.
I bet you there's a Horcrux
in there,
another piece of his soul.
Let's find it and kill it,
we're one step closer to killing him.
RON: And what happens
when we find it?
How are we supposed
to destroy it now,
you've given the
sword to Griphook?
HARRY: I'm still working
on that part.
He's weak.
Yes?
Mr. Ollivander,
I need to ask you a few questions.
OLLIVANDER: Anything, my boy,
anything.
HARRY: Would you mind
identifying this wand?
We need to know
if it's safe to use.
Walnut.
Dragon heartstring.
Twelve and three-quarter inches.
Unyie...
..Unyielding.
This belonged
to Bellatrix Lestrange.
Treat it carefully.
And this?
Hawthorn.
And unicorn hair.
Ten inches.
Reasonably pliant.
This... was the wand
of Draco Malfoy.
Was?
Is it not still?
Well, perhaps not,
if you won it from him.
I sense its allegiance has
changed.
You talk about wands
as if they have feelings...
..can think.
The wand chooses the wizard,
Mr. Potter.
That much has always
been clear to
those of us
who have studied wandlore.
And... what do you know
about the Deathly Hallows?
It is rumored
there are three:
The Elder Wand...
..the Cloak of Invisibility
to hide you
from your enemies...
..and the Resurrection Stone
to bring back loved ones from the dead.
Together,
they make one the master of death.
But few... truly believe
that such objects exist.
HARRY: Do you?
Do you believe they exist,
sir?
I see no reason
to...
..put stock into
an old wives' tale.
You're lying.
You know one exists.
You told him
about it.
You told him about
the Elder Wand
and... where he could go
looking for it.
He tortured me.
Besides...
..I only conveyed rumors.
There's...
..there's no telling
whether he will find it.
He has found it,
sir.
We'll let you rest.
OLLIVANDER: He's after you,
Mr. Potter.
If it's true,
what you say,
and he has
the Elder Wand...
..I'm afraid...
..you really don't stand
a chance.
Well, I suppose
I'll have to kill him
before he finds me,
then.
RON: Are you sure that's hers?
Positive.
Well?
How do I look?
RON: Hideous.
You can give that to Hermione to hold,
all right, Griphook?
We're relying on you.
If you get us past the guards
and into the vault,
the sword's yours.
Madam Lestrange.
HERMIONE: Good morning.
GRIPHOOK: "Good morning"?
"Good morning"?
You're Bellatrix Lestrange,
not some dewy-eyed school girl.
RON: Hey. Easy.
She gives us away,
we might as well use that sword
to slit our own throats.
Understand?
No, he's right.
I was being stupid.
HARRY: Okay.
Let's do it.
(PEN SCRATCHING PAPER)
(CLEARS THROAT)
I wish
to enter my vault.
Identification?
I hardly think
that'll be necessary.
Madam Lestrange.
I don't like to be kept
waiting.
GRIPHOOK: They know.
They know
she's an imposter.
They've been warned.
Harry?
What do we do, Harry?
Madam Lestrange,
would you mind presenting your wand?
And why should I do that?
It's the bank's policy.
I'm sure you understand
given the current climate.
No.
I most certainly do not understand.
I'm afraid
I must insist.
HARRY WHISPERS: Imperio.
(SNIFFS THEN SIGHS)
Very well, Madam Lestrange.
If you will follow me.
HARRY: What is that, Griphook?
(SQUEAKING AND GRINDING)
Griphook.
(ALL PANTING)
(ALARM SCREECHING)
(SCREAMING)
HERMIONE: Arresto momentum.
(ALL GRUNT)
HARRY: Well done, Hermione.
(ALARM CONTINUES SCREECHING
IN DISTANCE)
Oh, no,
you look like you again.
The Thief's Downfall.
Washes away all enchantments.
Can be deadly.
You don't say.
Just out of interest, is there
any other way out of here?
No.
What the devil are all
you doing down here?
Thieves!
- When you gave up the keys, you...
- Lmperio.
(SNIFFS THEN SIGHS)
(CREATURE ROARS NEARBY)
That doesn't sound good.
(GROWLING)
RON: Bloody hell.
That's a Ukrainian Ironbelly.
Here.
(ROARING)
It's been trained to expect pain
when it hears the noise.
HERMIONE: That's barbaric.
Lumos.
Blimey.
Accio Horcrux.
You're not trying that
one again, are you?
GRIPHOOK: That kind of
magic won't work in here.
RON: Is it in here, Harry?
Can you feel anything?
(HISSING AND WHISPERING FAINTLY)
(HERMIONE GASPS)
That's it.
Up there.
They've added the Gemino curse.
Everything you touch will multiply.
Give me the sword.
Stop moving.
Got it.
We had a deal, Griphook.
The cup for the sword.
I said I'd get you in.
I didn't say anything
about getting you out.
HARRY: Griphook!
- GRIPHOOK: Thieves! Help!
- Griphook!
Thieves!
(BOGROD CHUCKLES)
Foul little git.
Least we've still got Bogrod.
That's unfortunate.
HERMIONE: We can't just stand here.
Who's got an idea?
You're the brilliant one.
I've got something,
but it's mad.
Reducto.
Well, come on, then.
Relashio.
(RUMBLING FAINTLY)
(ALL YELLING)
GOBLIN: He's moving! Aah!
(PANTING)
RON: Now what?
Reducto.
Hold on.
RON: That was brilliant.
Absolutely brilliant.
HARRY: We're dropping.
- RON: I say we jump.
- When?
Now.
(YELLS)
(GASPING)
(ALL PANTING)
He knows.
You-Know-Who.
He knows
we broke into Gringotts.
He knows what we took
and he knows
we're hunting Horcruxes.
- How is it you know?
- I saw him.
HERMIONE: You let him in?
Harry, you can't do that.
Hermione,
I can't always help it.
Well, maybe I can.
I don't know.
RON: Never mind.
What happened?
Well, he's angry.
And scared too.
He knows, if we find
and destroy all the Horcruxes
we'll
be able to kill him.
I reckon he'll stop at nothing
to make sure we don't find the rest.
There's more.
One of them's at Hogwarts.
HERMIONE: What?
- You saw it?
- I saw the castle
and Rowena Ravenclaw.
It must have to do with her.
We have to go there now.
We can't do that.
We've got to plan.
We've got to figure it out.
Hermione, when have any of
our plans ever actually worked?
We plan, we get there,
all hell breaks loose.
He's right.
One problem:
Snape's headmaster now.
We can't just walk
through the front door.
Um, well,
we'll go to Hogsmeade,
to Honeydukes.
Take the secret passage
in the cellar.
It's...
There's something wrong with him.
It's like, you know, in the past,
I've always been able to follow
his thoughts.
And now everything
just feels disconnected.
Maybe
it's the Horcruxes.
Maybe he's growing weaker.
Maybe he's dying.
No.
No, it's more like he's wounded.
If anything,
he feels more dangerous.
Voldemort in parsel tongue:
(NAGINI HISSES)
(ALARM SCREECHING)
(MEN SHOUTING NEARBY)
- MAN 1: They're here!
- MAN 2: Search everywhere!
MAN 1: Look down by the stables!
You two, come with me!
MAN 3: Any sign?
(ALARM SCREECHING)
MAN 4: Potter!
OLD MAN: In here, Potter.
Did you get a look at him?
- For a second, I thought it was...
- HERMIONE: I know. Dumbledore.
(MEN CHATTERING NEARBY)
Harry?
I can see you in this.
(DOOR OPENS)
You bloody fools.
What were you thinking coming here?
Have you any idea
how dangerous it is?
You're Aberforth,
Dumbledore's brother.
It's you who
I've been seeing in here.
You're the one
who sent Dobby.
Where have you left him?
He's dead.
Sorry to hear it.
I liked that elf.
- Who gave that to you?
- The mirror?
Mundungus Fletcher,
about a year ago.
- Dung had no right. It belonged to...
- ABERFORTH: Sirius.
Albus told me.
He also told me
you'd likely be hacked off
if you ever found out
I had it...
..but ask yourself,
where would you be if I didn't?
Do you hear from the others much?
From the Order?
The Order's finished.
You-Know-Who's won.
Anyone who says otherwise
is kidding themselves.
We need to get into Hogwarts,
tonight.
Dumbledore gave us
a job to do.
Did he now?
Nice job?
Easy?
We've been hunting
Horcruxes.
We think the last one's
inside the castle,
but we'll need help
getting in.
That's not a job
my brother's given you.
It's a suicide mission.
Do yourself a favor, boy,
go home.
Live a little longer.
Dumbledore trusted me
to see this through.
What makes you think
you can trust him?
You think you can believe anything
my brother told you?
In all the time you knew him,
did he ever mention my name?
Did he ever mention hers?
- Why should he...?
- Keep secrets? You tell me.
- I trusted him.
- That's a boy's answer.
A boy who goes chasing Horcruxes
on the word of a man...
..who wouldn't even tell him
where to start. You're lying!
Not just to me, that doesn't matter.
To yourself as well.
That's what a fool does.
You don't strike me as a fool,
Harry Potter.
So I'll ask you again.
There must be a reason.
I'm not interested in
what happened
between you
and your brother.
I don't care
that you've given up.
I trusted the man
I knew.
And we need to get into
the castle tonight.
You know what to do.
HARRY: Where have you sent her?
You'll see
soon enough.
That's your sister, Ariana,
isn't it?
She died very young,
didn't she?
My brother sacrificed many things,
Mr. Potter...
..on his journey
to find power...
..including Ariana.
And she was devoted to him.
He gave her everything...
..but time.
HERMIONE: Thank you,
Mr. Dumbledore.
(DOOR CLOSES)
He did save our lives twice.
Kept an eye on us
in that mirror.
(WHISPERS) That doesn't seem
like someone who's given up.
She's coming back.
RON: Who's that with her?
Neville.
- Oh, you look...
- Like hell, I reckon.
This is nothing.
Seamus is worse.
Hey, Ab, we've got a couple
more coming through.
RON: Don't remember this
on the Marauder's Map.
That's because
it never existed till now.
The seven secret passages
were sealed off
before the start of the year.
This is the only way
in or out now.
The grounds are crawling with
Death Eaters and Dementors.
HERMIONE: How bad is Snape
as headmaster?
Hardly ever see him.
It's the Carrows you need
to watch out for.
Carrows?
Yeah. Brother and sister.
In charge of discipline.
They like punishment,
the Carrows.
HERMIONE: They did that to you?
Why?
NEVILLE: Today's Dark Arts lessons
had us practicing the Cruciatus Curse.
On first-years.
I refused.
Hogwarts has changed.
Let's have a bit of fun,
shall we?
Hey, listen up, you lot.
Brought you a surprise.
Not more of Aberforth's cooking,
I hope.
Be a surprise if we can digest it.
Blimey.
- Harry!
- Yeah!
Get the word out to Remus and
the others that Harry's back.
Okay, okay, let's not kill him
before You-Know-Who...
River, D.A. calling.
Do you read?
We have a new weather report.
Lightning has struck.
I repeat
What's the plan, Harry?
HARRY: Okay.
There's something
we need to find.
Something hidden here in the castle.
And it may help us
defeat You-Know-Who.
Right.
What is it?
We don't know.
- NEVILLE: Where is it?
- HARRY: We don't know that either.
- I realize it's not much to go on.
- That's nothing to go on.
I think it has something
to do with Ravenclaw.
Um, it'll be... small,
easily concealed.
Anyone, any ideas?
Well, there's Rowena
Ravenclaw's lost diadem.
Oh, bloody hell.
Here we go.
LUNA: Lost diadem
of Ravenclaw?
Hasn't anyone heard of it?
It's quite famous.
Yes, but, Luna, it's lost,
for centuries now.
There isn't a person alive
today who's seen it.
Excuse me. Can someone tell
me what a bloody diadem is?
It's a sort of crown.
You know, like a tiara.
(RUMBLING)
Harry.
Hi there.
Six months she hasn't seen me
and it's like I'm Frankie First-Year.
- I'm her brother.
- Got lots of those.
- There's only one Harry.
- Shut up, Seamus.
What is it, Ginny?
Snape knows.
He knows that
Harry was spotted in Hogsmeade.
(GROUP MARCHING)
Many of you are
surely wondering
why I have summoned you
at this hour.
It's come to my attention
that earlier this evening...
..Harry Potter was sighted
in Hogsmeade.
(MURMURING)
Now...
..should anyone...
..student or staff,
attempt to aid Mr. Potter...
..they will be punished...
..in a manner consistent with
the severity of their transgression.
Furthermore...
..any person found to have
knowledge of these events...
..who fails
to come forward...
..will be treated
as...
..equally guilty.
Now then...
..if anyone here...
..has any knowledge of
Mr. Potter's movements this evening...
..I invite them to step
forward...
..now.
(MURMURING)
It seems, despite your
exhaustive defensive strategies...
..you still have a bit of
a security problem, headmaster.
And I'm afraid
it's quite extensive.
How dare you stand
where he stood?
Tell them
how it happened that night.
how you looked him in the eye,
a man who trusted you,
and killed him.
Tell them.
(WIZARDS GRUNT)
MCGONAGALL: Coward!
(STUDENTS CHEERING)
VOLDEMORT: Harry.
MCGONAGALL: Potter?
(RUMBLING)
(GIRL 1 SCREAMING)
(GIRL 2 SCREAMING)
(GIRL 3 SCREAMING)
VOLDEMORT: I know that
many of you will want to fight.
Some of you may even think
that to fight is wise.
But this is folly.
Give me Harry Potter.
Do this
and none shall be harmed.
Give me Harry Potter
and I shall leave
Hogwarts untouched.
Give me Harry Potter...
..and you will be rewarded.
You have one hour.
PANSY: What are you waiting for?
Someone grab him.
FILCH: Students out of bed.
Students out of bed!
Students in the corridor!
They are supposed
to be out of bed,
you blithering idiot.
Oh.
Sorry, ma'am.
As it happens, Mr. Filch,
your arrival is most opportune.
If you would,
I would like you, please...
..to lead Miss Parkinson and the
rest of Slytherin House from the hall.
Exactly where is it I'll be
leading them to, ma'am?
The dungeons would do.
(CHEERING)
FILCH: Right.
Come on. Come on.
I presume you have a reason
for returning, Potter.
What is it you need?
Time, professor.
As much as you can get me.
Do what you have to do.
I'll secure the castle.
Potter.
It's good to see you.
It's good to see you too,
professor.
Hold the fort, Neville.
(STUDENTS CHATTERING)
GIRL: Hurry up,
come on!
RON: Harry.
Hermione and I have been thinking.
It doesn't matter
if we find a Horcrux.
- What do you mean?
- Unless we can destroy it.
RON: So we were thinking...
Ron was thinking. It was Ron's idea.
It's brilliant.
You destroyed Tom Riddle's diary
with a basilisk fang, right?
Me and Hermione know
where we might find one.
Okay.
Okay, but take this.
That way you
can find me when you get back.
- Where are you going?
- Ravenclaw common room.
Gotta start somewhere.
LUNA: Harry.
Harry!
Let me get this straight.
You're giving us permission
to do this?
That is correct,
Longbottom.
To blow it up?
Boom?
Boom!
Wicked. But how on earth
are we gonna do that?
Why don't you confer
with Mr. Finnigan?
As I recall, he has a particular
proclivity for pyrotechnics.
I can bring it down.
That's the spirit.
Now away you go.
You do realize,
of course,
we can't keep out
You-Know-Who indefinitely.
MCGONAGALL: Well, that doesn't mean
we can't delay him.
And his name is Voldemort, Filius.
You might as well use it.
He's going to try to kill you
either way.
Piertotum Locomotor.
Hogwarts is threatened.
Man the boundaries. Protect us.
Do your duty to our school.
I've always wanted
to use that spell.
Protego Maxima. Fianto Duri.
Repello lnimicum.
Protego Maxima.
Harry, wait.
I need to talk to you.
I'm a bit preoccupied
at the moment, Luna.
You won't find anything where
you're going.
You're wasting time.
- Look, we'll talk later, okay, Luna?
- Harry.
- Later.
- Harry Potter!
You listen to me right now!
Don't you remember what Cho said
about Rowena Ravenolaw's diadem?
"There's not a person alive
who's seen it."
it's obvious, isn't it?
We have to talk to someone
who's dead.
It's very impressive,
isn't it?
If you're to find her,
you'll find her down there.
- HARRY: Aren't you coming?
- LUNA: No.
I think it's best
if you two talk alone.
She's very shy.
HARRY: You're the Grey Lady...
..the Ghost of
Ravenclaw Tower.
I do not answer
to that name.
No, I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
I t's Helena, isn't it?
Helena Ravenclaw.
Rowena's daughter.
Are you a friend of
Luna's?
HARRY: Yes.
And she thought
you might be able to help me.
You seek
my mother's diadem.
Yes.
That's right.
Luna is kind,
unlike so many of the others.
But she was wrong.
I cannot help you.
Wait. Please.
I want to destroy it.
(VOLDEMORT CHUCKLES)
VOLDEMORT: They never learn.
Such a pity.
But, my Lord...
..shouldn't we wait for...?
My Lord.
Begin.
(RUMBLING)
That's what you want too,
isn't it, Helena?
You want it destroyed.
Another swore to destroy
it many years ago...
..a strange boy
with a strange name.
- Tom Riddle.
- But he lied.
He's lied to many people.
I know what he's done!
I know who he is!
He defiled it
with dark magic!
HARRY: I can destroy it
once and for all.
But only if you tell me
where he hid it.
You do know
where he hid it, don't you, Helena?
You just
have to tell me.
Please.
Strange.
You remind me of him
a bit.
It's here...
..in the castle, in the place
where everything is hidden.
If you have to ask...
..you will never know.
If you know,
you need only ask.
Thank you.
(STUDENTS CLAMORING)
Tell Professor McGONAGALL Remus
and I will handle this side of the castle.
Yes, sir.
SHACKLEBOLT: Hey, Dean, on second
thoughts, tell Professor McGONAGALL...
...we might need one or
two more wands this side.
REMUS: It is the quality of one's
convictions that determines success...
..not the number of followers.
Who said that?
Me.
You okay, Freddie?
Yeah.
Me too.
Speaking in Parseltongue...
Harry talks in his sleep.
Have you noticed?
No, of course not.
(YELLING AND SCREAMING IN DISTANCE)
Yeah?
You and whose army?
- You do it.
- I can't.
Yes, you can.
(YELLS)
(GASPS)
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
(WAILS)
(RUMBLING)
(GRUNTS)
(YELLING)
GINNY: Neville!
(PANTING)
That went well.
MCGONAGALL: Get inside!
This way, everyone. Take cover!
(SCREAMING)
HARRY: Stupefy!
Get your coat on!
Ginny. Neville.
Are you all right?
Never better.
I feel like I could spit fire.
You haven't seen Luna,
have you?
- Luna?
- I'm mad for her!
I think it's about time
I told her since
we'll probably both
be dead by dawn.
I know.
(DRACO GRUNTS)
Bloody hell.
We'll never find it on this.
- There he is, just there.
- RON: Brilliant.
He just vanished.
Just now. I saw it.
(RUMBLING)
Maybe he's gone to the
Room no one.
It doesn't show up on the map, does it?
You said that last year.
That's right.
I... I did.
Let's go.
Brilliant.
DRACO: Come on!
(VOICES WHISPERING)
(HIGH-PITCHED RINGING)
DRACO: Well, well.
What brings you here,
Potter?
I could ask you the same.
You have something
of mine.
I'd like it back.
- What's wrong with the one you have?
- DRACO: It's my mother's.
It's powerful, but it's
not the same.
Doesn't quite understand me.
Know what I mean?
Why didn't you tell her?
Bellatrix.
You knew it was me.
You didn't say anything.
Come on, Draco.
Don't be a prat. Do him.
DRACO: Easy.
Expelliarmus.
Avada Kedavra!
Stupefy!
(YELLS)
RON: That's my girlfriend,
you numpties!
(HARRY PANTING AND COUGHING)
(CHATTERING)
(SCREECHING)
HARRY: Got it.
RON: Run!
Run!
(RON SCREAMING)
Goyle's setting the bloody place on fire!
(ROARS)
(SCREAMS)
Come on!
This way!
We can't leave them.
He's joking, right?
If we die for them,
Harry, I'm gonna kill you.
(GRUNTING)
HERMIONE: Harry!
(HISSES)
(PANTING AND GROANING)
My Lord?
Avada Kedavra!
Come, Nagini.
I need to keep you safe.
(PANTING)
HARRY: It's the snake.
She's the last one.
It's the last Horcrux.
RON: Look inside him, Harry.
Find out where he is.
If we find him, we can find the snake.
Then we can end this.
LUCIUS: My Lord?
Might it be less, uh...
Might it not be more prudent
to call off this attack...
..and simply seek the boy
yourself?
VOLDEMORT: I do not need
to seek the boy.
Before the night is out,
he will come to me.
Do you understand?
Look at me.
How can you live with yourself,
Lucius?
I don't know.
Go and find Severus.
Bring him to me.
I know where he is.
OLIVER: Come on!
(YELLS)
(GRUNTING)
(SPIDERS SQUEAKING)
BOY: Crucio!
HERMIONE: No!
SNAPE: You have performed extraordinary
magic with this wand, my Lord...
..in the last few hours alone.
VOLDEMORT: No.
No, I am extraordinary...
..but the wand
resists me.
SNAPE: There is no wand
more powerful.
Ollivander himself has said it.
Tonight, when the boy comes,
it will not fail you. I am sure of it.
It answers to you...
..and you
only.
Does it?
My Lord?
The wand,
does it truly answer to me?
You're a clever man,
Severus.
Surely you must know.
Where does its true loyalty
lie?
SNAPE:
With you...
..of course,
my Lord.
VOLDEMORT: The Elder Wand...
..cannot serve me properly,
because,
I'm not
its true master.
The Elder Wand belongs to the wizard
who killed its last owner.
You killed Dumbledore,
Severus.
While you live,
the Elder Wand cannot truly be mine.
You've been a good and
faithful servant, Severus...
..but only I can live
forever.
My Lord...
(THUDS)
VOLDEMORT: Nagini, kill.
(SNAPE GASPING)
SNAPE: Take them.
Take them.
Please.
Give me something.
Quickly. A flask, anything.
SNAPE: Take them to the Pensieve.
Look at me.
You have your mother's eyes.
(SIGHS)
VOLDEMORT: You have fought valiantly...
...but in vain.
I do not wish this.
Every drop of magical blood
spilled is a terrible waste.
I therefore command
my forces to retreat.
In their absence,
dispose of your dead with dignity.
Harry Potter,
I now speak directly to you.
On this night, you have allowed
your friends to die for you...
...rather than face me yourself.
There is no greater dishonor.
Join me in the Forbidden Forest
and confront your fate.
If you do not do this...
...I shall kill
every last man, woman and child...
...who tries to conceal you
from me.
HERMIONE: Where is everybody?
Harry.
SPROUT: Oh, come on.
What's the matter with you?
TRELAWNEY: Oh, she's passed.
There, she's gone.
(SOBBING)
PETUNIA: Freak!
Come here.
I'm gonna tell Mummy. You're a freak.
You're a freak, Lily!
Come here.
SNAPE: She's jealous because
she's ordinary and you're special.
LILY: That's mean, Severus.
(LILY LAUGHING)
SORTING HAT: Gryffindor!
(STUDENTS APPLAUDING)
- Hi. I'm James.
- Hi. I'm Lily.
SNAPE: Just like your father.
Lazy. Arrogant.
HARRY: Don't say a
word against my father.
TRELAWNEY: Blood shall be spilt...
..and servant and master
shall be reunited once more.
VOLDEMORT: Severus.
SNAPE: No. Don't kill me.
DUMBLEDORE: The prophecy
did not refer to a woman.
It spoke of a boy born
at the end of July.
Yes, but he thinks
it's her son.
He intends to hunt them down now,
to kill them.
Hide her.
Hide them all. I beg you.
DUMBLEDORE: What will you
give me in exchange, Severus?
Anything.
LILY: Harry. Harry, you
are so loved. So loved.
Harry, Mama loves you.
Dada loves you.
Harry, be safe.
Be strong.
VOLDEMORT: Avada Kedavra!
(SCREAMS)
SNAPE: You said
you would keep her safe.
DUMBLEDORE: Lily and James put their
faith in the wrong person, Severus.
Rather like you.
The boy survives.
He doesn't need protection.
The Dark Lord is gone.
The Dark Lord will return.
And when he does,
the boy will be in terrible danger.
He has her eyes.
If you truly loved her...
No one
can know.
DUMBLEDORE: That I should never
reveal the best of you, Severus?
SNAPE: Your word.
DUMBLEDORE: When you risk your
life every day to protect the boy?
SNAPE: He possesses
no measurable talent,
his arrogance rivals
that of his father...
...and he seems
to relish his fame.
HARRY: Don't say a
word against my father.
SNAPE: James Potter?
Lazy, arrogant.
HARRY: My father was a great man.
Your father was a swine!
SNAPE: Drink the rest.
It will contain the curse to
your hand for the time being.
It will spread, Albus.
DUMBLEDORE: How long?
SNAPE: Maybe a year.
Don't ignore me, Severus.
DRACO: Harmonia Nectere Passus.
We both know Lord Voldemort has
ordered the Malfoy boy to murder me.
But should he fail,
one should presume the Dark Lord...
..will turn to you.
You must be the one to kill me,
Severus.
It is the only way.
Only then will the Dark
Lord trust you completely.
SNAPE: Avada Kedavra.
DUMBLEDORE: There will come a time
when Harry Potter must be told something.
But you must wait until Voldemort
is at his most vulnerable.
Must be told what?
DUMBLEDORE: On the
night Lord Voldemort...
..went to Godric's Hollow
to kill Harry...
..and Lily Potter cast
herself between them...
..the curse rebounded.
When that happened, a
part of Voldemort's soul...
..latched itself onto the only
living thing it could find:
Harry himself.
There's a reason Harry
can speak with snakes.
There's a reason he can look
into Lord Voldemort's mind.
A part
of Voldemort lives inside him.
So when the time comes...
..the boy must die?
Yes. Yes.
He must die.
You've kept him alive so that he
can die at the proper moment.
You've been raising him
like a pig for slaughter.
Don't tell me now
that you've grown to care for the boy?
SNAPE: Expecto Patronum.
Lily.
After all this time?
Always.
So when the time comes...
..the boy must die?
Yes. He must die.
And Voldemort
himself must do it.
That is essential.
HERMIONE: Where've you been?
- We thought you went to the forest.
- I'm going there now.
RON: Are you mad? No.
You can't give yourself
up to him.
HERMIONE: What is it, Harry?
What is it you know?
There's a reason
I can hear them...
..the Horcruxes.
I think I've known
or a while.
And I think you have too.
- I'll go with you.
- No, kill the snake.
Kill the snake
and then it's just him.
I'm ready to die.
The Resurrection Stone.
You've been so brave,
sweetheart.
Why are you here?
All of you?
We never left.
Does it...?
Does it hurt'?
Dying?
Quicker than falling asleep.
You're nearly there, son.
HARRY: I'm sorry.
I never wanted
any of you to die for me.
And, Remus, your son...
Others will tell him what his
mother and father died for.
One day, he'll understand.
You'll stay with me?
Until the end.
And he won't be able
to see you?
SIRIUS: No.
We're here, you see.
Stay close to me.
Always.
DEATH EATER: No sign of him,
my Lord.
VOLDEMORT: I thought he would come.
Harry?
No! What are you doing here?
Quiet!
Harry Potter.
The Boy Who Lived.
Come to die.
Avada Kedavra!
(MAN BREATHING FAINTLY)
DUMBLEDORE: You can't help.
Harry...
..you wonderful boy.
You brave, brave man.
Let us walk.
Professor, what is that?
Something beyond
either of our help.
A part of Voldemort sent here
to die.
And exactly
where are we?
I was going to ask you that.
Where would you say that we are?
Well...
..it looks like King's Cross station.
Only cleaner.
And without all the trains.
King's Cross,
is that right?
This is, as they say,
your party.
I expect you now realize
that you and Voldemort...
..have been connected by
something other than fate...
..since that night in Godric's
Hollow all those years ago.
So it's true then, sir?
A part of him lives within me,
doesn't it?
Did.
It was just destroyed many moments ago
by none other than Voldemort himself.
You were the Horcrux
he never meant to make, Harry.
I have to go back, haven't I?
Oh. That's up to you.
I have a choice?
Oh, yes.
We're in King's Cross, you say?
I think, if you so desired,
you'd be able to board a train.
And where would it take me?
(DUMBLEDORE CHUCKLES)
On.
(TRAIN WHISTLE WAILS IN DISTANCE)
Voldemort has the Elder Wand.
True.
- And the snake's still alive.
- Yes.
And I've nothing to kill it with.
Help will always be given at Hogwarts,
Harry, to those who ask for it.
I've always prized myself on
my ability to turn a phrase.
Words are, in my not
so humble opinion...
..our most inexhaustible
source of magic...
..capable of both inflicting
injury and remedying it.
But I would, in this case,
amend my original statement to this:
Help... will always be given
at Hogwarts
to those
who deserve it.
Do not pity the dead,
Harry.
Pity the living.
And, above all,
all those who live without love.
Professor, my mother's
Patronus was a doe, wasn't it?
That's the same
as Professor Snape's.
It's curious,
don't you think?
Actually, if I think about it,
it doesn't seem curious at all.
I'll be going now, Harry.
Professor?
Is this all real?
Gr is it just happening
inside my head?
Of course it's happening
inside your head, Harry.
Why should that mean
that it's not real?
Professor?
What should I do?
BELLATRIX: My Lord?
My Lord,
are you hurt?
- My Lord?
- I don't need your help.
BELLATRIX: No.
Come.
The boy.
Is he dead?
(WHISPERS)
Is he alive?
Draco, is he alive?
Dead.
(THUDS)
GINNY: Who is that
Hagrid's carrying?
Neville, who is it?
VOLDEMORT: Harry Potter...
..is dead.
No! No!
VOLDEMORT: Silence.
Stupid girl.
Harry Potter is dead.
From this day forth,
you put your faith...
..in me.
Harry Potter is dead!
(ALL LAUGH)
And now is the time
to declare yourself.
Come forward
and join us.
Or die.
LUCIUS: Draco.
Draco.
NARCISSA: Draco...
..Come.
VOLDEMORT: Ah.
Well done, Draco.
Well done.
Well, I must say
I'd hoped for better.
(VOLDEMORT'S FOLLOWERS LAUGH)
And who might you be,
young man?
Neville Longbottom.
(VOLDEMORT'S FOLLOWERS LAUGHING)
Well, Neville, I'm sure we can
find a place for you in our ranks.
I'd like to say something.
Well, Neville,
I'm sure we'd all be fascinated
to hear
what you have to say.
- It doesn't matter Harry's gone.
- Stand down, Neville.
People die every day.
Friends,
family.
Yeah.
We lost Harry tonight.
But he's still with us, in here.
So's Fred...
..and Remus.
Tonks.
All of them.
They didn't die in vain.
But you will.
- Because you're wrong.
- Ha-ha-ha.
Harry's heart did beat for us.
For all of us.
This is not over!
(HARRY GRUNTS)
Confringo!
(YELLING)
BELLATRIX: No! No, come back!
Lucius! Come back!
Come back and fight!
Come back!
I'll lure him into the castle.
We have to kill the snake.
- HERMIONE: You'll need this.
- ARTHUR: Neville!
(HISSING NEARBY)
(WHOOSH)
(YELLS)
(HISSES)
Not my daughter, you bitch.
(LAUGHS)
(VOLDEMORT YELLS)
HARRY: You were right...
..when you told Snape
that wand was failing you.
It will always fail you.
VOLDEMORT: I killed Snape.
But what if the wand
never belonged to Snape?
What if its allegiance was
always to someone else?
Come on, Tom. Let's finish
this the way we started it.
Together.
(BOTH YELLING)
(YELLS)
(STUDENTS CHATTERING)
Ha, ha.
I always figured
he would be a big fellow.
I couldn't find my wand.
I haven't lost my wand in my entire life.
It was lost in the folds
of my gowns.
I managed to find it and
I dispatched a few of them...
HAGRID: Harry.
(HAGRID CHUCKLES)
HERMIONE: Why didn't it work
for him,
the Elder Wand?
It answered to
somebody else.
When he killed Snape,
he thought the wand would become his.
But the thing is,
the wand never belonged to Snape.
It was Draco who disarmed Dumbledore
that night in the astronomy tower.
From that moment on,
the wand answered to him.
Until...
..the other night
when I disarmed Draco
at Malfoy Manor.
So that means...
..it's mine.
RON: What should we do
with it?
We?
I'm just saying,
that's the Elder Wand,
the most powerful
wand in the world.
With that,
we'd be invincible.
Together.
(WOMEN LAUGH)
FATHER: Look after each other.
- Bag?
- Yeah.
Jumper?
I'll miss you.
RON: Here they come.
Dad,
what if I am put in Slytherin?
Albus Severus Potter...
..you were named after two
headmasters of Hogwarts.
One of them was Slytherin...
..and he was
the bravest man I've ever known.
But just say that I am.
Then Slytherin House
will have gained a wonderful young wizard.
But, listen,
if it really means that much to you,
you can choose Gryffindor.
The Sorting Hat takes
your choice into account.
- Really?
- Really.
(WHISTLE BLOWS)
- GIRL: Bye, Mum.
- CONDUCTOR: All aboard.
Ready?
Ready.
BOY: Come on, Jay,
get a move on.
JAMES: Come on.
(FROG CROAKING)
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
Sync corrections by srjanapala