Watch Movies, TV Series & Live Sports
www.admitme.app
Will you close it a little?
- Helen.
- Well, if it isn't old Roy.
Old solemn Roy himself.
Sit down, Roy. Sit on the floor
and hang your legs over.
- Take your hands off her.
- Oh, I can't take my hands off.
You heard what I said.
Take your hands off her.
Who asked you
to this party anyway?
Helen, let me take you home.
Home? Who wants to go home?
I'm having a marvelous time.
I was until you came in.
I advise you to get out
before you're kicked out.
Keep your... Keep your
filthy hands off of my girl.
Your girl. You fool.
I wouldn't belong to you
if you were the last man on Earth.
You're nothing to me. Nothing.
Come on, Roy.
Let's get out of here. Come on.
Oh, let's have it out.
I don't love you. I never have.
I never had any fun with you anyway.
You and your high ideals.
You're too good to live.
You're just a stupid prig if you ask me.
You make me sick, do you hear?
Sick. Now, get out here.
I hate the sight of you!
Come on, Roy.
Let's go across the street.
Sweet, sweet baby.
Handsome, big, strong baby.
N'est-ce pas?
Mmm, n'est-ce pas,
kiss Papa, huh?
Oh, baby.
Hello, chčri.
Aw, don't take it so hard, Roy.
Forget it.
Is your friend sick?
No. He'll be all right.
Drink up, Roy.
I still can't believe it.
You just don't know
anything about women.
They're all the same.
I've been telling you that for years.
Maybe you'll believe me now.
- Oh, Helen's not that sort.
- Oh, nonsense.
- It's the war. She's changed.
- You're wrong, Roy.
War doesn't change people.
It's... It's like getting drunk.
It brings out what people really are.
You can't make me believe
Helen was like that before.
Well, she was.
I've known it all along.
You too?
Oh, I'm sorry, Roy.
Don't take it so hard. She isn't worth it.
- I suppose you're right.
- Of course I'm right.
Listen, Roy, never love a woman.
Just make love to her.
You see, like this. Look.
Go ahead, Roy. Try it.
That's the way.
Oh! What you do, baby?
All wet! No, no, no, no!
Imbecile! Aw, baby. Voilŕ.
Hey, listen, Monte. Monte.
Go easy. We gotta go up at 3:00.
Oh, listen, Roy.
To hell with this 3:00 business.
What do you mean?
Just that.
To hell with it.
Say, you're crazy, Monte.
We can't get out of it now.
Oh, why can't we?
Listen, Roy, all this idealistic stuff
won't get you anywhere.
You tried it on Helen
and what happened?
You got a kick in the face.
You can't go through life
thinking the way you do.
People take advantage of you
and make a fool of you
the way she did.
- It's beginning to look
as though you're right.
- Of course I'm right.
I was right about Helen,
and now I'm right about
this 3:00 business too.
This is another thing entirely, Monte.
Why is it?
They're just taking advantage of you
in another way, that's all.
It's chaps like you
that are meat for them.
All they gotta do
is make it sound heroic,
and you fall for it.
Listen, Roy,
what's the difference if we don't go?
- But we can't get out of it now.
- Why can't we?
Listen, tell 'em...
tell 'em the motorcycle broke down.
Tell 'em anything.
What do you say, Roy?
Well...
Come on, old ooo-la-la.
Oh, no, no, no, chčri.
Oh, baby.
N'est-ce pas?
Oh, oui, oui, madam.
Oh, baby.
Oh, stop looking at your watch, Roy.
You're not going anywhere.
Yes, I am and so are you.
Who says I am?
Listen, Monte, we're a little drunk
and we've been talking wildly.
There's no way out of this
and we know it. Come on, Monte.
No, no. Let me alone.
Come on, old ooo-la-la.
Monte.
Why, they'd court-martial us
in a minute if we didn't show up.
Why, that's desertion, Monte.
They shoot people for that.
Come on. Let's get out of here.
Come on.
I suppose you're right.
Oh, no, no, no, no. Monte.
What a pair of fools
we are.
Let's go.
Easy, now.
Easy.
Look out for the firing pin.
Righto. I got it.
Contactor.
Contact.
Ground speed here.
Keep this site trained on the target.
Then pull the release
when you hit the stop.
Do you understand?
Don't forget the leveler.
Good-bye.
Contactor.
Contact.
Remember this ship weighs
20,000 pounds. Good luck.
Thank you.
Roy, the depot.
Roy, look there!
They've seen us.
They're coming on.
For Christ's sake.
Hey, Roy, look.
They hit our right motor.
I got him!
Roy! Look over there.
It's our squadrons. They're coming!
Roy, they've gone.
Jesus.
Son of a Boche.
Hey!
It's me! Hey! It's me!
Goddamn it!
It's old Baldy. Hey! Baldy.
Hello. It's Baldy.
Look, Roy.
It's Baldy.
You see that guy?
Good old Baldy.
Good boy. See that? He's got him.
Hey, look. He's got him.
He's got him.
Oh. Look. They've changed around.
Our strut's gone.
That son of a bitch.
Roy, he got us! Roy!
Go down! Go down! Go down!
One more for Baldy!
No more control?
Pull her up!
Oh, my God! We're on fire!
We're burning!
Roy, get down!
Do something! Roy!
Ah, so. We meet again.
It was you who bombed
the depot at Spraug, nicht wahr?
Yes.
And you were flying
a German plane, nicht wahr?
- Yes.
- Very clever.
It is a pity you must
take your congratulations from me.
There are a few questions
I must ask you.
If you answer them simply,
it will be easy for you.
To what squadron of
the Royal Flying Corps are you attached?
Just why were you sent to bomb
that munition depot this morning?
It was our natural target.
But possibly it was to clear the way
for a little surprise attack, huh?
You are surprised.
We know all about it,
so you need not be afraid to talk.
Now, please, when and where
is the attack to be made?
Oh, you are stupid not to tell.
It is nothing.
For you the war is over, nicht wahr?
We are friends.
Hmm.
Listen, if you tell me,
I will see that you are sent to
a special camp reserved only
for certain prisoners of war.
It's near Munich.
Far away from all this.
You will have every comfort.
And in a few months from now
when the war is over,
you will be alive and in good health,
which is more than most of us
will be able to say.
So, you see?
It can be easy for you.
Now, please.
So, you will not tell?
Possibly you do not know
that flying a German plane...
is the same as wearing
a German uniform.
Any disguised soldier is a spy,
nicht wahr?
And you know
what happens to spies?
I think you two friends
had better talk it over.
I will give you 15 minutes.
If you change your mind
and tell, good.
If not, you will be shot.
Do you think he was bluffing?
No, he wasn't bluffing.
He's the man
I was to fight that duel with.
Really? Quite a coincidence.
He's got it in for me.
Nah, he's probably forgotten it
by this time.
The brigade will be
going over pretty soon, Monte.
Yes.
Roy, look.
Oh, save it to wipe your nose on.
God, what nerve.
Roy.
Roy, I can't face it.
I'm going to tell.
Don't be a fool, Monte. Do you realize
what it would mean if we told?
It would mean being alive
when this bloody war's over.
But, Monte, you can't.
To hell with your heroic stuff.
I wanna live.
I'm not gonna be shot down
like that. I'm going to tell.
Wait a minute. Monte.
But I...
Listen.
Let me go.
You?
Yes. You're all upset.
I'll bargain with him, and perhaps
I won't have to tell him everything.
I- I'll come with you.
No.
You said he's got it in for you.
Now, let me do it alone.
All right.
Tell the general I'm ready to talk.
Good. Come.
Ah, yes.
So, you have changed your mind?
Yes.
My friend will never tell,
but I wanna live. I'm ready to talk.
You are very wise.
Now, please, draw a rough map for me
showing your positions,
brigade numbers, disposition,
hour of attack, purpose, number of men.
Wait a minute.
I'll tell only on one condition.
Ah, so, a condition.
Yes.
If I give this information,
my friend will know it.
Back home after the war,
he'll tell everyone that I was a traitor.
You leave that to me.
Why not let me
have that satisfaction?
What do you mean?
I do not understand.
One does not kill a friend.
Friend. He's not my friend.
He stole the girl I love
and I hate him.
Huh. History repeats itself.
You make rather hard terms.
I'll tell
only on that condition.
One bullet.
What if I miss?
Give me two to make sure.
No. A good soldier
will need only one.
Very well.
Not so fast.
He will give you the bullet outside.
Well?
I didn't tell, Monte.
Why? What happened?
Has he changed his mind?
No. Don't you think
you can go through with it now?
What do you mean?
Of course we can.
It won't even hurt.
It'll all be over in a second.
We can stand anything for a second.
No, no, Roy. L-I can't do it.
I'm going to tell.
Listen, Monte. We tell,
the whole brigade will be wiped out.
Three thousand men,
and they all want to live too.
You wouldn't spoil
their chances, would you?
That's not my business.
I didn't start this war.
I didn't get them into this mess.
Let 'em take care of themselves.
They'll get wiped out
sooner or later anyway.
I wanna live. Live!
You won't tell, I'll tell.
Listen, Monte!
I'll tell! I'll tell!
Let me out!
I'll tell everything I know.
The brigade is moving up.
They're going to attack...
Oh. Roy.
Oh, Monte. Monte.
Monte.
Don't cry, Roy.
It was the only thing
you could do.
The brigade, Roy.
Yes, Monte?
They'll be all right now,
won't they?
Yes.
Who's that?
It's the general.
You... You thought we'd tell,
didn't you?
Good old Roy.
You won't tell, and I...
forgotten... it all.
Oh, Roy. Roy.
Yes?
Where are you?
Don't go away, Roy.
I'm here, Monte.
Can't you feel me holding you?
Hello, Karl. Fig eights.
Cold up here in the night patrol.
Awful to be in the dark.
Oh. I'm afraid.
Look out. Look out!
We're falling! We're going to crash!
Do something, Roy!
Quick! Quick! Quick!
It's all right, Monte. Monte?
It's all right.
Monte? Monte.
Oh.
Well?
You heard what my brother said.
Your brother?
I'll never tell you anything.
Achtung!
I'll be with you
in just a minute, Monte.
Come on, you Seventh Brigade.
We got 'em now.
>> Napisy pobrane z http://napisy.org <<
>>>>>>>> nowa wizja napisów <<<<<<<<
Watch Movies, TV Series & Live Sports
www.admitme.app