But behave as though
nothing had happened.
- Lunch is ready, ma'am.
- Thank you, Mary.
Congratulations.
That was a fine series of articles,
the best things I've read about the island.
As for that one today,
that was- that was the goods.
You said things
that needed saying.
From my point of view,
I can't tell you how grateful I am.
- In what way?
- In every way.
I've not been trusted.
The people here, West Indian...
they thought of me as a Fleury, a feudal planter,
bought their ancestors in the marketplace.
But now? I'm standing for the legislature.
Why not?
I combine black and white, the new and the old.
I've a foot in both camps.
And your article gave me
the guts that I needed.
- What'll it be, gentlemen?
- Rum and, uh, ginger. Two of them.
Just water.
I didn't see this before. But now I can
look out at those faces and I can say to them...
"My grandmother was
of African ancestry.
She came over in a slave trader
just as yours did."
Yes, I can say to them,
"I'm one of you now."
- Cheers.
- Hello.
- I want to talk to you.
You do?
Who the devil are you?
Fleury, Maxwell Fleury.
Ah. Oh, so you are.
What do you want to do?
Make a contribution to the Belfontaine Fund?
- What?
- The fund-The Belfontaine Fund.
I want to talk to you... alone.
There's something that needs
settling between us.
I can't think what.
Anyway, whatever it is, let's do it inside.
- Are you expecting a girl?
- A girl? What would I want with a girl?
Excuse me.
Shall we go in here?
- Make you a whiskey?
- No.
No, I don't believe in chaps
drinking themselves to death.
Leave that for retired colonels.
Remember that song?
You know, I was once married, Fleury.
It was in hospital
in Tripoli during the war.
My wife fell in love
with a Polish musician...
and thought that the best thing
for both of us was a quick divorce.
- What's that supposed to mean?
- Mean? Nothing. It's just a fact.
A second chance-That's what a man needs,
a blasted second chance.
Well, what was it needed settling?
- I want you to leave my wife alone.
- Your wife?
I'm not a fool. The trouble is
you weren't smart enough.
- The whole place stank of those fancy cigarettes of yours!
- Are you out of your mind?
I've had as much as I can take from you
and this island. Do you understand?
- Stay away from my wife.
- Look here. I'm fed up with idiots.
- Are you suggesting I've been making passes-
- I'm not suggesting anything.
- I'm just telling you.
- Then you can ruddy-well untell it and apologize.
And get this into your stupid skull.
I don't make passes at wives
of acquaintances, and I don't share my women.
And even if I did, I wouldn't take something
from someone like you...
with a tarbrush rubbed across his face.
Tarbrush! I'll show all of you!
Tarbrush! Tarbrush!
Carson?
Carson.
- I suppose there's no doubt
about it being murder?
No, not the slightest.
- Anyone in England to whom we can send a cable?
- Not that I know of, sir.
Uh, we could, of course,
put a notice in the Times.
Yes. That's the least we can do.
Was there a woman in the case,
do you think?
- Politics?
- No.
A thief, then.
All right, that's your affair.
I won't meddle.
It seems a bit sad, though,
a chap's life ending like that.
You'll see to it, won't you,
that he's put under with full military honors?
- Of course, sir.
- That will be all, sir?
Yes, that's all.
Good-bye, Colonel.
I suppose this business of Bradshaw's article
is all over Jamestown.
- That and Carson's death.
- Yes, sir.
- What's your opinion, Denis?
- About what, sir?
Having the wrong
sort of grandmother.
Well, um, it's difficult to
pick one's ancestors, sir.
Yes. It is, isn't it?
Send a girl in, will you?
I want to dictate a note to Whitehall.
Right, sir.
The governor has some dictation.
Would you go in to him?
I finished the letter to London.
Is it all right?
I've never known
anyone like you.
I never suspected
there could be anything like this.
You're not wearing it.
Well, should I?
Here, in the office?
Wear it.
Here. Let me.
You didn't look at the letter.
The letter? It's perfect.
Jocelyn, I've got the car.
Would you like to come for a drive?
Why don't you, Jocelyn?
We'll go on alone.
Well, I- I have to go past the house
and change my clothes.
All right.
- Hello, Colonel.
- Hello.
Mr. Bradshaw.
Appalling thing. Carson.
He and I were quite good friends.
I can't understand how it happened.
Is there anyone you suspect, Colonel Whittingham?
Now, Mrs. Fleury, you know policemen.
They suspect everybody.
What time did it happen?
The coroner puts it
at about 10:00.
That's odd.
I went to the club after I left Father's.
I was worrying about Bradshaw's article,
how they'd take it.
I may have passed Carson's house,
at the very moment-
How awful. You might
have saved his life.
A few minutes earlier, I might have met him
in the street. We'd have stopped and talked.
He'd have asked me in for a drink,
and then we'd have found this-
- I suppose it was a thief.
- Quite likely.
Maxwell, on your way to the club,
Bradshaw mentioned the time...
and it occurred to me that you might have
passed Carson's house.
Uh, did you see anybody
hanging about outside?
See anybody? No.
There was a car
that drove by afterward.
Afterward? After what?
After I passed Carson's house.
I'm sorry I can't be of more help, Colonel.
- Do you think she'll care, Colonel?
- Who?
The ex-Mrs. Carson.
He was very much in love with her, you know.
I couldn't say.
- Poor man. He came out here with such high hopes.
- Mmm.
Well, a chap can't pick the way he'll die,
or we'd all do better at it.
Good-bye, Colonel.
- Here, Colonel, sir.
- Right. Out you get.
I steal nothing, Colonel, sir.
I find purse in cane field.
No money in purse. I keep purse.
Why not keep purse, Colonel, sir?
Now, don't fuss.
Nobody's blaming you.
You just show me where you found that purse,
then you can go home.
What? No further than that?
No, Colonel, sir.
I found purse right here.
Right.
All right. Bring it back.
All right. Start it up.
No, no. You stay there.
Okay. Back you get.
Drive him to his village.
Here. This'll make up
for the day's work you lost.
- Thank you, sir.
- Everything okay, Colonel, sir?
Fine.
Three.
- Oh, hello, Maxwell.
- Hello, Mavis.
Hello, darling.
There's some news in the paper.
- Oh, what is it?
- They found the wallet.
- What wallet?
- Carson's wallet. Here.
Here. Let me see.
- Would you like a drink?
- Yes, I would.
- How about you, Mavis?
- I'd love one.
Poor Hilary.
That's all they're talking about at the club.
H.E. will probably get a cable
from the colonial office.
They're worried
about the tourist trade.
Of course, there is that
American newspaper man here.
Well, there's one thing sure. It is a small island.
He can't run far, whoever did it.
Tell Sylvia I had to go into town.
Get me 621.
Yes? Just hold on a minute.
Oh, never mind.
Good morning, Maxwell.
Anything I can do for you?
I was wondering, Colonel,
if you'd be kind enough...
to chairman a meeting up
in my district next week.
- I'm standing for election.
- Glad to.
- S-Sylvia all right?
- Yes, fine.
Good.
Uh, I see the papers say
you've found Carson's wallet.
Yes. Yes, Carson's papers were in it.
- That's how we identified it.
- That was stupid.
- What?
- Leaving the papers. At least, I'd say it was stupid.
Would you? Huh.
I'd say too clever.
I ran into Bradshaw.
He's certain it was a housebreaker.
Was he really?
I wonder why.
Is there any other
possibility?
A policeman has to keep
his eyes open, you know.
A chap my age
can't afford to miss a bit.
Particularly with the governor all stirred up.
You mean, it might have been made
to look like a thief s handiwork?
My dear fellow,
how would I know?
There are 15 possibilities.
I'm in the dark.
Which is the likeliest?
Never have preconceptions, my boy.
Open mind, that's the thing.
- Huh.
- You mustn't look too disappointed.
The work gets done.
Never fear.
Let's say I've guessed
who the murderer is.
A guess, mind you.
No more.
Well, it wouldn't do me the slightest
of good, my dear fellow. Not the slightest.
A court wants proof.
So, I- I just wait.
Patience, my boy.
That's the ticket.
Yes, I know that sounds-
sounds dull to you impatient chaps...
but that's police work.
Oh, he'll probably play into my hands,
whoever the fellow is.
I'm in no hurry.
You know, I- I said something
like that to a bloke once.
I can't remember who.
Oh, middle age, my boy,
no memory at all.
Oh, yes. Yes, in B.G.
That's where it was. Yes.
Yes, forgery.
What put me on to my man
was a- a slip he made.
Tiny one. Hardly noticed it.
Chap said "afterward" instead of "after."
Get the point?
Absolutely the key.
No. No, probably not.
I suppose I didn't explain it properly.
"Afterward." That's what gave me the clue.
"Afterward"?
Absolutely, my dear fellow.
That's what
put me on the scent.
I'm glad you dropped by.
Happy to do that chairman thing for you.
- You ring me up the day you need it. Cheerio.
- Thank you.
Halt!
You're late.
I'm sorry.
I almost didn't get here.
- Why not?
- Oh, it doesn't matter now.
It does to me.
Why?
Why did you choose
this place to meet?
This plantation used to
belong to my family.
It was the first on the island.
I wanted you to see it.
Your family?
I didn't know that.
It was destroyed during a slave uprising
in 1843, during the French rule.
I wonder what
could have caused it?
Any number of reasons.
A single insult, a whipping, a girl.
Who knows?
Do you know what happened
to the owners?
That was more than
a hundred years ago.
And, now you're here,
and I'm here.
Do you still feel that anyone whose skin
is different from yours is an enemy?
- Do you think I do?
- I don't know.
At carnival time,
my brother-in-law's car was damaged...
his telephone wires cut.
You hate Maxwell, don't you?
You think of him as an enemy.
I think of him as a snob,
as an arrogant plantation owner.
Is that the reason
why you almost didn't get here?
Or did they tell you
that you shouldn't be seen with me?
That I'm an upstart, a nobody
who's gotten control of the union.
That I'm a dangerous man
who should be watched carefully.
You don't suppose I'd listen to them?
I only believe in what I see and what I know.
Do you know what
they say about me?
Poor Mavis Norman,
always getting into trouble.
Always picking the wrong man.
- Do you think of me as an enemy?
- No.
What are you thinking?
That you feel you're lost,
but you're not.
Because you're looking
for something real.
And as long as you're looking
for something real, you're not lost.
I suppose you and your father discussed
that article of Bradshaw's?
- Of course.
- What did he say?
Well, he said we ought to announce
our engagement at once...
and then have
a celebration party.
- When did he say that?
- Last night. When he got back from Guiana.
And what did he say
about our getting married?
"First things first," he said.
"We can talk later about what people
in Victorian homes might call 'naming the day."'
How neat.
- What?
- Your father's no fool.
I thought it was
very decent of him.
What else could he say?
It wouldn't be diplomatic, would it...
for the governor to offend
the whole colored population of Santa Marta?
Engaged. And then no one can say
that G.H. draws a color line.
- Of course, marriage-
- I bel- My father's never lied to me.
Do you think he'd run
the risk of having a grandson...
an eventual heir,
who's part Negro?
He'll see to it that you go back to England.
Not without you.
It doesn't matter.
The marriage isn't important anyway.
Oh, now, Jocelyn,
we've got to get this clear.
- Bradshaw's article won't mean anything as far-
- It's clear.
It's perfectly clear.
A romance-
isn't that what you wanted?
Eighteen months was such
a long time in Egypt, and without a girl.
Jocelyn, you've got to listen to me.
When we're back in England this won't mean a-
I don't went to hear
about England.
Whatever happens,
I want you to remember one thing.
You'll never be more loved
than you are right now.
What time is it?
It's almost 8:00.
I think we should go.
We're going to be very happy in London,
you know, forever and ever.
Of course.
Forever and ever.
- Have you any Rock Hinde?
- Yes, we have.
I'll take your Rock Hinde.
- Yes.
- Give me some Rock Hinde.
Give me some Rock Hinde!
- Fish for dinner?
- Rock Hinde. You get it cheap here.
- Oh. I must tell my wife.
- Send it up to my house.
That election meeting
of yours is all set, I hear.
Yes. You're coming out there, aren't you?
I'm counting on it.
Anything new about Carson?
I mean, the man who did it?
I've come to the conclusion
it was an accident.
- An accident?
- Yes. Unpremeditated. A quarrel. That's what it was.
Last thing the poor devil wanted,
Carson dead.
If only he'd come to the police station
right away, we might have smoothed it out.
What a fool he was.
A fool?
Absolutely. You see, the chap who did it,
I'm- I'm sorry for him.
He's not strong enough
to bear the burden of his guilt.
Ever read a book called
Crime and Punishment?
- No. Why?
- Well, you should. It's about just this sort of thing.
A man who has
committed a crime...
and his relationship with a detective
who knows he's committed it...
but still can't prove it.
There's a-They have a-
have a secret together.
There's a-There's
a deep bond between them.
It's rather like a love affair...
because the detective is the only man
in the world who understands him.
And in his heart, the murderer wants
to be found out by the detective.
Now, this fellow
in the Carson case, you know...
what I'd like to do
is to go up to him...
take him by the arm
and tell him not to worry.
"I'll do my best for you,"
I want to say to him.
"I'm not out to punish you.
I'm not out to punish anyone.
"It's just that I've got to maintain law and order.
But I mean you no harm.
"We'll-We'll get it fixed
as manslaughter.
"That might mean
only five years...
"and the sentence could
be remitted for good behavior.
"It might be only three years.
"I know that sounds
a long time now, but...
"three years passes very quickly.
"Now, you look back three years.
Does it seem a long time?
"No, of course it doesn't.
"And, after all, three years
isn't such a big price to pay...
"for your peace of mind.
So, come now.
Confess. Tell me."
Well, that's what I'd like to say to the poor devil...
if he came to me.
Well, I'll be seeing you.
Oh, that book, Crime and Punishment,
I'll send it over to you.
When you get a chance,
you read it.
Yes.
- Hello.
Good evening.
Excuse me.
I won't be a minute.
Are you nervous?
So am I.
All these people.
It seems so strange and unbelievable,
our being here.
Do you remember the day
of the governor's party...
when poor Hilary Carson
suggested you run for election?
- I never really thought-
- I remember.
It must have come to his mind
that very moment...
because when he came out
to the house that morning-
- He came out to the house?
- Yes.
You knew Carson rather well, didn't you?
Well- No.
I- I wouldn't say well.
Why?
Why did he come out
to the house?
It had to do with
the Belfontaine Fund.
The Belfontaine Fund?
Yes, he wanted to find out
what sort of a gift your father wanted.
It was intended to be some sort
of token of his services to Santa Marta.
He said don't mention it to anybody,
particularly Maxwell.
It was intended as a surprise.
That's all. That's all it was.
Of course.
What did you imagine it was?
It's time to start.
May I have
your attention, please?
I'm here tonight as chairman of a meeting
at which Mr. Maxwell Fleury...
who is offering himself as your representative
in the Legislative Council...
will explain his position to you.
Now, you all know Mr. Fleury.
Few West Indian families
bear a name as respected as his.
Mr. Fleury.
The elections for which I stand before you-
The election for which I-
Quiet! Quiet! Stop this!
You've all been given
a chance to vote.
When the time comes,
you'll use it.
And now, let him
use his right to speak.
The floor is yours, Mr. Fleury.
I will not speak to you
from this paper.
This paper is filled with words
that come from my head.
I- I will try to speak to you with words
that come from my heart.
Many of you
out there know me.
You've cut my sugar cane
and harvested my coffee crop.
And, yet, I have not known you.
And in this, I've failed,
as I have failed in... other things.
To deny this would be
to deny truth, and...
I will speak
to you tonight only truth.
I have passed you in the fields
or in the cocoa sheds...
and you've been just a name,
or a face, or a number in a book.
And I've lived in a world
through which you moved only as... shadows...
to be feared or ignored.
I've now lived in the two worlds
of Santa Marta.
I know how they both think,
how they both feel.
I also know that
they cannot exist...
if they're cut off from each other
by suspicion and fear...
each in its own loneliness...
as no human being can exist,
in his own loneliness.
This bridge I can help you build.
I ask for your faith, your trust.
Do not deny them to me.
I'll answer any questions
from the floor.
The floor is now
open for questions.
I have a few, Mr. Chairman.
I was as moved
by Mr. Fleury's speech as anyone else.
And I agree when he says that the two worlds
cannot exist separate from each other.
The question I would like
to ask Mr. Fleury is this.
Does he think that
the only issue here is one of color?
Is he saying that that is the reason
why we should vote for him?
Is he saying,
"Vote for me because I am one of you"?
Is that what
you're saying, Mr. Fleury?
Because if you are,
I would like to take that issue up...
with your permission, Mr. Chairman.
Mr. Fleury said he has
existed in the two worlds of Santa Marta.
- Which do you think he'll represent?
- I would like to answer that.
When I'm finished, Mr. Chairman!
Would Mr. Fleury
also answer this?
You said that you came here tonight
only to speak the truth.
Wouldn't it also be true to say
that the only reason that you seek the election...
is to revenge yourself upon the whites
whom you now think despise you?
That the only reason
that you want to be black...
is because you're afraid that the white world
will not let you be white anymore?
That you want
to use us, our votes...
so that you can still rule
in that world that you still belong to.
And tell us another truth, Mr. Fleury.
In your heart, deep down inside...
don't you still think of us as slaves?
- As a stupid, ignorant people?
- That's a lie!
No, Mr. Fleury! That is the truth!
And the issue here is
not just one of color.
The issue here is,
who is really best fit to represent the people?
Who knows them the best?
Who feels for them the most?
Who's really a part of them?
Is it you, Mr. Fleury, or is it me?
Now you may answer, Mr. Fleury.
- Boyeur! Boyeur!
- Boyeur!
Boyeur! Boyeur!
Boyeur! Boyeur! Boyeur!
David Boyeur!
He's right!
I'm not one of you!
I don't belong to you!
I don't want to be one of you!
I never did!
All right, friends.
The meeting's over. Let's go home.
My comb's gone.
I must have left it. Lend me yours?
- Am I presentable now?
- Mm-hmm.
What was the name of the film
we were supposed to see?
- Red Shoes.
- Oh. Was it good?
A bit long.
Good night, darling.
Uh, Jocelyn...
there's something I want to say.
- Darling, can't-
- It won't take long.
I want us to be married
before I go back to England.
Why?
Because I've an odd feeling that
if we don't get married now, we never shall.
You know, you're the most difficult person
to get a wedding ring on.
Am I?
I'll try not to be.
You're up late.
I've been waiting for Maxwell to call.
How was the film?
A bit long.
Mother, there's something
I want to talk to you about.
Is there a match?
Fruit bowl.
You were saying?
In about three months,
I want to go to Canada.
I'd like to start
making the arrangements now.
Canada? Why on earth
do you want to go there?
Because I'm pregnant.
Does Euan know?
You're sure that you are?
There isn't any doubt.
Well, you're certainly calm about it.
You might show
some shame, some guilt.
If it will make you feel any happier,
I feel quite guilty.
I thought Euan's father wouldn't let us marry,
so I settled for what there was.
I thought, first of all,
I'd go to Trinidad, and then I changed my mind.
I think Canada's the best idea.
I could have it adopted. It shouldn't be hard.
There's only one thing.
I shouldn't like Daddy to know.
He's been through enough.
- That's why I need your help.
- My help?
You care about appearances,
what people will say.
Thank you.
Of course, you know that
you've behaved stupidly.
You have behaved like a peasant girl
in the cane fields.
I suppose that's neither here nor there.
It's the future that matters.
May I have another match?
You might at least strike it.
You're engaged.
You can get married in a hurry.
You've not quarreled with him?
He says he wants to marry me
when he goes back to England.
- I'm not marrying Euan.
- Why not? You're insane.
- You are still in love with him?
- Yes.
Then what on earth is there
to stop your marrying?
I've told you the reason.
Don't be ridiculous.
The English Peerage isn't that sacred.
Think of Euan.
Think of the jokes there'd be made about it.
You might have thought of that
two months ago.
I didn't know then about
my Jamaican grandmother.
- Is that the only reason why you're refusing to marry him?
- It is.
If you had the chance,
if things were different-
- No. They're not different.
- I know. I know. But supposing they were?
Would you give anything
to marry him?
Yes.
Very well.
I owe you this.
You need have no qualms
about marrying Euan.
There isn't a drop of African blood
in your veins. My husband isn't your father.
- Isn't?
- No.
Well, then who?
That's immaterial.
It's better you shouldn't know.
He's completely English.
You can rest assured of that.
I shall tell Lord Templeton who he is.
He has a right to know who will be
the other grandfather of his grandchildren.
Telling him will be the hardest thing
I've ever had to do.
But it must be done.
He may have
your old-fashioned ideas.
I must ask you for the same
consideration you asked me.
I'd rather your father-
I'd rather my husband didn't know.
You were always so devoted.
I never conceived the possibility
of another man in your life.
Children don't.
They think mistakes are their privilege.
Mother-
I don't want you to
talk to Lord Templeton.
I don't want you
to tell him anything.
But he should know.
I'll tell Euan... eventually.
But I won't have you
humiliate yourself for my sake.
Or for Euan's...
or even for Lord Templeton's.
Shall I put the car away, darling?
No, I'll put it away later.
Are you hungry?
Not very.
There's some cold lobster in the refrigerator
and a bottle of champagne.
We could have it upstairs.
Wouldn't you like that?
I suppose.
Do you know what
I was thinking on the way home?
That I've never seen snow.
Imagine being my age
and never seeing snow.
Oh, it would be so wonderful
to go to someplace after Santa Marta...
where they have real blizzards,
real winters.
When did Whittingham
send this over?
The other day.
I forgot to mention it to you.
Have you read it?
Yes.
The murderer confesses,
I suppose.
Yes.
Is he married?
The man in the book who does the murder?
- No, he's not married.
- Pity.
I might have been
tempted to read it if he were.
Why?
He wouldn't want to
hurt his wife.
He wouldn't want her ever to know about it
and suffer on account of it.
The detective knows, doesn't he?
I mean, in the book.
And the fellow who did it is in a trap.
And it's closing in,
getting tighter every day.
Not a chance of
ever getting out of it.
What about that champagne
you promised me?
Were you jealous
of Hilary Carson?
Yes. I envied him because
he was the kind of man...
I thought that I wanted
to be and I couldn't.
I thought you were
attracted to him.
Hilary Carson?
I loved you.
I thought you didn't love me.
I thought that
sooner or later...
you'd fall in love with some man
who was better suited to you.
I thought Carson was
that kind of a man.
- Maxwell.
- Yes.
You didn't have
anything to do with the-
Don't be foolish.
You know that
I'm incapable of killing a man.
I'm going upstairs.
I'll bring the champagne up.
Darling?
I-I'll be out in a moment.
I wonder when Jocelyn's
getting married.
Funny, a few weeks ago,
I'd have been envious of her.
I mean, London, a big house,
and being Lady Templeton.
Now it doesn't matter so much.
Do hurry, darling.
I saw a film the other day
about a little town in New England.
New England. That's where I'd like to live.
The characters in the film
lived in a little house...
and it had a wonderful kitchen
with all sorts of gadgets.
With a kitchen like that,
you don't need servants.
That's how I'd like to live.
Not in some big old house
built hundreds of years ago...
and getting dressed
for a lonely dinner.
You see? That's the sort
of woman you married.
Maxwell!
Darling, will you call
Colonel Whittingham...
and tell him that I'm coming down
to see him right away?
I like this.
I've resigned.
The governor found out about us.
Oh? Well, what did he say?
He left the decision to me.
Oh, he talked about the book too.
He was disturbed about that also.
But this is the best thing
you've ever done.
Even if it's true, he said, it isn't fair
to those who've had to stay on the island.
Fair? It's true!
It's so true and
so good that it hurts.
When are you leaving?
Friday.
- What about you?
- You needn't worry.
I'll be broke.
There's nothing much I've saved here.
And the book's a long way
from being done.
We've never looked ahead. We-
We never discussed anything...
but just lived from day to day.
Is there something
you want to discuss?
Yes, there is.
Life without you.
Writing things you won't
be the first to read.
Feeling things we can't share.
How long would it
take you to pack?
But I-
Mmm, two hours.
I don't have very much either.
There's a plane leaves
for England on Friday.
I'll send a car for you.
All right.
You don't seem very surprised-
at our going to England together.
Where you go, I go.
May I have your attention, please?
This is the final call...
for B.W.I. A Viscount
Flight 072 to New York...
connecting with B.O.A.C.
Monarch to London now loading.
Do you mind if I don't
wait until the plane goes?
Sylvia's alone.
Good-bye.
Well, sir. There they go.
Poor Julian.
Who'd have thought a son of his?
What will the indictment be
against Maxwell, Colonel?
Well, we'll try and get it in
as manslaughter, sir.
I meant to have a talk
with Euan when he arrived- father to son.
But I never did.
Now he's married.
Good-bye, sir.
There's the plane for England.
In the girl's case-
Does it work the other way around?
I mean, Denis Archer marries Margot.
Euan marries Jocelyn.
But, when it's the other way around,
does it make any difference?
Out here, yes.
How big is Santa Marta?
It's 50 miles long.
There are other countries.
My skin is my country.
Maybe the men looking at Margot
at some cocktail party in Bloomsbury...
or at a literary tea-
well, they'd envy Denis Archer.
Their own wives look sort of dull
when she walks into a room.
But if I were to walk in with you,
or a girl like you as my wife-
Do you care what stupid
and prejudiced people think?
You've never had to fight stupidity or prejudice.
Besides, I'd be a fool.
- Why?
- Because it would be inevitable.
What would be?
That night that she'd forget herself
and call me a nigger.
You can't mean that.
You can't possibly mean that!
- No. I don't.
- Then why did you say it?
Because here is my world.
These are my people, and this is where I belong.
If I went to England, who would I be?
What would I be?
- David Boyeur.
- No.
I'd be an exile in a bowler hat,
sipping tea, and carrying a rolled umbrella...
talking with the other exiles about how much
we could do if we were only there.
But I'm here.
I don't have to go.
And even here,
I'd be in your way, wouldn't I?
Yes, you would be
in my way.
- Besides, they'd never understand.
- Who wouldn't?
My own people.
They'd feel I betrayed them.
I have no choice.
You're like a rock.
Yes. I'm buried deep right here.
My people have their freedom.
They've got a vote.
They've got power now.
And I've got to show them
how to use it.
When I'm through here
in Santa Marta...
I'll go to St. Kitts and Barbados and Grenada-
the whole archipelago.
Shall I tell you why
you won't go to England?
You don't want that power for your people.
You want it for yourself.
You're afraid to go there
because you won't have it anymore.
- Do you really mean that?
- I wanted to admire you...
to feel that you were
superior to most men.
People don't count with you.
Nothing counts with you but power.
You use people.
You climb on their backs.
You can't mean that.
No, I don't.
You're right and I'm wrong.
I'm wrong and you're right.
- And that's the end, is it?
- Yes. That's the end.