- You're about to see a story
of bold knights and beautiful maidens.
- A story of love and hatred
and prejudice.
- Though our story is old,
- the love, the hatred
and the prejudice are ever new.
Watch Movies, TV Series & Live Sports
www.admitme.app
Help!
Ah! Holy god of Abraham, spare me!
Silence, if you value your life!
[gasping]
Holy, father, I beg you.
Silence.
Follow me.
This way.
You see.
They've been lying
in wait for you.
Where is he?
Where is this Jew?
Well?
He's gone, Sire.
Gone?
Disappeared!
Imbecile!
You let him get away!
They're Normans.
Saxons or Normans,
what does it matter to me?
Do I rejoice because the brave
Normans cross the channel
and defeat the brave Saxons?
What's the difference?
They both treat us like dogs.
You call them brave knights.
I call them thieves.
A rich merchant, I fear,
is fair game.
No matter. You have saved my life,
and I am forever in your debt.
[horses whinnying;
riders retreating]
If you keep to this road any
longer, sir, no one can help you.
I shall be lost otherwise.
I know this country.
Where are you bound?
To Ashby, the great tournament.
Why, then, we can
travel together.
Ahhhh. May I ask who you are,
that I may thank for my deliverance?
Merely a poor pilgrim
returning from the Holy Land.
Ah!
Come. To waste any more
time here would be dangerous.
There.
There lies Ashby.
Ahaaa.
The blessings of Jacob
be upon you, pilgrim.
How am I going to repay you?
Oh, I want nothing.
You shall have a horse and
armor for the tournament.
But, how did you
know, that I...
Ha, ha, I see who that was...
beneath your robe.
The chain mail of a knight
and the golden spurs.
You shall have everything
that you need.
Then, I must warn you, sir,
both horse and armor
may be lost in the jousting.
Ahhh, that's impossible.
Your lance's good use will
be as powerful as the rod of Moses.
[trumpet blare announces
the tournament at Ashby]
[crowd cheering]
[crowds applause
the entertainments]
[knight's horse neighs]
[crowds brawling]
[knights suiting up in
preparation for the joust]
knight Front de Boeuf
knight De Bracy
My little Pouqant, eh?
Ha, ha, ha.
knight Brian de Bois-Guilbert
[a knight Templar]
[arrival of Prince John
and retinue]
[acting king]
[crowd greets the prince]
Cedric, the Saxon.
[John and Fitzurse,
his advisor]
[Cedric with son Athelstane]
"Norman dogs!"
[Wamba in rear]
- Careful master. -Huh?
- They say Prince John
has ten thousand ears.
Well, let him here me, then.
I'll say it to his face.
[Isaac of York arrives
with daughter Rebecca]
[crowd applauding arrival
of Cedric's ward Rowena]
Who is that?
That's Cedric of Rotherwood, a Saxon lord.
I meant the lady.
Oh, that's his ward
the Lady Rowena
from the royal land
of Alfred the Great.
She's beautiful.
If a Saxon can
be called beautiful.
[trumpets announce
to start of the contest]
Challengers!
Reginald...Front de Beouf!
[cheers]
Maurice De Bracy!
and Brian...Guilbert!
[cheers]
[Brian de Bois-Guilbert
selects a lady to honor]
[Rowena, Cedic's ward?]
[or Rebecca, daughter
of Izaac of York?]
[her father refuses]
[crowd cheers Prince John]
[ de Bracy]  Listen to the crowd.
Prince John is well
accepted here today.
He would do well to take
over the throne now,
before King Richard gets
back from the Holy Land.
Richard dies
the moment he returns.
[the Norman contenders
salute Prince John]
Fitzurse.
- Yes, Your Grace.
Are we ready to begin?
Well, there's still the choosing
of a queen for the tournament, sire.
Um.
If it would please, Your Highness,...
- Um? - ...my daughter, perhaps.
It might appear unseemly
to announce you daughter
before the tournament
has yet begun.
Let the gallant knight who
conquers the field here today
make the choice.
These three noble challengers
will undertake all comers.
Each challenger may be selected
by touching his shield with a lance.
If the shield is touched
with the reverse end of the lance,
then sharp points
will not be used.
But, if the sharp tip of the lance
touches the shield...
then the combat is understood
to be...with sharp weapons.
If any knight should break the lance
of all three challengers here before me,
then Prince John will declare that knight
the victor in this day's combat.
The prince wants the victor
to choose the queen.
Prince John has declared
the victor will have the honor
of choosing our queen
of love and beauty!
[cheering]
Normans.
All three Normans.
[to Athelstane, his son]
Is there a Saxon to meet them?
Tomorrow.
I fight tomorrow.
[Lady Rowena laughs]
[challengers to the three Normans]
[applause]
Are you looking
for someone?
[opposing challengers
each select a Norman shield]
Your Highness,
no sharp points will be used.
[John] How disappointing.
[King's retinue laughs]
[de Beouf laughs,
meaning this will be easy]
[cheering the Norman knights]
[marshal signals
beginning of combat]
[Norman unhorses opponent]
[general crowd boos.
Prince's supporters cheer]
[Norman knocks over both
horse and rider opponent]
[loud cheers]
Is there no one here,
no one to stop them?
Tomorrow.
[again the Norman wins]
Who is he?
- Look again, master.
- Huh?
Perhaps you should ask,
Who was he?
A Saxon?
Without question.
Whew...
Have we no better than this?
We have, My Lord.
His name is Ivanhoe.
Your son, master.
I have no son.
You may have disowned him,
but he's still your flesh and blood,
and worthy of his Saxon name.
He is worthy of scorn
and nothing else.
[Wamba as jester]
Oh, what a disgrace.
Oh, what a pity.
My son ran off and left the city.
[the fighting continues
and Normans continue to win]
Next!
[Saxons reluctant to fight on]
Who's next?
[No one steps forward]
Ahhhhh.
[Prince's advisor laughs]
Your Grace, there are none left now
who will meet the challengers.
[an unknown knight rides
out of the woods]
[Cedric shouts]
Is it possible.
Will they let these Normans
invaders take the day?
The very honor of England
is at stake.
Surely you...
[the hooded knight
continues to approach]
How annoying that we
should finish so early.
So quickly.
And yet our company to know
that the three strongest knights
on this field,
are loyal only to you.
Your Majesty.
[the stranger enters the lists]
[cheering arises]
[cheering becomes jubilation]
It's him.
It's him. The Pilgrim.
Ah, Desdichado,
the Disinherited Knight. Welcome.
You have your choice.
However, the outcome
will remain the same.
I'm disappointed.
Would that
I trade places with you Front.
Never.
This one is mine.
[horse neighs twice]
[Front de Boeuf
is knocked off his horse]
[wild cheers
in the Saxon section]
[victor's horse rears]
A Saxon.
I'll wager he's a Saxon.
[Brian]  May I hope that you will now
give me the opportunity?
[strikes De Bracy's shield]
What a shame, Brian.
Now, you will never
get your chance.
[horse neighs,
then whinnies]
[De Bracy falls quickly]
[cheers]
Who is he?
Find out who he is.
[Rowena, Cedric, Rebecca
and Isaac wildly happy]
Have you confessed
yourself this morning
that you peril
our life so frankly?
The sharp end!
They will use the points.
Prepare yourself, then.
Look your last upon the sun.
[both lances broken]
[neither knight unhorsed]
[Brian Guilbert knocked off]
[loud cheers]
[rears horse in salute]
[Brian draws sword]
[victor draws sword]
Hold it!
You're allowed
the lance only.
[Marshal]
You're not allowed the sword!
You, Disinherited Knight,
we proclaim you the champion
of this day's tournament!
[loud cheering]
We shall meet again tomorrow.
When there are none to part us!
Brave knight,
we commend your valor.
and we award you this valiant
steed to match your courage.
[horse brought forward
amidst cheering]
[Rebecca falls in love]
You call yourself
the Disinherited One
By what other name
shall we know you?
[silence]
As a stranger in our land,
you may require assistance
in your choice of the Queen.
Let us say to you
that the fair Alicia
is considered the first
in beauty as in place.
Would you present your lance?
You may now
indicate your choice.
[he rides past Alicia
amidst cheers]
[he stops in front
of Rebecca and nods]
[but turns back and presents
the crown to the Saxon Lady Rowena]
[ heralds]
- Largesse! Largesse to the gallant knight
-loomed against the Queen of
Love and Beauty.
[crowd]   Long live
the Queen of Love and Beauty!
[Rowena, too, falls in love]
[crowd]  Long live
the Queen of Love and Beauty!
You can't just waste your
whole life in bitterness, father.
Bitterness?
You speak of bitterness?
What would you have me be?
Our Lord and Master, Prince John,
demands twice the contribution
I gave him last month.
Contribution. [Sigh]
It's a ransom.
But surely King Richard will return
to England and resume his throne.
What difference does it make to us,
Richard or John, in this...
...wicked country, we shall
always be persecuted.
No. All Christians
are not the same.
Think of the gallant
knight who fought today.
Ah, now there was a
brave and noble youth.
I'll wager that pilgrim
was Jewish.
Yes, Thieslen?
There's a stranger at the door, sire.
He wishes to speak to you.
Does he look dangerous?
I don't believe so. He wears
the garments of the pilgrim.
Ahhhh.
Veil yourself.
My friend.
Sir.
Forgive my intrusion.
I am here to pay
my debt to you.
Debt? What debt?
I owe you my life.
Not at all.
My daughter, Rebecca.
I am honored.
You owe me nothing.
You paid me back in full
today at the tournament.
May I offer you
a goblet of wine.
Nevertheless, I have brought
your horse, and I have here
the price of the armor.
Keep them. They're yours.
Why, I feel I must
at least pay you something.
My father owes you
a far deeper kindness
than any steeds
or arms could pay.
Please, let us look upon it
as our debt to you.
For his life.
If that is your wish.
Eh, your wine?
Forgive me, please.
I must prepare myself
for tomorrow's encounter.
Sir, you've been
far too generous.
I'm honored to have met you.
Thank you
I bid you goodnight.
[music weaves
a spell of romance]
[Lady Rowena]
[Wamba, the jester]
Whoo, whoo!.... Whoo.
Oh, you frighten me.
- Wait. I will leave
and come back again.
- Whoo, whoo.
There.
- Are you frightened, now?
Tell me.
Tell me at once.
Who was the mysterious knight?
Who was he?
Whoo...
Oh, Wamba, please,
don't play games with me.
What did he say?
His voice could
not be heard.
His face. His eyes, his nose,
his mouth could not be seen.
Why?
He wasn't there!
Oh.
Gone!
Into the night.
A good knight.
Gone, into the good knight.
I think it best.
Best?
Would not Ivanhoe,
if he were here?
Would not Ivanhoe be jealous!
Reign, you champion.
He'd have no reason.
I am faithful to Ivanhoe.
Ummm?
Would Cedric marries you
to the noble hog, Athelstane?
Never.
He will insist.
And I will refuse.
[Ivanhoe, "The Disinherited
Knight" at prayer]
Halt!
Wamba.
Well?
What did she say?
Did you talk to her?
She hasn't forgotten me?
Well, tell me, she
hasn't forgotten me.
My Lady is fair.
She would have a prayer.
For me?
For the brave knight
who won the day.
[blowing]
Are they the same?
What's your name?
Be gone, you knave!
Whoo....
Be gone!
[the second day
of the tournament]
[cheering the arrival
of Prince John]
[Cedric and Rowena arrive]
[herald]  The Queen of
Love and Beauty
shall be guided to her throne
by our royal liege Prince John!
[cheers and applause]
Where is Athelstane?
Master, that is a question.
Is he getting ready
for the combat?
He's a guest of the
noble lord Gurthog.
When I saw them last,
they were eating venison,
an enormous beast!
Be it known, it is forbidden
to thrust with a sword.
You may strike only.
A mace or battle axe
may be used at pleasure.
But the dagger
is forbidden.
Any knight unhorsed
may renew the combat on foot.
Any knight who breaks
the rules of this tournament,
will be subjected to public
ridicule and stripped of his arms!
[sides will attack en masse]
Glory to the brave!
Very well, let them begin.
[marshal signals]
[a full war combat attack]
[Cedric and crowd
cheers the melee]
[the acting king enjoys it]
[the three Normans
single out Ivanhoe for revenge]
You can stop the combat
at any moment.
Stop it? By the light
of heaven, I will not.
He gains the prize yesterday.
Let the others now have their turn.
[Ivanhoe is struck in the back
with the head of a lance]
[a new contender knight
rides onto the field]
[a true Black Knight]
[the Black Knight
attacks the Normans]
[Ivanhoe weakens]
[the Black Knight
comes to his aid]
[Ivanhoe unhorses
De Bracy]
[and prepares to continue
the fight of yesterday]
Hold!
Stop the conflict!
[the Black Knight
leaves the field]
[Ivanhoe displays
the victory sign]
[Cedric unknowingly
cheers his own son]
Honor to the brave!
Glory to the brave.
To the brave!
Glory to the brave!
[crowd] To the brave!
[Ivanhoe refuses assistance]
[and kneels for the crown]
His head must be bared
to accept the chaplet.
Ivanhoe!
The chaplet, My Lady.
I bestow upon you, Sir Knight.
This chaplet as a gift of honor
for this day's victory.
And upon these fearful wounds
no worthy wreath of chivalry
could ever be placed.
Help him.
Help him!
Your own son!
Will you do nothing?
My son has left my house.
He has deserted my country.
He has forsaken the Saxon cause.
He is no son of mine!
[Rowena sobs]
Please, help him
quickly, father.
How?
Take him to our house.
But he's a Christian.
By our laws we can't deal
with him, except in commerce.
He is gravely wounded,
and by our hearts
we cannot refuse him.
Think, if he should
die in our care.
He will not die, unless
we abandon him,
and if so, we must announce
it for his blood to God.
Quickly, his enemies
are all about.
[De Bracy]  Wilfred of Ivanhoe,
there is more to this than one day's battle!
If Ivanhoe has returned
from the Holy Land,
can King Richard
be far behind?
Well, let him come.
We'll crown his brother
before Richard
can gather his forces.
Then we'll take Richard
and welcome to him.
I, Brian de'Bert make you
this solemn promise
I shall meet this...
Wilfred of Ivanhoe
in mortal combat,...
and send him to eternity.
Stay there!
Get back there, get back.
Get back.
Who is it?
Who is it that bears him away?
Someone thought kind of him
with your grace.
On the road.
My Lady.
[gasp]
[breathing heavily]
You.
My father and I.
We bought you here
to care for your wounds.
We have special herbs,
ways of curing wounds.
Though we never
inflict them.
Herbs.
Secret preparations
handed down to us
since the days of Solomon.
You should be able to bear
armor again within eight days.
You may rest at our home in York,
until you health is restored.
We leave in the morning.
Is there not [gasp]
someone else here in Ashby who,
who could look after me
until I...
Not a step forward, today.
My dear, noble maiden, I...
No, I am not a noble.
I am but a poor Jewess.
Is it our race, then?
Is that why you do not
wish to travel with us?
I, uh...I, uh...I have no wish
to inconvenience you.
I accept you service, gratefully.
Rest, now.
I leave you.
Your Majesty.
Arise.
Did you find him?
At the house of Isaac.
The Jew of York.
They plan to take him
to York in the early morning.
[sigh] That was a
stroke of good luck.
I shall meet with Willoughby,
Forbes and Willister at York
within the week.
All my forces will be gathered there
to challenge my brother.
You're traveling alone?
I must for the moment.
You may retire, now.
- Oh, and Philippe.
- Your Majesty.
A good night's work.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
[sounds of festivities at
the Castle of Ashby]
[Prince John's high festival banquet]
[convivial laughter]
Well, where is she? Where is
our Queen of the tournament?
Is she...?
Yes. She is your ward,
is she not?
Where is the Lady Rowena?
She is exhausted by
today's events, she...
begs leave to decline
your courteous invitation.
We are not accustomed
by such a refusal from our
appointed Queens. It is
traditional that they attend.
Your customs are not
our customs.
Well! Perhaps you'll not object
if we drink a beaker
to the champion of
this passage of arms,
to your son,
Wilfred of Ivanhoe?
I cannot drink.
To your own son?
He deserted us.
He left his house, his country,
to fight in foreign lands
with your brother, King Richard.
Then let us hope my brother
holds him in more esteem than you.
[laughter]
I cannot forgive him.
I will not forgive him.
A willful youth who refuses the
commands and customs of his fathers.
I fill my cup.
To Cedric...himself.
This...ward of yours,
the Lady Rowena.
Yes?
A rose of loveliness.
And I trust a jewel of worth.
A Saxon of large possessions.
It is my intention that
she marry this gallant and
noble knight, Athelstane.
The last of the royal line of Saxons.
- Uh.
But, then...she is a minor,
is she not, and she is therefore
at our disposal
in marriage.
Indeed.
Uh, what do you think, De Bracy?
I'm told you're attracted
to the Lady.
Would you find it pleasing
to take her as your bride?
If her lands are to my liking,...
I will hold myself bound
to your Highness' wishes.
Huh.
The day my ward
marries a Norman,
will be that Norman's
last day on earth.
Hold. Sit down!
Both of you.
We've invited these honored
guests here this evening
and they shall remain
honored guests.
We've offered a toast
to Cedric of Rothrwood
and now we pray you,...
name us some woman in return.
It is a hard task for the conquered
to sing the praises of his conqueror.
Yet, I will name a Norman, even
though he led my only son astray
he is still the best
of your unfortunate race.
I drink this goblet to the health
of King Richard the Lion-hearted.
[some join in]
And now I hope you will excuse us,
we have remained here long enough.
Up, noble Athelstane.
We bid you good night.
I'm afraid, Your Majesty, that the
Saxon dogs have retreated in triumph.
It isn't possible, is it?
Could Richard be back
in England again?
What does it matter.
You have reserves, us here
of Maurice de Bracy, Front de Boeuf
and my own humble sort.
Enough for an army!
[laughter]
Here is my toast
and solemn pledge:
To Prince John, our
next king of England.
[all]  Prince John!
[chanting over and over]
Prince John!
- Ahhhh. Oh!
- Where is she now.
Where is the Lady Rowena?
- Weeping.
- Weeping?
[Rowena sobbing]
[door opens]
Come, we must
leave at once!
Would you go
without your son?
Ivanhoe has chosen to go
his own way. So be it.
- He chose?
- He's better fitted now to do
the juggling tricks of the Normans,
than uphold the honor
of his English ancestry.
Who was it that
defeated the Normans
- at the tournament?
- Silence!
Not another word.
We leave at once.
[gasp]
- Your Highness.
- Yes.
This arrived this morning...
from France.
Noooo!
What is it?
Uh...the Devil is unchained.
- Take heed...
- Richard?
He's escaped from France.
He's back in England.
We mustn’t lose
a moment, Your Highness.
Call your troops
together at York,
and meet, whatever force
he has head-on!
Your Highness.
At once.
My friends.
My friends,
we ride for York.
York?
We join Prince John
within the fortnight.
For what purpose?
For the purpose
of beating King Richard.
At last.
York is only a three day journey.
We have plenty of time.
Of course. You shall be my guests
at Torquson on the way.
Tankards and venison enough
to fill even your fat bellies.
What do you say?
[laughing]
Ahhhhh!
[Isaac and Rebecca's caravan
with the injured Ivanhoe]
Halt!
Halt, William.
Here, what are you doing?
Why did you stop?
Bandits.
Bandits, there are
no bandits!
Yeah, in the woods, maybe.
We're leaving.
You can't do that.
You can't leave us here!
No?
We're going.
No, stop! You can't take
those horses.
Those are my property!
Thieves!
Thieves.
[Rebecca checks on Ivanhoe]
Here.
Drink this.
[Ivanhoe coughs]
There.
Rest now.
Rest.
[Ivanhoe breathes heavily]
They were hired
to take us to York!
They've got my money.
Why should they care?
We are deserted.
Oh, God of Abraham,
what have I done?
Why must they
smite us so?
Father, look!
May God make them merciful.
Hold.
I greet you warmly, sir.
I trust you are
in good health.
Who are you?
Speak plainly, infidel.
I'm Isaac of York. I hired a guard
of men to escort us to York,
but they've deserted
us, as you can see.
Why?
They say there were
bandits in the forest,
but, heh, heh, who
am I to talk.
I beg you to let us
travel under your protection.
Dogs if infidels,
out of the way!
Sir, may I speak, please.
We have someone here.
An old person who is gravely ill.
I beg you to let this sick person
be transported with care,
under your protection.
It is no concern of ours.
Wait.
If this poor person is
truly in peril of life,
and if these two kind and earnest
people cannot defend themselves,
well then we must,
in all charity, give them help.
So be it.
They may travel in the rear.
[horn blows a signal]
What is it?
What's the alarm?
No alarm, sir. All is ready
for you at the castle.
We only wish to inform you,
there is a party of Saxons
in the forest there below.
You know them?
Cedric of Rotherwood, the Lady Rowena
and the noble knight, Athelstane.
How large is the party?
Ten or eleven.
Servants and all.
My good friend, De Bracy,
I wager that the hour has struck.
What?
It's time for us to
deliver your wife.
Your wife, De Bracy,
is awaiting you.
What was that?
What?
Ah, uh, nothing.
Huh.
[Saxon train attacked
by screaming Normans]
Forgive the intrusion, My Lady.
I am pleased to announce
that you are now the guest
of my good friend, Front de Boeuf.
I would sooner, sir,
go with bandits.
Much, indeed, that
is what you are.
De Bracy, are you certain
that you want to marry
this sharp tongue?
[laughing]
[de Boeuf]  Well,...
what have we here?
[ Brian]  I think, perhaps,
that we have caught more than
one bird on this occasion.
[de Boeuf]
An infidel,
[Brian]  and beautiful
beyond belief.
We can do you no harm, sir.
We have an old woman
here, who needs our care.
She shall have it,
I promise you.
[Wamba]
[Cedric]
Dogs. Norman dogs.
[Athelstane]  Barbarians.
But surely they will feed us.
Stop.
[De Bracy know the truth
about the "old woman"]
[first soldier]  What is it?
What affliction does this old hag have?
[second soldier]  I'll not go
close enough to find out.
[Ivanhoe coughing]
Set her down.
Set her down, please.
[Ivanhoe groaning]
Well, you may leave.
There. It's all right.
Shhhh. He's here.
Rest easy, Ivanhoe.
Don't be alarmed.
Don't shout, I beg you.
Where? Are we in York?
We...we are prisoners.
Here ye dog.
Help me.
Leave me alone.
[Isaac thrown downstairs]
[Wamba]  Lost again.
Lost again. What can I do?
Taken my master.
Left the fool.
[Black Knight]  Bandit or knave?
I am neither, sir.
Then, what are you?
I am a fool...Wamba,
for my master, Cedric of Rotherwood.
The Saxon?
A noble Saxon, sir.
The prisoner.
Prisoner? Where?
Front de Beouf's castle.
His ward, the Lady Rowena
and noble Athelstane.
There's also....
Would you mind, sir.
Thank you.
There's also Isaac,
the Duke from York,
and his daughter, Rebecca.
They were abducted?
Were, indeed, sir,
most certainly.
Just as surely
as you and I.
You? I?
What are you talking about?
Look about you, sir.
The bushes are moving.
Welcome, welcome, gentlemen.
What do you wish, a fool or a knight?
[Robert Locksley's men surround
and capture them, not knowing who they are]
[whistle warning]
Release him.
The Black Knight.
The tournament at Ashby.
You saved young Ivanhoe.
You hold that against me?
Against you?
There is nothing more dear to me
than the life of an Englishman.
If you are as good an Englishman
as you are a knight,
then I hold you in esteem.
Why do you pass our way?
Shortest distance to York.
Then you must stay awhile.
Taste our hospitality.
Please, I entreat you.
Mutually loving this one.
Help save my master.
He speaks of Cedric
of Rotherwood.
The Lady Rowena.
The noble Athelstane.
Prisoners, all of them.
Prisoners in the castle
of Front de Boeuf.
For myself, I would join
any enterprise to save them.
Where's Little John?
He's away from Torquilton.
And Will Scarlet?
He's just arrived.
Where's Friar Tuck?
Did you call, my lord?
- Where have you been?
Why, at Vespers, saying
prayers for all good Englishmen.
It appears you've been drinking.
More than usual.
Perhaps a pious taste
or two of our sacred wine.
Do you think you are in
suitable condition to give a
service in combat?
Hmmm, wazzz, a hissing here
and a weakness here.  I don't know...
[splash]
[general laughter]
Yes, they have good passed away.
I am ready!
Take shun, my wicked priest!
[Robin Hood]
Let us be off, Black Knight.
The fool will lead us
to his master.
[Front de Boeuf's castle]
You want my life?
Do you want my wealth?
Is it too much for you Normans,
that we Saxons still hold land
in this, our own country?
Very well, then.
Put us to death.
I ask only that you free
the Lady Rowena in honor and safety.
[Front de Boeuf laughs]
[he laughs again]
Norman swine!
My God, who would have thought,
that you, the descendent of Saxon kings,
should the prisoner of a vile Norman
in the very hall in which
our ancestors held court.
Perhaps, they'll hold us
to a moderate ransom.
Dogs.
Oh, my tongue
cleaves to my palette.
If they ever gone
to send us wine.
[door opens]
[door closes]
Why don't you
sit down, my lady.
If I am in the presence
of my jailor, sir, I will stand.
Dearest lady, you are in the presence
of your captive, not your jailor.
I don't know you, sir.
And no man dressed in spurs
and wearing chains would intrude
himself upon an unprotected lady.
It's my misfortune, that
I'm not known to you.
I hope the name of De Bracy
is known to all in deeds of chivalry.
De Bracy? I see no
deeds of chivalry on this day.
You are unjust, Lady Rowena.
Won't you allow at least
the passion of a man
drawn by your great beauty?
Sir, you speak the common
language of a minstrel.
Perhaps bold language
best justifies bold action.
I tell you now, you will
never leave this place
unless you leave it as the
wife of Maurice de Bracy.
Your wife!
Oh, I know, you have
great pride. I admire that.
It makes you even more suited
to take your place beside me.
When I do marry, sir,
it will not be to one who
despises the manner in which
I have been brought up.
Huh huh.
[chuckling]
Perhaps you dream that
King Richard will resume the throne.
That is an empty dream.
I can promise you that.
His fate will be as hopeless
as that of Ivanhoe.
What?
Ivanhoe!
Ah.
Do I see a touch
of tenderness, at last?
Where is he?
Do you know where he is?
I do.
Tell me, I beg you.
He lies gravely wounded
in a turret room above.
I don't believe you.
You didn't take the trouble to look.
You traveled in the horse litter,
with Isaac, the Jew of York,
Now, were I to inform our host of this,
Ivanhoe will no longer breathe, at all.
Smile....dear lady.
Simply smile at my proposal,
and you will have nothing to fear.
I can't believe that your
purpose could be so wicked,
and your power so great.
There are others.
Cedric, your guardian.
The fate of all depends
on your decision.
Lady Rowena, I would rather
you kept your original anger
than this.
Be assured, please. You have
no reason for tears, as yet.
I will leave you now.
To dwell upon your decision.
[door opens]
[door closes]
Watch Movies, TV Series & Live Sports
www.admitme.app