The island of Cape Breton,
the northeastern end of Nova Scotia...
is just a small chunk of land
sticking out into the Atlantic.
Roads haven't been built through
everywhere yet.
You mostly have to come in from the sea.
It needs an old hand to navigate
through the shoals offshore...
especially during the storms that come up
suddenly in the summertime...
and the little lighthouse
has saved many a life.
The village isn't much to shout about.
Just a quiet, peaceful place where
the people are proud of their church...
built with their own hands and what
little money they could scrape up.
Their farms don't bring in much...
but for a few months each year
when the cod are running...
there's a lot of excitement.
You should see the harbor then,
alive with boats.
They leave the women to take care
of the potatoes and livestock...
and put out to sea.
Not many of them are lucky enough
to have their own boat...
but they all get a share
when the catch is paid for at the cannery.
A fair-sized haul means everything.
It means food for the long winter...
new blades for tools,
grain bought for cattle.
That's why we watch each vessel
as she comes in...
to see how low she sets in the water.
Floyd, come on back here
and give us a hand with these fish.
Fergus, tack in on that line.
Help get this catch ashore.
Get that unloading net aboard.
-How many drags did you make?
-Two, three hours.
Take it away.
Get that boom over.
Don't tie it off, get it back onboard.
I don't want to hang around all day
on this reeking wharf.
-Look out!
-Hook's in his shoulder.
Hey, Dan'I!
-Do you know where the doctor is?
-Sure, he's dead.
No, the new doctor. Same place. Get.
Hurry up, bring him back, quick.
Come on, get going before this load
starts stinking the place up.
Yes?
I got to get the doctor.
Tim's been hurt down at the boat.
What is it, Stella?
There's a boy out here says a man's
been hurt down at the wharf.
I'll be right there.
Will you be giving me
some medicine, doctor?
No, Mrs. Poggety, just this diet list.
I think you'd better
have your teeth X-rayed.
-Oh, but Dr. Peterson always said--
-I'm not Dr. Peterson.
But what do my teeth to do
with my backache?
Well, it's taken medicine a good
many years to define that connection...
and I haven't time, unfortunately,
right now to explain it all to you.
Stella will take care of your things.
-Will you be back to supper?
-I don't know.
-When can I go back to work?
-No time at all.
The main thing is to see
there's no infection.
Would you like to put his coat on?
I'll take him in the buggy.
Hello, darling.
Hey, Locky. Going to the dance Saturday?
-Why? Your Gus going out with the fleet?
-I'll be on the wharf tonight.
Well, don't catch cold.
-So long, girls.
-Bye, Locky.
I looked for you, McCormick.
One half the fish you land yesterday
are undersize like little sardines.
Well, at 14 cents a pound I can't be
bothered sorting them. I'd starve to death.
If the buyer see them
he will not take them from me.
Well, boost your price
and I'll toss back the little ones.
And while we're talking about it...
-you miserable old skinflint....
-What's that?
Don't get your hackles up,
you Micmac Indian...
not with that tub of guts.
-Micmac?
-Micmac! You'd not last two rounds.
It's about time
somebody took you down a peg.
You sell our catch for fancy prices...
yet you knock down 12 cents the pound
on us farmers.
You do not like that?
Well now, you listen to me,
Mr. Locky McCormick...
you owe big bill in my store.
You know that.
Well, you pay or I take your stinky boat.
Why, you greasy old half-breed.
You try and take that boat
and I'll gut you out like a cod.
You keep your hands to yourself.
Pretty tony since you're working
for His Lordship, huh?
You mind your own business.
I've got to get supper ready.
I don't like to see you
working for this man, Stella.
He's a fine doctor. He's a....
Anyway he's something big.
Something even you can't pronounce.
Probably something not fit to mention.
What're you working your head off for,
anyhow?
What good's a dead uncle
if you don't use his money?
No hurry.
Plenty can happen between now
and the time the deeds will be signed.
You going to try to run it yourself?
That's a good farm, needs a man.
-We could make a lot out of that place.
-We?
Sure, I've been thinking things over.
You and me make a great pair.
We ought to get married,
the sooner, the better.
Well, this is a surprise,
Mr. Locky McCormick.
Blow your nose, don't look so silly.
Oh, Stella...
what dress you wearing
to the dance Saturday? The one I like?
Maybe.
-You're taking me then?
-Well, of course I am.
Fergus put in for it first.
We practiced a step for the jig contest.
I'm taking you.
He and Floyd can toss a coin to see
who dances with you, but I'm taking you.
The doctor's coming.
You'd better get out of here.
He's in my way.
-You're coming down to the wharf later?
-Might.
Thank you.
-Is the doctor in?
-He's eating his supper.
I've got to see him. She's awful bad.
I'll tell him as soon as he's finished
but I can't--
Stella?
-What is it?
-It's only Aggie MacDonald from the mill.
Nobody has anything to do with them...
and it's never a penny of pay
you'll get from her.
Well, she said someone was sick,
didn't she?
I didn't like bothering you,
but she's having so much trouble.
-The pain's that strong.
-I'll get my bag.
He didn't come at night last time.
It's 12 miles to the veterinary.
It's our cow,
she's the only good one we've got.
We'll fix her up.
He wouldn't have wanted me
to call you, Black wouldn't.
He'll say it costs money...
but if the critter dies,
then it's me who's to blame.
I'll do all I can to help.
In there.
Would you hold the light
a little higher, please?
She can't hear you. She's deaf, dumb.
That's too bad.
What she don't know don't hurt her none.
-By the way, it's a girl.
-Aye.
-Thanks for coming.
-Glad to help.
-Was she born deaf?
-No...
she took sick
when she was about a year old.
Come time to talk, no sound come out.
She growed up that way, dumb.
Blessing she has
such a fine father and mother.
That ain't her mother.
It's my sister, Aggie.
Her mother's dead. She killed her.
She died in childbed.
I guess sometimes it's meant to be.
Sometimes it's easier
to lose someone that way...
than to lose them when they're still alive.
I was in love with a girl.
She married another man.
I was wondering. A young chap like you,
burying himself here.
The other doctors was always old.
That was part of it.
There were lots of other things.
It's a pretty stale story.
Way things were going,
I sort of got fed up.
So I decided to look for another way.
Simple life, simple things.
If people would only learn
to let each other live...
it would be a different world.
What's the fee?
I wouldn't know.
I never delivered a heifer before.
I might take it out
in fishing in that pool of yours.
Looks like a wonderful place for trout.
-You're welcome anytime.
-Thanks.
Good morning, Stella.
I was early so I stopped in to tidy up a bit.
The dishes....
Please don't bother.
-Are you going out?
-For a little while.
That's a nice dress. New, isn't it?
-I made it myself. I make all my own--
-Very pretty.
I'll see you tomorrow.
We may have fish for dinner.
I like fish.
I've got the most wonderful way of--
No guarantees.
Look, Mrs. Lutz, the new doctor.
He hasn't been to church once
in three whole months.
Nice example.
He's a fine doctor. What he did for my Tim.
She's always talking about,
''He's a fine doctor...''
just because he put a bandage on a cut.
Hello?
Here, let me help you. Hello.
Now, where do they go?
Oh, the chickens.
Don't be afraid.
You watch me talk.
That is a...
rooster.
And these are...
hens.
Very good.
That's a tree.
Tree.
Yes.
Water.
Very good. Now if you give...
water to the tree...
it will grow.
Water to the tree, it will grow.
Yes, it will grow. The tree will grow.
It has very big roots. The roots go...
deep into the earth.
Earth.
And all of it together...
is land.
Land.
Good. Earth.
Eggs.
Four of them. Four.
No. One, two, three, four.
Four.
You're right. You're learning very fast.
Pretty soon you and I will be able to talk.
Talk. Right.
What're you trying to do, McCormick,
shake the clapper out of the bell?
-Where's my flour, Mac?
-Ain't it ready?
I can't see it.
The Dummy should be here to serve you.
She ain't done it.
I put it down for her.
You'll have to come back tomorrow.
Where can I get a team weekdays?
I'll have to wait till Saturday.
But if it ain't done then,
I'm going somewheres else.
It'll be ready. I'll make her remember.
How can you expect a dimwit
to use her head?
What's all this? What is it?
Water, ocean.
Ocean.
What's got into you?
I write it all down for you.
Here, it's as plain as the nose on your face.
Oh. Well, I guess I forgot.
Look.
Well, I was wondering.
She never makes a mistake.
Did you ever think
of sending her to school?
School?
She's deaf and dumb, man.
There's no teaching her nothing.
Here's the extent of her learning.
I make a sign at the top of each page.
A cross for Pacquet,
a circle for McCormick...
two lines for the McQuiggens and so on.
A mark for each bag.
I put them down when they come in,
she strikes them off when they're ready.
She's learned to identify every man
by his mark.
Must be over 40 names in this book
and she knows every one of them.
So that shows, Mr. MacDonald,
that your daughter is an intelligent girl.
Now, there's a special school
for the deaf at McGill.
Schools cost money...
and money don't grow on trees
in this country.
We're lucky to keep body
and soul together, we farmers.
I couldn't spare her. Thanks.
There's work enough around here as it is.
But she could be taught, I'm sure of it.
What's her name?
Me wife wanted her named after herself...
Belinda. Belinda MacDonald.
But they call her the Dummy around here.
They shouldn't.
Even though she can't hear,
these people have very keen perceptions.
-Aye.
-They notice things.
Come to think of it, she's fond of colors.
I took her to church once years ago.
They played the organ.
A look come over her face
as though she heard.
I knew all the time
she couldn't hear a thing.
Well, I'm losing time.
I must get on with my work.
Good day to you.
Would you mind if I talked to her
once in a while?
Talk?
When I was an intern at the hospital
I worked for a while with deaf children.
Why, I might even have one of the books
still kicking around somewhere.
I'd like to try
to teach her some lip-reading.
You'll be wasting your while, man.
But you're welcome here anytime.
-$1.80, Mrs. Lutz.
-Did you get the oilcloth?
No, but I will save it for you
when it comes in. Thank you.
Bye.
There's the doctor again.
Talking to himself.
-It's spooky.
-I think he's queer in the head.
Pretty smart
when it comes to making out his bills.
Hello. Happen to know what kind
of tobacco Black MacDonald uses?
MacDonald has not bought here in weeks.
Dr. Richardson, I receive your bill.
Rather steep for a stomachache, yes?
As far as I remember, it was three calls.
Two of them after midnight.
Dr. Peterson always took his fees out
in barter, like everyone else.
Mr. Pacquet,
I have to get cash somewhere.
You and a few others
are the only ones who can afford it.
You wouldn't have to pay me any bills
if you'd stick to that diet I gave you.
The only trouble with you is
you eat too well.
Now, I'll have this. See, 15, isn't it?
Or would you rather wait
and have me take out a splinter?
Get your filthy bug out of my dough.
The spuds is covered with them.
I can't pick everyone off single-handed.
And milk, and plow,
and blast stones without any help.
-Don't blame me.
-I'm not blaming you, I'm only telling you.
I suppose you want me to pull the plow.
I suppose I'm not doing my share, cooking,
and mending, and baking, and spinning.
-Who helps me?
-You got the Dummy.
A fine lot of help, that one.
All the grand ideas that doctor
has been putting into her head.
Filling her up with fancy notions.
You know what she was doing
instead of feeding the hogs?
Brushing her hair.
That's not fair to me.
I'm doing the work of six.
What's this I hear about you
loafing all day? There's work to do.
Aggie, did you see that?
She knew what I was saying.
Oh, tosh.
She can hear. Belinda, come here!
-I tell you she understands, woman.
-You're wandering in your head.
-But she came when I called her.
-She was reading your lips.
She's been a very good pupil.
Belinda, how do you say hello to a friend?
That's right.
''I am happy to see you.''
And I'm happy to see you.
-Telling me she can talk that way?
-Of course.
We've been studying
from a book of signs...
which were devised by a Frenchman
a couple of hundred years ago...
the Abbe de I'Epee, he was a priest.
See, each word has its own sign.
For instance, there's ''man.''
The sign is this: touching the hat brim.
-And what would ''woman'' be?
-This. Comes from a bonnet string.
And that's ''mother.''
Baby. You see, woman with a child.
It's beyond believing. It's as clear as day.
And that is the sign for ''day.''
You see, this represents the horizon and
this is the sun coming up over the horizon.
This is noon
with the sun directly overhead.
Afternoon, evening, and night
when the sun has disappeared completely.
Good morning.
Good night.
And that's ''bread.''
What is it? It's a butterfly. Sure.
It is a butterfly. It flutters.
Aggie!
Aggie, come here.
-I got something.
-What?
Look sharp now. Think fast.
What does this mean?
-It means you've gone loony.
-It's a butterfly. Look.
Don't go waving your hands at me,
I'm not the Dummy.
And if you want to have any bread to eat
while I'm gone, leave me be.
It's a good job you're going.
We'll have peace around here
for a couple of days.
It's like a miracle.
-Would she be saying ''father''?
-Yes, she did.
It's the first time she ever called me that.
Daughter, my daughter.
What do they want?
What's going on here, McCormick?
Where's my flour?
McQuiggens want theirs, too.
It's all done.
We'd better load it
before we get too dizzy from dancing.
It's there on the racks. Load it and get out.
Here it is, boys. Get to it!
All these are mine.
Put them on the bottom.
Yes, Lock.
-Afraid you'll crack a fingernail?
-Flour don't go good on my suit.
This floor's slick as a whistle.
Hey, Hector, come on. Give us a tune.
Hi, Stella, you're looking very handsome.
You like to dance.
Why don't you come with us?
-Yes.
-It'll be fun. Basket supper.
I'd love to. Unfortunately,
I have a previous engagement.
Two measles cases five miles apart.
Hey, the Dummy's dancing.
-Her name's Belinda.
-She looks kind of cute fixed up that way.
You keep away from that Dummy.
Keep away.... The Dummy and me?
I saw you taking in her legs.
Jealous of a dimwit.
I'm plum ashamed of you, woman!
One thing, she'd never tell on you.
-But keep away from her or I'll be able--
-Well, I guess that's all.
What are we waiting for?
I want some cider. Come on, hurry up.
Locky!
-What's the damage, Mac?
-You know what it is.
Locky, come on.
Everybody, sing. Everybody, sing now.
Didn't have time to finish them.
I can't do 10 things at once.
It's not my fault if my sister got sick.
Well, I'll only be gone a few days.
You can manage.
-Aggie!
-I'm coming.
Well, goodbye, Belinda.
Sometimes a body'd almost think
you understood.
You'll miss the train.
Besides, I don't want to leave Belinda
alone too long.
Nobody would bother stealing her.
There's Mrs. Johnny John-John
just back from hospital.
She looks right spry for a woman
who's just had her arteries cut out.
Not her arteries, Mrs. Lutz.
Get off my feet. You're drunk.
Mrs. Moore is her own worst enemy.
Not while I'm alive, she isn't.
Hello, Dummy.
Look what I brought you.
Want to dance?
First time a man kissed you, wasn't it?
Don't be scared, Dummy.
Your heart's pounding.
I caught a sea gull once,
it had the same scared look.
Hello, Mac.
Glad you're here. You've been missed.
Well, I'm sorry. I was busy with my call.
I've been worried about the girl.
There's something wrong.
-Why?
-You can see for yourself.
All right.
Hello, Aggie. You get back all right?
Wouldn't be here if I hadn't, would I?
-Is your sister better?
-Yes.
-Did she have a good doctor?
-Didn't have any. Doesn't believe in them.
Well, that's the right attitude
as long as one can afford it.
How's Belinda?
Getting peevisher by the day.
-Where is she?
-Around here somewhere.
Belinda. How are you?
Are you cross with me
for not coming to see you?
Well, you see, I couldn't.
Many men and women
suddenly decided to be sick...
at the same time.
Would you like to study your lesson now?
All right, no lesson.
Belinda, if you could only hear me.
You think I don't know what it means
being lonely like you are?
I've been lonely myself,
even when I was a child.
Already then I wanted to be a doctor.
I thought that helping others
might help me. It did somehow.
Then all those other things happened.
The war and all that came after.
Made me lose faith in everything.
In myself, too.
Belinda.
Belinda, you must help me.
I need you.
Yes. I need you.
If you only knew what it meant
seeing you smile for the first time.
Bringing happiness, if it's only
to one single human being, is....
Belinda, don't let me think
I've failed again.
You'll help me.
Mac. Mac, come here.
Mac, Belinda's great trouble
is nothing more than loneliness.
And she's got to have a chance.
Now, there's a doctor in Stepney,
I met him at McGill.
A brilliant diagnostician.
I don't know exactly what good
it would do...
but I'd like to take Belinda to him.
Belinda...
how would you like to go with me
to see a town?
T-O-W-N.
A big town.
You've done such wonders
with her yourself.
Why does she have to go see that fellow?
Because, Mac, I don't know enough
and I think he does.
Doctor like that costs money.
Don't worry about that. I'm going to write
and ask him for an interview.
I'm sure he'll do it.
I'm going to write him tonight.
No, Belinda, not women. Men.
Do you see any hope, Doctor?
Aye, that's why we keep on practicing,
Robert.
I understand your concern,
but she needn't worry.
The one fact I'm sure of
is there's no otosclerosis...
so as you know, it can't be hereditary.
There's no possibility the expected child
could inherit it.
Clinically, the birth of the child
could make all the difference...
if my theory is correct.
I cannot say for certain, nobody can.
But what you've accomplished
is remarkable.
I'd hardly say that.
I just tried a few things I knew.
You've always been an idealist
from way back.
Yeah, that's what makes good doctors,
Robert.
Keep in communication with me.
I'll be interested in following
the case with you.
-I'd be very grateful.
-Goodbye, lad.
Dr. Gray said it wasn't possible
to determine her condition...
after only one examination.
He said she was very healthy,
very intelligent.
And that he wanted to see her again.
Fine. Now maybe she'll have a chance.
She's worn out.
She slept nearly the whole way home.
Belinda, why don't you go upstairs to bed?
Good night, daughter.
She looks so grand in that dress.
Beats me why I never noticed it before.
Do you think I could take her to church
come Sunday?
She's only been there the once,
when she was a child.
Of course, why not?
Right now, how about taking the cows
to the barn?
I'm forgetting everything.
You're not very fond of Belinda, are you?
I've always been civil to her.
She's my brother's daughter.
You should see to it that she doesn't
have to carry those heavy sacks.
She's not too strong.
Doctor, you'll be doing
my brother and me a favor...
if you'll stop putting
those grand ideas into her head.
There were no complaints until you came.
She did her work like the rest of us...
like we all have to do if we want
to keep a roof over our heads.
I have to tell you, Aggie,
you're the only woman she knows...
and she'll be in need
of your sympathy and help.
-My help?
-Belinda's going to have a child.
Oh, no. No, it's not true.
There isn't any doubt.
When her father finds out, he'll kill her.
That's why I told you.
She doesn't know.
Doesn't even realize it herself yet.
-But he must find out.
-I'll tell him, at the right moment.
Oh, it's....
Do you have any idea who the man was?
No.
Don't let anything happen to her.
I've been pretty brusque with her.
You're making up for it now.
We MacDonalds, we're high-tempered.
We fight amongst ourselves...
but let trouble come from outside...
and we'll stick together.
We will open our services by singing
the first verse of hymn number 73.
I'm requested to publish
the banns of marriage...
between Laughlin McCormick
of Carcadie...
and Stella Maguire, spinster of this parish.
If any of you know
cause or just impediment...
why these two persons should not
be joined together in holy matrimony...
ye are to declare it.
This is the first time of asking.
We will close our services
by singing hymn number 43.
You're the lucky one. Congratulations!
Mr. MacDonald, I'm so happy
to see you at our church again...
and Miss MacDonald.
I didn't know I could be so proud
of my own flesh and blood.
Did you see the way
they all turned and looked at her?
Well, Stella, this is quite a surprise.
Thank you.
Well, good luck to you.
When's the wedding?
You mustn't forget your chores, girl.
Have you lost your mind,
Black MacDonald?
What's the matter now?
She's no mule! She can't stand all that.
What's got into you, woman?
I have to have this mash mixed, haven't I?
She's done it ever since we had pigs.
Well, she won't do it anymore.
Now you leave her to me.
Sit down.
You're as white as a sheet.
I'll get you some water.
-Here.
-What's wrong with her?
She's out of sorts.
The doctor told her to take it easy.
Look, I work from 4:00 in the morning
till dark. Year in, year out.
What she has to do is no hardship.
Belinda's a healthy girl.
She's not.
Now you leave her to me
and to the doctor.
What do you make a mystery of it for?
She's my daughter.
I've a right to know
if there's anything serious.
Belinda's gonna have a.... A child.
Oh, no.
-It couldn't be.
-It's true.
That dirty, filthy doctor!
No! No, you're wrong.
Who would it be then?
I don't know.
-Tell me his name.
-Hold your temper.
Hold my temper?
What kind of a father do you think I am?
Listen, child, who was it that hurt you?
How do you expect her to tell you?
She doesn't know
what you're talking about.
Keep out of this.
Show me. Show me the man's name.
Who was it? Who was it that hurt you?
She doesn't know! Leave her be.
Don't be a fool, woman.
She's no babe in arms for all she's deaf.
She's trying to shield the man.
Listen, child, show me.
Show me, I tell you.
Do I have to beat it out of you?
Oh, no. No, don't!
Stop it!
You don't know what you're doing!
-Let go of me! I got to find the man!
-Come to your senses!
Even if she could talk,
she couldn't tell you.
You've no right to go on this way.
-No right? I'm her father.
-Then act like a father!
Leave her be. I couldn't help it.
You're the one person that can give her
what she needs most:
help, comfort, and understanding.
What are you trying to do,
drive her insane?
-I couldn't help it. Hard to go on....
-Aggie, come on. Take her to her room.
-Have her get some rest.
-Yes.
Now, Mac, you've got to listen to me.
I understand how you feel
and I don't blame you...
but believe me,
it's blotted out of her mind.
The way you forget a nightmare...
because you don't wanna bring back
that terrible fear.
I've seen it in the war.
It's nature throwing up a barrier
to prevent something worse.
I don't know what you're talking about.
-I've got to find the man.
-What good will that do her?
I'll lay what he done
before the men of the village.
We'll show him what justice is.
And even if you do,
how will that help the girl?
Dragging her into a mess of scandal...
when she doesn't even know
what it's all about.
-It'll crucify her. Is that what you want?
-You know it isn't.
What am I going to do? The shame of it.
Mac, you've got to think of her now,
not of yourself and your pride.
There's only one shame,
failing a human being who needs you.
I'm going up and talk to her now.
He didn't mean to hurt you.
He's just.... Just very worried.
That's what makes him
seem harsh and unjust sometimes.
He works so hard.
That's why he hasn't been able
to give you more time.
You've been alone so much, Belinda...
but you're not going to be alone anymore.
You're going to be a mother.
Yes, Belinda.
You'll call it Johnny? But Belinda, you....
Well...
if you want it so much,
I guess you'll have a boy.
I'm sorry I couldn't get here any faster.
The horse could hardly break
through the drifts.
I was that worried.
Now, Aggie, I want you to get me
some more hot water, lots of it.
And woolen blankets. All you can find.
Why does it take so long? It's hours.
It's hard to get born and it's hard to die.
Do you have some brandy around?
I guess there's some.
-Aggie, now hold that just like that.
-Yes.
-On the corners.
-Her not making a sound, it's uncanny.
Here, try to drink this.
Got to keep that heart going.
What are you bawling about?
-How is she?
-She's all right.
The baby's here.
It's a boy.
Belinda, here's your boy.
Can he talk?
He certainly can.
That ain't dirt, that's good clean earth.
That won't hurt Johnny none.
I was brought up in a hog wallow.
You can't say I'm peaked.
What's eating you now?
You don't get something for nothing
in this world.
-What's that mean?
-It means no more credit.
We've had bad years before,
he's never stopped our credit.
Why didn't you try to reason with him?
Because nobody would listen to me.
I don't dare show my face in the village.
Everybody treating us like lepers.
Come, Aggie.
It's not like a MacDonald to give up...
because we're having a little hard time.
-We'll manage.
-Manage, is it?
And who's to manage the salt,
and the sugar, and the tea, and the like?
Where are they to come from?
We've managed to get deeper in debt
than anyone in Christendom.
We've managed to shut our eyes
to everything that's happening.
I don't even remember what
the grinding wheel sounds like anymore.
Try managing that!
He won't trust us for one more cent,
Pacquet won't, until that bill's paid.
Them sheets are white as snow.
I bleached them extra special.
The prettiest bride this town's ever seen,
that's what you'll be.
-And who told you about it first?
-You did.
The cards never lie. There he is.
There'll be many a broken heart
come this Friday night.
Hello, Stella. I can drop you off.
No, thanks.
Wait a minute. What's the matter?
Did Mrs. Poggety tell you to keep away
from men with blue eyes?
A grown-up girl about to be married
swallowing that hocus--
Can't you mind your own affairs?
Always being so superior.
Always finding fault with everybody.
You of all people, after what you've done.
-What have I done?
-You know well enough.
A girl who can't defend herself,
who can't even talk. Shaming her.
What do you mean?
Who said it? Locky?
Everybody says it.
The whole village is talking about it.
That's why nobody calls you.
So Locky said it.
I wouldn't have thought
you'd believe that, Stella.
Fog's rolling in.
Can hear the lighthouse
sounding off already.
Won't help the crops any.
The poorer the crops,
the peskier the crows.
Mac.
They're saying in the village
that I'm Johnny's father.
It's believable.
When they don't know the answer,
they make up one.
I've been around this place a lot.
At all hours.
I've been thinking about this
for a long time.
I've even thought of your leaving here,
but that wouldn't prove anything...
giving up something
you've worked for all your life.
I know of only one solution.
For me to marry Belinda.
That would really give them
something to talk about.
And pretty soon
the gossip would die down for good.
You're being generous, but it won't do.
You see, she kind of feels things,
and people, with her insides.
You don't love her,
you only feel a kind of pity for her.
You'd hurt her worse
than if you hated her.
Make me feel pretty cheap.
For a while there I guess I was thinking
I was quite a guy.
You're one of the best I've run across.
Sometimes you can be too good.
Harm others while doing it.
Well, look who's here.
I have something for Johnny.
You can see him. Watch.
Yes, you can see him hear.
-Coming up a blow.
-A storm?
Coming straight in.
I better get the cattle in.
I'll stay here. He has it.
Mac?
Mac!
Well.
You don't know me, huh?
You ought to, though.
What are you doing in here?
I just come by
to see about some ground barley.
That's a cute lad. Never seen him before.
Keep away from him.
What's the matter?
No harm in looking at him, is there?
-Don't be scared. I'm Locky.
-Take your hands off him.
All right, all right. He's a big boy, isn't he?
Spitting image of his father.
Well, all right, if you don't want business,
I can go somewheres else.
-Where you going?
-With you.
-Well, where to?
-Wherever you're going.
-Why?
-To tell them.
-To tell them what?
-What you done.
-So they'll know how low a man can get.
-You'll tell them nothing.
Go ahead, walk.
Something's wrong?
What's happened?
Belinda, what's the matter?
Belinda, what is it? What's bothering you?
Belinda.
''Our Father, which art in heaven...
''hallowed be thy name.
''Thy kingdom come.
''Thy will be done...
''in earth, as it is in heaven.
''Give us this day our daily bread.
''Forgive us our debts...
''as we forgive our debtors.
''Lead us not into temptation.
''Deliver us from evil.
''For thine is the kingdom...
''and the power...
''and the glory...
''for ever and ever.
''Amen.''
He's trying to sell him
his horse and buggy, he is.
He stopped talking when I came in,
but I heard enough.
But what will he do without them?
A doctor.
What practice he has he can cover afoot.
Just to the mill and back.
His luck's run out, that's what.
I saw it in the cards, so help me.
Black. Spades, spades, spades,
no matter where I put them.
That rig is worth
two times more than this bill.
I make business and I have the right...
to get back what is owed me
all fair and honorable.
But I do not want people saying
that I take advantage.
You don't understand.
You'd be doing me a favor.
I have to get rid of them.
You mean, something is wrong?
The horse is lame, maybe, yes?
No, he's sturdy as a horse.
But I'm in a hurry,
so I have to take what I can get.
-I'm leaving here for good.
-You are? When?
You seem pleased about it.
-No, I think it's better for you.
-Why?
You see, in this village,
we do not appreciate people coming here.
Strangers who do not follow
our ways of living.
There are men here who can be very angry
and something can happen.
-What?
-Anything.
Look, Pacquet,
put away the tar and feathers.
Do you want the rig or don't you?
She's as pretty as a picture.
Good luck, my boy. Now you can pay me.
You know I can. And I want that boat back.
You will have it.
-You've a good man, Stella.
-Thank you, Pacquet.
Charlotte, catch!
-Bye!
It's about time Locky settled down.
He's led a stormy youth.
Out on the ocean, you mean, Mrs. McKee.
You know what I mean.
Belinda, I want you
to promise me something.
If anything ever happens to Johnny...
I want you to send for Dr. Gray.
I couldn't come, Belinda. I won't be here.
I have to go away.
After all, I'm a doctor.
I can't help anyone this way.
I can't even make a living for myself.
Anyway, it's the only thing to do.
So I made an application.
I made an application.
A staff job at the Toronto Hospital,
and they've taken me on.
I got the answer today.
Do you understand?
Do you understand, Belinda?
In a month or two...
I'll be able to take care of things,
help you out.
I've talked it over with Aggie.
You see, the trouble is
I have to leave very soon.
Tomorrow, in fact.
No, Belinda. I won't be able to come.
I'm going across the Gulf.
Yes, very far away.
Yes, I'll be careful.
Belinda....
Forgive me, I didn't know.
Don't be sorry.
I'm very glad.
Come on.
Hurry up, we're late.
It is the honor of the community
we have to think of.
Respectable people do not stand by...
and see shameful things like this happen,
and do nothing.
As a member of the Town Council,
I say it is our duty...
to correct this unfortunate situation.
And we do not want anyone
to come from outside...
and meddle in this.
We want to do this quietly.
We can take care of it ourselves.
Yes, Mrs. Moore?
Isn't it cruel to take a baby away
from its mother?
A creature who's a disgrace
to the whole village?
Who can't even teach a child his prayers?
Is it a crime to save a baby
from a life of misery?
These women can't provide for a child.
Already they've sold most of their cattle.
The place is run down.
There's no man to work it.
Why, the baby will be like her,
running loose like an animal.
The doctor. When he finds out,
couldn't he make trouble?
After what he did?
Sneaking out of town
in the middle of the night?
He will be too smart
to ever show his face here again.
I could almost feel sorry for her.
It's a good thing she can't think or feel.
Nothing better could happen for the child
than the offer we got.
He will have a name,
a home with respected parents...
Mr. and Mrs. McCormick.
Now, there's no need for a lot of red tape.
All we have to do is
get the release from the girl.
She only has to sign it.
It is an easy thing to make a cross.
With the release we send this petition.
I do not think there will be any trouble.
If the girl had normal intelligence
she would be grateful.
What are you stopping for?
Let's end this bickering.
He has the makings of a fine, sturdy lad.
I'm telling you again,
I'd sooner not take him...
than let you turn him
into a thickheaded farmer.
And I tell you he'll have to earn his keep
when he's growed.
What if he gets sick? It'll cost money.
Whose money?
I don't recall you bringing in any.
Well, it's ours, ain't it? You're my wife.
And you expect me to pay for the honor?
You needn't worry.
I'm not fooling myself
about why you married me.
And I know what started you on the idea.
You want the kid because of that doctor.
'Cause you think it's his.
You're sweet on him
and couldn't hogtie him for yourself.
I loathe him.
A man that would do a thing like that.
All right,
then don't think to pamper the boy.
He'll work as soon as he's able.
Giddap there. Giddap.
I'll go by myself. Give me the letter.
What for?
She won't understand it anyhow.
Give me that letter.
Can't hear, can't read.
And don't be all day about it.
My coat?
May I see the baby?
May I hold him?
Belinda.
Would you let me take care of him?
I mean, take him home just for a while.
He'd be very happy,
he'd have everything he wants.
You could see him whenever you like.
Please let me, just for a little while.
You have all this work.
Why not, Belinda? I only want to help you,
can't you understand?
Just sign here. Just make a cross.
If you don't give him to me,
they'll come and take him.
Belinda, listen, please! Let me take him.
I won't....
-What's happened?
-Locky, I can't do it.
What are you talking about?
He's ours, been given to us,
all legal and proper.
We must give him up.
We're being mean, Locky,
mean to the Dummy.
You think she had no feeling,
you should see her with the baby.
We just can't take him, she's his mother.
His mother.
Well, let me tell you something.
I'm his father.
What?
His father, I'm telling you!
He's as much mine as hers.
Locky, I told you to keep away from her.
It's all over and in the past.
Unfortunate it is, it happened.
A man wants children and I want him.
Something in here wants him.
By the Godfrey, I'll have him !
Where's the kid?
Get out of the way.
It is the duty of the Crown Prosecutor...
to present the facts
which will prove to you...
that beyond a doubt,
Belinda MacDonald is guilty of murder.
This is a difficult case...
due to the unfortunate circumstances
of the accused.
But you and I, gentlemen,
must not allow these circumstances...
to bring about an undue amount
of sympathy for the accused.
A murder has been committed
and the full penalty must be paid.
Is there any reason you know of,
Mrs. McCormick...
why she should have killed your husband?
No.
-Your witness.
-No questions.
Miss MacDonald.
When the McCormicks...
arrived that afternoon...
is it true that you were
in the house alone?
Does she understand?
Well, what did she answer?
She's not answering my question.
She hasn't answered any of my questions.
All she says is,
''I want my baby, I want my baby.''
There, ''Tell them
to give me my baby, please.''
The defendant obviously
doesn't want to answer the question.
My Lord...
under the circumstances,
the defendant is naturally confused.
Apparently she does not understand
the interpreter.
Since she was trained in the sign language
by one of the witnesses...
Dr. Richardson...
would it be permissible
for him to translate for her?
-Permission granted.
-Dr. Robert Richardson.
Would you mind facing her directly
so that she can read your lips?
Were you alone in the house...
when the McCormicks came to see you?
Did you understand?
''I was with my baby.''
After you attacked Mrs. McCormick
and she ran out--
I object, My Lord.
The defendant has not admitted
attacking Mrs. McCormick.
Objection sustained.
I'll phrase the question differently.
After Mrs. McCormick left,
what did you do?
Isn't it true that as soon as she left
you went to get the gun?
''I was very much afraid.''
So you did take the gun deliberately?
Objection!
The defendant has made
no such admission.
My Lord--
If the Prosecution will be patient,
I might be able to help.
Please try to understand
what it means to be as she is...
living in a world apart,
shut off from everyone...
never hearing the warmth
of a human voice.
Think of the loneliness and the fear.
These people, although tutored,
are governed almost solely by intuition.
Belinda's been instructed
in certain fundamentals.
-She knows right from wrong...
-My Lord--
...but something in her was stronger than
the precept, ''Thou shalt not kill.''
My Lord, I object.
Dr. Richardson is completely out of order.
He's not the counsel for the accused.
Your Lordship, I insist this girl obeyed
an impulse older than the laws of man:
The instinct of a mother
to protect her child.
Any further breach of your capacity
as interpreter...
I shall hold as in contempt of this court.
Objection sustained.
Now please proceed.
When did you get the gun?
After Locky McCormick came in?
''Yes.'' Why?
''I was afraid he would hurt my baby.''
And that was your only motive?
Was there any other reason
why you were afraid of him?
Your Lordship! The interpreter,
in rephrasing my question...
is trying to coach the defendant.
This man is totally unqualified.
He's deeply involved in the case himself
and I can prove it.
May I present new evidence?
-Has it any bearing on this testimony?
-It has.
Permission granted.
Dr. Richardson, in your earlier testimony...
didn't you deny being the father
of Belinda MacDonald's child?
-I did.
-Did you write this?
I did.
I should like to read a passage
from this letter.
''...physician takes a lot more time....
''Work is hard. Be here soon.
''I have found a house for us.
''It is small but it has
a beautifully sunny room...
''for our little son.''
I challenge this man's integrity
as a witness and as an individual.
His actions speak for themselves.
Betraying this girl, ignobly fleeing scandal.
He's laid himself open
to a charge of perjury.
His very appearance here is an affront
to the dignity of this court.
He has violated the ethics
of an honorable profession.
He should be stricken
from the medical register...
expelled from decent society.
No! No!
It was Locky's fault!
It was him, Locky. He's the baby's father.
It was his fault!
He told me
the day we went to get the baby.
I wanted the baby but...
somehow when I saw her with him
I couldn't.
I said, ''We shouldn't, it's mean,
she's his mother.''
And he said.... He said:
''I'm his father.''
In this court's opinion,
the evidence is incontrovertible.
That she acted in defense of her home...
against a man
whose guilt has been proven.
The court expresses the hope
that the jury's verdict...
will stand as a reminder
that justice in this Dominion...
will always protect the private citizen...
against those who would interfere
with his rights...
and his dignity as a human being.
I'm glad that it turned out the way it did.
I know, Belinda.
You don't have to say anything.
English
Watch Movies, TV Series & Live Sports
www.admitme.app