All right, Eleanora.
Eleanora.
Miss Holiday.
You better haul
your little black ass in here.
Slow.
It's about time.
Girl, if you wants to lay around all day,
you is in the wrong end of the business.
When I give it away for the first time,
it ain't gonna be to no $2 john...
in East Baltimore. That's for damn sure.
At the rate you going, by the time
you decide to give it away...
you'll have to pay some john
$2 just to take it.
I's here, y'all. I got my $2.
That's dynamite.
And I see just the woman I want.
Come here, baby. Come to Papa.
Got a surprise for you.
I got a surprise for you.
I got a surprise for you, too,
if you don't leave me alone.
- Come here, sweetie.
- What?
Come over here.
Let me tell you something. Come on.
Come on. I know. I know. Listen.
I'm trying to talk to this...
Now, what do a fine man like you
want with a child like this?
She ain't 15 years old yet.
- What that got to do with anything?
- I know.
I come here to spend my money.
Suppose I take you over here
and show you a real woman...
who could give you your money's worth.
No.
No, that one's
plenty woman enough for me.
Don't try to give me no jive, broad.
I see what I want.
I come here to spend my money.
And I see what I want, and this is it.
- Come on. Come on, now.
- Well, you can't get what you see.
And since you don't want
what you can get...
then you know where you can go,
and this is it.
We don't need his kind, no way.
Imagine him making all that fuss
over one young kid.
- He must have been good and drunk.
- Yeah, drunk or blind. Shit.
All right, honey.
You can go now. That's enough.
Honey.
You are wearing this thing out
and me with it.
Now, why don't you take it with you
and make it a good home?
You mean, I can have it?
If you can get out of here with it
before I can count to 10. One...
two, three, four...
five, six, seven, eight...
nine, ten.
Eleanora. Eleanora.
The good Lord
give you two long legs to run with...
and He give me two strong hands...
to beat your black behind blue
the next time you slowpoke home...
when you know we got an all-night drive
before we get to Cousin Charlotte's.
- Sorry.
- Now, here.
You take these here keys
and make sure you use them.
I don't wanna come back here Sunday
night and find the house all cleaned out.
Talking about cleaning,
you didn't do the steps this week...
and the oven could use
a good scrubbing.
I didn't have time to make the beds,
and there's washing to be put out.
Wave goodbye to your cousin Eleanora.
I'm gonna call Reverend Jones and
make sure you get to church on Sunday.
Now, you be a good girl, Eleanora,
and next time you can come with us.
There's a letter inside
from your mama from New York.
And empty out the pan under the icebox.
Do
Want to anyway
I don't care what people say
If I should
Take a notion
To jump into the ocean
Ain't nobody's business
If I do
If my man ain't
Got no money
And I say take all
I's here. Got my $2.
It's dynamite. That's dynamite.
Come on. Come on.
Don't be afraid of me.
I'm not gonna hurt you.
I'm not scared of you,
'cause you handsome.
- You know what I mean?
- Come on.
- Okay, I...
- Come on. Come on.
Come on, sweetie, sweetie.
Let me take a look at you.
Oh, my goodness.
Why don't you sit down on the...
- Okay.
- Come on.
Okay, wait, wait, wait. Sit down.
Can't do nothing standing up, now.
Come on. Sit down. Okay.
Now take your hat off,
and rest your coat.
Funny girl!
And then the missus woke up...
and saw
that he hadn't come home all night.
And then wouldn't she hit the ceiling!
Went running all over the place...
flopping that old yellow nightgown
of hers, you know...
and looking for him
and calling, "Charles?
"Charlee?"
I sure hope they get
their problems all settled...
before they get back here
in the morning. Uh-oh.
Got my polishing to do. See you, girl.
- This your kid, Sadie?
- Yes, sir.
You know she shouldn't be walking
around by herself in this neighborhood.
- You know what I mean?
- Yes, sir.
Guess you heard about what happened.
I came all the way from Baltimore
to see you, Ma.
My baby.
Thank you, Mama.
Sure is gonna be great
staying together again, ain't it, Ma?
Ain't it, Ma?
Honey, you know there ain't nothing
your mama wouldn't do for you.
Nothing in the world.
You can stay the night, but the madam's
coming home in the morning.
I understand, Mama.
Sister Edson.
I bet you, if I called her and asked her...
She's a lady from our church, and she's
always willing to help nice, young girls.
And since you're my daughter...
I bet she'd be willing
to let you do some housework...
for your room and your board.
- I'm sorry, baby.
- It's all right, Mama.
Can't fault you for what ain't your fault.
I'll be all right.
Come in, missy.
Excuse me, miss.
Is you "Miss Lorraine Edson...
290139th Street, Harlem"?
Yes, honey, I sure am.
And you must be Sadie's girl.
Yes, ma'am. I am.
Well, the good Lord's
delivered you safe and sound.
My mama told me to say thank you
for taking me in.
And she told me also to tell you...
that you have
the best rooming house in Harlem...
and that I ain't supposed to be lazy
and I supposed to work real, real hard.
Well, now,
that's a fine spirit you got, honey.
And I want you to
just make yourself right at home.
Okay.
Rest your things. Look around.
I'll be right back.
That's a fine young girl.
Well, now, honey, I'll show you
my whole place, upstairs and down.
I don't want to see the upstairs,
Miss Edson...
'cause my Mama told me
you had a job for me as a cleaner.
And that's what I got, missy.
I mean, you're the one
with other things on your mind.
Wishful thinking, I call it.
'Cause, girl, let's face it...
you got a long way to go...
before you can earn $2
for just 10 minutes of your time...
or ain't you looked at yourself lately?
That lazy bitch.
She don't look where she's going.
Ain't it a shame how some
of God's children have it so easy...
and others have it so hard?
"Ain't it a shame?"
Last night, night before
Two different robbers at my door
Come on.
Kid, come on, beat it.
- Mister, is the boss around?
- You're saying goodbye to him. Bye-bye.
Okay, but look,
I work in the neighborhood already...
and I'd be willing to quit working
and come up here and work for you.
Yeah, I'd be very happy to quit, too.
Come on, honey.
- But I can sing. I really can.
- Yeah.
I can dance, and I know the words
to every song that's out today.
I mean, I've been really rehearsing
and everything.
That's very good. So do I.
But I tell you...
in order to be a showgirl,
you gotta have something to show.
Well, I got something. I really do.
All you have to do is push it up a bit
and put some lip rouge on.
I could do it, mister, give me a break.
Look, really, I'm good.
- All you have to do is give me a chance.
- Listen, girlie.
Listen to me. I don't wanna hurt
your feelings, but no amount of slinky...
and makeup is gonna change you
into a female that looks...
like that.
Louis, so good to see you.
I'll get you a great table. How about
a nice table for Mr. McKay?
What you looking at?
Don't your mama make you wash steps?
Shake it to the east
Shake it to the west
Shake it to the one
that you love the best
- Now?
- No, not yet, don't you peek, Mama.
- Not yet.
- Now?
- No.
Now come with me.
Surprise.
Jesus. Lord have mercy.
I ain't never,
in my whole life, seen such a fine hat.
Just like them fancy ladies
up on Sugar Hill.
Oh, Lord, and just to think
my baby give it to me.
Honey, I just loves it.
God bless Sister Edson.
I can see she's doing right by you.
Every time you come over here...
you're looking better and better. Still
cleaning and washing, no cooking yet?
No, not yet.
Hey, Mama, I gotta go. It's getting late.
I don't wanna miss my train.
Honey, I forgot.
I got a surprise for you, too.
I got me a new job starting next week,
and it's gonna be close by you...
and I'll be able to walk over
most evenings, won't that be nice?
And we can visit.
That'll be swell, Mama.
That'll be just swell.
- Just what we always wanted.
- Yeah.
We'll be able to
spend more time together.
That'll be real great.
Lord have mercy. My baby done
made me so happy this day.
Eleanora, you're late again. Girl,
you done missed two tricks already.
You better get the spirit, sister,
and get yourself on up them steps...
and quit your lollygagging.
Didn't you mama teach you
how to close doors?
If you don't want this job,
somebody else sure do.
You fine, young thing.
You're new in the neighborhood.
So, honey, I gotta love you real good.
Looky here
what Lorraine done sent to me.
I never accomplished any great feats...
but you know something, baby?
I'm something else under them sheets.
You see my father was a jockey,
and he taught me how to ride.
He said, Big Ben, you got to get it
from side to side.
Now, in case you don't know who I am...
I'm Big Ben, baby. Yeah, the lover-man.
We gonna have ourselves a ball tonight.
Lorraine done sent me this fine dinner.
Young and tender.
This is where her head was.
Won't be there when I get through.
'Cause, see, I'm from the city,
and I'm gonna kiss your little titty.
Young, and fine, and mellow.
Light as a feather.
Big Ben told all his men
Don't you take no numbers
After half past ten
What? What's the matter
with you, woman?
Ain't nothing personal, mister,
but I just quit the business.
Hell, bitch, you crazy?
Ain't this a killer?
Lorraine.
Hey, Lorraine. Lorraine.
What's happening?
Who's making all that noise up there?
- He said his name is Big Ben.
- Big Ben?
Ain't you supposed to be upstairs
with Big Ben?
- I ain't doing it.
- What you mean you ain't doing it, girl?
You give my place a bad name.
Big Ben's the best customer I got.
You can't do that.
All the girls love Big Ben.
He's my best customer, and I'm trying
to make something out of you.
I sent him up to you.
Now, what's the matter with you, girl?
You better get the spirit, sister, and
get on back upstairs and do your work.
- The Lord knows I'm trying to help you...
- Miss Edson, honey, I done quit.
Done quit?
Well, you get on away from around
here, then. 'Cause you ain't nothing.
You ain't never been nothing,
and you ain't gonna be nothing.
'Cause you don't go messing like that
with Big Ben.
- That's right.
- Get your ass back in the house.
- You looking for someone, Miss?
- Yes.
I noticed your sign in the window...
and I'm a featured dancer
at a club downtown.
And I don't have much time,
but I happen to live in the neighborhood.
And I'm looking
for something a little closer to home.
So you're a dancer now?
Okay, dancer. Dance.
Yeah, that's fine, girls. Take 10.
Thank you, honey. Just real nice.
Beautiful. Wonderful.
I tell you what,
watch your step as you leave.
You know the way out. Be careful.
Hey, baby, you know how to sing?
Yeah, I know how to sing,
but he wants a dancer.
You ain't got nothing to lose.
You better try to think up a song.
- I can sing anything. Shoot.
- All right, let's try something.
- What you know?
- But he doesn't like me.
He ain't got nothing to do. I can
handle him. What can you sing?
- I can sing All of Me.
- Jerry, I'm sorry, brother. Just go on.
All of Me, man,
you ain't never heard this like this.
- All Of Me.
- Church, take you home.
This a friend of mine, man, I didn't...
You gonna love it. Jerry,
you're a good person in your heart.
- You know you're gonna love it.
- Okay, okay, let her sing. Sing.
All of me
Ain't Miss Holiday something?
Why not take all of me
Can't you see
I'm no good without you
Take my lips
I want to lose them
Take my arms
I'll never use them
Your goodbye
Left me with eyes that cry
How can I
Go on without you
You took the part
That once was my heart
So why not
Take all of me
Yeah
Come on, you girls, come on,
you gotta get dressed.
We open in 15 minutes. And you...
Tonight, you get your chance.
Wait a minute.
What'd you say your name was?
- Eleanora.
- Ella... Ella who?
Billie. Billie Holiday.
Billie Holiday, that's my name.
Okay, Billie. One of the girls
will show you where you put your things.
Tonight, all you gotta do is watch
the other singers and do what they do.
Okay, you're an angel, Jerry.
Yeah, wait a minute. I'll be a bum
if you don't pull in $15 in tips tonight.
$15. Now, that's my definition
of a good singer.
Okay.
Go on, Billie Holiday.
What you frowning about, baby?
Don't worry about it.
What she miss on the top...
she can pick up on the bottom.
I hope that works both ways.
Don't worry about it.
One day, she picked the table up.
All right, Mama, go ahead.
Next time, you could pick up the floor.
We don't need a janitor.
Go on. Go on. Jerry's watching.
Right there, Jack.
Come on, baby.
That's a new girl just breaking in.
Some day he'll come along
Yes, sir.
The man I love
And he'll be big and strong
Pick it up.
The man I love
Pick it up. Come over. Come on.
And when he comes my way
I'll do my best to make him stay
You're pitiful.
He'll look at me and smile
I'll understand
Pick it up. Pick it up. Pick it up.
Then in a little while
He'll take my hand
And though it seems absurd
- Come on. Come on.
- Pick it up.
You think you're too good
to pick up money?
- Want me to put my foot in your ass?
- Would you shut up?
Maybe he'll come Sunday
Maybe Monday
You gotta do better than that, hon.
Maybe not
Go. Get it. Get it.
Still I'm sure he'll come one day
Maybe Tuesday
Will be my good news day
He'll build a little home
Just meant for two
From which I'll never roam
Take the money. Come on,
I can do better than that myself.
And so all else above
Go ahead, pick it on up.
I'm dreaming of
The man I love
Schmuck. Me and my big heart,
and you and your friends.
- Who does she think she is?
- A lady. With a hell of a voice.
We ain't gonna end up
with a quarter tonight.
Shit, you ain't paid me in two weeks...
what you bullshitting about a quarter?
Billie, Billie, go get it. Get the money.
Go on. Get it.
Do you want my arm to fall off?
Take it. Take the money. Take it, Billie.
I fell in love with you
The first time I looked into
Them there eyes
'Cause you have a certain little
Cute way of flirting
With them there eyes
They make me feel so happy
They make me feel so blue
Take it.
I'm falling
No stalling
- Here's some money.
- Work it out, baby.
My heart is jumping
You've started something
With them there eyes
You'd better look out, little brown eyes
If you're wise
Sing like a lady. Come on, lady.
They bubble
Gonna get you in a whole lot of trouble
Ooh, baby
Them there eyes
Here's your cut, Billie.
I like you. I think you're gonna make it.
Thanks, Jerry. I like you, too.
Say, baby, that's beautiful.
Here, take some.
Get out. Come on,
you were beautiful tonight.
I just wanna tell you thank you.
I love you.
You were beautiful. Just pretty.
Thank you.
I really was scared, I'll tell you that.
You should have been scared.
Them niggers is dangerous.
- Billie.
- What you doing?
- Yeah? Yeah, Jerry.
These are for you.
There's a car waiting for you upstairs.
- Thanks, Jerry.
- Here's your money, Yvonne.
A car waiting for me upstairs.
Don't flash them moon eyes at me.
I didn't send you nothing.
There was never a doubt in my mind.
Besides, there's a card,
and you probably can't even write.
Don't have to know how to read, neither,
to know what that card's saying.
If he spent as much time
running his numbers...
as he does them damn gardenias,
he could have one hell of a business.
Think you're pretty smart, don't you?
Well, what do you know?
You got a great thing going in here.
Leave that nigger alone.
He is dangerous. You understand?
He pulls that bit on everybody,
got a room full of girls at home.
You just gonna be another one. You
wanna be that? You got too much going.
This is one face
that won't get that hungry.
I don't stand in no line for nobody.
All right.
Not even Mr. Louis McKay.
Jerry?
- Tell him the answer is no.
- No?
No.
That'll show him, 'cause he usually gets
everyone he wants.
He can get this one, too,
but not on the first night.
Good night, lady.
- Good night, Billie.
- Good night, Jerry.
What's the matter?
You don't like gardenias?
They're okay.
So?
So you don't put them on
just to go to someone's apartment...
for a late-night supper.
- So that's how it is?
- That's how it is.
Pardon me, lady, I must have
got you mixed up with someone...
who used to reside at Missus...
What's her name?
If that's what you thought, nigger,
why'd you give me them damn flowers?
Why didn't you
just give me some money?
I did.
Hey, Billie. Listen, listen, all right?
You don't mind
if I call you Billie, do you?
- Don't call me nothing.
- No, listen.
Listen, I know a place downtown.
It's open all night.
A fantastic place. You can eat.
You can have food. You can dance.
You can do anything you want.
Now, come on.
Just like the late-night-supper stuff?
No, no, this is for real, baby.
Listen, there's my car right there.
We can go on right down there
right now. Listen, I like you.
I wouldn't do anything to harm you.
- I'm so thrilled.
- Really, seriously.
Please, Billie.
- Please? Pretty please?
- Pretty please.
All right?
Come on. You look so pretty.
What's been going on?
Good evening.
Mr. McKay, it's nice to see you again.
Paul, come stai?
- Bene. Bene. How are you?
- Good.
Gosh, you stayed away a long time.
A sound
UntiI that day
You came my way
With pleasure I never found
It all might have been
Had you been around
Thank you very much,
ladies and gentlemen.
Fantastic. Fantastic. Thank you, ladies
and gentlemen. Thank you, Janie.
She gets better-Iooking every day,
doesn't she, guys?
Well, how do you like this place?
Isn't this something?
I wanted to bring you here because
I thought you'd really enjoy yourself.
It ain't so hot. I been
to a whole lot of places like this before.
Is that so? Right. Well, where?
Huh?
- Where?
- Where what?
You said you've been
to a lot of places like this before.
- Where?
- Did I say that?
I heard you say that.
Maybe I misunderstood what you said.
What do you think you said?
I said, you ain't so hot.
Well...
I...
I just love the way you talk,
you know what I mean?
Well, you make me...
You know... I've never met
nobody like you before, you know?
You kind of make me speechless.
- Do, I really? I mean, really?
- I mean, yeah.
Right. I don't know
what to do with myself, you see.
I don't even know what to do with
my hands and everything, you know?
You sure have pretty teeth
when you smile.
Okay.
And that, you know...
That dress.
I want to tell you about that dress.
That dress brings out
the best tones in your skin.
Do you feel like dancing?
I don't know.
Well, I feel like dancing.
Go on and dance, then.
Ain't nobody stopping you.
You mean,
you want me to dance by myself?
Okay.
Thank you. I really appreciate that.
Yeah, you really a nice lady, you know?
Come on, now.
Mr. McKay...
I have a confession to make.
What's that?
This place is fantastic...
and so are you.
Yeah.
- What are you doing?
- Nothing.
Can't you do it sleeping?
I really can't believe
I'm here with you, you know that?
If you don't go to sleep, you won't be.
That's what I get
for breaking a house rule.
I like to have breakfast alone,
you know what I mean?
What are you doing, woman?
You want me to leave, don't you?
Look, when I want you to leave,
I'll let you know, okay?
Okay.
Just so you don't get any big idea,
you understand?
- We'll take this a day at a time.
- Okay.
All right.
Anything you say.
Louis?
Now what?
How do you like your eggs?
I want a pig foot
And a bottle of beer
Is she great? Is she beautiful?
Okay. Okay, folks,
we got a little celebration.
Our lady...
herself, Miss Billie...
appearing in this nightclub for one year.
And in honor of the occasion...
Bring that in, and be careful with it.
Everybody gets a piece.
I mean a hunk. A hunk of the cake.
Courtesy of the house. Yeah.
And everybody's gonna get
a glass of champagne...
courtesy of Mr. McKay over there.
Okay. Hey, Mr. Piano Man.
Come here.
You're the guy who discovered her.
How about you propose the toast?
Hey, I'm for that. Hey, Billie.
We got Old Cheapie
to spring for something.
You're beautiful, Jer. Damn, Jer!
Damn, but everything's beautiful.
He even paid the band, Billie,
since you been here.
Beautiful year. And everybody... Girls.
Look at the uniforms!
All right.
Look, even the hoes is making money.
That's only because
you're our biggest trick.
Anyway, Billie, we love you sincerely,
very much, in our hearts.
We sure do.
- You gonna play, Piano Man?
- Yeah.
Key a bar. Okay.
Break it.
For she's a jolly good lady
Which nobody can deny
Hey, Billie, I want you to meet
two friends of mine.
- This is Harry and Reg. Come on in.
- Yeah.
Come on in. There she is.
- Hi, Harry.
- Hi.
- Hi, Reg. How are you?
- Really nice to meet you.
I hate to interrupt you. I know you're all
celebrating and everything...
but I just sure appreciate meeting you.
My name is Harry Bradford.
That is, if you didn't get it.
- Over there, this is Reg Hanley.
- Hi. Nice to meet you.
- Louis McKay.
- We...
We're just fans of yours.
And I need all the fans I can get.
Pull up a couple of chairs, fellows,
and join us.
Thank you.
Where do you fellows play?
Well, actually,
we're playing no place right now.
Fact is, we're trying to form a band
to take a tour around the country...
and we wanted to talk to you
about joining us.
Joining you? You serious?
Very.
A colored singer with a white band?
Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah?
You must want to keep playing no place.
Well, you see, that's exactly the point.
We wouldn't be just another band
with you singing.
We'd be something special
because, well, you're special, Billie.
Here.
There you go.
Thank you.
We'd go straight to the top. I know.
I don't know about no straight to the top.
I'm just trying to get to a club downtown.
We all are.
Of course, you don't understand, see,
the way you get downtown is...
I mean, you know, the way you do that
is that you go out on the road...
and you build up your name
in the sticks, and then, blam!
You get snapped up by network radio,
who're always looking...
for someone big with the hicks
to sell them soap or something.
Yeah, then you come back
to New York...
and besides radio,
there's records, club dates downtown...
- you name it, Billie.
- Just like that, huh?
Well, it works that way sometimes.
You mean to tell me that I have to travel
all the way to East Jesus and back...
before I can get in some club downtown
less than five minutes away from here?
- Well...
- They full of shit, ain't they?
I just think it'd be fantastic
if you just came with us.
- How about that?
- I'm sorry, fellows.
I think your band
is gonna have to start without me.
I'll tell you what.
Piano Man's got my telephone number.
If you give it some second thoughts,
give us a call.
How you like my timestep, Reg?
I think we might have a part for you,
Miss Holiday...
but we'll have to see your legs.
You know the last time
I saw fields and farm animals...
I was hitching up north from Baltimore
to see my mama.
Leader, I am trying to follow a rule
called "food three times a day"...
but I sense we are dangerously behind.
Let me explain to you.
This is only Tuesday,
and I only feed on Friday.
Stop complaining, Oklahoma.
That's a horrible-Iooking thing.
You mean we have all this fun,
and we still get paid?
Well, about $12 a week,
to do with what you will.
$14? Would you take $8?
Fantastic. I'll take
whatever you give me.
I get the chance to travel.
I get a chance to do everything.
I sense we're in for a lot
of candy stores and a lot of jelly beans.
Can you imagine
someone liking to tour?
Yes, some fun, Billie.
Miss Holiday...
you're in the South now.
Jesus, look at this.
You got a half an hour, that's all.
Billie, let me help you out of there.
- A whole half-hour?
- Let me help you out.
Half an hour's all we got.
- Put your shoes on, man.
- Get on out here.
Billie, what'll it be? What do you want?
What do I want? What do I really want?
What do you really want?
Well, I'll tell you.
- What?
- I really want...
a steak smothered in onions.
And I really want
a big pot of collard greens.
Right.
- And I want some yams.
- Right.
- I want some black-eyed peas and rice.
And I want...
potato pie.
One hot dog, coming up.
- Mustard?
- Oh, crap.
- Hey, Reg...
- Hello, I'm from the Board of Health.
Billie, you ain't missing a thing.
I cried for you
What a fool I used to be
Now I found two eyes
Just a little bit bluer
I found a heart
Just a little bit truer
And I cried for you
Now it's your turn
To cry over me
Still think it's fun, Billie?
Watch it, will you?
Sorry to say it's that time again.
This has been the Oasis Cosmetics
Hour from New York, New York...
featuring the new mellow sounds
of our Sweet Sam...
and His Society Swingers.
- So untiI tomorrow night...
- Man, did you hear that?
- Here we go again.
- Did you hear that?
- Yeah.
- Sweet Sam and His Society Sissies.
That's supposed to be us, man.
That should be our gig.
Do you want to be a sissy?
Man, here we are, riding our asses off
all over this cotton-picking country...
trying to win these hicks over,
and what do we got to show for it?
Zero. Nothing, man. Bullshit.
Where is that big radio cat
that's supposed to discover us, Reg?
Where is that son of a bitch, anyway?
Watch your mouth.
Can't you see there's a lady present?
That's right.
Show some respect, you motherfucker.
Billie.
Who is it?
It's Harry.
What do you want?
Can I come in?
Come on.
Gonna be a rehearsal downstairs
in 10 minutes.
Oh, boy.
We got a full day off next week.
I'll be dead by next week.
I'm taking the night off.
You take tonight off...
and, sure as hell, that'll be the night...
that Mr. Network Radio Scout
is sitting out front and all the things...
I mean, everything that we've been
doing goes right down the drain...
because, let's face it, Billie,
you are the cream in our coffee.
You got that the wrong way around,
don't you?
We are just another band without you.
Okay.
Give me a shot of that bourbon
in my bag, will you?
Well, how about a real...
A real what?
One shot and you'II...
be flying.
Look, Harry, like I've been telling you...
what you do is your business.
I may be tired, but I ain't dumb.
You're walking across a street. A truck
hits you. You're laying in the street.
They take you to the nearest hospital.
What's the first thing they do?
They give you a shot of morphine.
Now, morphine ain't an aspirin.
It's dope.
Do you think that makes you an addict?
One goddamn little shot ain't gonna...
make you a junkie,
but, you know, it keeps you flying.
Okay, Harry.
If I get hit by a truck, I'll call you, okay?
Now get out of here.
Reg, how much longer
before we get to the next town...
- or a gas station or something?
- Well, from the looks of things...
it's gonna be back roads
and cow pastures for quite a while yet.
Pull over to a clump of bushes
or something then?
- No.
- A hedge?
- Come on, please.
- All right.
You have but to ask, madam,
this vehicle is at your disposal.
- How about the lake?
- Come on.
All right.
You should take a look at it out here.
It's beautiful. Look at those trees.
Hey, Billie. Where you going?
You forgot the sheet music.
Just turn your head.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Come on, Billie.
Let's go. All aboard.
Southern trees
Bear a strange fruit
Blood on the leaves
And blood at the root
Here is a fruit
For the crows to pluck
For the rain to gather
For the wind to suck
For the sun to rot
For the tree
To drop
Here is a strange
And bitter
Crop
Now we're proud to present our
feature vocalist, Miss Billie Holiday.
You're mean to me
Why must you be mean to me
Gee, honey, it seems to me
You love to see me crying
I don't know why
I stay home
Each night when you
Left all alone
Singing the blues and crying
You treat me coldly
Each day in the year
You always scold me
Whenever you're mean to...
Ladies and gentlemen...
Miss Holiday has been experiencing
some dizzy spells.
I'm sure she'll be back with us
in just a little while.
We will continue
with an instrumental right now...
and I'm sure she'll be all right.
Thank you very much.
Thank you.
But if you treat me right, Daddy
I'll stay home every day
If you treat me right, Daddy
But you're so mean to me, baby
I know you're gonna drive me away
Love is just like a faucet
It turns off and on
Sometimes when you think it's on, baby
It has turned off and gone
How about singing
that Old Black Joe there, Billie.
Come on, now. Don't go.
Sing Old Black Joe.
Thank you. Thank you very much.
Thank you.
You know that ditty Old Black Joe,
don't you, honey, baby?
Now, I'd love to do them all for you.
I'd love to do it for you...
but we got something planned here.
A little number called
What a Little Moonlight Can Do.
You only shudder
'Cause your poor tongue
Just won't utter
The words
I love you
Miss Billie Holiday.
Let's give her another hand.
Hey, baby.
Baby, what you doing here?
Here, I've been trying
to get you on the phone. Oh, baby.
I missed you so much.
You look so good, baby.
How'd you get here?
Get your clothes off.
I like your style,
but I can't say much for your timing.
Why don't we wait till we get home,
get a nice hot bath?
No.
Whatever you say.
My, my, the man is ready.
Well, so am I.
We've been having a rough tour.
Baby, I'm so happy you're here.
Now, this is all I'm gonna do.
And I want you to do the rest.
You're hurting me.
Jesus.
All right, that's it. Come on, let's go.
- I know what you're thinking.
- This tour's over.
I'm the one who sent you here,
and I'm taking you back home...
so get your things, let's go.
Wait a minute.
I know what you're thinking.
I don't wanna hear about it.
Just come home.
I'm not hooked.
No, I ain't going.
I ain't going, Louis.
Billie, listen to me.
All right.
Billie, it...
Believe me when I tell you
that this is for your own good.
Don't preach to me, Louis.
All that I plan for you
is done with you in mind.
You affect my whole life, baby.
I love you.
- Lf you go down, baby. I go down, too.
- I'm not going down...
because there ain't no place down there
I wanna be.
Be going up, baby.
It'll just take a little time.
I love you, too. I love you.
Sure, I've taken a few shots,
but only when I needed it...
and I'm not hooked, Louis. Wait, baby.
Only when you needed it.
What do you think hooked is?
All I had to do is listen to your voice
on the telephone, and I knew.
Who do you think you're talking to?
One of those old fake cats
you be running around with?
I've been on those streets all of my life.
I know what that shit is.
It's good, ain't it?
Wait. Wait, wait.
We're going home, now.
Wait, hey, baby, wait.
See? You don't understand.
Now, you don't know how it is...
when people are looking down at you
and laughing at you...
and think that I'm a loser.
And if I go home now,
I'll think that I'm one, too.
I gotta prove it to them,
I gotta prove it to myself.
What're you proving with that needle?
That you're not woman enough
to make it without a crutch...
a magic way out
when the going gets a little too rough?
I want you to make it, too, baby,
but not this way. Not this way.
Okay.
Okay, I promise you
I won't take any more stuff.
I promise you. I gotta stay out here.
You're gonna let me stay?
- No.
- Louis, please.
I get it. I'll be big, and then I can work
at a good club, and we'll be together.
I promise you, I won't take
any more stuff. Come on, Louis.
Come on, Louis,
won't you take your clothes off?
Come on, Louis, please. I can't go now.
I gotta take you home, baby,
because I know...
I ain't going.
Hey, Crazy Maurice and Weird Lucille
want us to go out there with them.
Lady, what do you have this door
locked for? You cool?
I'm fine, Harry.
Come on in.
Well, there he is. How the hell are you?
He's fine.
I just dropped by to see
if you needed anything...
like a trip back to the hotel
or something...
but I guess you got it covered...
- so I'll catch you later, okay?
- See you at the hotel.
Bye. See you at the hotel.
Harry's a good friend.
That's what every little girl needs,
a good friend like Harry.
Okay.
I'm gonna get some gas for the car,
and I'll take you back to the hotel.
Louis...
I love you.
I promise you. No more stuff, okay?
I promise you.
Nine.
- Come on, Billie.
- Five.
- Eight.
- Seven.
Here we go, babe.
$2 she hits them.
- Jesus Christ!
- What?
Billie, get out of sight.
- Billie, come on.
- No, goddamn.
Billie, get out of sight.