("Finally Single"
by Mucho DeNiro playing)
♪ Turnt up, yeah, they turnt up ♪
♪ Hangover in the morning
can't hurt much ♪
♪ We get dumb drunk,
they lift shirts up ♪
♪ Say ... 'cause my ex
wasn't worth much ♪
♪ Yeah, 'cause I'm finally single ♪
♪ Have a toast,
I can finally mingle... ♪
(phone vibrating)
That feels good.
It's my wife.
Shh.
- (music stops)
- (beeps)
Hey, babe.
No, still at work.
It's these high-frequency traders.
I got to clean up their mess.
No, you can go ahead and eat without me.
I, uh... I'll find something here.
All right.
Okay. I love you, too.
(both moan)
(phone beeps)
You're such a big, bad liar.
I know.
(exhales)
I need to be punished.
We good for next week?
I'm always good for next week.
(door opens)
(door closes)
(knocking)
Did I forget the gratuity?
I gave you an extra $50.
Who the hell are you?
(to "She'll Be Coming 'Round
the Mountain"): ♪ I'll be making ♪
♪ Turkey sandwiches in my sweats ♪
♪ I'll be making
turkey sandwiches in my sweats ♪
♪ And I'll be using high-fat mayo ♪
♪ 'Cause Trish is upstairs sleeping... ♪
WOMAN: ♪ You'll be making
a turkey sandwich ♪
♪ In your sweats. ♪
Who are you?
Sorry. Didn't mean to scare you.
I was just on my way out.
- I'm Feather.
- Feather?
If Riana had a friend named
Feather, I would've remembered.
Who's Riana?
"Who's Riana?" Okay, that takes me back
to my first question: Who are you?
ROGER JR.:
Feather, you forgot your belt.
D-Dad... y-you're up.
Yeah, I'm up. I was just getting to know
- your friend, Feather.
- Sorry. I'm such
a space case.
W-We were just...
upstairs. Yeah, making decorative belts.
- Studying.
- Otherwise, how would someone
just lose their belt, like, poof,
"My belt is gone"?
You're hilarious, Mr. Murtaugh.
It's Detective Murtaugh.
Not that hilarious.
Can I just say, we're all adults here.
Oh, are we?
You raised a great young man.
You should be proud.
Bye, babe.
- (door opens, closes)
- Dad, uh, let me explain.
- We-we had...
- I know what you had.
You had the audacity
to bring a girl in my house
while your mother and I
are up there sleeping?
And you think we wouldn't find out?
- It's not a big deal.
- It's not a big deal?
Well, guess what?
I'm grounded forever.
Maybe longer.
We'll talk about this tomorrow.
Get upstairs.
(chuckles)
(seagulls cawing)
(snoring)
WOMAN: Mm.
Mm, morning.
Yep.
That's what it is. (groans)
You got somewhere to be?
Uh, yeah. I got this thing
that I, uh,
just completely forgot about.
Um...
yeah, look, there's some OJ in the fri--
no, do not drink the OJ
that is in that refrigerator.
Um...
(Murtaugh laughs)
My boy got some action last night.
What? Who did?
RJ.
Not only is he Princeton-bound,
but it turns out, he's inherited
his dad's charms with the ladies.
That's good news. (chuckles)
Yeah, that's what-- hey.
What in the...?
Is that a bathing suit you got on?
Uh, all my pants were stained up
and I didn't want to
look unprofessional.
Okay, you know what's unprofessional?
Is you blinding me
with those pasty legs.
Exactly. They need a little vitamin D.
Riggs.
You gonna tell me that this right here
is not even a little weird,
even for you?
Uh, this line of questioning
is a little weird.
And uncomfortable.
(sighing): Okay, it's
gonna be that kind of day.
(indistinct radio transmission)
Okay, so who is he?
Dale Reynolds, 35.
Had quite a party followed
by an accidental overdose.
Or not so accidental.
The bluish skin,
bleeding foam around his mouth,
all point to an OD, but...
check out the knot in the tourniquet.
BAILEY: It's on the outside of his arm.
Which means he had help.
What you got there, legs?
A wedding ring stuffed in his pocket.
Dale Reynolds, you cheating bastard.
MURTAUGH: Okay, well,
someone had to be the last
person to see him alive.
So, let's find that girlfriend,
boyfriend, intern, escort...
(woman laughing)
(echoing): Nice place you got here.
MURTAUGH: And make sure
that you call his, um...
- BAILEY: His wife?
- MURTAUGH: Yeah.
BAILEY: Yeah, tell her
we found her husband dead
in a hotel room, smelling like
another woman's cheap perfume.
I'm on it.
Is that what that smell is? (sniffs)
Doesn't seem to be
coming off the corpse.
I think...
it's coming from...
Riggs?
(water running)
(indistinct radio transmission)
Sinner.
Me?
No, him.
Synced & corrected by -robtor-
www.addic7ed.com
AVERY: Bailey, what do you got?
There's security footage
of a van arriving
and leaving the hotel garage
that times out with our killer.
Okay, do you have a plate?
A partial and we're looking into it.
Good enough news.
Mr. City Attorney, in the house.
What a rare, unexpected treat.
Did I-- did I know you were...?
I just thought I'd pop in.
Awesome. You heard
we caught a grizzly one.
You're hear to scrub in?
We need to talk.
I have concerns.
Never a great opening.
Martin Riggs...
- how's he doing?
- Riggs? He's...
he's doing well.
Adjusting to the culture.
He-he should be here any minute,
you could ask him yourself.
I intend to.
But I want to hear from you first.
Make sure there aren't any issues
I should have heard about already.
None-- none that I can think of...
off the top of my head.
(elevator bell dings)
If you're sick, you should go home.
- I'm not sick.
- You threw up.
Barely. It was more about your cleanse.
MURTAUGH: Look, all I'm saying
is that you're not yourself,
and when you are yourself,
you're barely function...
AVERY: Roger.
You know Ronnie Delgado?
He had some concerns
about your partner, Riggs.
I was hoping you could, uh...
Why? 'Cause he wore shorts today?
- Shorts?
- Roger,
maybe you could
tell the city attorney how well
- your partner is doing.
- Is he drinking?
Behaving erratically?
(laughs)
Riggs? Drinking?
Um,
um... (clears throat)
I don't know what he does
after hours, but
you're asking:
is he drinking during the day?
Is-is what you're asking.
- Where is he?
- Hmm.
He's probably doing paperwork.
He loves paperwork.
AVERY: He does a lot of paperwork.
I'm gonna see if I can find him.
- Yes.
- Good idea.
- I think you can.
(sighs)
(grunts)
Riggs?
Are we okay?
Oh, hey, Doc.
Yeah, just another day in paradise.
What are you doing
under a vending machine?
Well, I needed a break
and this is a break room.
And now, I'm trying to get...
(straining): this... little...
(grunts)
Got it. (groans)
(sighs)
(chip bag rips open)
So, is this it?
Have we finally arrived at rock-bottom?
No, there's still some places to go.
Oh, Duke. How'd we do?
Uh, I got most of what you wanted.
Except for your wallet,
I couldn't find it.
No worries. Thanks, buddy.
Oh,
okay, so you're eating floor chips
and you sent a uni to
retrieve your pants?
Ah.
A wool cap.
It is getting chilly outside. Duke!
This is looking like a
pretty clear cry for help.
(sighs)
Well, as usual,
you're not wrong.
Would you like to help me out?
Yes. Yes, I would.
Well, apparently,
I've misplaced my wallet.
And I'm starving,
so if I could borrow a buck,
that would be great.
I'm sorry, Riggs, all I have is a ten.
No problem, that'll work perfectly.
One successful cry for help.
AVERY: Be honest.
Is he getting worse?
I don't know. It's Riggs.
One minute, I think he's doing better.
The next minute, he has me jumping
off a skyscraper into a pool.
So, worse. You're-you're saying worse.
No, what I'm saying is:
I'm too busy trying to stay alive
than to crack the mystery
of the shorts-wearing detective.
All right, fair enough. But now,
Delgado's got his eyes on him.
Remember, I put you two together
so that you could lift Riggs up,
not so that he would...
Bring me down?
WOMAN: Heroin?
It wasn't his doing.
Your husband was murdered
by a forced overdose.
And, um...
what about the woman? Hmm?
And the hotel room?
Was that his doing?
(sighs)
Was there anyone that-that
had it out for your husband,
or had a grudge against him,
anything like that?
Um, a couple of months ago
somebody threw a brick
through our window
in the middle of the night.
Okay. That's a start.
Do you know who?
No. But-but Dale did.
He said that it was a work thing.
And that I shouldn't worry,
that he would get a restraining order.
♪ ♪
MURTAUGH: Suspect's name is Ben Garvey.
He's got a restraining order.
And he's got a warrant for violating
said restraining order.
Perfect. A daily double.
- Ben Garvey!
- Yeah.
Of the brick-throwing Garveys?
MURTAUGH: Hey, LAPD.
We need to ask you a few
questions about Dale Reynolds.
Yeah, sure.
Okay, um... Just give me a second.
♪ ♪
All right.
♪ Put the pedal to the metal,
hustle hard ♪
♪ I be on my job on another level ♪
Split up.
♪ Us against the law ♪
♪ You ain't even looked
for what you found ♪
♪ I ain't backing down ♪
♪ Now I'm comin',
ain't no turnin' back ♪
Hey! Hey!
♪ Ain't no turnin' back... ♪
Give me the nail gun.
All right.
Hey!
Hey, now that was...
(cocks gun) Drop it!
I'm not going to jail
for violating some restraining order.
MURTAUGH: You're right.
You're going to jail for
the murder of Dale Reynolds.
♪ Now I'm comin',
ain't no turnin' back. ♪
Riggs, no, no, no, no, no, no!
(all yelling)
(groans)
(all groaning)
Ow.
I honestly thought that
tarp would hold. (groans)
Yeah. Oh, yeah, it's the tarp's fault.
Not just nails, two types of screws.
And an Allen wrench.
You're lucky.
No, luck had nothing to do with it.
MURTAUGH: Ha!
I mean, you know, perp had a
nail gun pointed at my partner,
I had no choice.
Really?
No choice?
Didn't we just talk about our choices?
About playing it safe?
Or was I imagining that?
My options weren't great.
Oh, you had options.
How about trusting your partner, huh?
How-How about waiting for backup?
Shooting the guy in the leg?
But no, you had to take the one
where we plummeted
off a building,
through a tarp, into a box of nails?
I made sure that was
a controlled plummet.
- Oh, you made sure?
- Yeah, I made sure.
Because you got x-ray vision.
And you saw what was on
the other side of that tarp.
You had no idea
where we were landing.
So, uh, I'm just gonna go...
recalibrate the forceps.
I think she just made that up.
You know what, Riggs?
There's gonna come a time
when there's nothing
on the other side of that tarp.
And I'm not letting you
bring me down with you.
Now get dressed.
We have a suspect to interrogate.
GARVEY: Dale Reynolds was a snake.
He cheated on his wife
with my kid sister, Cynthia.
And that's why you killed him?
I didn't kill him.
Are you getting mixed signals
with this guy?
- I'm confused,
- I don't...
The son of a bitch
killed Cynthia.
He introduced her to heroin.
So your sister OD'd?
- And that's why you killed him.
- The same way he killed Cynthia.
I already told you,
I didn't kill him.
Even though I hated him,
and I wished he was dead.
This is... See, this is
where we get into, like,
that whole confusing problem area.
Mr. Garvey? (clears throat)
Where were you between the hours
of 8:00 and 10:00 last night?
I was at church.
RIGGS: I mean, that's either
the greatest alibi of all time
or the worst,
I genuinely don't know.
I don't know.
♪ ♪
Hi. Welcome to St. Valens.
The soup kitchen is down this walkway.
Yeah, we're LAPD.
Which doesn't mean we don't like soup.
(chuckles) Rog.
Do I detect a chowder?
MURTAUGH: We're looking
for Darryl Patterson.
Father Patterson? Yeah,
he's in the main sanctuary.
And, uh, yeah, it's a fish chowder.
With the little, tiny crackers?
(phone buzzing)
Bailey has a lead on the van.
I'm gonna check in with her.
So is that a yes or
a no on the crackers?
Riggs.
I'm on it.
PATTERSON: Ben Garvey?
Yeah, I saw him here
most of the evening.
I heard his confession
then he sat in on Mass.
What'd he confess to?
(soft chuckle) Come on, Detective,
you know I can't tell you that.
Sacred seal of confession.
Come on, Father.
That's just a wooden box.
It's not about the box,
it's about what happens
when you step inside.
You'd be surprised.
Yeah?
You walk in, unload all your crap,
you walk out, clean slate.
Seems a little too easy to me.
Well, that's an oversimplification.
You're welcome to try.
Money back guarantee if it doesn't help.
I'll pass.
Look, you got a
fairly large congregation.
How would you know
if a guy like Ben Garvey
slipped out during Mass?
What is it you think he did?
The man he blames for killing his sister
was murdered last night.
Well, I'm sorry to hear that, I...
I know Ben struggled
with Cynthia's loss,
but I also know in my heart he
couldn't do something like that.
Unfortunately,
what we know in our hearts
doesn't necessarily qualify
as hard evidence, Father.
Well, evening Mass is live-streamed.
- Ben Garvey sits up front.
- (phone buzzing)
Would a time-stamped video qualify
as hard evidence?
_
Yeah, that would be great if we
could get those videos, Father.
Thank you for your time.
You're welcome back any time, Detective.
(muffled music playing) ♪ Love seems ♪
- (door alarms dinging)
- ♪ All I want ♪
♪ Love seems ♪
♪ All I need ♪
(gate creaks open)
♪ Love seems ♪
♪ Everything ♪
(cocks gun)
♪ I know ♪
♪ Everything bleeds ♪
♪ ♪
I think we're too late.
♪ Everything bleeds. ♪
♪ ♪
Okay, I'm gonna call it in.
Hey, Bailey.
Yeah, we got the van.
Looks like the same guy.
It could be another victim.
Rog?
- Huh?
- Come here.
(grunting)
There we go. Come on.
(gasps loudly)
(door closes)
♪ ♪
(woman giggles)
(phone buzzing)
(sighs)
(beeps)
On the house.
WWOOFing? What the hell is that?
It stands for Worldwide
Opportunities of Organic Farms.
And you're gonna give up Princeton
because you want to be a farmer?
TRISH: What about your education, honey?
Why can't you go to college
and have a garden?
- Do that.
- TRISH: Yeah.
Grow your own food.
And the we don't have to pay
for a meal plan.
That's not how it works.
You live on farms all around the globe,
and me and Feather are gonna
start in New Zealand
and work our way around.
Feather? The girl from the other night?
- Yeah, the one that lost her belt.
- What...
She lost her belt?
You didn't tell me...
- Where'd her belt go, RJ?
- Where'd the belt go?
You guys are being ridiculous.
Okay, look,
I get it.
You're on this road and you meet
this exciting girl,
and she says, "Hey, you know what?
"There's a whole world out there
if you go off-road."
Maybe I don't like the road I'm on.
Maybe Princeton is your dream.
I need to figure out
w-what's mine, what I want.
Well, I want to get back to the
belt, that's what I want.
(knocking on door)
The thing is,
- you can get lost, okay?
- Mm-hmm.
You can go off-road
- and never make it back.
- TRISH: Yeah.
People do.
Howdy.
Was this planned?
What? Ooh.
- Dinner.
- It's not a good time, Riggs.
We're having a family, uh...
- Crisis.
- Yeah.
- Oh, I'm great in a crisis.
- Yes, Riggs, please,
I can't talk to these people anymore.
Oh, come on, they're all right.
I mean, your dad can be a little chatty.
I did not come empty-handed.
Martin, you didn't have to.
Oh, forget it. So, uh...
what's the problem?
Besides all that,
RJ wants to blow off college.
I want to see the world
with my girlfriend,
and we're gonna start in New Zealand.
Ooh, New Zealand. Wellington,
the capital...
(clicks tongue) beautiful.
- Go for it.
- Thank you.
Crisis averted. All right, let's eat.
I'm gonna grab a plate.
RIGGS: Anybody need anything?!
(video game gunfire)
Feather, huh?
Somebody named her that?
Yeah.
That's a name, all right.
He's out there filling RJ's head
with more foolishness,
if that's even possible.
I'm gonna go put an end to this.
Roger, don't.
Don't interfere.
If we push, RJ will push back.
So what do we do,
just sit back while his life
- goes down the drain?
- No, it's a phase. RJ will turn around.
I mean, when he finds out
how much a ticket to New Zealand costs.
Hmm.
You love her?
I do.
Never let her go. You hear me?
Yeah. We got plans to go...
What did I just say?
Y-You said never let her go.
Bingo.
(Riggs sighs)
Feather?
She spell that with a "Ph"?
What's going on with Riggs?
The drinking?
TRISH: That much drinking.
He's drowning in it.
I've never seen it this bad before.
He should sleep on the couch.
Or in the garage.
The couch.
Or the driveway.
(snoring lightly)
Hey, you good?
Mm-hmm.
I've got some pillows
and sheets and stuff for you.
Oh, no need. I am a simple man, buddy.
No, the sheet is for the couch, not you.
Oh... (clears throat)
- Yep, yep, yep, yep.
- No, no, no, no,
- no, no, no, no.
- You get your boots.
- All right.
- I got this.
- Oh. (clears throat)
(grunts, groans)
You all right? Mm-hmm.
Look at this little...
this little pouch you've made.
Okay.
Hey, if you wake up in a couple hours,
and you think about driving home,
do me a favor, don't.
Okay?
I cheated on my wife.
What?
Last night.
I drank too much,
and, um...
I didn't intentionally do it,
but I cheated on her.
Want talk about it?
We just did.
You want to hit those lights for me?
(clears throat)
WOMAN: For someone who was
buried alive, she's doing okay.
Vitals are stable, but she could be out
for another couple of days.
I'll call you if anything changes.
Thank you.
Same van, same message
left at the scene-- "sinner."
So it wasn't Garvey.
We got one less suspect
and one more victim.
What do we know about her?
Valerie Rausch, 48.
Never married, pays taxes,
and works as a social
coordinator at a senior home.
That's a job?
Okay, Dale Reynolds
let his girlfriend die
of a heroin overdose.
And then someone shot him
full of heroin.
The question is...
Why does a never-married
social coordinator
get buried alive?
Mm-hmm.
WOMAN: It's like something
out of a nightmare.
Poor Valerie. Who would do
something like that?
We were hoping you could point
us in the right direction.
I wish.
- Mr. Raines.
- Hmm?
We talked about this.
Shut it down.
(computer beeps)
Valerie's adored by the residents.
Me, not so much.
Does she have an office or a desk
or something we can look at?
A locker. I'll open it for you.
Are you a Mexican?
My last husband was a Mexican.
- Beautiful man.
- He sounds great, but...
Don't believe what anyone says.
You know Valerie.
She's an angel of death.
O-Okay...
And she killed Ethel Puckelwitz
for her life insurance.
Smothered her with a pillow
till she couldn't breathe.
Mm-mm.
You all right?
- V-Valerie was suffocated, right?
- Yeah.
I think I know
who we might be looking for.
Good, because I think
I know where to look.
I found this in Valerie's locker.
Church bulletin.
Guess which church.
PATTERSON: Valerie Rausch?
Yeah, I know her.
Well, she was buried alive last night.
Do you have any idea why?
We're thinking it might
have something to do
with her nasty habit
of smothering senior citizens
to get their life insurance.
He doesn't look surprised.
- He doesn't look surprised.
- If I told you something like that,
I'd be surprise... Would you not be...
- Would you please?
- I would go, huh? What?
Whoa, that's a surprised look.
That's what I was going for.
Let me guess, Father,
Valerie walked into
your little magic box
and told you all about
her unconventional use
of orthopedic pillows, and...
If such a thing happened,
I would have urged her
to turn herself in.
But she didn't, and someone
punished her for it.
Just like with Dale Reynolds.
What do you want from me?
A confession would be nice.
You know I was in the sanctuary.
Then tell us who it could be.
Who else knows what Valerie Rausch
and Ben Garvey confessed to you?
No one. It was between
the confessor and God.
(groans)
- It is so difficult to subpoena God.
- Mm-hmm.
All right, let's go turn
the confessional upside down.
Ooh, that's the surprised
look I was hoping for.
See that?
What are we looking for, anyway?
Hell if I know.
Kinda underwhelming, isn't it?
Hey, uh, I took your keys last
night when you weren't looking.
I took a bottle of Blue Label
this morning from the den.
Yeah, well, I knew
you were gonna do that,
so I switched it with a crappier bottle.
The girl from the other night...
...I don't even know her name.
I don't really remember anything.
I was... I was black-out drunk.
Well, that's got to be unsettling.
Is this happening a lot?
Waking up with unknown girls?
Getting blacked-out drunk.
More often than I should.
Well, that's got to be...
Well, I'm sure that wasn't
easy for you to say.
I think it's important that you did.
You know, realizing that
this is something
you need to look into.
And I appreciate...
No, I'm honored
that you would share that with me.
MURTAUGH: I mean,
I know I'm your partner and all,
but-- and I don't even care
if this is reciprocal or not--
but I consider you a friend.
(laughs softly)
Yeah, it's true.
I mean, you don't... you don't
have to say anything,
just... just process it.
Riggs, you processing?
Riggs?
Riggs! (voice echoes in church)
(whispers): Sorry.
(door opens, hinges creaking)
Oh, right here. Let's see.
Uh-huh.
RIGGS: Bingo.
Hey, what you got behind
this door right here?
A maintenance room--
it's where Reuben keeps
supplies for the grounds,
for the soup kitchen.
The soup guy who had
the little tiny crackers?
(hinges creak)
I'll be damned.
Marty. I heard I might find you here.
Uh, it's almost never true. Um...
We're gonna need the room a few minutes.
You know what, I gotta go, too.
- We've got this vigilante killer...
- You'll take a minute!
For me.
We missed you Friday night.
Catholic Church gives a grieving
spouse a year and a day
to mourn a loved one.
I-I know you're not
a religious man, but...
Friday was a year and a day.
That's why I picked the date.
Anna and I knew
this first one was gonna be difficult.
But we wanted to mark it,
to remember Miranda.
With family.
With friends.
Everyone she loved.
You were her husband.
I still am.
What were you doing Friday night
that you couldn't make it?
I was in no shape to be around people.
From what I've heard,
you're in no condition a lot.
(exhales) Ronnie, listen...
Marty.
You want to be a drunk,
you be a drunk.
But I won't allow you
to blame my daughter for it.
MURTAUGH: There's a BOLO out
on Reuben Tomar's car.
LAX, bus station, train station,
all have been alerted.
- Okay. So, what do we know about him?
- He grew up
in St. Valens Church
after losing both parents.
MURTAUGH: His father
was a violent alcoholic.
He beat his mother to death.
Actually got sent away to prison for it.
We have a problem.
Father Patterson is M.I.A.
Hospital security has
his car in the parking lot.
Sign of struggle and blood on the seat.
Why would Ruben take his priest?
Maybe he wanted to repent.
Pretty sure that's not how it works.
(grunts)
AVERY: Okay.
Valerie Rausch, Dale Reynolds.
Reuben went after them
for a reason. Why them? Why now?
Ruben found out they got away
with murder during confession.
So he punished them the same way
they committed their crimes.
If Father Patterson knew
that Reuben's dad was abusing his mom,
he sure as hell would hold him
accountable as well.
Reuben, stop.
God will forgive you.
Like you forgave my father.
You freed him of sin.
Instead of saving my mom.
So now, you are going to
suffer as she suffered.
(leather belt creaking)
Dad liked to use belts.
Did he tell you that?
When he confessed to you?
The BOLO paid off. Here's Reuben
blowing a red light
on Normandie and Sunset
about 15 minutes ago.
Well, that's just a couple of
blocks from his childhood home.
The apartment where his mother died.
- Yep.
- Go.
♪ ♪
Stay with me, Father.
Please.
No more.
I read the coroner's report.
He hit her
39 times
before she died.
I'm only up to ten.
My mother could take it.
So can you.
Childhood home
of deranged serial killer?
Seems kind of textbook.
- (whispers): Is that the house?
- Mm-hmm.
All right.
PATTERSON: Please, stop! (blows landing)
Rueben, please.
Clear, left!
Clear!
Rog?
Yeah. (groaning)
You got this?
I got it.
Ambulance on their way.
(groaning)
Uh-uh-uh. Come on.
You need to come with me.
I'd rather go with God.
Eh, that's not really a good option.
You know.
Look.
I mean, I know it's majestic,
and the white dove,
and everything, but...
Hey, hey, hey, no!
(yells)
(grunting)
Hey!
I got you.
I'm gonna pull you up.
(grunting)
(metal groaning)
Rog, it's not gonna hold.
You're gonna fall, too.
(grunting)
Rog, it's not gonna hold.
Let me go.
No!
I'm not gonna let you go. (grunting)
Rog! Let me go.
I'm not letting you go.
Rog. It's okay. It's okay.
No. I'm not letting you go!
Ow!
What is wrong... You hit me!
Rog! You need to let me go, Rog!
I'm not letting you... go!
(screams)
(both groaning)
(moaning)
- Ow.
- (exhales)
Rog.
Tell the truth.
Did you know this tree was down here?
- I can't believe you hit me!
- Well...
AVERY: So, I read your report.
- Have some questions.
- You shouldn't. Everything's in there.
The shiner. Walk me through that.
You're on the roof with the suspect.
When did he punch you?
Suspect did not punch me.
Then who... Please, don't say
- Riggs.
(clears throat)
Do me a favor.
If Delgado asks, tell him...
Baseball to the face,
got hit by space debris,
swordfishing accident...
Yes. Any of those things.
Why did he do it?
It's not his fault.
I had it coming.
I tried to save his life.
(sighs)
(exhales)
Quite the watering hole
you got here, Ronnie.
Can I buy you another drink?
Get another one of these
and a club soda. Thanks.
You don't have to abstain on my account.
It's not just you.
I'm starting to forget things about her.
Little things.
God knows I don't want to,
but, um... I am
and... I can't do anything about it.
So let us help you through it.
Look.
I really appreciate everything
you've done for me.
I do.
I can't do this.
I think it's best
If I don't see you guys anymore.
Martin.
You're our family.
No.
She was your family.
I was just lucky for a little while.
♪ Living too fast ♪
Be well, Ronnie.
♪ What are we doing here? ♪
♪ Too distracted ♪
Hey.
It's late. What are you doing?
I was just looking for things to do
with the money we saved on Princeton.
You're torturing yourself, honey.
No. I ran the numbers.
You know, we could take a cruise
around the world in a first
class cabin nine times.
You like travel.
Yes... But it's a boat.
I get seasick.
Well, there's a deserted town
in North Dakota
that we could buy.
RJ and Feather could move there,
and he could be the mayor
of Stupidville.
(laughs) Stop.
Don't drain the college fund just yet.
I have faith RJ
will make the right choice.
Maybe it'll take
a few months, maybe a year.
Feather just broke up with me.
Or sooner.
- Hey, baby.
- Aw.
What happened?
She said she's not in a
head-space for a relationship,
with everything that's going on
in the world.
- Oh.
- Mm, mm-mm.
So, the WWOOFing is...
- It's off.
- Oh.
ROGER JR.: Now she's going to Greenland
to measure glacial melt.
By herself.
She's so flighty.
So flighty.
(knocking on door)
Maybe it's her.
(whispering): Please, don't be her.
Oh, please, honey. (laughs)
Let it be anybody but her.
♪ Change ♪
Hey! What's up, J?
(sighing): Oh. It's you.
♪ Y'all need to take a minute
to stop and listen ♪
What's up with that?
Feather.
Ah.
Poor guy. Well. I brought you
this as a thank you
for saving my life, but, uh,
maybe RJ needs it more than you do.
Hey, look at this.
The seal's not even broken.
I'm touched.
Ah, well. Can I pour you a shot?
Oh, no. I'll just have a glass of water.
You know, there's no alcohol in water.
Yeah.
You know, Feather used to tell me
that ground water is
contaminated by dry cleaners.
MURTAUGH: Listen.
I know you don't want to hear
this right now,
but you're gonna meet
so many Feathers
- in your life.
- He's right.
And you know where
you meet girls just like her?
The best, smartest,
most interesting women
in the world?
- Rio.
- College.
College.
What if I went to college
in Rio?
- Ah! Very good!
- Ah...
MURTAUGH: That's not gonna happen.
Synced & corrected by -robtor-
www.addic7ed.com