Excuse me. I was looking
for the Weekly Volcano office.
I wish to see
Mr. Dashwood.
A friend of mine desired me
to offer a story by her.
She... She wrote it.
She'd be glad to write more
if this suits.
Not a first attempt,
I take it.
No, sir. She has sold
to Olympic and Scandal,
and she got a prize for a tale
at the Blarneystone Banner.
A prize?
Yes.
Sit.
We'll take this.
Oh, you will?
With alterations.
It's too long.
Um, but you've cut...
I took care to have
a few of my sinners repent.
The country just
went through a war.
People want to be amused,
not preached at.
Morals don't sell nowadays.
Perhaps mention that
to your friend.
What compensation...?
How do you...?
We pay 25 to 30
for things of this sort.
- We'll pay 20 for that.
- Oh.
You can have it.
Make the edits.
Should I tell my...
uh, my friend
you'll take another
if she had one better than this?
We'll look at it. Tell her
to make it short and spicy.
And if the main character's
a girl,
make sure she's married
by the end.
- Or dead. Either way.
- Excuse me?
What name would she like
put to the story?
Oh, uh, yes.
None at all, if you please.
Just as she likes,
of course.
Oh, well, heh...
Good morning, sir. Good day.
Yes!
My Beth would
like you very much.
I'd like a room for two.
Perfect. That's 4.50 a week.
And that's a good price.
Isn't that a little expensive?
This is a
boardinghouse, not a charity.
I need the rent on time.
Good
afternoon, Miss March.
Oh, good afternoon.
You're on fire.
Thank you.
You're on fire!
- Thank you.
- I have the same habit. You see?
Oh.
Kitty and Minnie are waiting.
- Oh, my students need me.
- Always working.
Money is the end and aim
of my mercenary existence.
No one gets
ink stains like yours
just out of
a desire for money.
My sister Amy's in Paris,
and until she marries
someone obscenely wealthy,
it's up to me
to keep the family afloat.
Goodbye.
The Decadents have
ruined Paris, if you ask me.
These French women
couldn't lift a hairbrush.
- Amy!
- Hm?
I said, these French women
couldn't lift a hairbrush.
Oh, yes. Very true,
Aunt March.
Oh, don't humor me, girl.
What do they write,
your troublemaking family?
Mother doesn't say
anything about Beth.
I feel I should go back.
They all say, "Stay."
You can do nothing
if you go back.
The girl is sick,
not lonely.
And you shouldn't go home
until you and Fred Vaughn
are properly engaged.
Yes, and until I've completed
all of my painting lessons,
of course.
Oh, yes, yes.
Of course.
- Stop the carriage! Laurie!
- What are you doing?
- Laurie, Laurie, Laurie!
- Amy!
- Laurie! Ha, ha!
Amy!
- How are you?
- Oh!
My, you've grown so much.
You wrote you'd meet me
at the hotel.
- I couldn't find you.
- You didn't look hard enough.
I didn't recognize you.
You're so beautiful.
- Oh, stop it.
- I thought you liked that?
- Where's your grandfather?
- In Germany.
He's still traveling.
I'm on my own now, relaxing.
- Flirting, gambling and drinking.
- Yes. Don't tell your mother.
Are you chasing
some young girl across Europe?
No.
I couldn't believe Jo
turned you down. I'm so sorry.
Don't be, Amy. I... I'm not.
Amy!
Amy March!
- Come back this instant!
- Oh, Aunt March.
Come. Come on.
- Aren't you looking grand?
- Get him off me!
We need to be somewhere.
Off you go!
Come to
the New Year's Eve party.
Everyone will be there,
including Fred.
Pick me up at the hotel
at 8, The Chavain.
Oh! And, Laurie,
dress for festivities!
Top hats and silks!
I will.
I'll wear my best silk.
It's Laurie.
I know.
Twenty yards of blue silk,
as well as pink.
Someone will be by for it later.
Oh, Meg, that would
look so lovely on you.
I know the dressmaker
to send you to.
You'll be the prettiest wife
in Concord.
Oh, I... John needs
a new coat for winter,
and Daisy and Demi
need new clothes.
And his wife
needs a new dress.
I can't. It's...
I just can't.
He'll be so pleased
with how you look,
he'll forget
all about the expense.
I don't suppose it's too much
of an extravagance.
Will 20 yards do?
- Yes.
- Very good.
Fifty dollars?
What was I thinking?
Mommy!
Oh, my loves.
Go play.
Beth!
Beth?
There lies your way,
due west.
Then westward ho!
Grace and good disposition
attend Your Ladyship.
You'll nothing, madam,
to my lord by me?
Stay, I prithee,
tell me what thou thinkest of me.
That you do think
you are not what you are.
If I think so,
I think the same of you.
Then think you
right, I am not what I am.
Like, a big one.
Like, a big one... Like that.
Excuse me?
I only speak English.
I'm sorry, what?
- What did you say?
- Come dance!
Oh!
I know exactly
who I wanna dance with.
I'll take this off.
Who will you dance with, Jo?
You know I never dance.
Why can't we all go?
It's not fair.
- Wear your regular shoes.
- These fit last winter.
My nose will simply
not look refined.
I like your nose.
- Now, Jo.
- Don't touch me.
I feel ridiculous.
I don't wanna look it.
You could be pretty
if you tried.
- Don't want to. Won't.
- I don't want to go,
but I wish
I could hear the music.
I'll keep it in my head
and sing it for you.
- Ought they to smoke like that?
- It's the dampness drying.
What a queer smell,
like burnt feathers.
Now I'll take this off and
you'll see a perfect ringlet.
Why is her hair off?
- Meg, I'm so sorry.
- What have you done?!
I'm sorry.
You shouldn't have
asked me.
Marmee!
I can't go, I'm spoiled!
My hair!
Don't stare, don't put
your hands behind your back,
don't say "Columbus,"
don't say "capital."
- All right.
- Don't shake hands.
Don't whistle.
Meg March,
you look so pretty.
Well...
Meg.
Thank you.
No, it's so early. No.
Fine.
Ooh! Sorry. I didn't know
anyone was here.
- Not at all. Stay if you like.
- I won't disturb you?
No. I don't know
many people here.
I felt rather strange
at first, you know?
Mm, so do I. Heh.
Miss March, isn't it?
Yes, Mr. Laurence, but I'm not
Miss March. I'm only Jo.
And I'm not Mr. Laurence,
I'm only Laurie.
Don't you dance?
I don't know
how you do things here yet.
I've spent most
of my life in Europe.
Europe! Oh, that's capital!
Shouldn't use
words like that.
- Says who?
- Oh, Meg.
She's my older sister. Here.
Hm...
Oh, that's her. See?
- The girl in the violet dress.
- Mm. It's very pretty.
She reminds me to be good
so Father will be proud of me
when he returns.
Where is he?
He volunteered
for the Union Army.
And I wanted
to go fight with him.
I can't get over my
disappointment in being a girl.
Jo, would you like
to dance with me?
I can't because...
Because of what?
- You won't tell?
- Never.
I scorched my dress.
See? There.
And Meg told me to keep still
so no one would see it.
You can laugh if you want to.
It's funny, I know.
I have an idea
of how we can manage.
Oh!
- What?
- My foot.
- I've hurt my ankle.
- Oh!
How am I gonna get home?
I don't see what you can do,
except get a carriage
or stay all night.
- Carriages are too expensive.
- Let me take you.
- It's right next door.
- No, thank you.
- We cannot accept.
- You must take mine, please?
No. It's so early.
You can't mean to leave yet.
I always leave early.
I do, truly.
What choice
do you have, hm?
Goodness gracious.
What have you done?
She's lame and can't walk.
She's hobbling.
Clear that chair.
You're supposed to be asleep.
Help your sister,
then back to bed.
Make room.
Meg is a wounded soldier.
- I sprained my ankle.
- Oh, Meg, you'll kill yourself
for fashion
one of these days.
Here. Hannah, we need ice!
- Oh, come in. Come in.
- Is it all right?
Apologies for the chaos.
I enjoy baking
in the middle of the night.
Don't mind the clutter,
Mr. Laurence. We don't.
Laurie, please.
- Can I call you Teddy?
- Yes.
You must be part
of their theatricals.
- They could use an extra player.
- I'm Amy.
- Hello.
- You'll have to fight Jo
for the male roles
or play a girl.
- Have a scone.
- Yes, thank you.
And ice.
Laurie, how are your ankles?
- Do you need ice?
- No, thank you, ma'am.
Just call me "mother" or Marmee.
Everyone does.
You wore those pink shoes?
Ah, It's cold.
- But they look so good, okay?
- Do you want more ice?
Feels like being
a fine young lady
to come home from a party
in a carriage
and have maids wait on me. Ah!
For the writer in the attic.
Because you enjoyed
the play so much tonight,
I wanted you to have this.
It will help you study character
and paint it with your pen.
I would love to read
what you're writing,
if you'll trust me.
I promise honesty and whatever
intelligence I can muster.
Yours, Friedrich.
- Fred, would you like a glass?
- I will. Thank you.
Would you excuse me
a second?
Laurie.
Amy.
I waited an hour for you.
I feel caught.
Hm.
Amy, please. Amy.
Do you want to know
what I think of you?
- What do you think?
- I despise you.
- Why do you despise me?
- With every chance
of being good,
happy and useful,
you are lazy, faulty
and miserable.
- Ooh, interesting.
- Well, selfish people
- like to talk about themselves.
- Selfish?
- Yes, very selfish.
- Oh.
With your money, talent,
beauty, and health...
Oh, you think
I'm beautiful.
Yes, you like that,
you old vanity.
With good things to enjoy, you
find nothing to do but dawdle.
I'll be good for you, St. Amy.
I'll be good.
Aren't you ashamed
of a hand like that?
- I'm not.
- Looks like it's never done
a day of work in its life,
and that ring is ridiculous.
Jo gave me this ring.
I feel sorry for you.
I really do.
I just wish
you'd bear it better.
You don't have to feel sorry.
- You'll feel the same one day.
- No, I'd be respected
if I couldn't be loved.
What have you done lately,
oh, great artiste?
Perhaps you're fantasizing about
spending Fred Vaughn's fortune.
Fred Vaughn,
ladies and gentlemen!
Fred, I...
I'm so sorry.
Those are just stories,
of course.
But I'm working on a novel.
And your novel...
it will be like this?
Yes. So far, anyway.
With plots like this?
- Duels and killing and...
- It sells, so...
Why don't you sign
your real name?
Oh, my mother
wouldn't like it.
It's too gory for her.
I wanna help with the money
I make and not worry her.
Mm.
You know, I...
I don't like them.
Honestly, uh...
I mean, I... I think
that they're not good.
Uh, but...
They're...
They're published
in the papers,
and people have always said
that I'm talented.
Oh, I think you're talented.
Which is why I'm being so...
So blunt.
Well, I can't afford
to starve on praise.
Are you upset?
Of course I'm upset.
You just...
You told me
you didn't like my work.
Jo, I thought
you wanted honesty.
I... Yes, I do.
Has no one ever talked
to you like this before?
Yes, I've been rejected
plenty of times.
Do you have anyone
to take you seriously, Jo,
- to talk about your work?
- And who made you high priest
of what's good
and what's bad?
- No one, and I'm not...
- Then why are you acting like it?
Your reaction indicates
there is some truth...
My reaction indicates
that you are a pompous blowhard.
Shakespeare wrote
for the masses.
Shakespeare was the greatest
poet who ever lived
because he smuggled his poetry
in popular works.
- I'm no Shakespeare.
- Thank goodness.
We already have him.
If you know so much about it,
why don't you just
do it yourself?
Because I'm not a writer.
- I don't have the gifts you have.
- No, you don't.
You will always be a critic
and never an author.
And the world will forget
that you ever even lived.
- Oh, I'm sure they will.
- But...
I... But I...
No one will forget Jo March.
I can believe it.
Listen.
We are not friends.
You are not my friend.
And I don't want your opinion
because I don't
like you very much.
So just don't talk
to me anymore. Thank you.
Oh, Josephine,
this came for you.
Oh, thank you.
Beth.
Merry Christmas, world.
Merry Christmas!
- Merry Christmas.
- Give me another orange.
- Jo, we've been up for hours.
- What have you been writing?
Oh, I got carried away
with our revenge play
last night, Poison.
No, no poison.
It's Christmas.
Won't be Christmas
without any presents.
- It's dreadful being poor.
- It's not fair.
How come some girls
have pretty things
and others have nothing?
We have Father, Mother
and each other.
We haven't got Father as
long as this war drags on.
I wish I had money
and plenty of servants,
so I never had to work.
Or you could be
a proper actress.
They aren't all fallen women.
- I can't be an actress.
- I have lots of wishes,
but my favorite one
is to be an artist in Paris
and do fine pictures and be
the best painter in the world.
That's what you want, Jo,
to be a famous writer?
Yes, but it sounds crass
when she says it.
- Why be ashamed?
- I'm not.
My wish is to have us
all be together
with Father and Mother.
- That's what I want.
- Beth is perfect.
- Amy.
- What about your music, huh?
I do that for us. I don't need
anyone else to hear it.
You must not limit yourself.
Mother proposed not having
presents this year
because men are suffering
in the Army.
We can't do much,
but we can make
our little sacrifices
and do it gladly.
Don't play mother
just because she's not home.
- Jo, that's so boyish.
- That's why I do it.
- I detest rude, unladylike girls.
- I hate affected little chits.
- Jo!
- My nose! My nose! Ow!
It's already no good!
Jo! Jo!
I know you don't care
what I think,
but you don't want your mother
to find you like this, do you?
We care what you think.
You're more family
than old Aunt March.
- Don't, Jo.
- Where is Marmee? I'm starving.
Goodness only knows. Some
poor creature came a-begging.
Your ma set straight off
to see what was needed.
I wish she could help others
at a time convenient to us.
Joanna and I
are very hungry.
- Dolls don't get hungry.
- I've rewritten the climax.
We need to set it to memory.
Amy, get the costumes.
I have made
the most divine crown,
and I painted my old shoes blue,
so she looks like a princess!
The melancholy piece
is pretty good.
Wait until
you see this new speech.
I don't see how you
write such splendid things.
- You're a regular Shakespeare.
- Not quite.
Miss Michelangelo, can you
rehearse the fainting scene?
- You're as stiff as a poker.
- I can't help it.
I never saw anyone faint.
I don't intend
to make myself
all black and blue.
If I can fall down easily,
I'll drop.
If I cannot, I shall fall
gracefully into a chair.
And I don't care if Hugo
comes at me with a pistol.
- Hannah?
- I'm not acting.
I didn't even say anything.
I knew what you were going
to say. I'm not acting.
I need both of you
to kneel right there.
- I need you to kneel.
- I don't want to.
This is supposed to be
our special scene.
- No one's gonna be looking at us.
- Smile.
- I don't want to.
- You have to.
I think Meg should be
the director.
So I think that
she'll need to kneel...
- But it's our scene.
- If you'll kneel and look...
Merry Christmas, girls.
- Marmee!
- Oh, merry Christmas!
I'm so glad to see you so happy.
How's your play?
Jo, you look tired. Were you up
again all night writing?
- Of course.
- Amy, come kiss me. Thank you.
Merry Christmas.
How are my girls?
- I'm so hungry.
- Look at this.
- I could eat a horse.
- Don't say that, Jo.
What?
What is it?
Not far from here lives
a poor young woman, Mrs. Hummel.
Her five children are in one bed
to keep from freezing,
and there's nothing to eat.
Will you give them
your breakfast
as a Christmas present?
Is this where you say
that Father would want us to?
Yes.
Thank you.
And thank you, Mr. Laurence,
for including me.
You're welcome.
Perhaps you could tutor
my grandson in manners,
as well as mathematics,
huh?
Oh, girls...
Be careful.
Watch yourselves.
Out here with no sleeves.
It is good angels come to us.
Hello. I'm back.
And have food and blankets.
And sweaters.
And we brought some medicine.
So these are my girls.
Say hello.
He is not well.
Girls, why don't you
unpack the food?
Would you like some?
You want one?
- Yeah, have it all.
- Why don't we get some firewood?
It's good, isn't it?
That's nice, huh?
Marmee, we don't need our toes.
I think I've lost one.
Has anyone else
lost their toe?
- That was amazing.
- I can't feel my feet.
- Is it fairies?
- Santa Claus.
- It's Aunt March.
- Mr. Laurence sent it.
- The Laurence boy's grandfather?
- Yes.
- Why?
- He saw you
giving your
Christmas breakfast away.
He wanted you
to enjoy the day.
I thought he was a mean old man.
It's so generous.
His grandson, Laurie,
put the idea into his head.
I know he did.
We should make friends with him.
Boys scare me, and that
big old house scares me.
Jenny Snow says
Mr. Laurence disowned his son
after he went off
with an Italian woman.
Now his grandson
is an orphan
and spends his time in that
house locked up with his tutor.
He's a very kind man
who lost his little girl
when she was only a child.
Now his son as well.
- His daughter died?
- So sad.
Doesn't Laurie
seem so romantic?
- He's half Italian.
- What do you know?
You've barely spoken
to him. Ow!
I'm not responsible
for this feast,
but I have got a surprise.
A letter from Father!
Don't I wish I could go?
Jo, we can't give up
our only brother.
It must be so disagreeable
to sleep in a tent.
Jo sits in back,
so we can't see her cry. Ow!
- What if I do?
- Will he be coming home?
He'll stay and work faithfully
as long as he can.
We won't ask
for him to come back
a minute sooner
than he can be spared.
"Give them all
my dear love and a kiss.
"Tell them I think of them
by day, pray for them by night
"and find my best comforts
in their affection at all times.
"A year seems a very long time
to wait before I see them.
"But remind them
that while we wait,
"we may all work,
so these hard days...
"need not be wasted.
"I know that they will
be loving children to you.
"Do their duty faithfully.
"Fight their enemies bravely.
And conquer themselves
so beautifully."
The Witch's Curse,
a play by Jo March.
Make it sweet
and swift and strong...
"That when I
come back to them..."
Spirit, answer now my song.
"...I may be...
fonder and prouder
than ever..."
"of my little women."
Brava!
Excuse me. Excuse me.
Excuse me.
Your stop, ma'am.
Oh, thank you.
She's gone? Why?
I don't know. She just left.
She didn't say
if she was coming back?
We didn't have
a heart-to-heart, professor.
Why are you just sitting there?
Please, go, go. Dust something.
And what about the girls?
She was the best teacher
they ever had.
I know.
It is so hard to go back
to work after such good times.
I wish it was Christmas
every day.
Or New Year's.
Wouldn't that be exciting?
We are a bunch
of ungrateful minxes.
Don't say
such despicable things.
I like strong words
that mean something.
I have to go back,
and I don't have any limes.
- Limes?
- Girls are trading pickled limes,
and I'm in debt.
I owe ever so many limes.
- Will this do?
- What'd you do that for?
- Meg, thank you.
- I know what it is
to want things
and feel less than other girls.
That and the drawings
will wipe out my debt.
- What drawings?
- Nothing.
I'm glad Mother
doesn't make me
go to school
with those girls.
Hurry. I'll be late.
Beth, after shopping,
I need you
to work through
the new sums and spelling.
- I'll check it when I get home.
- Oh, fine.
Bye.
Ooh!
- Josephine.
- Yes?
- Oh! Josephine.
- Yes? Here.
Is there a reason
you stopped reading Belsham?
I'm sorry.
I'll continue.
You mind yourself, deary.
Someday you'll need me
and you'll wish
you had behaved better.
Thank you, Aunt March,
for your employment
and your many kindnesses,
but I intend to make
my own way in the world.
Oh, well.
No. No one makes
their own way.
Not really.
Least of all, a woman.
You'll need to marry well.
- But you are not married.
- That's because I'm rich.
And I made sure
to keep hold of my money.
Unlike your father.
So the only way to be an
unmarried woman is to be rich?
- Yes.
- There are precious few ways
- for women to make money.
- That's not true.
You could run a cathouse.
Or go on the stage.
Practically the same thing.
Other than that,
you're right.
Precious few ways
for women.
- That's why you should heed me.
- So I can get married.
No. So you can live a better
life than your poor mother has.
- But Marmee loves her life.
- You don't know what she loves.
Your father cared more about
educating freedmen's children
than he did about caring
for his own family.
Yes, but he was right.
Well, it's possible
to be right and foolish.
Well, I don't think so.
Well, you're not paid
to think.
I know you don't care much
about marriage now.
Can't say I blame you.
But I intend to go
to Europe one more time
and I need a companion,
so how would you like to be
the person I take?
I'd like that
more than anything.
All right, then read.
And don't sneak around.
I don't like sneaks.
President Lincoln.
No, Father's fighting for him.
My father says
the war is a waste
and we should let
them keep their labor.
Susan, it is immoral.
Everyone benefited
from the system,
including you Marches.
Why should only
the South be punished?
Maybe we should
all be punished.
The Marches
love a cause.
Fine. Just do Mr. Davis.
- I don't know if I should.
- I'll wipe out your debt
and give you
five more limes besides.
...your spelling and, moreover,
your reading habit.
Miss March.
Sit down.
Sit down, Laurie.
Latin is a privilege.
Please,
you have to learn this.
I can't afford
to lose this position.
- Return to the Cicero...
- There's a girl out there.
- No, there is not.
- Yes, Mr. Brooke, there's a girl.
No, there is not.
I'll never get
to go home again.
- Oh, there is a girl.
- That's a girl.
Hello there. Are you hurt?
- I'm Amy.
- Hello, Amy. I'm Laurie.
I know. You brought my sister
back after the dance.
I would've never
have sprained my ankle.
I have lovely small feet,
the best in the family.
But I can never go home again
because I'm in such trouble.
Look.
Mr. Davis hit me.
Tell the servants I want this
painting purchased immediately!
- Amy! Are you in here?
- Meg! My hand. Look.
- Jo.
- What richness.
- It hurts so much.
- You ought to be
the happiest boy in the world.
A fellow can't live
on books alone.
- I could. What did you do?
- Nothing.
I did a drawing,
and then Mr. Davis hit me.
Oh, Christopher Columbus,
look at that.
That's my grandfather.
Are you scared of him?
I'm not scared of anyone.
He looks stern,
but my grandfather
was more handsome.
Jo, we do not
compare grandfathers.
You think
he's more handsome, eh?
Oh... No, actually,
you are very handsome.
- I didn't mean...
- I knew your mother's father.
You've got his spirit.
Oh, well, thank you, sir.
You are not to attend
that school anymore.
Good. That man
has always been an idiot.
- Jo will teach you.
- Me? I already teach Beth.
- You're a good teacher.
- Yes, women being taught at home
is more proper, I believe.
Only because schools
for women are poor.
Indeed. Quite right.
I wish all the girls
would leave
- and he would die.
- You did wrong.
- There will be consequences.
- I didn't even do anything.
- I just did a drawing.
- Thank you so much
- for taking care of Amy.
- Oh, yes, of course.
My girls have a way
of getting into mischief.
Well, so do I.
Then you'll run over
and we'll take care of you.
Come over whenever you'd like.
Invite Beth as well.
- Yes! Beth would adore the piano.
- Is she the quiet one?
Yes, that's our Beth.
Tell that little girl
to use our piano.
Jo, borrow whatever book
you'd like.
- Can I come look at paintings?
- Yes.
There's also
a lovely greenhouse.
We must go. Girls.
- Can you buy this painting?
- I'm going to take this one.
- If that's okay.
- I'll bring it back soon.
Thank you again.
Thank you for my hand!
- Thank you!
- Goodbye.
Oh, uh, Miss Meg?
You forgot your glove.
Well, back to work.
Back to work.
Order! Order.
Order. Order!
A new play written
by Miss Jo March
will appear
at the Barnville Theater
in the course of the next
few weeks that will surpass
anything ever seen before
on the American stage.
Starring
the greatest actress
from here to the Mississippi
River, Miss Meg March.
- Yes. There we go. Very good.
- Excellent. Bravo, bravo.
- Weekly report. Meg good, Jo bad.
- Mm-hm.
Beth very good.
And Amy sort of middling.
- Very well done, sirs.
- Excellent.
- Excellent, excellent.
- Bravo.
Mr. President and gentlemen,
I wish to propose the admission
of a new member.
One who would be
deeply, deeply grateful
and would add immensely
to the spirit of the club.
I propose...
Mr. Theodore Laurence!
- Absolutely not.
- No.
- What? Come, now. Let's have him.
- He's a real boy.
We don't want any boys.
- This is a club for ladies.
- Yes.
- I think we should do it.
- Why?
- Even if we're afraid, I say yes.
- It's Laurie.
- What? No.
- It'll change everything.
- All right, I call a vote.
- Put your hands up.
- Don't put your hand up.
Put your hand up. It's Laurie.
Fine. Aye.
There is no time
like the present...
Ladies, ladies, please, please.
This is my stratagem.
I deserve the blame.
Jo only gave in to it
after lots of teasing.
Yes. I merely wish to say
as a slight token
of my gratitude that I...
- Yes, yes.
- Go on.
As a means of promoting
friendly relations
between adjoining nations.
And thus, I propose
this set of keys
for a little post office I've
made in the forest by the pond.
Yes, four keys.
They're for you, darling.
- Meg, yes, yes. And for you.
- Oh, thank you very much.
This is for me. Without further
ado, thank you for your favor.
I will take my seat
as part of the club.
- Yes, well. Of course. Yes, yes.
- Bravo, bravo.
Welcome, Laurie.
- Three, four, five.
- You both got five.
- I asked the doctor.
- That's a draw, I think.
- It doesn't make sense.
- I can't believe it.
Hello.
Jo!
Daisy and Demi!
Can I have a hug?
Oh, you've gotten so big.
I wish you were here
to teach them.
I know. Well, I'm here now.
- So good to have you home.
- Take this off.
I think the
loneliness got to Beth,
though she ain't
said anything.
- Where is Beth?
- She's upstairs. Oh, my Jo.
We thought she was better, but
the fever'd weakened her heart.
Take this and find her
the best doctor you can.
You need this
to live in New York.
No, I'm not going back.
I'm using the rest
to take her to the sea
and get her strong.
When's Amy coming home?
- We didn't want to worry her.
- Does she not know?
Beth insisted
we not tell her
because she didn't want
to ruin Amy's trip.
Amy has always had a talent
for getting out
of the hard parts of life.
Jo, don't be angry
with your sister.
I can't seem to find anything.
Marmee, have you seen my glove?
When did you last see it?
Jo! Jo, where are you?
- I can't find my other glove.
- Take mine.
- We're going to be late.
- Where are you going?
You're not invited.
You're going
somewhere with Laurie.
- I know it.
- Yes, we are. Now stop bothering.
- You have the tickets?
- Yes. Hurry.
- You're going to the theater.
- Meg, please, can I come?
- Sorry, you weren't invited.
- You can't go.
Don't be a baby
and whine about it.
I've been shut up here.
I never get to go anywhere.
- Beth has her piano. I'm lonely.
- I can teach you chords.
I don't want chords.
I want to go to the theater.
I think you'd hate to poke in
where you're not wanted.
We already have to deal
with dull Mr. Brooke.
- I like him. He's kind.
- But I can pay for myself.
You will not come.
I'm sorry, my sweet,
but Jo is right.
- No! Please.
- Next time.
- Come, Meg. Stop petting her.
- Please, please, please!
Ugh, you'll be sorry
for this, Jo March!
- Amy!
- You will! You'll regret this!
Stop looking at me like that!
Oh, um...
- I loved every second of it.
- Ow! Jo!
- I thought the actress was... Oh!
- She was very, very good.
- Yes, she was really good.
- She was. She was very good.
Bye!
Oh, I love the theater.
Meg, you're a million times
better than she was.
Although she was
a terrific fainter.
I wonder how she managed
to turn so white.
That Mr. Brooke,
could he be any more obsequious?
I thought he was
very well-mannered.
Hold on. Let me
just get this idea down.
Beth, what's your
favorite eye color?
- Purple.
- Mr. Brooke has blue eyes
and an old soul, which is
more important than money.
Has anyone taken my novel?
- No.
- No. Why?
Amy, you've got it.
- No, I haven't.
- That's a lie.
I haven't got it, I don't know
where it is, and I don't care.
- Tell me, or I'll make you!
- Ahh!
- I burnt it up!
- Marmee!
I burnt your book. I told you
I'd make you pay, and I did!
All right, Jo! Jo! Jo!
Please get off her!
- Jo. Amy.
- Ahh! Ahh!
- Get her off!
- I hate you!
I'm sorry, Jo.
Amy.
It's just the only thing
you care about is your writing.
It's not as if
I could've hurt you
by ruining one of your dresses,
and I really did
want to hurt you.
I am the most sorry for it now.
I'm so sorry.
Oh, Jo...
don't let the sun go down
on your anger.
Forgive her.
Help each other.
And you begin again tomorrow.
She doesn't deserve
my forgiveness.
And I will hate her.
I will hate her forever!
Morning. Brisk and brilliant
out. Last day at the river.
- Get your ice skates.
- Let's go!
Jo, you promised me
I could come last time. Jo!
Is she going to be
like this forever?
It was a very hard loss
for her.
Is there nothing I can do?
Go after her.
Don't say anything
till Jo has got good-natured
with Laurie,
and then just say
some kind thing.
I'm sure
she'll be friends again.
Jo, wait!
I'm coming!
You said
I could come last time!
Jo, Laurie, wait!
I'm coming!
Wait!
Jo!
Stay near the edge.
- It's not safe in the middle.
- Got it.
Jo!
Jo, I'm coming!
Jo, let's go!
Uh...
Jo, wait!
Jo!
- Are you all right?
- Yes.
- Help! Help me!
- Amy. It's Amy.
- Come on. Come on, Jo.
- Ahh! Jo!
Ahh, Jo!
Jo, get a branch.
Get a branch.
- Amy.
- Jo!
- Amy. Amy.
- Ahh!
Help! I can't breathe!
Jo, help me pull. Amy,
grab the branch. Grab it, Amy.
I'm so sorry.
Oh, my sister, my sister.
She's asleep.
If she had died,
it would have been my fault.
She'll be fine.
The doctor said that he didn't
even think she'd catch cold.
What is wrong with me?
I've made so many resolutions,
and I've written sad notes,
and I've cried over my sins...
but it just
doesn't seem to help.
When I get in a passion,
I get so savage.
I could hurt anyone,
and I'd enjoy it.
You remind me of myself.
But you're never angry.
I'm angry nearly
every day of my life.
You are?
I am not patient by nature.
But with nearly
40 years of effort,
I'm learning to not let it
get the better of me.
Well, I'll do the same, then.
I hope you'll do a great deal
better than me.
There are some natures
too noble to curb
and too lofty to bend.
Jo.
Oh, Beth, my love. Oh!
- You didn't need to come.
- Oh, I never should have left.
Do you need anything? Here.
Take some water.
It's so good
to see your face.
We're going to the sea
to get you strong and well.
- The sea?
- Mm, I want you dancing
by the time
Amy gets back.
She's not cutting
her trip short, is she?
- No, no.
- Good.
Is there any news?
What does she say?
She writes
that Laurie is there.
I'm glad he's with her.
He won't respond
to any of my letters.
Do you miss him?
I miss everything.
I know.
Hurry up!
Meg's gonna be gone for a week.
- We're coming!
- Take the other carriage, Laurie.
Spy on Meg. Make sure
she doesn't fall in love.
- I will.
- It was nice of Annie
to invite me
to her debutante ball.
- Thank you for letting me go.
- Just be who you are.
And wear this to the ball.
It was mine when I was your age.
I've never understood
saving jewelry until marriage.
You should have something
that's just yours.
Pretty things
should be enjoyed.
Yes, pretty things
- Can I see it?
- Hannah!
I wish I could go
to the debutante ball.
Do you think this is a good
idea, her going away like this?
Girls have to
go into the world
and make up
their own minds about things.
- Don't forget about us.
- I won't, Jo. It's only a week.
- It's beautiful.
- It's not yours.
It would look good on me.
She needs to have
some decent shoes.
Thank you for the carriage,
Mr. Laurence.
- I don't know how to repay you.
- Nonsense, nonsense.
I said hi to the horses.
They're very nice.
Although
there is one thing.
It occurred to me today
that my daughter's piano
suffers from want of use.
Any of your girls
like to run over
and practice on it now and then?
Just to keep it in tune.
If they don't care to come,
why, then never mind.
Oh, sir,
they do care.
Very, very much.
You're the musical girl, huh?
I love it dearly.
And I'll come
if you are quite sure nobody
will hear me and be disturbed.
Not a soul, my dear.
- Miss you.
- Bye.
- Can I borrow your ribbons?
- No.
- Bye!
- Be good. Enjoy the ball.
- Bye. I'll be back soon.
- Don't go and get married.
Don't go fall in love.
- Come back right now.
- I love you.
- Right this second.
Whoa, there.
Oh, ha, thank you.
I'd be so excited about tonight.
- Of course.
- Oh, no, I don't actually...
What dress will you
wear tonight, Meg?
- I will wear this one.
- That one?
Can't you send home
for another?
- I haven't got another.
- Only the one?
- Oh, that's so funny.
- Not at all.
There's no need
in sending home, Daisy.
I'm going to
call you Daisy now.
I've got a sweet dress
laid away.
You'll wear it to please me,
won't you, Daisy?
- Um, if it's all right.
- Of course.
Everyone's in love
with you, Daisy.
- You have to keep my dress.
- I can't keep your dress.
- You have to. Please.
- No.
Everyone loves you in it.
Have fun, little Daisy.
Laurie. I didn't know
you were going to come.
Supposed to be
a surprise.
And what
a lovely surprise it is.
- Why are they calling you Daisy?
- It's their pet name for me.
Meg is a perfectly
good name.
It's just like playing a part
to be Daisy for a little while.
What would Jo say?
You wouldn't actually marry
one of these men, would you?
I might.
You'll get
a terrible headache tomorrow.
- Do you like how I look?
- No, I don't.
Why not?
I don't like fuss and feathers.
You're the rudest boy
I ever saw.
Please forgive me
and come dance.
I'm afraid it would be
too disagreeable for you.
I don't like your dress, but
I think you are just splendid.
- Really?
- Really.
I know it's silly,
but please don't tell Jo.
Let me have my fun tonight.
I'll be desperately good
for the rest of my life.
I'm sorry, John.
The silk was
the first real expense.
Ahem, $50, while a lot,
is not, I suppose,
too much for a dress
with all the notions
that are needed
to finish it these days.
It's not exactly
even a dress yet. It's...
It's just the fabric.
Oh.
I see.
I know you're angry,
John.
I don't mean to waste money,
but I can't resist
when I see Sallie buying
all she wants
and pitying me
because I don't.
I try to be contented,
but it is hard.
And I'm tired of being poor.
I was afraid of this.
I do my best, Meg.
Oh, John.
My dear, kind,
hardworking boy.
It was so ungrateful
and wicked.
How could I say it?
- Perhaps you meant it.
- No, I didn't.
We'll work out a way
to get you your coat as well,
and then won't we be grand,
the two of us?
I can't afford it,
my dear.
- John.
- I need to go to bed.
John.
And I really am very sorry
that you've had to do
without so many
beautiful things...
and that you're married
to someone
who can't give
them to you.
Hello, Amy.
I don't want to see you.
Amy, don't be mad at me.
I'm sorry for how I behaved.
- Have you been drinking?
- Why are you being so hard on me?
- It's 4 p.m.
- Someone has to do it.
When do you begin your
great work of art, Raphaella?
- Never.
- "Never"? What? Why?
I'm a failure.
Jo is in New York
being a writer,
and I'm a failure.
That's quite a statement
to make at 20.
Rome took all the vanity
out of me,
and Paris made me realize
I'd never be a genius,
so I'm giving up
all my foolish artistic hopes.
Why give up? You have
so much talent and energy.
Talent isn't genius.
And no amount of energy
can make it so.
I want to be great
or nothing.
And I will not be
some commonplace dauber,
and I don't intend
to try anymore.
What women are allowed into
the club of geniuses anyway?
- The Brontes?
- Hm.
- That's it?
- Yes, I think so.
And who always
declares genius?
- Men, I suppose.
- Cutting down the competition.
That's a very
complicated argument
to make me feel better.
Do you though?
Do you feel better?
I do think,
male or female,
- I am of middling talent.
- "Middling talent"?
Then may I ask
your last portrait be of me?
- All right.
- Now that you've given up
- your foolish artistic hopes...
- Mm-hm?
what are you gonna do
with your life?
Polish up all my other talents
and become
an ornament to society.
Mm, that's where Fred Vaughn
comes in, I suppose.
- Don't make fun.
- I said his name.
- You're not engaged, I hope.
- No.
But you will be if he goes down
properly on one knee?
Most likely, yes.
He's rich.
Richer than you, even.
I understand queens of society
can't get on without money,
although it does sound odd
from the mouth of one
of your mother's girls.
I've always known
I would marry rich.
- Why should I be ashamed?
- Nothing to be ashamed of,
as long as you love him.
I believe we have
some power over who we love.
It isn't something
that just happens to a person.
I think the poets
might disagree.
Well, I'm not a poet.
I'm just a woman.
And as a woman, there's no way
for me to make my own money.
Not enough to earn a living
or to support my family.
If I had my own money,
which I don't,
that money would belong
to my husband
the moment we got married.
If we had children,
they would be his, not mine.
They would be his property.
So don't sit there and tell me
that marriage isn't an economic
proposition, because it is.
It may not be for you,
but it most certainly is for me.
Oh, that's Fred.
Can you unbutton me, please?
Thank you.
How do I look?
Do I look all right?
You look beautiful.
You are beautiful.
Fred!
I've missed you.
This is Fred Vaughn
and his sister, Kate.
Of course you know
Mr. Brooke.
This is Meg, Amy,
Beth and Jo.
- So pleased to meet you.
- Oh, how elegant. Heh.
I'm Amy March.
You remember that name.
I'm gonna find you
one day in London.
Oh, I certainly will.
- Oh, that missed a boat.
- That's very kind.
- Well...
- Sorry.
I know
something you don't know.
Tell me this second.
Has Meg perhaps
mislaid a glove?
- Mr. Brooke has it!
- Yes.
- How do you know?
- I saw it.
- Where?
- In his pocket.
- All this time?
- Yes.
- Isn't it romantic?
- No, it's horrid.
- I thought you'd be pleased.
- At the idea of anybody
coming to take Meg away?
No, thank you.
You'll feel better when
somebody comes to take you away.
I'd like to see anyone try.
I would like to see
someone try as well.
"We could never have
loved the earth so well
"if we had had
no childhood in it,
"if it were not the earth
"where the same flowers come up
again every spring
"that we used to gather
with our tiny fingers.
"What novelty is worth
that sweet monotony
"where everything is known
and loved
because it is known?"
- How great is that?
- Mm.
I love to listen
to you read, Jo,
but I love it better when you
read stories you've written.
I don't have any new stories.
Why not?
Haven't written any.
You have a pencil and paper.
Sit here
and write me something.
I-I can't.
I don't think
I can anymore.
Why?
It's just...
no one even cares
to hear my stories anyway.
Write something for me.
You are a writer.
Even before anyone knew
or paid you.
I'm very sick, and you must
do what I say.
Do what Marmee
taught us to do.
Do it for someone else.
If you're walking to Vermont,
there's a Mrs. Sewall
in Keene, New Hampshire,
who will give you
room and board.
There you are.
You should go home.
I can take care of this.
No, I need to be here.
I've spent my whole life
ashamed of my country.
No offense meant,
but you should still be ashamed.
I know. I am.
- Hello, sir.
- Hello, ma'am.
Do you have sons in the Army?
Yes, ma'am.
I had four.
But two were killed,
and one is a prisoner.
I'm going to the other,
who's very sick
in a Washington hospital.
You've done a great deal
for your country, sir.
I'd go myself if I was any use,
but as I ain't, I give my boys.
Sir, I'll get you a blanket...
to keep you warm.
- Thank you. God bless.
- Bless you, sir.
Mrs. March. Telegram
from Washington, ma'am.
- Is Jo back yet from Aunt March?
- No, I haven't seen her yet.
- I've got it!
- Want another pair of shoes?
Thank you. I can't miss
the last train.
- Did you get Father's shirts?
- Yes, I did.
What can I do to help, Beth?
- Thank you for being here.
- Of course.
- You find the blanket?
- If I may be of more assistance,
please tell me.
I'll look in on the girls
without fail.
Do we need
more books or cloth?
- Thank you.
- I've always admired your husband.
I pray for a quick recovery.
I found these linens.
- Hannah, medicine?
- The medicine is packed.
- Oh, I'm sorry.
- I came to offer myself
as escort to your mother.
Mr. Laurence has commissions
in Washington.
It would give me satisfaction
to be of service to her there.
- Oh!
- Thank you.
Of course.
All right, while I'm gone,
Hannah is in charge.
Remember to check
on the Hummels.
It will be a difficult winter
for everyone.
Will this be enough
for the train?
Twenty-five dollars?
That's not like Aunt March
to be so generous.
I didn't go to her.
I couldn't bear to.
- Where'd you get the money?
- I only sold what was my own.
- Oh!
- Jo! Your hair!
- Your one beauty.
- You look like a boy.
Well, it doesn't affect the fate
of the nation, so don't wail.
Oh, I'm so proud
you're my daughter.
I was just crazy
to do something for Father.
It'll be good
for my vanity anyway.
- That could be nice.
- Never do that.
- Isn't what I wanted for her.
- Oh, Teddy.
Oh, Jo.
My girls,
I love you more than words can say.
Be good to each other.
Pray for Father's recovery.
And I'll be back as soon
as I can. Love you.
Jo.
What is it? Is it Father?
No.
It's my hair.
I would feel the same way.
I know you would.
Laurie, when are you
going back to your grandfather?
Very soon.
You've said that a dozen times
in the past month.
Short answers
save trouble.
Well, he is expecting you,
so why don't you do it?
- Natural depravity, I suppose.
- Natural indolence, you mean.
I'll only plague him if I go,
so I might as well stay
and plague you longer.
You can bear it. In fact,
I think it agrees with you.
Stop it. Stop.
- What are you doing?
- I'm looking at you.
I mean, what do you
intend to do?
- With life?
- Yes.
I've been writing an opera.
- I would be the central figure.
- That's a waste of time.
What would you have me do?
Go and work for your grandfather
and make something of yourself.
You're not playing fair.
Here.
That's... That's very good.
When did you do this one?
It was the day at the beach.
First time I met Fred.
That's right.
What's he doing?
He's in London on business.
He'll be back in a few weeks.
Don't marry him.
What?
Why?
Why? You know why.
No. No.
- Yes.
- No. Laurie.
- What?
- You're being mean.
- Stop it. Stop it.
- What? How am I being mean?
I have been second to Jo
my whole life in everything.
I will not be
the person you settle for
just because
you cannot have her.
I won't. I won't do it.
I won't. Not when I've spent
my entire life loving you.
I'm making a mold
of my foot for Laurie
to remind him
I have nice feet.
Mr. Brooke writes that Father is
still very weak but improving.
Mr. Brooke also says
that Mother
is the best nurse
a man could ask for.
I wish all the letters were
from Mother and not Mr. Brooke.
I'm grateful for any letters.
I think the purple is
very fitting for Mr. Laurence.
- Do you agree, Amy?
- Quite.
The design is very cunning.
I had to thank him
for allowing me
to play the piano
at his house all the time.
I'm going for groceries.
- Jo, can you get more firewood?
- Mm-hm.
You haven't been to
the Hummels. We should go.
We barely have enough
to feed ourselves.
I have to finish this story.
- Marmee said...
- Marmee told us to do lots,
but we can't
possibly do them all.
I always go myself. You haven't
kept up with your tasks.
- We do. We work.
- Don't worry. We'll find a time.
- But it's been weeks.
- We'll go soon.
My foot is stuck!
I can't get it out!
Stop it, Jo! I can't get it out!
I'm going to lose my foot. Ow!
Fine. I'll go myself.
Hello. For Mr. Laurence.
Oh! Here she comes.
Beth, look what
they got you!
A letter from
the old gentleman.
Open the note.
Oh, Beth, just look.
Jo, read the letter.
I cannot.
"Miss Beth March,
I have had
"many pairs of slippers
in my life,
"but I never had any
that suited me so well as yours.
"And they will always remind me
of the gentle giver.
"I like to pay my debts and hope
you will accept this gift.
Your grateful friend and
humble servant, James Laurence."
Oh, Beth!
So sweet. "Your humble servant."
- Isn't it beautiful?
- Look how shiny it is!
- Yes.
- It has gold that goes
- all the way around.
- All the way around!
- His handwriting is beautiful.
- It's got a little drawer here.
Sir, I wanted
to thank you for...
You remind me...
so much of my little girl.
Hm?
The piano is yours.
I should have given it
to you long ago.
Thank you.
My child...
you're burning.
The Hummels
are very sick.
She's resting.
How is she?
Is there anything I can do?
- What is it?
- Scarlet fever.
What's scarlet fever?
I visited the Hummels.
The baby has died.
Have you all
had it before?
- Meg and I have, but Amy hasn't.
- She'll have to be sent away.
I don't want
to be sent away.
- Aunt March can take her.
- I don't like Aunt March.
- It's for your own good, child.
- Should we send for Mother?
Now, we shouldn't
worry her.
I've never wished for money
more than now.
Listen, we'll nurse her
and she'll get better.
She will.
"The post office in the forest
was a capital little institution
"and flourished wonderfully,
"for many things
passed through it.
"Poetry and pickles,
music and gingerbread,
invitations, scoldings
and even puppies."
- It's all about us.
- It is.
- I love it.
- Mm, it's just a little story.
Nothing like
what you usually write.
- Think it's too boring?
- No, it's my favorite one.
- Really?
- Write me another.
- Yes, ma'am.
- Keep writing them.
- I will.
- Even when I'm not here.
- Don't say that. Don't say it.
- I have to tell you.
- No, you don't.
- I've had a very long time
to think about this, and...
- And I'm not afraid.
- No.
Nope.
It's like the tide going out.
It goes out slowly,
but it can't be stopped.
I'll stop it.
I stopped it before.
You will get better,
Father will get better,
and we'll all be
together soon, all right?
We...
We can't stop God's will.
Well, God hasn't met
my will yet.
What Jo wills
shall be done.
Amy.
Come here.
- Yes?
- Come, sit.
If you are very good, one day,
this ring will belong to you.
- Really?
- If you keep being
a proper young lady,
just see if it doesn't.
You are your family's
hope now.
Beth is sick,
Jo is a lost cause,
and I hear Meg
has had her head turned
by a penniless tutor, so...
it'll be up to you
to support them all.
And your indigent parents
in their old age.
So you must marry well.
Hm?
Save your family.
All right, that's, uh...
That's all I wanted
to say to you.
So you can go back
and do your little painting.
- Hello, Aunt March.
- Oh.
That Laurence boy
was just here.
- He was?
- What a disappointment
he's turned out to be.
Must be the Italian in him.
Uh, when...
When will he be back?
Mm, he's gone.
To London.
Why?
What do you need
to discuss with him?
I... I just told Fred Vaughn
I wouldn't marry him.
Meg.
I'll come home to
help with the children.
I just... I'm so worried
for Beth.
Stay. I asked for leave. I will
take care of the children.
Oh, John.
One other thing.
Send your fabric
to the dressmaker
as soon as possible.
- I can't.
- I don't want to hear a word.
I want you to have that dress.
My old coat will be fine
for the winter.
- John, I...
- It's all settled.
John, I really can't.
I sold the fabric
to Sallie.
You did?
I don't want you
to be unhappy.
I couldn't be.
John Brooke is my husband.
And I am his wife.
Oh!
Hannah! It's all right.
It's all right.
What do we do?
We should send for your mother.
- Marmee!
- Bless you.
She's worse. I didn't know
what else to do.
- Jo, how is she?
- My girls.
My sweet Beth.
Hannah, make a clear broth.
Jo, get ice.
We need to cool you.
Who's with Father?
John stayed with him.
We need to change
the linens.
We're going to move you,
sweet girl.
- Oh, look at her.
- That's it.
Hold on. It's okay.
I know.
Please fight.
Don't go quietly.
Fight.
Please, please, just fight
to the end and be loud,
and don't just
quietly go away, Beth.
Marmee?
Oh! Oh!
Jo.
Merry Christmas, Beth.
Popcorn. Make sure
it's in the middle.
- I know.
- You're doing the sides first.
The sides aren't spaced
for my popcorn.
I'm making a popcorn garland.
You're wasting decorations,
and they're not dangling right.
The sides are most important.
If you don't have the sides...
Here's another Christmas gift
for the March family.
- Oh, my God! Father!
- Father!
Father!
My little women.
How you've grown.
Oh, Beth.
Merry Christmas, my dear.
- Merry Christmas to each of you.
- Merry Christmas, Father.
Merry Christmas.
Oh, thank God.
- Thank God you're home.
- Thank God for you.
Now I can be angry
with you in person.
I can't believe
today is my wedding day.
Mm.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
Jo.
We can leave.
We can leave right now.
I can make money.
I'll sell stories.
I'll do anything.
I'll cook. I'll clean.
I'll work in a factory.
I can make a life for us.
- Jo...
- And you should be an actress,
and you should have a life
on the stage.
Let's just run away together.
- I want to get married.
- Oh, why?
Because I love him.
You will be bored of him
in two years,
and we will be
interesting forever.
Just because my dreams
are different than yours
doesn't mean
they're unimportant.
I want a home.
And a family. And I'm willing
to work and struggle.
But I want to do it
with John.
I just hate
that you're leaving me.
Don't leave.
Oh, Jo.
I'm not leaving you.
And besides...
one day,
it will be your turn.
I'd rather be a free spinster
and paddle my own canoe.
I would.
Can't believe childhood is over.
It was going to end
one way or another.
And what a happy end.
What excessive promises...
giving yourself away
to get the other.
What a gift.
Always given before is known
the cost or the reward.
I pronounce you
man and wife.
You may kiss
the bride.
Oh, don't have to make a fuss.
You don't need
to see me to the carriage.
Oh, I'm happy to.
I hope you will be
happy now...
that you've ruined your life
the same way your mother did
by marrying your father.
My dear sister,
you're too kind.
And thank you
for today's festivities.
You're most welcome.
Thank you, Aunt March.
Oh, I don't like
to be, uh, kissed.
- Oh, I'm sorry.
- Well, you will be sorry
when you've tried love in a
cottage and found it a failure.
It can't be worse than
some people find in big houses.
Oh, I quite understand
your meaning, missus.
I don't miss a thing.
We know this.
And you're not
entirely wrong.
I may not always be right,
but I'm never wrong.
Oh, and here is the only
sane member of the family.
I really can't take
any more of this.
- I know.
- You can imagine.
Marmee! Marmee!
Marmee, Marmee, Marmee!
- What?
- Aunt March is going to Europe.
Oh, and she wants me
to go with her! Ha, ha!
That's wonderful!
Now I know why I spent
all those boring hours
reading to her.
No, no,
she wants me to go.
As her companion.
- Europe, with you?
- Yes, she wants me
to work on my art
and my French, of course.
You don't really
like French though, do you?
That's wonderful, Amy.
- Father! I'm going to Europe!
- Oh, ha, ha!
Meg married.
Amy off to Europe.
And now that you're a graduate,
you'll be off on a long holiday.
I'm just not good like Beth,
so I'm angry and restless.
You don't have
to stay here, Jo.
Why? Should we run off
and join a pirate ship?
- No. No.
- It's no use, Jo.
- Don't.
- We gotta have it out.
- No.
- I have loved you
ever since I've known you.
I couldn't help it.
I tried to show
and you wouldn't let me.
- No.
- But I must make you hear now
and give me an answer because
I cannot go on like this!
- Please don't.
- I gave up billiards.
I gave up everything you
didn't like. I'm happy I did.
It's fine, and I waited, and
I never complained because I...
You know, I figured
you'd love me, Jo.
And I realize
I'm not half good enough
- and I'm not this great man...
- No! Yes, you are.
You're a great deal
too good for me.
I'm so grateful to you, and I'm
so proud of you, and I just...
I don't see why I can't
love you as you want me to.
I don't know why.
You can't?
No. I can't.
I can't change
how I feel, and...
it would be a lie
to say I do when I don't.
I'm so sorry, Teddy.
I'm so sorry,
but I just can't help it.
I can't love anyone else, Jo.
I only love you.
It would be a disaster
if we married.
- It wouldn't be.
- We'd be miserable.
- I'd be a perfect saint.
- I can't! I can't!
I've tried
and failed. I can't.
Why does everyone
expect it?
Your family
and my grandpa expect it.
Why are you saying this?
Say yes.
- Let's be happy together, Jo!
- I can't say yes truly,
so I'm not going
to say it at all.
And you'll see that
I'm right eventually,
and you'll thank me for it.
I'd rather hang myself
than realize this.
- Teddy.
- I would rather be dead.
Teddy, don't say that.
Teddy.
Listen, you'll find
some lovely, accomplished girl
who will love you
and adore you.
She's gonna make
a fine mistress
for your fine house,
but I wouldn't.
- Yes, you would, Jo.
- Look at me.
I'm homely, I'm awkward,
and I'm odd.
- I love you, Jo.
- And you'd be ashamed of me.
- And we would quarrel
because we can't help it
even now.
I'd hate elegant society,
you'd hate my scribbling,
and we would be unhappy.
And we'd wish
we hadn't done it,
and everything
will be horrid.
Is there anything more?
- No, nothing more.
- All right.
Except that...
Teddy, I don't believe
I will ever marry.
I'm happy as I am,
and I love my liberty
too well
to be in any hurry
to give it up.
- I think you're wrong.
- No.
I think you will marry.
You'll find someone
and love them.
You will live
and die for them.
That's your way,
and you will.
And I'll watch.
Oh. I don't want
to disturb your writing.
I don't do that anymore.
It didn't save her.
You're much too
lonely here, Jo.
Wouldn't you like
to go back to New York?
What about your friend
Friedrich?
- Wasn't that his name?
- No.
I ruined our friendship
with my temper,
just as
I ruin everything.
I'm sure I'll never
see him again.
I doubt that a sincere friend
would be deterred.
I wish that were true.
If I was a girl in a book,
this would all be so easy.
Just give up
the world happily.
Laurie's returning, you know.
- Oh, he is?
- Mm.
There was a letter from Amy.
She's coming home.
She's devastated about Beth.
Aunt March is very ill,
so Laurie will accompany them.
- That's good of him.
- Mm.
- What is it?
- I don't know.
I've always been quite
content with my family.
Don't understand it.
Perhaps, um...
Perhaps I...
was too quick
in turning him down.
Laurie.
Do you love him?
If he asked me again,
I think I would say yes.
Do you think
he'll ask me again?
But do you love him?
I care more to be loved.
I want to be loved.
That is not the same
as loving.
I know.
You know, I just...
I just feel...
I just feel like...
women, they...
They have minds
and they have souls,
as well as just hearts.
And they've got ambition
and they've got talent,
as well as just beauty.
And I'm so sick of
people saying
that love is just
all a woman is fit for.
I'm so sick of it.
But I'm... I'm so lonely.
Couldn't let you travel alone
with Aunt March being so sick.
Even if you despise me.
I don't despise you, Laurie.
Beth was the best of us.
I'm not marrying Fred.
- I heard about that.
- And you are under no obligation
to say anything
or do anything.
I just didn't love him
as I should.
We don't need to talk about it.
We don't need to say anything.
My dear Teddy,
I miss you more
than I can express.
I used to think that the
worst fate was to be a wife.
I was young and stupid.
But now I have changed.
The worst fate is to live
my life without you in it.
I was wrong to turn you down
and to run away to New York.
Oysters!
Lobsters!
Jo.
Jo. Jo.
Wake up.
- Teddy! Oh, you're back.
- Are you glad to see me, then?
Yes.
Oh, I was worried.
Mm. Here, come sit.
How's Amy?
Did she bother you
all the way from Europe
with her preening?
Yes, but I like that.
- Where is she now?
- Your mother has her at Meg's.
- We stopped on the way.
- Oh.
There was no getting my wife
out of their clutches.
Your what?
I've done it now.
It was meant to be
a surprise.
We were engaged
and were hoping to wait,
but that is to say that
now we are man and wife.
You and Amy?
Yes.
Are you in love?
I want to say one thing
and then put it away forever.
I've always loved you.
But the love I feel for Amy,
it's different.
And I think...
you were right about this.
I think we would've killed
each other.
Yes.
I think it was meant this way.
Oh, Teddy.
You're the only one that ever
calls me that, Jo. "Teddy."
What does Amy call you?
"My lord."
That sounds like her.
Well, you look
deserving of it.
Could we still
be friends, Jo, please?
Of course, my boy. Always.
She's a painter.
Are you excited?
- Laurie told you?
- Yes, yes.
Amy, I'm so happy for you.
This... This was meant to be.
Oh, I'm so relieved.
Thank you.
I wanted to write, Jo.
I wanted to write.
I wanted to explain, but
everything was happening so fast
and I was worried
you'd be angry at me.
- No. No.
- No, you're not angry at me?
Life is too short
to be angry at one's sisters.
- I really miss her.
- I know.
Thank you.
Mr. Laurence.
Jo. Heh.
Oh, Jo.
I couldn't bring
myself to, uh...
The house doesn't seem right
without her, and...
Couldn't go in,
knowing she wouldn't be there.
I know I'm not half
so good as my sister,
but you know I'll be a friend
to lean on, if you'll let me.
All right.
Dear Mr. Dashwood,
enclosed are
the first few chapters
of a piece
I've only begun working on.
It could suit as a story
for young people,
but I think it is
probably quite boring.
However, I'm sending it to you
just in case
it has something of value,
though I doubt it.
Jo March.
I thought she hated me.
She could still hate you
and leave you the house.
What about you and John?
We can't manage a grand house
like this. It's too big.
I should sell it,
but I'd love to do something
that would really make
Aunt March turn in her grave.
- I wouldn't mind that.
- A nice turning.
Just a rotation,
nothing terrible.
What will you do?
I'd like to open a school.
We never had
a proper school.
Now there are
women's colleges opening.
There should be a school.
For Daisy.
And what will Demi do?
I'll open a school
for boys and girls both.
What about writing?
- What about it?
- What are you working on?
I started something, but
I don't think it's very good.
- Everyone likes what you write.
- No, they don't.
I do.
Well, it's just
about our little life.
So?
Well, who will be interested
in a story
of domestic struggles
and joys?
It doesn't have
any real importance.
Maybe it doesn't
seem important
because people
don't write about them.
No, writing doesn't confer
importance. It reflects it.
I don't think so.
Writing them will
make them more important.
- When did you become so wise?
- Hm-mm. I always have been.
You were just too busy
noticing my faults.
Which were never
there, of course.
Dear Miss March,
I read the chapters you sent
and I have to agree,
they aren't very promising.
But, please,
send more stories
of the scandalous variety,
if you have any.
Or, shall I say,
your friend can.
My apologies for the joke.
I couldn't help it.
Jo, come down!
Coming!
I'm starving.
Oh, uh, Jo,
you might wanna wait because...
I'm famished.
But, Jo, dear,
you have a guest.
Mm. I don't know anyone.
I'm sorry to intrude,
but...
It's you.
Oh, uh...
Hello.
I'm Josephine March.
- I'm Jo.
- Josephine, is that you?
Welcome! Welcome.
This is Kitty and Minnie.
And I see that you have
already met our professor.
And he's
a very accomplished man.
And your mother says
that you are a writer.
I keep a diary, you know.
We have a lot of
interesting people here,
intellectuals
and Europeans...
Jo, I hope it is all right. I
got your address from Ms. Kirke.
- Who's this? Who are you?
- I'm sorry to intrude.
I was close by,
and I thought I'd...
- But I'll be going.
- No, no.
Please stay.
We have more than enough room.
- Can someone tell me who this is?
- Shh.
I don't want to be a burden.
You're not a burden
at all.
- Yes, of course. Please.
- I'm Laurie. Who are you?
I'm Friedrich Bhaer.
We were at the same
boardinghouse in New York.
Oh, Jo,
he's very handsome.
Do you intend
to stay in New York?
No. I've been offered
a professorship in California.
And, as I have
nothing keeping me here,
I thought
I might go west.
It is new there,
and they are
less particular
about immigrants.
Perhaps I should go west.
You're not an immigrant,
so perhaps you should stay home.
I'm going!
- Jo!
- Joseph, not Josephine.
I know Joseph.
Pretty well, actually.
Oh, wow!
This is a beautiful
instrument.
Which one of you plays?
Oh, it was
my sister Beth.
We all play a little, but...
But none
so well as her.
It is very hard to lose
a sister.
I'm sorry.
- Do you play?
- Yes. I do.
It would make us so happy
if you'd play now.
She wouldn't want
the piano to sit silent.
I don't wish to offend.
Not in the least.
- It was so lovely to meet you.
- Lovely to meet you. Goodbye.
It was a real pleasure,
Mr. Bhaer.
- Bye, Laurie.
- Goodbye.
- Thank you for everything.
- Lovely to have you.
If you ever come to California,
I would love to see you.
I don't know that I will,
but thank you.
Well, goodbye.
Goodbye.
What?
Why are you all
looking at me like that?
What a wonderful man.
I hope he comes back.
He would make
a terrific friend for me.
- Father, he wasn't here for you!
- No?
- Jo, you love him.
- What? No, no, I don't.
Yes, you do! I am half
as smart as you,
but I can see it
so plainly. You love him.
- Doesn't she?
- Good instinct. You love him.
I have never seen you so happy.
What else is love?
You need to go after him.
Prepare the horses.
- We can catch him.
- I'm coming too.
- No, I'm not going.
- Yes, you are.
- Amy is right.
- Exactly!
Never thought
I'd prepare a carriage
to help Jo March chase a man,
but I like it.
- He's moving to California.
- That was fiction!
He was practically begging
for a reason to stay.
- But it's raining outside.
- That doesn't matter.
- Come with me. I need to fix you.
- Jo!
Laurie, will you
stop standing there
and go get the horses ready?
Thank you.
You never ask about my mother,
even when you know
I've seen her.
I assume
she's still alive.
But I ask
after your mother.
And I have no idea why.
You're willfully
missing the point.
That's true.
What do they want?
I have no idea.
Are you publishing this?
What happens
to the "little women"?
Tell me you have
the rest of this book.
What?
I'm just trying
to fix this hair.
Stop, stop, stop.
Stop the carriage.
- Stop!
- Stop the carriage!
Stop. All right, Go. Out. Out.
Go. Go, go, go.
- Go!
- Jo, your hair!
Kiss him with love!
Frankly, I don't see why
she didn't marry the neighbor.
Well, because the neighbor
marries her sister.
Right, right.
Of course.
So who does she marry?
No one. She doesn't marry
either of them.
No.
No! No, no,
that won't work at all.
She says the whole book
she doesn't want to marry.
Who cares?
Girls want to see women married,
not consistent.
No, it isn't
the right ending.
The right ending
is the one that sells.
Trust me. If you decide
to end your delightful book
with your heroine a spinster,
no one will buy it.
It won't be worth printing.
I suppose marriage
has always been
an economic proposition,
even in fiction.
- It's romance.
- Heh, heh, it's mercenary.
- Just end it that way, will you?
- Heh, fine.
- Go!
- Jo, your hair!
Kiss him with love!
Go!
- You look so beautiful!
- Go, Jo!
Jo!
I... I don't want you to leave.
I want you to stay.
- You do?
- Yes.
I would never leave
if you wish me to stay.
- No, I want you to stay.
- I have nothing to give you.
It doesn't matter.
My hands are empty.
They're not empty.
I love it. It's romantic.
It's very moving.
That's very emotional.
- Well, thank you.
- We could call the chapter...
"Under the Umbrella."
- That's good.
- Perfect.
Now, there's the question
of the contract.
I'm prepared to give you
5 percent of the royalties.
So I get 5 percent
of the profit.
Five percent of the net profits,
after I recoup.
Huh. Well, what about
a payment up front?
I'm the one taking the risk
in printing this book.
Yes, but it's my book.
And if it does well,
we'll both make money.
If not,
I can stay in business.
Oh, so I get nothing
if it fails.
No, I'll give you $500 right now
to buy out the copyright.
- The copyright?
- That's the right for reprinting,
that sort of thing. Sequels,
characters for other stories.
Might that
be worth something?
Well, only if it's a success.
I see. It seems like something
I would want to own, no?
Didn't you say your family
needed the money immediately?
Yes, they do, which is why
I wanted up-front payment.
No. It's too risky. I'll only
pay for the copyright.
You keep your $500,
and I'll keep the copyright.
Also, I want 10 percent
of royalties.
Five point five percent.
That's very generous.
- Nine percent.
- Six percent, and that's it.
Mr. Dashwood, if I'm going
to sell my heroine
into marriage for money,
I might as well get some of it.
Six point six percent.
- Done.
- And you don't need to decide
- about the copyright right now.
- No, I've decided.
I want to own my own book.
Where is she?
She's here, everyone!
Come on!
Now, see if you can make a B.
Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org
Watch Movies, TV Series & Live Sports
www.admitme.app