♪ Now is the month of maying
when merry lads are playing ♪
♪ With a laugh we go around to merry, merry,
merry sound of the tabor and the pipe ♪
♪ The tabor and the pipe,
with a laugh we go around ♪
♪ To the merry, merry, merry sound of the
tabor and the pipe, the tabor and the pipe. ♪
My, my, my.
- Oh, good afternoon Miss Morrison.
- How you do Mrs. Perkins?
Nice and pretty all this, isn't it?
That one little Mary dancing over there,
the one in the blue dress. Cute, isn't she?
- Yes.
- I was queen of the May once..
Don't look it now, do I?
Kip...
You mind if I sit here beside you?
Oh, of course not
Miss Morrison, I'd be very glad.
Hardly expected to find you
alone on a day like today.
No? Well I guess a fellow
likes to be alone sometimes.
- Where's Barbara?
- I don't know.
- Somewhere around I guess.
- You guess?
- You and she haven't quarreled, have you?
- Oh, no.
No, nothing like that.
There's one of those
New York singing teachers in town and...
she's been having auditions.
- Sort of takes up most of her time.
- She didn't tell me about it.
Yeah, this fellow says that if she went to New
York and had her voice trained he could...
He could make her an
opera star in about seven years.
You know, a career, success and all that.
- She won't do it.
- I think she will.
You see, her folks
aren't standing in her way.
Just me.
I wouldn't worry too
much about it if I were you Kip.
- It'll all work out, you know.
- Thank you, Miss Morrison.
- Goodbye.
- Bye.
- Well, here we are.
- Oh, it was such a beautiful drive.
Oh, you enjoyed it, fine, I'm so glad.
- There.
- Hello Barbara.
- Hello Miss Morrison.
- I was wondering where you were.
Well I, oh
Miss Morrison, this is Mr. Bulliet.
- How do you do?
- Miss Morrison.
I've missed you these last few days.
When you coming over to see me?
Very soon, I've lots of things to
tell you, I may be going to New York.
Oh, how exciting.
Miss Roberts has an
extraordinarily promising voice.
We're going to try to make a star out of her.
Oh, that is exciting.
- You must tell me all about it child.
- Later this afternoon?
- Yes, I'll be home all day, you stop by.
- Thank you.
- Good day, Mr. Bulliet...
- Yes, good day Miss Morrison.
Good day.
Who was that?
Miss Morrison? Oh, she's a
darling, she lives next door to us.
Nobody really knows anything about her.
Her cupboard is rattling with skeletons, eh?
Not really, she's a very
sweet, sheltered old lady.
Well, I've be leaving Mr. Bulliet.
Thanks so much for the drive.
That's quite all right
my dear, glad to have you.
Morning.
There you are, I was
wondering what had happened to you.
I only walked as far as
the maypole on the green.
You haven't made yourself
tired walking all that way?
No, no, no.
- Of course not.
- I'll make you some nice, hot tea.
You shouldn't have gone, you know, not today.
May day seems almost
the same as any other day...
- sometimes.
- Yes, yes.
I'll get the tea.
♪ Do you remember the day... ♪
♪ When we were happy in may? ♪
♪ My dear ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ Sweetheart, sweetheart, sweetheart ♪
♪ Though our paths may sever ♪
♪ To life's last faint Ember ♪
♪ Will you remember? ♪
I've heard enough,
I don't want to talk about it anymore.
But Kip, you don't understand,
you just Ben pig-headed.
All I know is that I can offer you a
home and my love, like keep in comfort.,
That's not good enough for you, I'm sorry.
And I'll be as pig
headed as I darn well choose.
- I have the right to a career.
- Sure, you got a right to a career.
And I got a right to a home and wife
but that can go hang itself, can't it?
All right.
Go ahead and have your career.
See how far it gets you, I'm through.
Well, I'm through too
and I never want to see you again.
I, I don't want to see
you again either, goodbye.
Goodbye.
Barbara.
Oh...
I think I'm going to cry, you mind?
Oh, there, there, child.
It really isn't as terrible
as it seems, you know.
There...
But I was right, wasn't I? I was right.
You mean you never want to see him again?
No, I never meant that.
But I'm right about
going to New York, aren't I?
Why, I regret it all my life if I didn't.
That's what he won't
see, why won't he see it?
How can he be so selfish?
Perhaps it's because he loves you child.
- Couldn't love me and talk to me like that.
- Oh, I think he could.
If losing you meant
losing everything else too.
Oh, it isn't that. It's just selfishness.
He doesn't want me even to have a chance.
Can you understand Miss Morrison?
I want to try, that's all.
I just want the chance to become a famous singer
like, like Tetrazzini or Jenny Lind or...
or Marcia Mornay.
Yes...
Yes, I can understand.
- But I can understand other things too.
- What other things?
I've never talked to you
about myself, have I child?
No I...
I never talk to anyone usually, but...
I'm going to talk to you about myself now.
You see...
I was Marcia Mornay.
You...
Yes...
Many, many years ago.
I was very young.
It's Paris...
In the court of Louis Napoleon...
Oh Nicolai, I'm beginning to feel nervous.
- For no reason.
- For every reason, I'm frightened of kings.
- Louis Napoleon is an emperor.
- Same thing.
Not at all, kings descend from kings.
Louis Napoleon descended from
little corporals, there is a difference.
- Oh, you see, I'm still nervous.
- You mistrust my judgment?
Oh Nicolai.
I present my singers at court...
when they are fit to be presented
at court, neither before or later.
You're walking too fast.
- It's undignified.
- I feel undignified.
Getting sticks.
Now, what do I do when I'm
presented to the emperor?
- Curtsy.
- Nothing else?
- You mistrust my sense of etiquette too?
- No Nicolai.
Mademoiselle Mornay and monsieur Nazaroff.
After hearing you at
the opera the other night...
we're all impatient to hear
you sing again mademoiselle.
Mademoiselle Mornay is
deeply honored your majesty.
Would mademoiselle care to
rest herself a few moments...
- after her journey from the theater?
- Oh, thank you your majesty.
Shall we waltz?
I do anything wrong?
Curtsy was a little
stiff, only the empress noticed it.
- Oh, I feel much better now, thank you.
- Naturally.
So that's his latest protegee or
is protegee quite the right word?
- There is another.
- I don't envy her.
- I hear he drives his singers unmercifully.
- Oh no, not all the time.
He can be very human.
- What?
- Yes?
So I hear.
You see that gentleman
a bubble with gaiety over there?
That is Trentini.
The great composer? Oh, Nicolai.
Sounded almost naive.
Now, if Trentini wrote an opera
for you, you would become immortal.
Oh but, do you think he
would write an opera for me?
No, not without persuasion.
- Mademoiselle Mornay.
- See that you sing well.
♪ Nous venions de voir Le taurreau,
trois garçon, trois fillettes... ♪
♪ Sur la pelouse il faisait beau
et nous dansions un boléro... ♪
♪ Au son des castagnettes. ♪
♪ Dites-moi matin, Si j'ai bonne mine ♪
♪ Dites-moi, Ce matin,
vous me trouvez la taille fine? ♪
♪ Vous me trouvez la taille fine? ♪
♪ Les filles de Cadix aiment assez cela. ♪
♪ Les filles de Cadix aiment assez cela ♪
Les filles de Cadix aiment assez cela. ♪
♪ Et nous dansions un boléro,
Un soir c'était dimanche ♪
♪ Vers nous s'en vint un hidalgo,
Cousu d'or, la plume Au chapeau, ♪
♪ Et Le poing sur la hanche: ♪
♪ Si Tu veux, Cet or est à toi ♪
♪ Passez votre chemin, beau sire... ♪
♪ Les filles de Cadix aiment assez cela ♪
♪ Les filles de Cadix aiment assez cela. ♪
♪ Tous ces fiers enfants de la Gaule,
allaient sans trêve et sans repos ♪
♪ Avec leur fusil sur I'épaule,
courage Au cœur et sac Au dos ♪
♪ La gloire était leur nourriture
Ils étaient sans pain, sans souliers ♪
♪ La nuit, ils couchaient sur la
dure avec leur sac pour oreiller ♪
♪ Le régiment de Sambre et Meuse
marchait toujours Au cri de Liberté ♪
♪ Cherchant la route glorieuse
qui I'a conduit à lhimmortalité ♪
♪ Le régiment de Sambre et Meuse
marchait toujours Au cri de Liberté ♪
♪ Cherchant la route glorieuse
qui I'a conduit à lhimmortalité ♪
♪ Le régiment de Sambre et Meuse
marchait toujours Au cri de Liberté ♪
♪ Cherchant la route glorieuse
qui I'a conduit à lhimmortalité ♪
♪ Le régiment de Sambre et Meuse
marchait toujours Au cri de Liberté ♪
♪ Cherchant la route glorieuse
qui I'a conduit à lhimmortalité ♪
If I may pay you a sincere
compliment mademoiselle Mornay...
you are the first singer I've met in years...
that did not open the conversation by
asking me to write an opera for her.
Thank you very much.
You know, I'm afraid I
must claim credit for that.
It was I who told
mademoiselle Mornay you had retired.
- You did what?
- So Patellli told me.
- And who told Patellli?
- You mean it's not true?
It is not, I haven't the
slightest intention of retiring.
Oh, a relief.
- When did Patellli tell you this?
- Oh, let me see, I...
I've gone to him to commission an opera for
Mlle. Mornay, it must be nearly a week ago.
- So you admire Patellli's music, eh?
- I think it will live.
- So will mine.
- Oh longer, far longer sir.
But...
when genius is hard to approach, one
is forced to approach Patellli instead.
Quite.
- Is he writing this opera?
- So he gave Mlle. Mornay to understand.
Treacle, he writes treacle.
Mlle. Mornay needs a composer to
serve that voice, not a ballad scribbler.
- Mlle. Mornay, another compliment.
- Oh, thank you signore Trentini.
You want quality, inspiration...
not tum tum tum, tum tum tum.
You need a, a Schubert a Mozart a...
A Trentini?
- You are too kind.
- I give honor where honor is due sir.
But then, don't give it to Patellli.
And deprive mademoiselle of her opera?
Other composers write operas beside Patellli.
But not by request, for example you, sir.
I have not yet been requested.
Then on behalf of Mlle. Mornay,
may I ask you to write her an opera?
I would be honored.
Thank you signore.
Oh, Nicolai, Nicolai, I'm so happy.
Ellen, I'm to have an opera written
specially for me by the great Trentini.
- Oh mademoiselle, how splendid.
- It isn't wonderful? An opera by Trentini.
By Trentini...
Oh Nicolai, I can never, never thank you.
You, you've been so kind, so patient, so...
so wonderful, I can hardly believe it's true.
Oh, I can't believe it's really true.
It...
it'll gradually penetrate.
Oh, you remember when I met
you that day in New York?
How you told me if I obeyed
you, you'd make me famous.
And how I laughed because I
didn't believe anyone could.
Oh Nicolai, Oh, Nicolai...
How could you know then
what I was going to become?
I was so plain and gawky
and I know I croaked when I sang.
Marcia...
- Come here.
- Yes, Nicolai.
- Do you realize what tonight means?
- Yes, I think so.
- Means my share of the work is over.
- Oh no, Nicolai...
You've worked, you always obeyed me.
You've let nothing stand between you and
your career, you deserve your success.
During all our association,
I've never once come
into your private life, have I?
- No.
- I've never demanded anything of you, have I?
No, you've been very sweet Nicolai.
You've been half afraid I would, haven't you?
Now and then I've seen it in your eyes...
wondering when the
lightning was going to strike.
- No Nicolai.
- You were right to.
After all, I've trained other
women and demanded things of them.
You knew all about it.
I owe all of my
success to you, I always will.
If there, is any way I can repay you?
There is.
Poor Marcia, I'm asking a very high price.
I want to marry you.
- Oh Nicolai...
- You've only to say yes or no.
I know you don't love me, now...
but I love you.
Well? Which is it?
Oh, I should be very happy to marry you.
Oh Ellen, I was worried, it's quite late.
Yes, I know. I'll be
along in just a few minutes.
Ellen is right, you've 3
hours' sleep to make up young lady.
Ellen, close the curtains and don't
wake mademoiselle till midday tomorrow.
- Oui monsieur...
- Oh, not as late as that.
You're singing tomorrow night.
By Jove, it's tonight now.
What sort of voice do you think you'll be in?
After the alarums and
excursions of this evening.
I may not wake you till
just before the performance.
- Good night.
Good night.
Dear Nicolai.
- Oh Ellen?
- Oui mademoiselle?
Ellen, I'm going to be married.
Why, that's very nice Mlle,
I'm sure. May I congratulate you?
Thank you.
- Aren't you surprised?
- No mademoiselle, I rather expected it.
- I hope you'll be happy.
- Thank you.
It's really a tremendous
compliment, isn't it?
I mean, he's such a great man.
Of course, I'm a little
confused about everything.
So many things have happened at once.
Singing for an emperor and having an opera
written specially for me and now this. I...
I sort of can't make anything seem real.
I'd just go to sleep and forget all about it
till tomorrow, otherwise you'll be tired.
But I'm not the least bit sleepy, I...
I feel restless and, and unsettled and...
Oh I...
I want to do something to
bring me back to my senses.
- Ellen...
- Oui mademoiselle?
- Give me a dress.
- Whatever for?
I'm going out for a ride, just a little ways.
I must get some fresh air to make me wake up.
- What sort of a dress?
- The brown moire.
Ah, oui, oui.
But mademoiselle, do you think
monsieur Nazaroff would approve?
Oh, but he needn't know,
I only be gone a few minutes.
He'd be furious if he finds out.
- Oh, you won't tell him Ellen darling.
- What happens if he finds out for himself?
Oh mademoiselle, there's no sense
in what you're doing, it's, it's silly.
Yes, I know, I know but I keep telling
you, I'm only going a little way.
I only be gone 10 minutes at the most.
I simply must get away by
myself Ellen, just for once in my life.
- Driver.
- Where to madame?
Just keep driving
until I tell you to turn around.
- Just anywhere?
- Yes, just anywhere.
It shall be so, giddup Jemmy.
- Have you had a quarrel?
- What?
He'll have cooled down
by the time you get back.
Oh yes, yes, I hope so.
- Oh driver, driver...
- Had enough?
- Yes, yes. Take me back home please.
- It shall be so.
Jemmy, Jemmy, come back.
Don't worry ma'am,
don't worry, don't go away.
I'll be back in a minute.
Jemmy, come back do you.
I'm mad at you, why you do this?
Come back, I'll kill you.
Jemmy...
♪ Plantons la vigne,
c'est I'eau qui vient de vigne ♪
♪ Vignons, vignons, vignons,
C'est I'eau qui vient de vign' en vin ♪
♪ C'est I'eau qui vient de vigne ♪
♪ De vigne en
pousse, la voilà la Jolie pousse ♪
♪ Poussi, poussons, poussons Le vin,
la voilà la Jolie pousse Au vin, ♪
♪ Ia voilà la Jolie pousse ♪
♪ C'est I'eau qui vient de bouche en vin
c'est I'eau qui vient de bouche. ♪
♪ C'est I'eau qui vient de terre en vin
c'est I'eau qui vient de terre. ♪
♪ De verre en
bouche, la voilà la Jolie bouche ♪
♪ Bouchi, bouchons, bouchons Le vin, la voilà
la Jolie bouche, la voilà la Jolie bouche ♪
Bravo, bravo, bravo...
Come on, sing out about the fat prima Donna.
- Commencez la musique.
- Allez.
♪ Mon ami, Mon ami,
see the prima Donna fair ♪ ♪
♪ With a line and a line
and a woolly mop of hair ♪
♪ Hear the prima Donna sing, la la la
All the people think she's fine, la la la ♪
♪ Because they're full of wine ♪
♪ Oh, vive I'Opera, vive I'Opera ♪
Higher.
♪ Now a dot and a dot
and a bit of this and that ♪
♪ And a curve and a curve
for the lady is always fat ♪
♪ Hear the prima Donna sing, pi pi pi,
you can bid romance adieu, la la la ♪
♪ She's big enough
for two. Oh, vive I'Opera ♪
♪ Vive I'opera... ♪
Higher.
♪ With a dash and a dash
and some fingers for her arms ♪
♪ With a touch and a touch.
Oh, the lady is full of charm ♪
♪ Hear the prima Donna sing, whoo, whoo,
she can always please the crowd, la la la ♪
♪ Because she sings so loud ♪
♪ Oh, vive I'Opera, vive I'Opera. ♪
Higher.
♪ Mon ami, bien
aime, see my little protegee ♪
♪ Iackadee, lackaday,
madame must prefer ballet ♪
♪ How madame would skip and prance, la la
la, if she ever got the chance, la la la ♪
♪ She'd really rather dance ♪
♪ Oh, vive I'Opera ♪
♪ Vive I'Opera ♪
- Alors, c'etait bien, ma belle Amie?
- Oui, magnifique.
- Do it again.
- Oh, no.
- Jumping swordfish, you're American.
- Yes.
- Yippee.
- Please.
But don't you realize how wonderful
it is? You've been sent from heaven.
I've been starved, starved for the sound of
one, good, clean, healthy American voice...
and then suddenly you come into my life.
Not only an American voice,
not only an American woman...
but a beautiful, adorable,
glamorous, glorious, radiant...
indescribable vision
of perfected loveliness, shake.
- Anyone ever tell you all that before?
- No, not all at once.
Well, then I'll tell you again when I get my
breath back. You're the most beautiful...
No, don't trouble. I think I can remember it.
It's no trouble. Who are you? Where
you come from? Will you be in Paris long?
May I see you tomorrow?
- No.
- No, I'm afraid not.
- Why not?
I'm a prima Donna.
- And you don't like prima Donnas.
- Nonsense. Why, I adore prima Donnas.
Oh, yes?
If there's anything I like before and
above everything else it's a prima Donna.
Any of these fellows will tell you.
Hey fellows, don't I adore prima Donnas?
Yes.
There, you see? Now, may I see you tomorrow?
Ecoutez mes amis, it's
mademoiselle Marcia Mornay, the singer.
Yes, I saw her last night at the opera.
Marcia Mornay?
Let's have a song.
Come on, let's go have a song.
Belay, haul off, give the lady air.
Where are your manners, you blocks,
you stones, you senseless idiots.
- But we want a song.
- But mademoiselle wants privacy.
Back to your old
sofas and cheeses, you termites.
I saw her first.
- The thing is now become intimate.
- Thank you.
- I'm glad I have a champion.
- Mademoiselle, you have an adoring slave...
a protector, a worshiper who
would give his life for you.
The least you can do is
to have supper with him.
No, I'm awfully ashamed
but I'm afraid I'll have to refuse.
Give me one good reason why.
Well, I've just had supper.
I couldn't eat another.
I'm crushed, humiliated.
Also a little offended.
What about a small ration
of bacon and two eggs? No.
About, one egg?
La belle dame sans merci.
Will you have supper
with me tomorrow night then?
- I'm singing at the Opera.
- After the opera? Before the opera?
Lunch, have lunch with me.
You can't shake your head at that too.
- I can, I must...
- I see, you don't like me, eh?
Oh, but I like you very much
and I like your voice too.
Oh, but really you have a
wonderful voice, really but...
Well, I, I'll just be awfully busy
during the rest of my stay in Paris.
I really can't see you again.
Oh, just for a few minutes,
3/4 of an hour for lunch tomorrow.
I've a real Virginia ham...
if you're a true American,
you can't look a gift ham in the frill.
Oh Noah, lost your ark?
- There's my cabby, I really must be going.
- I'll see you to your coach.
Oh no, please. Please, I'd rather you didn't.
You're not going mademoiselle.
We can't let her go, can we?
No, not without a song, eh?
- Then I'm never going to see you again?
- No.
Will it matter to
you if I die of a broken heart?
Oh, you won't.
I'm in a terrible hurry, good night.
Thank you so much for
taking such good care of me.
Come to lunch tomorrow.
- Oh, but I can't, besides I, I...
- I'm Paul Allison.
And I live on the top floor of this house.
I'll expect you for lunch tomorrow and I won't
let go of your hand till you say you'll come.
Oh well, it won't do any good,
quite impossible, I promise you.
- Let go of my hand please.
- Not till you promise to come to lunch.
Virginia ham, promise?
Why, I can't.
- Please let go.
- No.
Oh Mr. Allison, I may get into
terrible trouble through all this.
- Not till you promise.
- Oh driver, home please.
It shall be so, Jemmy..
Really, really, this has gone far enough now.
- Let go of me, please let go.
- Not till you promise.
- Oh Mr. Allison, get off.
- I won't let go till you promise.
Let go of my hand.
Will you hurt yourself. Do be careful.
- Promise?
- Yes, yes, yes. I promise, I promise.
♪ I will cook you ham and eggs ♪
- ♪ Fried Virginia ham and eggs ♪
- Hurry, hurry driver.
♪ Like we fix them way down south,
they will melt right in your mouth ♪♪
♪ Hey, what's the matter
your clatter is too much noise? ♪
♪ Ah, what a vision
I'm losing my head, such poise ♪
♪ And tomorrow she's coming to lunch, oh. ♪
♪ Will you be a good fellow
and soften that bellow and... ♪
♪ Heavenly ham and scrambled eggs ♪
♪ We know you like ham
but get out to the street, tout de suite ♪
- ♪ But I'm hopelessly, madly in love ♪
- ♪ You're in danger of bodily harm ♪
- ♪ Oh, what delicate charm ♪
- ♪ Look out, the gendarme ♪
♪ Friends, are we all for one? ♪
♪ One for all and all for one ♪
♪ You're in a spot, tell
us what can we do for you? ♪
♪ It may look a bit funny but I have no
money so I need to borrow a franc or two ♪
♪ Before we can lend it,
for what will you spend it? ♪
♪ She's coming to lunch ♪
♪ No request was ever harder
but we'll help you fill your larder ♪
♪ Just enough for ham and
eggs, Virginia ham and eggs ♪
♪ Here's a two, make it two,
no, no, make it 3 have a crew ♪
♪ That'll do, that'll do. Oui, oui ♪>
♪ What a treat, what a treat
for the sweet madame ♪
- ♪ To eat ham... ♪
- Hey...
You aroused every
gendarme in Paris, scatter, now.
? And eggs?
Have you got to shout
the roof off every time you come in?
Have you seen what the time is?
I've known people to have died, who
been shouted at when sleeping, ain't it?
Where were you all night?
I warned you, I am furious.
- Archipenko, I've met her at last.
- And who if I may ask, who is that her, eh?
The loveliest woman in Paris.
What? Again?
And she's coming to lunch
here, tomorrow, Archipenko.
♪ Oh, vive I'Opera ♪
- Mr. Allison, please...
- ♪ Oh, vive I'Opera ♪
I ask you.
With humility and tears in
my eyes, I'm asking you.
How do you expect me to train your voice
when you come home at this time of the night?
- I mean, of the morning.
- Night.
Morning, the sun is already rising.
You bad boy.
You, you, you drinking in low haunts.
Making fun with strange ladies.
Will I ever put you into the opera when
you play such, such shnookety gooks.
Mit your voice, eh?
I ask you, how do you expect me to do it?
- How do you expect anyone to do it?
- I don't.
There you got it, there you
are putting your thumbs on it.
You, you, you ain't got ambition.
You ain't got application.
You are fooling about it, ain't it?
Honestly Paul Allison,
you are breaking my heart.
- That's what I am.
- Oh, but Archipenko...
guess who's coming to lunch.
Guess who? Now we're going to play games, eh?
- Marcia Mornay.
- And another thing I want to...
- Hello, please, what was that name?
- Marcia Mornay is coming to lunch.
- Marcia Mornay...
- Yes.
The prima Donna from the opera is...
♪ Marcia Mornay is coming to lunch ♪
♪ Marcia Mornay is coming to lunch,
Marcia Mornay is coming to lunch ♪
♪ She's coming to lunch ♪
- Had a nice time?
- Yes, how much is it?
On account of Jem it's
discounted. I'll make it 10 francs.
Oh I, I seem to have...
Well, I'll have to throw the money
to you from that window up there.
- That'll be all in all ma'am.
- Thank you.
Oh Ellen...
May I ask for an explanation.
If there is one?
I'm sorry, I've been
very foolish, forgive me.
- Where have you been?
- I went for a drive in a cab.
- With whom?
- With no one.
- I'm not lying.
That was a very sane and rational thing
to do at this time of night, wasn't it?
Oh Nicolai, please try to understand.
I was excited, overexcited and happy I...
I couldn't sleep, I only intended
to drive a little way so I could sort of...
think things over and calm down.
And then there was
an accident, the horse broke loose.
I had to wait in the cab
until the driver caught him.
That's what happened, honestly.
Well, the driver's still downstairs, I didn't
pay him, you can ask him if you like.
I'll go down and pay him.
- How much does mademoiselle owe you?
- 40 francs.
She, she tells me you've had an accident.
Yes, the harness broke and Jemmy ran away.
But it's always happening
monsieur, think nothing of it.
I...
Never, never mind about the change.
He's coming back now.
Oh mademoiselle, I implored you not to go.
But I haven't done anything I shouldn't.
Was he very angry?
He didn't say anything, he just stood
there, waiting. He never moved once.
- Forgive me.
- Oh, it was nothing.
- You had a right to be angry.
- I had no right whatever.
- Good night.
- Thank you very much.
- Goodbye.
Goodbye.
- Hello Paul.
- Hello.
You wish you were
going there tonight, don't you?
- Well, don't you?
- I am going.
- So am I.
- Got your tickets?
- Not yet.
- Oh, then you're not going.
- The house was sold out days ago.
- I'm going in the gallery.
Have you seen that line of people waiting?
It's halfway around the opera house already.
Tell me, is Mornay
really as great as they say?
Oh, what a voice she has, what a voice.
There's never been anything like it.
I've got two seats in the front row.
Front row?
And what a trouble it took to get them.
Hey, waiter.
- Monsieur?
- Here.
Here they are. My friend, all the money
in Paris wouldn't buy those two tickets.
You wish you'd booked early now, don't you?
- Your change monsieur.
- Oh, yes.
- Hey, what are you doing there? What is...
- Pardon monsieur.
- Fool you...
- Sorry.
Clumsy.
- Oh, allow me.
- Thank you.
For that, you get no tip.
- Good day.
♪ Teedle dum tum, teedle ta,
teedle teedle ta ta... ♪
♪ Teedle teedle dum, teedle
teedle tum tum, teedle teedle ta ♪
♪ Teedle teedle dum tum ta ♪
♪ Teedle eedle ee tum tuttle ta da ♪
Smack my silly face, kick me.
That's what I'm, Mr Allison goodness gracious
and for goodness' sake, what a tragedy.
- What's gone wrong now?
We got ham, we got eggs, we got
wine, we got bread, we got fruit...
- But we only got two plates.
- What?
You hear me? Only two plates, our
lunch is a catastrophe, we are ruined.
There she is now.
One.
Coming.
- Hello.
- I knew you'd come.
Well, I shouldn't.
And you're just as beautiful in the daytime.
Come in.
- Well, I only came to tell you that I...
- All that matters is that you're here.
Oh, excuse me.
This is August Archipenko,
Mademoiselle Marcia Mornay.
- How do you do?
- Oh mademoiselle, what an honor.
- I can only say what an honor.
- Thank you.
Archipenko is my maestro.
He try to make an opera singer out of me.
Yeah.
Professor of music...
from the Weingarten University mit experience
in Munich and Salzburg and proud...
possessor of 7 diplomas.
- But no pupils except me.
- Yeah.
- How do you like our little suite?
- Oh, I like it.
It sort of reminds me
of when I first started.
Oh, but you haven't seen it all.
Well, over here, the view from the
balcony embraces the Tuileries,
the Place de la Concorde, the Louvre
and the backyard of the local milkman.
We see him watering the milk every morning.
- But I can't stay Mr. Allison.
- Ah, no?
I really only came because I
didn't want to break my promise.
I'll have to go right along.
But I'm awfully sorry.
- Oh, but we...
- Oh, is all for me?
Yeah, we got a Virginia ham too.
- Ham?
- Yeah.
And eggs.
Eggs?
Ham and eggs.
Awfully sweet of you.
You, you couldn't just
stay for 10 minutes, could you?
It wouldn't take that to
have everything ready.
- Well?
- Could you?
- Just 10 minutes?
- Not another second, Archipenko.
Oh, but...
Oh, well.
♪ Carry me back to Old Virginny ♪
A little more fuel, more fuel.
The music, the music.
Please not the music, the music...
Quick, the plates, the plates.
- The plates.
Ach Du lieber.
Your highness, mi lords, gentlemen...
also members of the opposition, I give you...
- Mademoiselle Marcia Mornay.
Oh, thank you sirs.
Gentlemen...
I give you Virginia ham served in saucers.
- Virginia ham served in saucers.
- Sol.
Sol and prosit.
Let's just pile them up for now
and wash them later, eh?
- Yes'sum.
- That's my honey child.
♪ Carry me back to Old Virginny ♪
♪ There's where the cotton
and the corn and taters grow, ♪
♪ There's where the birds
warble sweet in the springtime ♪
♪ There's where the
darke'ys heart am longed to go. ♪
♪ There's where I
labored so hard for old massa ♪
♪ Day after day in the field of yellow corn ♪
♪ No place on earth
do I love more sincerely ♪
♪ Than old virginny ♪
♪ The place where I was born ♪
♪ Carry me back to old virginny ♪
♪ There's where the cotton
and the corn and taters grow ♪
♪ There's where the birds
warble sweet in the springtime ♪
♪ There's where this old
darke'ys heart am longed to go ♪
♪ There's where I
labored so hard for old massa ♪
♪ Day after day in the field of yellow corn ♪
♪ No place on earth
do I love more sincerely ♪
♪ Than Old Virginny ♪
♪ The place where I was born ♪
Ach Du lieber. Bravo, bravo, bravo.
Excuse please, I was just a little bit
listening, I didn't want to disturb you...
Makes you kind of homesick, doesn't it?
Oh no, I, I don't have time to get homesick.
But you would like to go
back sometime, wouldn't you?
- Oh, sometime yes.
- Are you from Virginia too?
Me?
- Oh no.
- Maryland?
- But you are from the south?
- Oh yes sir.
- Mississippi? Georgia.
- No, sir.
- Alabama?
- No.
- North Carolina? South Carolina?
- Louisiana?
- No.
- But you must've come from someplace honey.
- Oh yes, I sure enough did.
Where from?
- Virginia.
- Virginia?
All right then, I'll, I'll remember
you to the folks when I go back.
- Oh, you not going back, are you?
- I've been thinking about it.
Oh no, you mustn't, I mean...
with a voice like yours, you, you really
should stay here and become a great singer.
That's just, exactly, explicitly
what I am always saying, aint it?
Oh, I don't want to be an opera singer.
But, don't you like to sing?
Oh, I like it all right when
I'm happy about something...
or when I sang to you like I did then.
But mademoiselle, he ain't
got ambition, he ain't got application.
Oh, Archipenko wants to sell me into slavery.
I want to sell him into slavery,
I want to put him into the opera.
That's where he belongs, but will he work?
Oh no, not if I get wild horses
to drag him there, he will not work.
That bad boy.
Oh mademoiselle, please say something.
Do something that will make him work.
Oh, but he wouldn't
listen to me, why should he?
I could think of a lot
of good reasons why I should.
Then how can I make you work?
How? You can...
Oh, the time.
- What I've been doing here all this time?
- You can't go now.
You don't understand,
I've got to go, I'm, I'm awfully sorry.
- Auf wiedersehen.
- Please.
- Goodbye.
Oh, I'll come down with you.
Oh no, please don't. I'd rather you didn't.
And Paul, I mean Mr. Allison...
- I'd like you to promise me something.
- Anything.
Don't ask to see me again, ever.
- Oh, I won't promise that.
- Oh, but you must please.
I can't very well explain but...
I shouldn't have come
here in the first place.
Then why did you?
Well, I told you I didn't
want to break a promise.
- Is that all?
- Yes, yes. Oh, please try to understand.
It's been lots of fun and I've loved it
but it's all over now, it's finished, bye.
Home, quickly.
But I Tell you the tickets were stolen.
I even remember the numbers, row 8, 6 and 7.
- Row 8, 3 and 4.
- 6 and 7.
- 3 and 4.
- Will you keep out of this a minute.
Please, take us to our seats.
It's impossible monsieur,
those seats are occupied.
- But call the manager.
- I'm sorry, the manager isn't here.
Why not? It is
his duty to be here, where's he?
- I do not know monsieur.
- Oh please, go and get him.
I cannot go, monsieur.
- Don't be so insulting.
- I cannot leave my post.
Let us through to our
seats, I told you the numbers.
I think I even know who is in them.
- Row 8, 3 and 4.
- 7 and 8.
Sir, kindly step aside,
you are causing a disturbance.
I am going to have you discharged for this.
Come on Mimi, we find the manager.
There she is.
Look those eyes, aren't they marvelous?
She's beautiful.
Watch how she moves
her hands, isn't she graceful?
Well?
Oh...
- How you get in here?
- I did my best to make him go, but...
Will you get out of my dressing room
at once or must I call an attendant?
Oh, no, no, no. I'll go.
I only came to tell you that...
I think you sing more beautifully than I
thought anyone ever could and to thank you.
- I told you I didn't want to see you again.
- But I want to see you.
Well, now you've seen me.
- Ellen, open the door for him.
- But there's one thing before I go.
- Quickly.
- Tomorrow is May day.
- It's a fair at Saint-Cloud, may I take you?
- No.
- Goodbye.
- Please?
Oh, don't be
absurd, you know it's ridiculous.
- But it isn't.
- Will you go? You mustn't be found here.
I'll go if you come to Saint-Cloud tomorrow.
I can't, I mean, I don't want to.
Won't anything make you go?
- What?
- Come to Saint-Cloud tomorrow.
Who is it?
Monsieur Nazaroff wishes to know if you
will receive the critics in 3 minutes Mlle.
Yes, yes I will.
Now you must go. I mean it. You really must.
- Come to Saint-Cloud tomorrow?
- Yes, yes I will.
- I'll call for you at 10 o'clock.
- Oh, for goodness sakes, don't do that.
- I'll meet you there.
- At 10 o'clock?
- Yes, yes. Only go, go.
- Right.
Go.
If you gentlemen will excuse me for a moment.
- Oh, I beg your pardon, sorry. Excuse me.
- Not at all sir.
- I'm afraid I was in your way.
- Oh, no, it's my fault.
I'll see if mademoiselle
Mornay is ready to receive you.
Who was the visitor?
Oh, just a silly young man.
He wasn't troublesome Nicolai.
He'd been out front and wanted to see
me so he could talk about it afterward.
Wasn't important, really.
The critics are outside scratching
at the door, shall I let them in?
- Well I...
- Remember...
these critics are the people
who count in your life from now on.
They fill the orchestra
seats for us, silly young men...
only fill the gallery.
Yes Nicolai.
- Monsieur, are you not coming to the fair?
- Sure.
- Where's your sweetheart?
- Oh, she's coming.
Good, you can't have any
fun without a sweetheart.
Thank heaven, I was
afraid you weren't coming.
I know, I couldn't get away any earlier.
Ellen, take the carriage
and wait over there somewhere.
Lovely.
Oh yes, but I was mad to have come.
Look...
until we leave, you are
going to forget who you are and...
what you are and
everything else except it's May day...
and the sun is shining
and we're going to have fun, eh?
- Swing?
- Love it.
- Fun?
- Oh yes.
Here...
Well, I'm showing you how to do it.
- Bravo.
- Oh, right in the middle.
Madame.
♪ Sul mare luccica I'astro d'argento ♪
♪ Placida è I'onda Prospero il vento ♪
♪ Venite all'argine barchette mie ♪
♪ Santa Lucia, Santa Lucia ♪
♪ Santa Lucia ♪
♪ Venite all'argine barchette mie ♪
Bravo, what a voice.
Dance?
Great.
- Shall we go over it?
- Yes.
Let's sit here for a while.
Oh, thank you.
Well, are you sorry you played truant today?
- No.
- Have you had fun?
Fun? I never knew there
was such fun, such happiness.
I've never been so
happy in my life, it's been wonderful..
- I know something much more wonderful.
- What?
You.
Oh, have you forgotten I'm a prima Donna?
- No, but you have.
- Oh, no, I haven't.
No, in about 3 hours I'll be singing the page
song from The Huguenot's in a boy's wig.
This will all seem as though
it had never happened.
By, by tomorrow,
I'll have forgotten all about it.
- No, you won't.
- Oh, yes, I do.
No. I'm going to sing you
a song to remember it by.
Unless you'd rather I just
went on talking nonsense.
Oh no, do sing it please.
- It's about more things than May day though.
- Oh, what?
Sweethearts. See, you're mine.
Only in the song.
♪ Oh, love is so sweet in the springtime ♪
♪ When two hearts are singing in May ♪
♪ No years that are coming can bring time ♪
♪ To make me forget dear, this day ♪
♪ I'll love you in life's gray December ♪
♪ The same as I love you today ♪
♪ My heart ever young will remember ♪
♪ The thrill it knew that day in May ♪
♪ Sweetheart, sweetheart, sweetheart ♪
♪ Will you love me ever? ♪
♪ Will you remember this day ♪
♪ When we were happy in May ♪
♪ My dearest one? ♪
♪ Sweetheart, sweetheart, sweetheart ♪
♪ Though our paths may sever ♪
♪ To life's last faint
ember will you remember ♪
♪ Springtime, lovetime ♪
♪ May ♪
I love you, I always
loved you, I always will.
Oh, Paul. Paul, darling.
Please...
- There's someone else.
- Yes?
The one at the theater, Nazaroff, isn't it?
Yes.
- Do you love him?
- Yes. Yes, I do.
- I'm going to marry him.
Oh Paul, Paul, it shouldn't have
happened, I shouldn't have let it happen,
But was such fun, so exciting and...
I kept hoping it would
end like that and not like this.
Can you forgive me?
I find it hard not to, the way things are.
Paul, I want you to know this.
I'm not just marrying him
because he's good and kind...
and because he needs me.
There are stronger ties than that, you see...
everything I have,
everything I am, I owe to him.
Even being here today,
even meeting you the other night.
He's made all those
things possible for me, all of them.
When I first met him, I was nothing.
Nobody believed in me.
I'd even stopped believing in myself...
and yet he gave up everything,
his whole career, all his other pupils...
just so he could guide me to success.
That was 4 years ago.
In all that time, he's never
stopped believing in me.
once broken a promise.
Nor failed me.
That's why I can't fail him now Paul.
Even...
Even for something I want far more.
I understand.
I met you too late.
Yet something inside
me won't let me believe it.
Please Paul...
let's, let's just remember this day.
We will Marcia.
One day to last us all the rest of our lives.
It will, it will.
I'll always love you dear.
And I'll always...
remember you...
and your song.
♪ Sweetheart, sweetheart, sweetheart ♪
♪ Will you love me ever? ♪
♪ I will remember the day ♪
♪ When we were happy in May ♪
♪ My dearest one ♪
♪ Sweetheart, sweetheart, sweetheart ♪
♪ Though our paths may sever ♪
♪ To life's last faint
ember we will remember ♪
♪ Springtime, lovetime ♪
♪ May ♪
Bye.
Goodbye.
Mr. Nazaroff, we greatly appreciate
your having selected our hotel.
Not at all sir, we've
always been very happy here..
- Genaro.
- Si, signore.
- Adolph.
- Ja.
See that madame's
broth is prepared immediately.
I trust that this suite will prove
adequate and satisfactory in every way.
- Yes, very nice.
- Madame's room is through here.
Whatever you may wish
will be attended to instantly.
Thank you very much.
Gentlemen, tell, tell the
press they needn't wait.
- We no interview today.
- Very well.
- Fanchon.
- Yes sir?
Where's the board of
directors from the opera house?
Well sir, I had arranged
with the hotel management...
I'm sorry sir, but the
gentlemen haven't arrived as yet.
They were to met me here,
I'm accustomed to punctuality..
- See what's delayed them please.
- Certainly sir, at once.
- It's a very pleasant suite madame.
- Yes, they all are.
Wish we'd stay in one place long
enough so we could take a house.
I'm tired of hotels.
I'd like a hot bath Ellen, you ask
them if they'll arrange for one please?
Oui, oui, madame.
We'll have to leave for your
official reception in an hour.
I've left word you're not
to be disturbed till we go.
Thank you Nicolai.
Mary.
The gentlemen from the opera are late.
Doesn't really matter.
You don't have to see them at all,
as a matter of fact, I'll attend to them.
Thank you Nicolai.
- You tired, after your voyage?
- Oh, not very.
Wish we didn't have to go
to that reception though.
Oh, so do I.
Oh, by the way, you'd better wear
your jewelry, they'll expect it..
All right.
- You glad to be back in America?
- Oh yes.
You don't exactly show it.
Do I have to?
When I'm not on parade?
Poor darling, you are
rather tired, aren't you?
Oh, I'm sorry Nicolai.
I'm just not awfully excited
about anything, that's all.
I'm sorry.
I should've remembered that, that
excites you less than anything else.
Why do you say things like that, Nicolai?
I don't know.
Have no right to, have I?
After all, you've been a perfect wife.
You've been faithful and
loyal, obedient and affectionate.
In the face of all that,
it's unimportant, I suppose.
Never once, in all the
years that we've been married...
have I ever felt I completely possessed you.
You've no right to feel like that.
I know, all I regret is...
it's made me love you too much.
Come in.
- The directors from the opera are here sir.
- Tell them I'll be with them immediately.
Very well.
I wouldn't worry too much about it Nicolai.
Your bath will be ready in a moment madame.
Thank you.
- Will you be seated gentlemen?
- Thank you.
Oh Mr. Nazaroff...
it's a great pleasure to welcome
you and madame Mornay to New York.
It's a very proud day
for us sir, a very proud day.
Very generous of you to say so sir.
Now, we have here the
contracts, the arrangements,
and all the other formalities to be observed.
I think you'll find them quite in order.
- Traviata?
- Yes, Traviata, yes.
We sold out the opening night already and the
booking for the season is exceptionally high.
Our advance publicity has been out two weeks,
entire supporting cast is been contracted.
And the scenery and costumes
are almost complete.
So, you see, we've
not been idle Mr. Nazaroff.
No, far from it.
In fact, you've gone to enormous pains
to cast, dress and advertise an opera...
that madame Mornay has not the
slightest intention of appearing in.
- Not Traviata?
- But the cast is been signed.
- The scenery is cost $1,000 to date.
- Yes, and all the costumes.
- Traviata is a beautiful opera.
- We decided on it after long discussions.
- But without consulting madame Mornay.
But naturally, we
took it for granted that you'd...
Which is so unwise.
What opera do you suggest then?
- Czaritza.
- Czaritza?
Czaritza.
But Czaritza has never
been presented here before.
Quite, but Trentini wrote it
especially for madame Mornay.
What could be more perfect
for her opening in New York?
But Czaritza needs a baritone.
We have no baritone important
enough to sing opposite madame Mornay.
I'm afraid that is a slight exaggeration.
We have a very
efficient baritone in Paul Allison.
- Perhaps you may know him Mr. Nazaroff.
- No.
I've heard him spoken of to
his credit, as a matter of fact...
Madame Mornay will be quite
satisfied to have him sing with her.
But he's not well enough known to the public.
The public will be there to
hear and see madame Mornay.
I'll get in touch with Paul
Allison when I leave here.
Thank you.
Then that concludes the discussion gentlemen.
- Where's madame?
- She's in the bath.
- Marcia?
- Yes?
I've arranged the details.
You open with Czaritza.
- 4 weeks rehearsal, starting this afternoon.
- Will that be time enough for them?
It'll have to be.
- Who they got for Petrov?
- Paul Allison.
Paul.
Well...
- Couldn't they get someone better known?
- Why should they?
Nothing to worry about dear,
he's got a very fine voice they tell me.
I've heard of him before.
Don't want to hurry you, but we got to go
straight on to rehearsal after the reception.
The hour is drawing close.
Yes, yes, yes. I'll be there.
See, half an hour late.
She think we got nothing better to do...
than to kick our heels
all day long in this blasted barn?
Drown all prima Donnas, I say.
If I were president, that's what I'd do.
I'd drown all prima Donnas and replace
them with the choir boys, they're punctual.
- You called the rehearsal for 1:30.
- Well?
- It's just 1:30.
- 2 o'clock.
1:30.
Well, what I said about drowning
all prima Donnas still holds good.
Permit me madame Mornay, May I
present Mr. O'Brien, Mr. Abrams.
- How do you do?
- You gentlemen of course know Mr. Nazaroff.
It's a great honor madame, a great honor.
Very great honor, yes.
- Now, if you are ready for rehearsal madame.
- Oh, quite.
Permit me to introduce our stage director.
Madame Mornay, Mr. Rudyard.
- How do you do?
- I am honored madame, deeply honored.
- This is Mr. Nazaroff.
- Your servant sir.
- Our conductor, signore Pugliemi.
- How do you do?
Signore.
And now madame, Mr. O'Brien,
may I present the cast to you?
Of course.
This is Mr. Paul Allison, our baritone.
- How do you do?
It's an honor madame, to sing with you.
Thank you...
Very much.
Mr. Nazaroff, Mr. Allison.
- How do you do sir?
- How do you do?
And this is our basso, Mr. Dubrovsky.
- Enchante madame.
- Merci bien, monsieur.
- Excuse me Archipenko.
- Mr. Archipenko to you, if you please.
Hello. Hello. Good afternoon, good afternoon.
My dear Paul, I'm
awfully sorry I'm a little late.
How do you do?
Oh, madame, how wonderful to see you again.
You know, all these years I have
been saying little prayers for you...
because on account of you giving Paul
the incentive, the ambition, the application.
You remember that day Paris...
When I was a student
in Paris several years ago...
madame was kind enough
to encourage me with my career.
That's the truth, from
that day on, he began to work.
Mr. Rudyard, will you begin rehearsal please?
Oh yes, yes, of course.
- If you please Mr. Archipenko.
- Excuse me.
If you please.
Places.
On account of the chorus,
we'll begin with the last act.
- Madame Mornay, you are familiar with yours.
- Yes sir.
Personally Mr. Nazaroff, I'm delighted you
insisted on Czaritza instead of Traviata.
You know, it's just the chance
young Allison has been waiting for.
Yes, I'm sure it is.
If you please.
♪ Mon coeur Ne pleure point
La Mort Du noble Czar ♪
♪ Qui avait sans amour ♪
♪ Dieu, me pardonne. ♪
♪ Que I'assassin recoive la vie eternelle ♪
♪ Toi, son epouse impenitente ♪
As-Tu trahi ton Czar.
♪ Pourquoi pleure la juste
Mort d'un tyrant? ♪
♪ Tu as raison, c'est is tyranic,
Les cosaques Du Czar qui meurt. ♪
♪ Oh, Oh patre. Russie Dieu Te libere Amen. ♪
♪ Mon dieu C'est toi? ♪
♪ Le Czar est Mort. Vive la Czarina ♪
♪ Pour I'assassin, pour Le traitre,
voici I'arret a' signer. ♪
♪ Defends toi vite, ou Tu mourras. ♪
♪ Vous hesitez? Signez. Au Mon Du Czar ♪
♪ Dieu a Donne a Ce
monde, la liberte et I'honneur ♪
♪ Pour vous, je Donne ma
vie, Oh, Reine Au ma patrie. ♪
♪ Tu Va mourir, amour Si tendre. ♪
♪ Alors, Le chien mourra. ♪
♪ Mon coeur, aussi. ♪
♪ Je Donne ma vie et un peuple vivra.
La viese gagne Au prix dela Mort. ♪
♪ J'entends Le tambour, etj'ai fait Mon
devoir, je vais mourir, Mon ame est en paix ♪
♪ Oh, sombre destin, Oh, devoir cruel
D'etre condamne a Mort. ♪
♪ Ton crime odieux nous separe,
Tu as merite ton sort. ♪
♪ Tu vas mouri paria main Du boureau
Qui, sans pitte, a'abat et chatie ♪
♪ La homte suit dams la tombe
et tumeurs en vain. ♪
♪ Laisse nous seuls,
j'ai a tui parle un instant ♪
♪ Votre Majestee. ♪
♪ Ton Czar. ♪
♪ Mon amour, Te souviens Tu des passes.
Reves, des reves passes. ♪
♪ Sort sans pitte qui separe,
Nos coeurs Au asuil meme de la Mort. ♪
♪ La deliverance, La vie, commence
De tout min coeur a jamais, je t'adore. ♪
- ♪ Mon ame, s'enivre. Tu me delivres. ♪
- ♪ Biens ame, Mon amour t'appararaitras. ♪
- ♪ Quittez un etre Si Cher. ♪
- ♪ Et ton courage me soutient. ♪
- ♪ Ou dans is siel ou L'enfer ♪
- ♪ Je t'aime. ♪
♪ Joie dans Mon coeur,
I'extase me dit assez. ♪
♪ Je n' aime Au monde Que toi.
C'est I' amour qui jamais Ne renounce ♪
♪ Moi Mon ame chantait,
un chant divin, divin dans tes bras. ♪
- ♪ Mon ame chantait, chantait. ♪
- Je vis bien aime, Mon amour, viens. ♪
♪ Viens, douce Mort. Amour vivra, ♪
♪ L' amour invincible.
Seigneur, protege nous. ♪
♪ Dieu aies pitie de lui. ♪
- Paul, don't ever leave me again ever.
- I love you darling, I love you.
- And I love you too.
- You're not going back to him.
I'll take you away tonight.
♪ Seigneur, a genoux, ales pitie de moi, Dieu
Te benisse, Le seigneur protege Mon amour. ♪
♪ Dieu, recevez I'ame de monbien Amie, ecoutaez
ma priere Dieu, Te protege Mon amour. ♪
Good boy, good boy.
You've never had such a reception madame.
It was wonderful, I heard the director saying
it's the greatest success they've ever had.
Ellen...
I'd like you to take a
message to Mr. Allison for me.
Tell him...
Tell him not to do anything until I see him
tomorrow morning, I'll come to his flat.
Well, go on. Go, hurry, hurry.
Madame will see no one.
Postpone our press
reception till sometime tomorrow.
Yes sir.
Tonight you surpassed even yourself.
They're referring to it...
as a living emotion.
Whatever it was...
it was extremely effective.
Thank you.
Was a great deal that you never thought
important enough to tell me, wasn't there?
Very little.
Very little?
Yet it stood between us for 7 years.
And I brought you two together again.
It has its humor, hasn't it?
Or doesn't it strike you as
being particularly humorous?
Nicolai, I'm very tired and confused.
Will you wait till we get back to
the hotel? We can discuss it then.
Very well.
Thank you.
Oh madame, you were glorious, glorious.
- Wonderful, simply wonderful.
- Thank you.
We're having a
little reception at Delmonico's and...
- I wondered if madame isn't too tired...
- Most charming of you sir.
As a matter of fact, madame is exhausted.
I'm taking her directly back to the hotel.
- I'm very sorry Mr. O'Brien.
- Oh, please, please. I quite understand.
- Some other evening then, perhaps.
- Yes, thank you.
Mr. Allison...
permit me to thank you
for a most magnificent performance.
We are deeply indebted to you
for your indispensable cooperation.
- It's for me to thank you sir.
- Not at all sir, not at all.
Good night.
- Good night madame.
- Good night sir.
Good night.
Supper is ready sir.
Now...
Suppose we find out exactly how we stand?
Nothing could've
stopped this happening Nicolai.
I never realized what a terrible
mistake I made when I left him.
I, I thought then that
I had to keep my promise to you...
after all you'd done
for me, I tried to forget him.
I tried to put him out
of my mind but I was never able to.
And now tonight, I, I realize that...
I love you more than anything else in life.
But I can't go on living without him.
- So you wish to be set free, is that it?
- Oh Nicolai, yes.
Yes Nicolai.
Nicolai...
Very well, if that's what you really want...
I won't stand in your way.
Good night.
It's very late and you're tired.
It's time you were asleep madame.
It couldn't have happened any other way.
You've nothing to reproach yourself with.
Now go to bed madame.
I'll stay with you until you fall asleep.
- What's that?
- Just a door banging.
When things happen
you never thought could happen...
something inside won't let you believe it.
You...
You'd have to keep on
repeating to yourself it's true.
A door banging? Well, who...
Nicolai? Nicolai?
- Ellen, Ellen, Ellen...
- Yes, madame?
Get me a cloak quickly.
I'm glad you've come here.
I suggest we get this over
as reasonably as possible.
We will.
I'm giving Marcia her freedom.
And you yours...
Mr. Allison.
What have you...
Paul, Paul...
Paul, no...
No.
Paul, Oh...
No...
That day...
Did last me...
all my life.
Don't cry, Marcia...
You won't be lonely.
I'll be close.
Always...
Paul...
Oh, Paul...
So that's why I live here alone.
Where nobody knows me, except Ellen.
Poor Miss Morrison.
Marcia.
I only told you to help you decide about Kip.
I found Paul too late.
But you and Kip have the
whole world ahead of you...
- If you want to take it.
- Oh, I do.
I've been such a fool about Kip.
Thank you so much.
And I'm going to come
see you much more often.
Then you won't be so lonely.
That's very sweet of you.
Oh, there's Kip now.
Thank you for helping me.
I'll never forget it, never.
- Hello Kip.
- Hello.
- Came by to apologize.
- I'm sorry too.
I've been...
thinking things over.
Well, I haven't any right to
stand in your way like that.
Oh Kip...
I, I came by to wish you luck in New York.
Thank you.
I'm not going.
- Not going?
- No.
Oh, gee.
Gee, that's swell.
Well...
It's time you came in, it's turning a little
chilly and you let your tea get all cold.
I'll only be a moment or two.
Yes, yes. I'll make you some fresh tea.
♪ Will you remember the day ♪
♪ When we were happy
in May, my dearest one? ♪
♪ Sweetheart, sweetheart, sweetheart ♪
♪ Though our paths may sever ♪
♪ To life's last faint
ember we will remember ♪
- ♪ Will you love me ever? ♪
- Will you remember the day ♪
♪ When we were
happy in May, my dearest one? ♪
♪ Sweetheart, sweetheart, sweetheart ♪
♪ Though our paths may sever ♪
♪ To life's last faint
ember we will remember ♪
♪ Springtime ♪
♪ Lovetime ♪
♪ May ♪
Watch Movies, TV Series & Live Sports
www.admitme.app