All right. Pack her up there.
Hey, Sandy,
Put on a straight line, will ya.
Come on, Alec, get off that lard.
What do you think this is?
Cover your exit, will ya?
Come on Alec, get those hatches off.
Come on, let's get to moving.
That's a mighty haul of fish, Captain.
Yeah, the tuna are running outside.
We're ready. Let it go.
- Hello, Alec.
- Hello, Min.
Hello.
- Hello, sweetie.
- Hello, Min.
- How's everything?
- Fine. Had a great trip.
- That's fine. Where's Bill?
- He's over here.
Hello, Bill.
- Hello, Min, how are you?
- Right in the pink.
- Say, Min.
- What?
- I got a surprise for you.
- What is it?
- 6 bottles of vodka.
- Vodka?
You've drunken vodka?
I've drunk everything
from bug juice to rotgut.
I got it off a fellow
outside the 12 mile limit.
- Ivan Novich. You know him.
- Oh the Russian.
Yeah.
How much is it gonna set me back?
$10 for the 6 bottles.
- TEN BUCKS?
- Yes.
I'd kill a Russian for ten bucks.
Ten bucks, why?
Why don't you go 50/50?
You'll swill most of it down.
Now ain't that gratitude?
After me boarding with you for years
and paying my rent every week.
Well, you ain't sore, are you, Bill?
Yeah. Well no, I'm not so sore now.
You go up to the hotel.
I'll be up in a minute and
we'll crack one of those bottles.
- You old hooliver.
- I'll be right up.
Brush up on your minute tour gulf.
Come on, let's get these fish
off of here.
What do you think this is,
a holiday, Alec?
- Come on, gang, I'll see you later.
- Okay, Min.
- Hey, where's Nancy?
- She's upstairs.
Weird.
- Hey, Nancy?
- I'm coming.
Why do you always hang around
upstairs for?
They're fumigating the bed.
Fumigating the bed again.
Min, a couple things.
That cop was here again.
You can go belly-aching around
after all I done for you?
Honestly, I didn't see.
I told them you've always
been good to me.
Yeah, now cut out the applesauce.
Just what did you say?
Well, I told them that my mother
I left me here when I was a baby.
And that you'd brought me up.
And I helped you with the work.
- That you've always been good to me.
- Oh that's all right.
Did they say anything about
taking you away from me?
Yes, he did.
Well?
What did you say?
I said I couldn't stand
to be taken away from you.
You ain't lying?
Honest, Min, I ain't. I swear it.
Yes.
Oh well, go on.
Take that fish in the kitchen.
Hey!
He didn't say nothing about
coming back, did he?
I said he didn't say
nothing about coming back.
Oh no. No.
All right, get out of here.
Go on, go on.
Well, Nancy.
Ain't you gonna say hello to me?
What for, Alec?
Any mail for me?
Not a chance.
That blonde forgot about you long ago.
Maybe I could do with a
brunette for a change..
- Oh yeah?
- Yeah.
Did you miss me?
Who are you kidding?
- Nobody.
- Oh yeah?
Come on, Nancy, don't be stingy.
Let me go. I've got work to do.
What was he saying to you?
Oh. He was only kidding.
Alec's like that.
Aw, he didn't mean nothing.
Sticking up for him, huh?
I want to tell you something.
Any time he comes here and
he says to you...
Hey Min! Come on out here.
I'm wait for a shave.
Go on. Finish your work.
Come on, Min. Will ya?
Come on, quit your poking around.
I want to get a shave. Get out here.
Oh yes.
What's eating on you?
Fleas.
Besides that?
Well... Alec's been
making eyes at Nancy.
The way you worry about her,
you'd think she's your own kid.
Sometimes I wish she was.
Don't go feeling sorry for yourself.
So you give me a pain in the neck.
Yeah, you ain't so hot yourself.
When I was young,
I used to make them sizzle.
Back in the Civil War days,
they were not so particular.
What's that about the Civil War days?
Aw, Min!
Did you ever hear the story about
the old Civil War veteran?
Yes. Now pike pike now
when I was a kid.
You get out of here!
All ears.
- Say, uh-
- I don't want to hear it now.
Hey handsome, how are you?
Well, how are you?
I'm fine.
Hey, there.
What are you doing up there?
Cut that out!
You don't you watch what you're doing?
Aw, gee, I didn't do it on purpose.
Oh no. Of course not.
Hey, you ain't so special.
I oughta give you my bucket too.
Yeah, you do and you'll be sorry.
- Oh yeah?
- Yeah!
Any more gab out of you
and I'll have a go.
Hey, what's the matter?
What's the problem? What's wrong?
- He's a liar.
- Who's a liar? Why?
I just dumped some trash overboard
and he said I did it on purpose.
You can't call her no liar.
I won't let you.
She just threw a bucket at me.
I did not.
If you don't like it around here,
you get out! See?
I'm running a decent joint.
I don't go for you boys
chasing around here at all.
Get out of here! Now go.
Min, what's the matter?
He calls her a liar. He insults me.
I want him off the place.
Calm down. Listen.
That's old man Cameron's son.
He runs the cannery
over there where I work.
I don't give an abalone
if he runs the jail.
And he can't park his putt putt
under my pylons either.
- Hey, where are you going now?
- None of your business.
Paying my taxes around here.
I ain't gonna have nobody tell me
what I'm going to do.
Don't touch that water.
You'll get in trouble!
I pay my taxes.
What are you doing in that boat?
I'll gonna get this bucket.
Get the bucket and come on out!
Come out right now.
I don't want anybody hanging around-
Hey, stop it.
Stop that motor.
Help!
Stop!
Bill!
Help!!
Bill! Bill!
You're trying to kill me.
Rats! I'm dead.
Hey, give us more speed!
Help!
- Hello, Min.
- Hello, Bill.
How are you feeling now?
Feeling?
I ain't got no feeling.
I'm numb all over.
My neck is broke.
- Your neck?
- Yeah, my neck.
- Let me get my big paws on it.
- Wait a minute.
- I won't hurt you, Min.
- Well be careful.
I'll be careful. You just hold still.
Let me get a hold of you.
Is that all right now?
Ow, you got your big
thing in my spherix!
That's all right? How is your spine?
My spine.
It's never been better in this life.
- Oh Bill, wait a minute.
- I'm waiting now.
Come on, I'm fine.
- I'm fine, Bill.
- Fix it all right?
Yeah, you'll fix it. Yeah, I'm fine.
Cut the cards and
I'll tell your fortune.
I'm fixed all right.
I had a dream last night.
About me, Min?
No, about a canary flying
in the window.
- Oh you did.
- Yes I did.
Look it there. See all them spades.
I tell you there's nothing
but trouble around here.
- Hey Min!
- What is it?
The cops!
The cops? What do they want?
- They are for me.
- For you?
They'll get your over my dead body.
Min, pull in your horns. Cops is cops.
Cops or no cops, they're not
gonna take the kid away from me.
Bill, I'm scared.
Come out with me.
What do you want?
Groot's my name. I'm a truant officer.
How long have you had this girl?
Ever since she was six months old.
Where did you get her?
Her mother left her here.
Where is her mother now?
How do I know?
She kicked the bucket.
Reports come in this girl
is terribly overworked.
She don't work any harder
than anyone else.
That's the gospel truth I don't.
The cook gets up at 4 o'clock.
But I don't get up until 5.
I suppose you finish your work
about 9 o'clock at night.
Sure I do. Sometimes 8:30.
Oh. Of course. Or course.
Well, that's why you don't go to school.
I won't go back to school.
I hate those stuck-up kids.
They give me a pain in the neck.
You've been kept from school.
Come on, tell me the truth!
Don't be afraid!
You think I'd tell a lie to a cop?
Shut up and answer this guy
as if he was a gentleman.
Yes, ma'am.
A young girl like you needs schooling.
A nicer environment.
Discipline.
You can't get that here.
I do too.
I don't walk a chalk line.
Min wears the life out of me.
Don't you, Min?
That's discipline, ain't it?
It certainly is.
Another complaint is that you've been
a party to the selling of liquor.
- You mean booze?
- Yeah.
You think we'd give that
bootleg stuff to the gang?
Why we wouldn't give that to Bill!
You've seen it around, haven't you?
Sometimes.
When some of the fellas
brings him a flask.
Then he breaks it over his head.
That's just how sore it makes him.
Say, you're not going
to take this kid away from me?
I think as much of her
as if she was my own kid.
I... who are you?
Perhaps you remember me?
I'm superintendent of Nancy's school.
We were very much interested
in her when she attended.
I thought now that she's going back.
You might let her come to our home.
Mrs. Southard will be very kind to her.
Can help a little in the household.
It will be a nice quiet
environment in which to study.
I don't want to go.
Now you shut up now.
No, she ain't going.
She's gonna stay right here with me.
Get that? Right re with me!
Of course, she can go to school though.
I don't mind if she goes to school.
Now you see that she's in school
tomorrow morning at 9 o'clock.
And if I have more complaints
about this place,
I'll see that it's closed up!
Yes, yes.
Gee that was a tight squeeze.
I'm gonna wet my whistle.
That was a swell lie I told
about the booze, wasn't it?
It sure was. I couldn't have
done much better myself.
Min, they can't take me from you.
I would just die.
Aw, cut the bull now.
Go on out in the kitchen where you
belong. Go on. Get out of here.
What does it read?
- 32.65.
- All right. Hand it over.
Nancy, how about a dance?
Swell.
Yeah, I'll take that too.
Hey! You get out in the kitchen
where you belong!
Go on, get out of here. Go on!
And Alec Johnson!
You watch your step!
Ohh!
You come out here and
I'll sock you in the jaw, Min.
Is that so?
Come on in here.
I'd like to see you try it.
You're a sneak. A sneaking thief.
That's what you are.
Gee Min, but you're a hellion.
Yeah.
I guess that's why I like you.
Is that so?
A bum. That's how you are.
So that's where you keep your socks.
You know it ain't safe.
Some dirty skunk might peek
through the keyhole some night.
Is that so?
Well, if he does,
I'm ready for him.
You trust me, don't you?
Sure I trust you. You're too dumb
to be anything but honest.
That's the same way I feel
about you, Min, too.
Gee, it's hot in here.
Open up a window or something.
No Bill,
nobody's gonna
get my hard-earned dough from me.
I've been over 40 years
saving up them dimes and nickels.
When I get enough, I'm going back
to Seattle, where I come from.
And I'm gonna buy myself
a sealskin cap. Mm-hm.
Yes and a new bridge
with three gold teeth in them.
- Min!
- What?
There's Alec with his arm
around some gal.
- It ain't Nanc is it?
- I think he is.
Don't whistle. Wait a minute.
Gee, it's swell out here.
You know, I love this old boat.
I used to come here when I was a kid.
I dreamed about going places.
You'll be going places before long.
And you won't be alone either.
Who's gonna take me, you?
You said it.
We'll sneak away, me and you.
And we'll go up to Frisco.
Yeah? Fat chance I've got
of getting anywhere.
Hey you know Nancy, you're
a lot prettier out here.
That's gotta stop.
You won't have to work
anymore if you come with me.
I know a way you can
make a lot of money.
Let me go.
You smell like hot steam.
Well? What's the idea?
You get in the house! Go on! Get!
Bill. Calm him down.
What's the idea?
Ain't Min asked you a dozen
times to let that kid alone?
Gee Min, I didn't do nothing.
Go on. Get up there. Go on.
I saw you fooling with Alec?
Oh I didn't do nothing, Min.
I washed dishes and
cooked stuff all day long.
Well, I'm crabbing about that.
Girls got to have some fun.
You call that fun?
- He didn't mean nothing by it.
- Hmm.
That's what you think.
I don't see why it ain't right
for me to dance and flirt
and have a good time like
the rest of the girls who come here.
- You don't?
- You don't try to stop them.
You tell them "Go out and dance and
have a good time in your joint."
But me.
Well you ain't gonna have a
say over me much longer.
I'll be old enough
to put makeup on and
dance and drink with
the gang if I want to.
- Then I'll show you.
- Yeah.
You'll be showing me.
That teacher and the cop was right.
This is no place for a kid like you.
What are you doing?
You're not going
to send me away, are you?
You're gonna live
with the school teacher.
Don't do it, Min.
I don't want to leave you.
- Now you stop...
- I'm sorry I made you sore.
Stop squawking now.
And go and pack your duds.
I'll be a good kid, I swear it.
Please don't send me away. No.
I want to stay here with you.
I'm sending you away because I don't
want you to make me no trouble.
I don't care nothing about you. Just me.
Go on now.
You ain't got no time to use.
Now we ain't got no time to lose.
Go on.
- Don't send me away.
- Now you listen to me.
No.
You may think she's no common kid.
Oh no.
Yeah, her father was a doctor
in the Northwest someplace.
And her mother brought her
on here when he died.
When she drifted in here,
she was dying when
she come to this place.
Well, that's all there is.
You see she ain't legally mine.
So there won't be
no papers to sign or nothing.
But I'm just like your own kid.
You can't send me away.
Why this is a swell joint.
Gee if you can't be happy here,
you're dumber than I thought you was.
Well, that's all there is to tell.
I guess I'll beat it.
Min! Min! Please!
Go on away.
I got my work to do.
Min, please!
Hello, Nancy, how are you?
Fine, how are you, Captain?
Fine.
Can I fish?
Sure. Help yourself.
Gee, that's great.
So you got homesick for us, did you?
You're darn right, I did.
That's why I'm back.
Up easy.
Did Min say so?
I don't know.
I stopped in to see her.
They said she was at the grocery.
But she'll let me stay when I explain.
Yeah?
Mm-hmm.
That's a great fish, Nancy.
Aw, gee!
How did I do that?
Oh, up to your old tricks again?
Here's your cap.
What you need is a darn good spanking.
Is that the way you treat a lady?
You're no gentleman!
You big abalone.
What's the matter with you?
Come on in here!
Say.
Say. What are you doing here?
Did you see what he did to me?
Yes, I did. And that's what
I ought to be doing to you.
What are you doing back here,
playing hooky?
I can't stand it any longer, Min.
I come back for good.
You think you come back for good.
You're gonna get right out of
here and go right back to school.
I can't go back, Min.
- You can't?
- No I-I-
What have you done?
- Uh...
- Well.
- I hit a girl in the eye.
- Well?
She called me wharf rat.
Why didn't you give her-
That's exactly what I did.
That isn't here or there.
You just go back to Southards
where you belong.
Now go on! Get out of here.
Oh Min, I can't stand it
at the Southards any longer.
The evenings are so quiet.
Gee, they don't ever have a fight.
Don't get sore.
It's just like a jail up there.
Well...
that's just what you're aiming to do.
Send me to jail.
What do you mean?
I mean just what I say.
If the cops don't find
you're not at school,
they'll take my license away.
You're just an ungrateful little brat.
That's what you are.
Trying to ruin my business.
Go on back to Southards where
you belong. Go on, on, on.
Go on now.
Oh but let me explain.
I'll explain.
Will you get out of here?
Go on now.
Please.
Give me just one more chance!
I'll give you a chance.
Get out of here. Go on now!
And I never want to see you here again!
Yeah.
He did?
That's funny.
Hello Min.
Hello, Min.
Hello, Bella Pringle.
What are you doing here?
You know what I'm doing here.
Come on upstairs to my room.
Wait a minute.
How long you been here?
About an hour.
Belle's my old friend of mine
from Seattle.
About 14 years since
we've seen each other.
Let's drink to old times.
You said it.
How long you gonna be here?
Oh I don't know.
Say.
I thought maybe I'd
look over the place.
And get the lay of the land.
Yeah. Stick around a bit.
Oh get you.
I don't mind, Bill.
Ain't nothing doing around here.
- Naw?
- No.
There's a boat going to Frisco
this afternoon.
Yeah?
Who says I was leaving
here this afternoon?
Come on, Bill.
Come on.
Show us the bottom of the bottle.
You're like a sieve, ain't you?
Belle, come on upstairs to my room.
Wait a minute. Will ya?
Wait a minute.
Here's to ya, big boy.
You ain't so bad.
I've seen worse.
Yeah, I've been told that before.
Hey Belle, I've got something
to tell you. Come on upstairs.
Come on.
Pardon me.
What are you doing here?
You know what I'm doing here.
- Where's my kid?
- She's dead.
- You're a liar!
- Who's a liar?
You're a liar.
She died in Fresno
five or six years ago.
What she die of?
You know she was a puny kid.
That's right.
- Tough luck for me, ain't it, Min?
- Yeah.
I thought that kid would take care
of me in my old age.
It's too bad.
Come on Bella, take off your duds
and rest a bit. You look all in.
- I'm a wreck.
- Yeah.
Ain't it just like a kid?
The more you do for them,
the more ungrateful they are.
I know. There ain't
no gratitude in the world.
There ain't nothing.
No there ain't. That's right.
- Nothing, I'm telling you.
- All right, Belle.
You just rest there a while.
You'll be all right now.
- Min?
- What?
Just one more little drink.
You'll find them in the bureau
drawer there. The last-
I'll be back in a minute.
Hi, baby.
Hello, big boy. Come on in.
How's chances for a little snort?
I won't be difficult.
Come on. Sit down.
Make yourself at home.
Here you are, kid.
Ma'll kill you for it.
What's the little thing, boy.
Why don't you turn
on something snappy?
That's the way I always feel when I
see a swell-looking guy like you.
You mean that?
And how!
Wait, I'll turn on the phonograph.
Make it snappy, baby.
- Oh how do you do?
- How do you do?
I come to see Nancy.
- Won't you sit down?
- No.
I can say what I got to say standing
on my feet as well as I can sit-
Min!
You've came for me!
Come for you? Nothing. Oh.
- How do you do?
- Hello.
We're so grateful to you
for sending Nancy home.
We think she'll be much
happier here as time goes on.
Yeah I hope you're right.
- Min, I...
- Will you shut up?
Say, her mother left some
money for her with me.
And I got it here
and it's a big wad too.
- Really?
- Yes, it's real.
I had intended to keep it myself.
But every once in a while,
my conscience goes crazy.
And I have to do the right thing.
Well anyhow...
when she was dying,
she says to me "Min..."
"when my Nancy grows up to be a girl,
I want you to see that she goes
to a young lady's school."
My mother said that?
Will you stop horning in?
When you gonna send her?
Now speak up quick before
you get the dough.
I know a very fine school up north.
The Westmoreland School.
A friend of mine is head of it.
That's the ticket. Here.
You see that see goes quick too.
Because she's never gonna get
nothing hanging around here.
Not that I give a hoop.
Min, you've been so kind to me.
Aw. Can the baloney, will ya?
- Won't you say goodbye?
- Goodbye.
And you see that behave yourself
the next joint you go to.
You come on out here.
I want to see you.
I just want to tell you.
Get that kid out of here before
24 hours or I'll take her back.
- But why?
- Never mind why. You just do it.
All right.
Why you dirty...
What kind of a drunk? Get out of here!
Hey Bill, wait!
I'll get you for that!
I'll get you someday!
Bill, she's trying to kill me!
Bill, help me.
Min's trying to kill me!
You filthy old wretch you.
You dirty old rotten louse!
Well.
That's what I'll give you.
I'll get you!
You come back!
You ain't mad at me, Min, are you?
No,
I ain't mad at you.
We just had a couple snifters.
And I got to feeling kind of wild.
Can’t you take a joke?
You stupid dummkopf!
Don't you talk to me.
Stop your fooling, will you, Min!
Oh now, Min!
Now, now, ho, Min.
No, Min. No, Min!
There goes my mother's picture!
Will you stop that?
Min, will you stop that!
Stop it, Min.
Stop what?
Come here. Come here!
Min, you're pulling my pants off.
Now stop that!
Stop this, Min.
Get this thing out of my eye,
will you?
Get your hands out of my-
Don't call me a dummy.
Stop that!
I'm warning you.
Stop it, will ya? Cut it out!
Cheat with me, will ya?
Hey, Min!
Dog gone you anyway!
Will you come here? Come here.
Come here, you prick.
Come here, you.
Come on out here!
Come on out here and finish this!
Go on away from here, Min.
And let me alone, will ya?!
What you so quiet for, Min?
You give up?
Give up?
Give up nothing. You come out!
Aw, stop that, dear.
Stop that, will ya?
Stop it.
Come out here and take
your licks like a man.
- Come on now!
- Stop it!
Give me that thing, will ya?
Give me that ax.
Give me the ax
before you hurt yourself, Min!
- Give me!
- Give me that.
You'll be sorry!
Dog gone you anyway.
I don't bite my arm!
Stop!
Now stop that, Min!
Min now mad.
Bill, you ain't hurt? Be ya?
Are you hurt, Bill?
Oh, gee. You made me so sore.
Bill!
Dear Min,
I'll be home soon.
And I do hope you
changed your mind about seeing me.
Last Christmas they told me
you had gone away.
And the day I was leaving,
I saw you on the wharf.
Bill, she seen me on the wharf.
You couldn’t hide that face
of yours with a beard.
It'd break my heart if I thought I'd
done anything to hurt your feelings.
After all your kindness to me.
Do you realize it's over two years
since we've seen each other?
I'm so grown up, you wouldn't know me.
Bill, she's grown up.
Sure, she is. Why not?
Do remember Dick Cameron?
I'll tell you a secret.
We're coming home on the same boat.
Oh Min, he's wonderful.
I'll tell you all about him
if you'll only see me.
- Say hello to Bill for me.
- Hello.
We're coming on the HS Alexandria.
With love and kisses, Nancy.
Bill, when does the Alexandria get in?
It docks in the morning.
The morning.
Oh don't go blubbering around.
Too windy?
Let's get married
as soon as we get home.
Dick, I'd love to have Min
come to the wedding.
Of course we'll ask her.
But I think she'll won't come.
I do.
If I beg her to.
She doesn't care for you
very much, does she?
Oh yes she does.
Then why doesn't she want to see you?
I don't know.
But I'll see her tomorrow.
And I know she'll be happy
when I tell her...
What's the excitement?
I'm sorry but gentlemen are not
allowed in the ladies' cabins.
Oh.
That's a lie.
There is no gentleman in my stateroom.
Besides, he ain't no gentleman.
Oh, it's snooty time.
We're not good for you.
You remember Dick.
Yes, I'm happy to see you.
How do you do?
Where's my grip? My valise.
- Hello Bella.
- Hello, old rigamathing.
What are you doing here?
I just thought I'd look
the old place over.
Are you coming down to the joint?
No. Not a chance.
Aw, come on. Let bygones be bygones.
I wouldn't be a bit surprised.
Min pays.
A nice kid came in this morning.
- She did?
- Sure, come on.
Come on, Bella.
You go right upstairs.
Hey Min.
You ain't gonna give me another sendoff
like you done a couple years ago.
Oh no. Everything's all right now,
Bella.
Where is that big bozo?
I don't know where he goes.
Hey, you. Come on back!
We're all friends again.
Yeah, we're all washed up, Bill.
All right.
Hey, listen you.
You never saw me before
in all your life.
I don't even know you.
Hi, you big hippo.
As far as I'm concerned,
you just stink.
Yeah? Yeah.
Aw, Min.
You can't guess who I just
saw down at the dock.
She had clean ears and...
What are you laughing, you hyena?
Was I laughing?
Maybe I was thinking about
something funny.
Okay, Min.
Hey, Min?
Hey, what?
Where is that hair tonic?
You drank it.
Oh, so I did.
Min, come here a minute.
Aw, what do you want?
The back of my hair needs
touching up a bit.
What it needs is a couple
of fine tooth combs.
If you find any gray hairs,
pull them out.
- Yeah.
- Oww!
If I pulled them all out,
you'd be bald as an egg.
A bad egg. That's me all right.
What's the matter, got the dropsy?
Oh say, Bella.
I got fine tonic down
in the barbershop.
I'll bring it right up. You wait here.
Don't you think you'd
better see her alone?
Maybe I had.
I won't be long.
Min, darling.
What are you doing here?
Didn't you get my letter?
Yeah I got your letter. What of it?
Well, I wanted to tell you about...
If you want to tell me anything,
you come on in the barbershop.
Go on.
Well...
Shoot. Get it off your chest.
Min, I'm going to be married.
To Dick Cameron.
And we want you
to come and live with us.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
Listen, Min.
We're going to live in Boston.
- In Boston?
- Yes.
He's going to have part
of his father's cannerys.
- Oh Min.
- Yeah.
We're going to have a sweet home.
With green terraces and gardens.
And a beautiful orchid room for you.
With windows that look
right out on the sea.
And I'd be at home
in a trellis in an orchid room.
Dick's going to give you a limousine
for a wedding present.
What is lemonzine?
One of those lovely motor cars.
Oh, automobile.
Think of it.
Can't you see us?
You and me...
staying in a home
with our noses in the air.
Oh it's just like a dream.
A dream... Say.
Now I want you to get this right
under your bonnet.
I ain't gonna never leave this joint.
And I ain't never gonna live on charity.
Oh, Min.
I didn't mean it that way.
You misunderstood me.
Well, understand this then.
You go live your life and
please let me live mine!
Charity!
But Min, Dick wants you.
Yeah? Now you go! Get out of here!
Ohh.
So it's the snooty girl
that I met on the boat, huh?
How do you do, dearie?
Min, you were so long
getting that hair tonic
I thought for goodness
you were drinking it.
Say, Bella,
what do you say you and me open a real
bottle just for the sake of old times?
Baby, you're an elk.
That's right.
What's the matter, Nancy?
She never wants to see me again.
What happened?
I tried to tell her what
we wanted to do for her.
Oh, Dick!
She just doesn't care anymore.
That's all right, honey. I do.
We'll forget all about her.
Going down the coast, Bill?
Yeah, going down off Mexico.
The tuna's running down off Magdalena.
How soon you shoving off?
About a half hour.
Gee ain't she a pip?
Yeah. That's Cameron's boat.
Young Cameron is gonna get married
today. They're going east in it.
Yes, Min was telling me.
She sure is a beaut.
Now cut them three times towards you.
- All right.
- That's it.
Keep your shirt on.
Yeah. Little nervous today, ain't you?
Oh there you go. Bellla?
- Yes?
- King of diamonds!
- You're gonna meet a rich guy.
- Ha!
Gee, Min. You're a pain
in the eye to me.
That's over.
Yes, sir, it is.
- Say, Bella.
- Yes?
Come on back here.
You're gonna wear diamonds.
- Yeah?
- Mm-hmm.
- Oh, I wouldn't be a bit surprised.
- Mm-hm.
Say, Min. Where's a curling iron?
What for?
What do you suppose what for?
To pick my teeth with?
I want to crimp my hair up.
In the top drawer of the
bureau there on this side.
All right.
Thinking of taking
the afternoon boat to Frisco?
I don't know.
Go on, talk. I ain't deaf.
I can hear you from here.
Whoa, you're gonna ride in a big car.
Oh a hoist?
Oh no, a swell car. Yours.
- Mine?
- Mm-hmm.
Gee I tell you when you get this guy,
you're gonna be sitting pretty.
- When I get him?
- Yes, it's all here in the cards.
Frisco is the place. I tell ya.
Yeah, that's a swell line, Min.
But I ain't thinking
of getting out of here.
- No?
- No.
- Ain't you?
- No, I ain't.
I kinda like this joint.
I think I'll stick around a while.
Well, I think you're foolish.
It's all here in the cards.
You think so, Min?
Gee, that must be the whistle
from the yacht, huh?
That's a fishing boat.
No, it ain't, Min.
I seen it this morning from the porch.
Alex pointed it out to me.
It belongs to the Camerons.
I hear that Cameron guy,
that young fella
is gonna get married this morning
to a girl by the name of Smith.
Oh.
- Ever hear of her?
- Sure.
There's a million Smiths around here.
They say she used to
hang around the waterfront.
I have never seen her.
That's a lie, Min! And you know it.
That's my kid.
What are you talking about,
Bella Pringle. You're crazy.
I ain't so crazy.
You can't make a fool of me no
longer, you dirty lying rat!
I don't know what your game is.
But you can't make a sucker
out of me no longer.
Now Bella!
You can throw me out
of your dirty old joint.
Now I'm gonna get even with you, Min.
For everything you ever done to me.
See?
Bella I...
I- I don't know what you mean.
What do I mean?
I'll show you what I mean!
I'll nail you on a cross.
You can you dirty little stuck-up brat.
Bella!
I'll teach ya.
You don't know what you're saying.
Oh I don't, huh?
The game is over, darling.
Yes, Bella.
At the end of a long journey.
You're darn right they'll
be diamonds around me.
And I'll see that I get them too.
And that she'll give them to me.
Or I'll know the reason why.
Hey.
The dirty little snob.
Turning up her nose against me
as if I'm not good enough for her.
You wouldn't hurt the kid.
Aw, say, please now...
Leave me alone, will ya? A fat chance!
She's a swell kid.
The first break she's ever had.
Break? I'll give her a break
for hiking out on me.
- It wasn't her fault.
- Ha!
She never even knowed she had a mother.
I suppose you told her
that the stork brought her.
Well, I told her you was dead.
That's where you're out of luck,
you filthy old liar.
I'm gonna show you up. Both of you.
You wouldn't do that. It'd kill her.
Say, this is her first chance
to be happy and respectable.
Respectable? Ha ha ha!
Respectable!
So she's gonna live in a swell house
on the top of a hill, is she?
And she's gonna have diamonds
and servants to wait on her?
And I'm gonna be right there
to get my share, believe me.
I'm gonna get those diamonds
you seen in my castle.
Or I'll know the reasons why.
He's gonna have a church wedding, huh?
And the mother's gonna be right there
in time to kiss the blushing bride.
If they see you at the church...
Aw, dry up, will ya?
You've had your say.
Aw, don't.
Don't look at me like that, Min.
I ain't afraid of ya!
I ain't afraid of any of ya!
If they don't like me,
they know what they can do.
They can pay me to get rid of me.
And plenty too.
If they don't do it, I'm gonna
yell it from the housetops.
I'm gonna stand on the corner
and I'm gonna spit at them!
So good-bye, Min.
I'll point my finger
right straight at her.
And tell her who she really is.
And what I think of her.
You know me, Min.
When I call a spade a spade,
nobody forgets.
Mm-hmm.
You ain't gonna leave this room.
No? Who's gonna stop me?
I'm gonna stop ya.
You ain't got the guts to do it.
You got you just where I want you.
Yeah?
Now you listen to me.
You, gutter rat!
You or nobody else is gonna
ruin that kid's chances!
No, sir.
I loved her with all the clumsy love
that I had.
And I'm gonna tell you something.
She's a swell kid.
Clean, loyal.
Even to an old sea cow like me.
And I'm warning you, Bella.
You ain't gonna leave the room!
I ain't?
No, you ain't.
- You mean that?
- Umm.
Gee!
Min!
Min.
What did you do that for?
What did you do it for?
That boat of mine is
all ready to go to Mexico.
You're going with me.
Min, come on. Let's go. Will ya, Min?
Bye!
- Bye!
- Goodbye, Nancy!
Min, let's go, will ya, please?
Let's go, Min.
Bye!
Come on.
What's the matter?
She ain't done nothing.
She knows. Come on!
Aw, don't get tough with her.
Watch Movies, TV Series & Live Sports
www.admitme.app