How we doing, Richard?
We should pass over the English coast
15 minutes ahead of time, sir.
Well, with this load on our
back, that's good going.
Just trust the RAF, sir.
- What the hell is that?
- The shuttle ignition.
Disappeared? And what
happened to the Moonraker?
Good God.
Yes, yes, of course, Minister. Right away.
Moneypenny, is 007 back
from that African job?
He's on his last leg, sir.
Any higher, Mr. Bond, my ears will pop.
I don't think I'm ever going
to fly with anyone else.
You're so right, Mr. Bond.
This is where we leave you, Mr. Bond.
A little premature, isn't it?
Enjoy your flight.
- Good morning, Moneypenny.
- James.
But why are you so late?
I fell out of an airplane
without a parachute.
- Who's in there?
- Q and the Minister of Defense.
You don't believe me, do you?
- And you should go right in.
- Yes, Moneypenny.
- 007. At last.
- Good morning, sir.
I think you know Frederick
Gray, Minister of Defense.
- Commander.
- Minister. Q.
007.
Moonraker?
- What do you know about Moonraker?
- What I read in the newspaper, sir.
Then you'll know that
Moonraker, the space shuttle,
was being flown over here
on loan from the Americans
on the back of a 747.
Yes, which crashed somewhere in the Yukon,
aircraft and shuttle totally
destroyed, correct?
- That's the official version.
- The truth is rather more disturbing, 007.
Look at this.
Now, that's the scene of the crash.
Wreckage strewn over a large area.
That's all that's left of the fuselage.
We've been through it
with a fine-toothed comb,
but there's no sign of
Moonraker, not a trace.
Are you suggesting the shuttle
was hijacked in midair?
That's for you to find out, 007.
The shuttles are built in
California by Drax Industries.
Yes. We were responsible for the
safety of that shuttle, Commander.
The United States government
is justifiably concerned.
I can imagine. Then, California
must be the place to start.
- I agree.
- Don't make any mistakes, 007.
The situation is critical. We've
got to find that shuttle.
Yes, sir.
If that's all, gentlemen...
Just a minute, 007. I've
got something for you.
Roll up your right sleeve, will you?
This is now being issued
as standard equipment.
Strap it on your wrist.
It's activated by nerve impulses
from the wrist muscles.
Like this?
Oh, thank you, 007.
- Be careful, will you?
- Yes, Q.
Ten darts, five blue-tipped
with armor piercing heads,
five red-tipped, cyanide coated,
causing death in 30 seconds.
Very novel, Q. You must get them
in the stores for Christmas.
Good morning, gentlemen.
- Welcome to California, Mr. Bond.
- I like it already.
My name is Corinne Dufour.
Oh, and you're going to be showing
me around, are you, Corinne?
No. I'm just a humble pilot in the
service of the Drax Corporation.
This is the Drax estate now. Everything
you see belongs to Mr. Drax.
- Owns a lot, doesn't he?
- What he doesn't own, he doesn't want.
We're approaching the main complex now.
That's where the Moonraker shuttle is made?
That's right, workshops, hangars,
design and experimental blocks,
test centers, everything.
Very impressive.
I'd heard that Hugo Drax is obsessed
with the conquest of space.
Now, I can believe it. Good Lord.
The Drax residence. Every
stone brought from France.
- Cute, isn't it?
- Magnificent.
Why didn't he buy the Eiffel Tower as well?
He did, but the French government
refused him an export permit.
Look there. Those are
the astronaut trainees.
Mr. Drax is financing the entire
training program out of his own pocket.
He seems to have an eye
for a good investment.
Mr. Drax will see Mr. Bond in
the drawing room, Miss Dufour.
- Thank you, Cavendish.
- This way, please, sir.
Mr. Bond, sir.
- Mr. Bond.
- Mr. Drax.
Allow me to present, before they
leave us, Countess Lubinski,
Lady Victoria Devon, Mr. Bond.
How do you do?
Well, my dear fellow, your
reputation precedes you, of course.
I'm honored that your government should
send you on so delicate a mission.
Delicate, Mr. Drax?
Well, to apologize in person for
the loss of my space shuttle.
How would Oscar Wilde have put it?
"To lose one aircraft may be
regarded as a misfortune,"
"to lose two seems like carelessness."
Well, an apology will be made to
the American government, Mr. Drax,
when we've discovered why there was no
trace of the Moonraker in that wreckage.
And your loyalty commands
respect, Mr. Bond.
You have arrived at a propitious moment,
coincident with your country's
one indisputable contribution
to Western civilization.
Afternoon tea.
- May I press you to a cucumber sandwich?
- Thank you, no, nothing at all.
The shuttle, is it made
entirely here in California?
No. I own a number of subsidiaries
throughout the world,
producing components.
The conquest of space represents
an investment in the future
of the entire human race, Mr. Bond.
It is, therefore, logical to seek out
the best that each nation has to offer.
- Are you referring to people or skills?
- Both, Mr. Bond.
- Am I too soon?
- Not at all.
I'm sure Mr. Bond is
eager to start his tour.
Miss Dufour will escort you to
Dr. Goodhead who will show you around.
Ask anything you like.
- Thank you for being so cooperative.
- A pleasure.
Look after Mr. Bond. See
that some harm comes to him.
You'll find Dr. Goodhead
first on the right.
- Oh. Thank you for the ride.
- Call on me if you need anything.
Good afternoon.
- Can I help you?
- Yes. My name is Bond.
James Bond. I'm looking for Dr. Goodhead.
- You just found her.
- A woman.
Your powers of observation
do you credit, Mr. Bond.
James, to my friends.
Holly Goodhead.
- Are you training to be an astronaut?
- I'm fully trained.
On loan from NASA, the
Space Administration.
Well, Mr. Bond, I guess
we'd better get started.
You don't want to lose time as
well as a space shuttle, do you?
This is it, the Moonraker.
Capable of being launched
into space by rocket...
Orbiting the Earth and reentering
the atmosphere to land
like any conventional aircraft.
This is the centrifuge training.
It simulates the gravity force
you feel when shot into space.
The speed is controlled by the
instructor from up there.
Why not try it?
Why not?
- Strap yourself in firmly.
- Yes, Doctor.
Now your arms.
That's to prevent you from
knocking yourself out.
I see.
How fast does it go?
It can go up to 20 Gs,
but that would be fatal.
Three Gs is equivalent
to take-off pressure.
Most people pass out at seven.
You make a great saleswoman.
You don't have to worry. This is
what we call a "Chicken Switch."
You just keep your finger on that button,
the moment the pressure gets too
much for you, release the button
- and the power's cut off.
- Just like that?
Come on, Mr. Bond. A 70-
year-old can take 3 Gs.
Well, the trouble is there is never a
70- year-old around when you need one.
- You want me?
- Mr. Drax says to telephone him.
All right, I'll call him from my office.
You go ahead. I'll be right back.
The instructor will supervise the session.
Enjoy yourself.
Yes. We're taking good care of him.
I don't know what could've happened.
Something must've gone
wrong with the controls.
Let me help you.
My mother gave me a list of
things not to do on a first date.
Maybe you won't need it.
That's not what I came for.
No. What do you want then?
Would your feelings be shattered
if I were to say information?
- Why should I tell you anything?
- Why, indeed?
You presume a great deal, Mr. Bond.
What goes on here besides the
manufacture of Moonraker?
And the astronaut training program?
There are other laboratories,
but not much is happening now.
No?
They were working on something very
secret, but everything's been moved.
Where to?
I don't know.
What about that list of your mother's?
I never learned to read.
What are you doing?
You whetted my appetite for information.
Is there a safe in here? Thank you.
James, no.
That's amazing.
There you are, you see?
You have a heart of gold.
Eighteen karat.
You must go.
Well, you go first. I'll
turn off the lights.
Thank you.
- Take care of yourself.
- And you.
My dear Bond.
This is Mademoiselle Deladier
and La Signorina del Mateo.
- Ladies.
- I'll see you at lunch.
A pity you leave us. Such good sport.
Unless you're a pheasant.
Really, Mr. Bond. Take my gun,
a stray bird may fly over.
I only stopped to thank
you for your hospitality.
Fraser will get you to the
airport in plenty of time.
Come now.
- I doubt if I'm in your class.
- Oh, you're too modest, Mr. Bond.
Over there.
You missed, Mr. Bond.
Did I?
As you said, such good sport.
You called for me, Mr. Drax.
You were with Bond last night in my study.
No, I...
- You showed him the safe.
- I didn't.
I'm terminating your employment.
You will leave immediately.
Franco, I'll call you to
tell you where to meet me.
Could I interest you in something?
Why, I'm tempted to say yes immediately.
But I think maybe I'd
better have a look around.
Please. Go anywhere you wish.
And in 1955, the Venini
Museum and Glass Works
was taken over by Drax Industries.
And here, ladies and gentlemen, we
have some of the rarest examples
of the glassblower's art.
As you know, everything was
done absolutely by hand.
Here is a vase done by Lorenzo Graziati,
sometime between 1850 and 1860. If
you'd like to follow me over here.
This exquisite bowl was fashioned
about 1520, over 450 years ago.
If it ever came on the market,
it would certainly fetch a price
in excess of one million American dollars.
But if any of you are
thinking of taking it...
Now, we have here a very
early 17th century dish
with an aquamarine medallion.
Over here, we have something
very, very interesting.
This glass-handled sword,
the only one of its kind in the world,
was owned by General Menotti
in the late 18th century
and is the work of Bruno...
14th century.
Dr. Goodhead.
I can only hope your presence
here is a coincidence, Mr. Bond.
- I dislike being spied on.
- Well, don't we all?
You're staying at the Danieli, aren't you?
- Yes. How did you know?
- Well, I like to keep abreast of things.
May I ask what you're doing in Venice?
I'm addressing a seminar of the
European Space Commission.
My, heavy stuff.
But there again, I keep
forgetting that you are
more than just a very beautiful woman.
If you're trying to be ingratiating,
Mr. Bond, don't bother.
I have more important things on my mind.
That's what I'd like to talk to you about.
- Dinner this evening?
- This evening I'm giving my address.
Well, then, can you think of reason
why we don't have a drink afterwards?
Not immediately. But I'm sure I shall.
Franco.
Play it again, Sam.
- What the hell are you doing here?
- Convalescing.
Your friend Cha just tried to kill me.
And you think I had
something to do with it?
Well, the thought had
flashed across my mind.
- What's Drax up to in that laboratory?
- Why don't you ask him yourself?
- You leaving me your telephone number?
- I don't see the point.
Now I do.
Not what I want to get stuck with tonight.
James, why don't you pour yourself a drink?
Thank you.
Daily diary.
Fairly deadly diary.
Bollinger. If it's '69,
you were expecting me.
Trifle overpowering, your scent.
Standard CIA equipment.
And the CIA placed you with Drax, correct?
- Very astute of you, James.
- Oh, not really.
I have friends in low places.
Could this possibly be the moment
for us to pool our resources?
It could have its compensations.
Where are you planning on going from here?
I'm not planning on going anywhere.
Oh, I suppose you're right, Holly. We
would be better off working together.
- Detente?
- Agreed.
- Understanding?
- Possibly.
- Cooperation?
- Maybe.
- Trust?
- Out of the question.
Send the night porter up for
my bags immediately, please.
I hope you know what you're doing, Bond.
I've played bridge with this fellow Drax.
007 doesn't usually push the panic
button unless it's something serious.
- I should hope not.
- Good morning, Inspector.
- Good morning.
- I see you've covered everything
- with our Italian friends.
- Yes, sir.
- Is this it?
Gas masks?
We can't afford to take
any chances, Minister.
Frederick Gray. What a surprise.
And in distinguished company,
all wearing gas masks.
You must excuse me,
gentlemen, not being English,
I sometimes find your sense of
humor rather difficult to follow.
On behalf of the British
government, I apologize.
I think you owe us an explanation, 007.
I've never been so humiliated in my life.
Your man should be taken
off the assignment.
I'll see you at the consulate.
I'll have to do what he says.
Well, before you do that, sir,
have Q do an analysis of this.
I took it from the laboratory.
Tell him to exercise extreme caution.
It is lethal.
So, there was a laboratory.
You better take two weeks
leave of absence, 007.
Do have any thoughts about
where you might go?
I've always had a hankering
to go to Rio, sir.
I think I can recall your mentioning it.
007, no slipups or we're both in trouble.
Yes, a minor crisis has been averted.
No, no, nothing serious,
but all merchandise
is to be rerouted as from today.
Now, regarding a replacement for Cha,
do you have someone in mind?
Oh, yes, well, if you
can get him, of course.
Flight BA128 to Rio de Janeiro
now boarding, gate number seven.
Welcome to Rio, Mr. Bond.
- The President Suite.
- Really?
Well, don't bother showing me the rest.
If I get lost, I'll take a cab.
- Do you come with the suite?
- It depends who's renting it.
Vodka martini? Shaken not stirred.
Why were you following me from the airport?
I was trying to meet you.
My name is Manuela.
I work for Station VH. We have
been asked to assist you.
M thinks of everything.
Tell me, Manuela, do the initials
C and W mean anything to you?
C and W? Yes, Carlos and Wilmsberg.
They are very big importers in Rio.
A subsidiary of the Drax Group, I believe.
They have a warehouse on Carioca Avenue.
I'd like to pay it a
discreet visit tonight.
Tonight? I think you may find
that a little difficult.
Difficult or not, it's
something we have to do.
And meanwhile,
how do you kill five hours
in Rio if you don't samba?
- There's the warehouse.
- And not a soul about.
- I think there's a way around the back.
- Good thinking.
This is it.
Don't talk to any strange men.
I'll be back.
- Are you all right?
- Yes, but I'd rather dance with you.
I did tell you not to
talk to any strange men.
- Did you find anything in there?
- Only this.
"Drax Air Freight."
Do you know which airport
they operate from?
Yes. San Pietro. Do you
want me to take you there?
No, I think you need some rest.
- Come on. I'll drop you off.
- Okay.
- Haven't we met before somewhere?
- The face is familiar, as is the manner.
It's become distinctly chilly since Venice.
Well, that was before you walked out on me.
Yes, nearly tripping over your
suitcase on the way through the door.
So?
So why waste time working
against each other?
I've checked Drax's warehouse in town.
It's empty.
That's no surprise. Since I've been here,
those planes have been
taking off every two hours.
- Yes. He's moving out.
- Where to?
That's what we're going to find out,
now that we're working together.
- I still don't know if I trust you.
- I don't know if I trust you either.
That's what makes it more
exciting, doesn't it?
- What's wrong?
- I don't know.
But I'm sure we're better off out than in.
Bring that chain.
- Hang on, James.
- The thought had occurred to me.
I might have guessed.
- Do you know him?
- Not socially.
His name's Jaws. He kills people.
Here, give me the chain.
Come on. Hang on to me.
Jump.
- Have you broken something?
- Only my tailor's heart.
- What was that for?
- For saving my life.
Remind me to do it more often.
Oh, thank you, but we're in great shape.
Sorry about that.
James! You look as though you've
just fallen off a mountain.
Well, it's funny you should
say that, Moneypenny.
As a matter of fact, I was
in a cable car and...
- Never mind.
- The other courtyard.
- There you are, 007.
- Balls, Q?
Bolas, 007.
- Good. Have that ready for Army Day.
- Yes, sir.
- Where's M?
- He's in the office over there.
This way.
- Good morning, 007.
- Good morning, sir.
- You're just in time. Sit down.
- Thank you, sir.
- Q's come up with something.
- Splendid.
- Any news of Dr. Goodhead?
- Afraid not. Right, Q.
Well, it's a breakdown on that phial
of liquid you picked up in Venice.
- You know, you seem to be right, 007.
- Thank you.
It's a highly toxic nerve gas that
appears to have no effect on animals.
May I see the formula?
It's a chemical formula of a plant.
Orchideae anegra. A very
rare orchid indeed.
Yes. It was thought to be extinct.
Until a missionary brought one back
from the upper reaches of the Amazoco.
Well, actually he brought it back
from the area of the River Tapirape.
Well done, James. You better
get up there and fast.
And I've got something to get him there,
if 007 can be trusted to look after it.
Mr. Bond, you defy all my attempts
to plan an amusing death for you.
You're not a sportsman, Mr. Bond.
Why did you break off the
encounter with my pet python?
I discovered he had a crush on me.
Jaws.
Moonraker One on preset launch
program, minus two minutes.
Retract crew access arm.
CAA retracted.
- Transfer orbiter power.
- Internal power transferred.
Activate hydraulics.
- Hydraulics activated.
- Activate auxiliary power unit.
- APU activated.
- LH2 replenish.
- Status confirmed.
- Pressurize MPS helium tanks.
Helium flight pressure confirmed.
What exactly are you up to here, Drax?
- And why the orchids?
- The curse of a civilization.
It was neither war nor pestilence
that wiped out the race
who built the great city lying around us.
It was their reverence
for this lovely flower.
Because long-term exposure to
its pollen caused sterility.
Correct, Mr. Bond.
As you discovered, I have
improved upon sterility.
Those same seeds now yield death.
Not, of course, to animals or plant life.
One must preserve the balance of nature.
Moonraker launch program now commencing.
Minus 20 seconds.
- SRB gimbal profile.
- Activated.
- Cooling pumps.
- On.
- IMU to inertial.
- IMU confirmed.
Moonraker One, liftoff.
We have liftoff.
Moonraker Two, T minus ten,
nine, eight, seven, six,
five, four, three, two, one.
Main engine start.
Moonraker Two, liftoff.
- Moonraker Three.
- Moonraker Three, liftoff.
- Moonraker Two, confirm program pitch.
- PP confirmed.
Moonraker Four on preset launch program.
Moonraker Four, liftoff.
Moonraker One, SRB jettison.
We have separation. Confirmed.
Moonraker Three, confirm program pitch.
Moonraker Five, on preset launch program.
- Minus ten...
- Drax, one more thing.
You delivered a shuttle to the U.S.
government,
then you hijacked it. Why?
Because I needed it.
One of my own Moonrakers developed
a fault during assembly.
Now, you have distracted me enough.
Jaws, Mr. Bond must be cold after his swim.
Place him where he can
be assured of warmth.
- Confirmed.
- Moonraker Two, go for orbit.
Velocity, 1,000 feet per second.
- All systems...
- SRB jettison.
Separation motors fired.
Moonraker Five, cleared for launch.
James.
Thank God, you're safe.
Moonraker Five, transfer orbiter power.
Hydraulics activated.
- Activate auxiliary power unit.
- APU activated.
- LH2 replenish.
- Confirm.
Even in death, my munificence is boundless.
When this rocket lifts off,
I shall be leaving you in
your own private crematorium.
Mr. Bond, Dr. Goodhead, I bid you farewell.
- EPS, power on.
- EPS, power confirmed.
Come on, the air vent.
Fuel tanks go, and go.
Moonraker Five, preset.
External LH2 pressure.
- Retract crew access arm.
- CAA retracted.
Get back quick.
T minus ten seconds, nine,
seven,
- six, five, four...
- Bang on time.
- Four, three, two...
- Come on, quick.
Straight on.
Moonraker Six, astro-technicians
prepare to embark.
I repeat, Moonraker Six
astro-technicians, prepare to embark.
- Moonraker Five crew.
- All systems go.
Moonraker Six, start launch sequence.
- Go for orbit.
- Confirm.
We have separation.
Moonraker Five ground crew stand down.
Thrust 6.8 million pounds.
We're going the wrong way.
Moonraker Six, preset
launch program completed.
Pilots proceed from base to launch area.
Shuttle go. Boosters go.
Launch pad go.
- External LO2 pressure?
- Confirmed, 21 psia.
- External LH2 pressure?
- Confirmed, 42.5 psia.
- IECF to internal power.
- CAA retracted.
Moonraker Six cleared for launch.
T minus 10 seconds.
Nine, eight, seven, six, five, four,
three, two, one, go.
It's all right. We're on a
prearranged flight program.
That's Drax in Moonraker Five.
- What about the others?
- I don't know. Let's see.
We're all on parallel courses.
So, we must be headed for
a rendezvous in orbit.
Let's see what cargo we have.
- The animals went in two by two.
- What do you mean by that?
Noah's Ark. This operation.
We're converging.
- Control rockets?
- Yes, we're slowing down.
What's that?
There's no image on the radar scanner.
An entire city in space and still
nothing on the radar scanner.
- So nobody on Earth knows it's there.
- Right.
Drax must have a radar-jamming system.
All Moonrakers prepare to
initiate docking procedures
and continue radio silence.
Moonraker Six, you are now in manual.
Initiate docking sequence.
All shuttles now docked. Execute
station activation procedure.
Gravity, normal conditions.
Life-support system, nominal.
Moonraker Six technicians,
commence operational sequence.
- Sequence four initiated.
- Check airlock seals.
ALS secure.
All personnel to Command satellite.
All crews to M5 segment.
Moonraker Six technicians to M2 segment.
Moonraker One and Three to M1 segment.
Moonraker Four and Five to M4 segment.
Moonraker Two to M5 segment.
Units four and seven,
man console as planned.
Units one, three, five and six,
assume pre-assigned stations.
- Pressure on-line?
- Confirmed.
- Life support?
- Normal.
Those are the globes I saw in Venice
with the nerve gas phials inside.
First there was a dream.
Now there is reality.
Here in the untainted cradle of the heavens
will be created a new super-race,
a race of perfect physical specimens.
You have been selected as
its progenitors, like gods.
Your offspring will return to Earth
and shape it in their image.
You have all served in humble
capacities in my terrestrial empire.
Your seed, like yourselves,
will pay deference to the ultimate
dynasty which I alone have created.
From their first day on Earth
they will be able to look up
and know that there is law
and order in the heavens.
All units, start Operation Orchid.
If we were visible from
Earth, they'd investigate.
Where do you suppose that
radar-jamming system is?
We didn't pass anything on the
way here, so let's try this way.
Station two, check coordinates, mode four.
Initiate globe launch timing sequence.
Orbital communicator, level 10.
Zero gravity.
This is it, the radar-jamming system.
- Coordinate conversion program.
- Check.
- Side lobe gain.
- Spectral response.
- Check.
- Spin stabilizer correction factor.
- Okay.
Gigahertz reflector efficiency.
Solar photon screen.
Where did you learn to
fight like that? NASA?
No, Vassar.
- Switched off?
- Permanently.
Now we can be spotted from Earth.
- This doesn't look good at all.
- It's over 200 meters in diameter.
Yes, yes.
Will you please listen, General Gogol?
We didn't put it up there.
Neither did we, Colonel Scott.
So what are you suggesting?
We've taken action already. We're
sending up a vehicle to intercept.
Very well, but if we don't hear
from you in the next 12 hours
we take action ourselves and hold you
responsible for the consequences.
We'll be in touch, General.
- Sorry to have woken you.
- I was already awake.
How can I sleep? Nothing but problems.
Problems, problems.
Marine astronauts to launch pad.
- Launch pre-program complete, sir.
- Launch globe number one.
T.D.R.S.S. reports a launch, sir.
Continental U.S.A. Vandenberg.
There are no launches scheduled.
Check radar-jamming system.
Well?
Jamming power supply and
backup have failed, sir.
- Investigate immediately.
- Investigate number 28, immediately.
James Bond.
You appear with the tedious
inevitability of an unloved season.
I didn't think there were
any seasons in space.
As far as you're concerned, only winter.
And the treacherous Dr. Goodhead.
Despite your efforts, my finely wrought
dream approaches its fulfillment.
Your dream, whatever sort of nightmare
it is, hasn't a chance, Drax.
You think not? We shall see.
We're coming up to second launch position.
Launch globe number two.
No doubt you have realized the
splendor of my conception.
First, a necklace of death about the Earth.
50 globes, each releasing its
nerve gas over a designated area,
each capable of killing 100 million people.
And the human race as you
know it will cease to exist.
Then a rebirth, a new world.
U.S. spacecraft on course
to intercept us, sir.
Activate laser. Prepare
to destroy spacecraft.
You see, my dear Bond, we're well able to
protect ourselves against all enemies.
Allow me to introduce you
to the airlock chamber.
Observe, Mr. Bond, your route
from this world to the next.
And you, Dr. Goodhead.
Your desire to be America's
first woman in space
will shortly be fulfilled.
Leaving you on your flying stud farm,
conceiving your new master race?
If you like, yes.
And of course, anyone not measuring up
to your standards of physical perfection
- will be exterminated.
- Certainly.
Interesting.
Most interesting.
Jaws, expel them.
Jaws! You obey me!
Expel them!
Hold them!
Sir, U.S. spacecraft, three
minutes to intercept.
Stand by to laser it.
- Initiate firing sequence.
- Initiating.
U.S. spacecraft in laser
range, 25.5 and closing.
Range 15.
Range 10.
Prepare to fire. Five, four, three, two...
It's stopped rotating.
Open the cargo doors.
Number one platoon, EVA.
Let's try docking.
Colonel Scott will take the first landing!
Intruders have docked at
satellite seven, sir.
Double the guard at every
entrance in this satellite.
Report intruders' progress
throughout the space station.
Number three globe ready
for launching, sir.
Proceed!
Group One, attack enemy.
All units shoot to kill.
- Colonel Scott, don't shoot.
- Hold your fire.
Corridor five penetrated. Intruders
advancing on Command satellite.
Maintenance crew needed, section three.
At least I shall have the pleasure
of putting you out of my misery.
Desolated, Mr. Bond?
Heartbroken, Mr. Drax.
Allow me.
Take a giant step for mankind.
- Where's Drax?
- He had to fly.
How's Scott doing?
He's got control of the Command satellite.
We put the launching gear for
the globes out of action.
When the station breaks up, they'll disintegrate.
They'll harm no one.
But the three that have gone,
they'll kill millions.
Those three must be destroyed.
Come on!
Colonel, get your men off
as quickly as possible.
Your mission is completed.
Sergeant, round up your men, get
them back to the shuttle. Fast!
Back to the shuttle, everybody!
On the double!
Moonraker Five, that's the answer.
Drax's shuttle is armed with a laser.
We can track those globes and destroy them.
It's hopeless, sir. The corridor's blocked.
They can't get to us now.
All right, let's go.
Docking release system is jammed.
Release the door lock. I'll see
if I can operate it manually.
It's jammed too.
Well, here's to us.
Jaws, we can't disengage. The
docking release system is jammed.
Can you help us?
We're free.
Don't worry, they'll make it.
It's only 100 miles to Earth.
Let's get a read-out on those globes.
I have the three globes on the screen.
We should have a visual in a minute.
There it is.
The laser's on automatic. Code 945 set.
One down, two to go.
Number two straight ahead.
What is it?
We're skipping on the Earth's atmosphere.
In range.
- We should see the last one soon.
- There it is.
- It's getting hot.
- It can't be helped.
I'm coming in at a steeper angle than I
should in order to catch that last globe.
I can't hold this course much longer.
We'll break up at 200,000 feet.
Just a few seconds more.
Automatic firing system negative. Must be the heat.
Switching to manual.
Controls aren't responding.
- The wings are beginning to glow.
- Just hold her steady.
Steady.
It's entering Earth's atmosphere!
James, this is our last chance.
Steady.
Colonel Scott reports picking up two
survivors from the space station,
a tall man and a short blonde woman.
Right. Okay.
Dr. Goodhead reported their
position 20 minutes ago.
They're just coming into range of our
tracking ship in the Pacific Ocean.
We should have audiovisual
within a few minutes
from the remote onboard TV monitors.
Houston calling Dr. Goodhead. Houston calling.
Confirm your position.
As this is the first joint venture
between our two countries,
I'm having it patched directly to the
White House and Buckingham Palace.
Well, I'm sure Her Majesty
will be fascinated.
- We have audiovisual.
- At last.
- 007.
- My God, what's Bond doing?
I think he's attempting re-entry, sir.
- James?
- I think it may be time to go home.
Take me round the world one more time.
Why not?