There was a boy
A very strange enchanted boy
They say he wandered very far
Very far
Over land and sea
Don't be fooled! Evil!
A little shy
Turn away from this village of sin!
And sad of eye
But very wise...
... was he
And then one day
A magic day...
...he passed my way
And while we spoke of many things
Fools and kings
This he said to me
The greatest thing
You'll ever learn
Is just to love
And be loved...
...in return
The Moulin Rouge.
A nightclub...
...a dance hall and a bordello...
...ruled over by Harold Zidler.
A kingdom of nighttime pleasures...
... where the rich played with...
...the young and beautiful creatures
of the underworld.
The most beautiful of all these...
... was the woman who I loved.
Satine.
A courtesan, she sold her love to men.
They called her
"The Sparkling Diamond. "
And she was the star...
...of the Moulin Rouge.
The woman I loved...
...is...
...dead.
I first came to Paris...
...one year ago.
It was 1899, the Summer of Love.
I knew nothing of the Moulin Rouge,
Harold Zidler or Satine.
The world had been swept up in a
Bohemian revolution, and I had...
...come to be a part of it.
On the hill near Paris
was the village of Montmartre.
It was not,
as my father said--
A village of sin.
--but the center of
the Bohemian world.
Musicians, painters, writers.
They were known as
the Children of the Revolution.
I had come to live a penniless
existence. I had come to...
... write about truth, beauty,
freedom...
...and that which I believed in
above all things: love.
Always this ridiculous obsession
with love!
There was one problem.
I'd never been in love.
Just then, an unconscious Argentinean
fell through my roof.
He was joined by a dwarf
dressed as a nun.
How do you do?
My name is Henri Marie Raymond
Toulouse-Lautrec-Montfa.
l'm terribly sorry. We were upstairs
rehearsing a play.
A play. Something very modern called
Spectacular, Spectacular.
lt's set in Switzerland.
The unconscious Argentinean
suffered from narcolepsy.
Perfectly fine one moment,
then unconscious the next.
How is he?
Wonderful.
The Argentinean is unconscious.
Now the play will not be ready to
present to the financier tomorrow.
-l still have to finish the music.
-Someone else can read the part.
Where on earth will we find
someone to play...
...a young, sensitive
Swiss poet goatherder?
Soon I was upstairs, standing in
for the unconscious Argentinean.
The hills animate
With the euphonious symphonies
Of descant
Oh, stop!
Stop that insufferable droning!
lt's drowning out my words!
Just stick to some decorative piano.
There were artistic differences
over Audrey's lyrics.
A nun wouldn't say that
about a hill.
How about, "The hills are vital
intoning the descant"?
"The hills quake and shake--"
"The hills are incarnate
with symphonic melodies"!
"The hills--" "The hills--"
The hills...
...are alive...
... with the sound of...
...music
"The hills are alive with
the sound of music." l love it!
The hills are alive...
-...with the sound...
-...of music.
lt fits perfectly!
With songs they have sung
For a thousand years
lncandiferous!
-You should write the show together.
-Excuse me?
Toulouse's suggestion was not
what Audrey wanted to hear.
Goodbye!
Here's to your first job in Paris.
Toulouse, Zidler will never agree.
Have you ever written a play before?
No.
The boy has talent!
l like him.
Nothing funny.
l just like talent.
"The hills are alive
with the sound of music."
With Christian, we can write...
...the Bohemian revolutionary show
we always dreamt of.
How will we convince Zidler?
Toulouse had a plan.
Satine.
They'd dress me in a suit and
say I was a famous English writer.
Once Satine heard my poetry,
she'd be amaZed and insist that...
...I write Spectacular, Spectacular.
But I kept hearing my father's voice:
You'll end up wasting your life at
the Moulin Rouge with a cancan dancer!
-l can't write the show!
-Why not?
l don't know if l am
a Bohemian revolutionary.
-Do you believe in beauty?
-Yes.
-Freedom?
-Of course.
-Truth?
-Yes.
Love?
Love? Love?
Above all things,
l believe in love.
Love is like oxygen.
Love is a many-splendored thing.
Love lifts us up where we belong.
All you need is love!
You can't fool us! You're the voice
of the Children of the Revolution!
We can't be fooled!
To the writer of the world's first
Bohemian revolutionary show!
It was the perfect plan.
I was to audition for Satine
and taste my first glass of absinthe.
There was a boy....
l am the green fairy.
The hills are alive
With the sound of music
Freedom, beauty...
...truth and love
The hills are alive
With the sound of music
We were off to the Moulin Rouge.
I would perform my poetry
for Satine.
Harold Zidler and his infamous girls.
They called them his "Diamond Dogs. "
Hey, sister, go, sister
Soul sister, go, sister
If life's an awful bore
And living's just a chore
That you do 'cause death's not much fun
I've just the antidote
And though I mustn't gloat
At the Moulin Rouge
You'll have fun
So scratch that little niggle
Give a little wiggle
You know that you can
Because we...
...can cancan
Don't say you can't can't can't
You know you can cancan
Don't say you can't
Because you can
Here we are now
Entertain us
We feel stupid
And contagious
Got some dark desire
Love to play with fire
Why not let it rip?
Live a little bit
We can cancan
Don't say you can't can't can't
You know you can cancan
You can cancan
Outside, it may be raining
But in here it's entertaining!
If you love love love
To be free free free
The Moulin Rouge is the place to be
Because we can cancan!
Yes, we can cancan!
Here we are now
Entertain us
Outside, things may be tragic
But in here, we feel it's magic
The cancan.
Because we can cancan!
Go, sister
Soul sister
Hey, sister, go, sister
Soul sister, go, sister
Because we can cancan!
Yes, we can cancan!
Creole Lady Marmalade
Because we can cancan!
'Cause it's good for your mind!
Mission accomplished.
We've successfully evaded Zidler.
lt's her! The Sparkling Diamond.
The French are glad to...
...die for love
They delight...
...in fighting duels
But someone else was to
meet Satine that night.
But I prefer...
...a man who lives
Zidler's investor.
And gives expensive...
...jewels
The Duke.
A kiss on the hand
May be quite continental
But diamonds are
A girl's best friend
A kiss may be grand
But it won't pay the rental
On your humble flat
Or help you feed your pussycat
Men grow cold
As girls grow old
And we all lose our charms in the end
But square cut or pear-shaped
These rocks don't lose their shape
Diamonds are a girl's best friend
When will l meet the girl?
Tiffany's!
After her number. l've arranged a
special meeting, just you and Satine.
Totally alone.
Cartier!
After her number, l've arranged
a private meeting.
-Just you and Satine. Totally alone.
-Alone?
Yes, totally alone.
'Cause we are living
In a material world
And I am a material girl
Come and get me, boys.
Excuse me.
Black Star! Roscor!
Talk to me, Harry Zidler!
Tell me all about it!
There may come a time
When a lass needs a lawyer
But diamonds are
A girl's best friend
There may come a time
When a hard-boiled employer thinks
You're awful nice
Don't worry. l'll sally forth
and tee things up!
-ls the Duke here?
-Liebchen, would Daddy let you down?
Terribly sorry.
Where is he?
Toulouse is shaking a hanky at him.
Excuse me, Christian. May l borrow?
-Are you sure?
-Let me peek.
l'm ever so sorry! How embarrassing!
That's the one. l hope that demonic
little loon doesn't frighten him off.
Clean yourself up, you bourgeois pig!
Sorry.
-Will he invest?
-Pigeon!
After spending the night with you,
how could he refuse?
What's his type? Wilting flower?
Bright and bubbly?
Or smoldering temptress?
l'd say smoldering temptress.
We're all relying on you, gosling.
Remember, a real show in a real theater,
with a real audience...
...and you'll be....
A real actress.
'Cause that's when those louses
Go back to their spouses
Diamonds...
l have exciting news!
...are a girl's...
...best...
...friend
l believe you were expecting me.
Yes. Yes.
l'm afraid it's lady's choice.
l see you've met my English friend--
l'll take care of it.
Let's dance.
Hit her with your most modern poem!
To the beat of the rhythm of the night
Dance until the morning light
Forget the worries on your mind
You can leave them all behind
That went well.
-lncredible.
-He has a gift with the women.
l told you. He's a genius.
That Duke certainly can dance.
How wonderful of you to
take an interest in our show.
lt sounds very exciting.
l'd be delighted to be involved.
Assuming you like what l do.
l'm sure l will.
Toulouse thought we might be able to...
...do it in private.
-Did he?
-Yes, you know, a private...
...poetry reading.
A "poetry reading."
l love a little "poetry"
after supper.
Hang on to your hat!
Diamonds
Square cut...
...or pear-shaped
These rocks...
... won't lose their shape
Diamonds...
...are a girl's...
...best....
Satine! Satine! Satine!
l doubt the Duke will get
his money's worth tonight.
Don't be unkind, Nini.
You've frightened her away.
But l can see some lonely
Moulin Rouge dancers...
...looking for a partner or two!
So if you can Hunk Hunk...
...you can Hunkadola with them!
Out of my way!
Oh, Marie.
Oh, these silly costumes.
Just a fainting spell.
Back out front, girls.
Make those gents thirsty. Problems?
-Nothing to worry about.
-Don't stand around, then.
Come out of the garden, baby
You'll catch your death in the fog
Young girls
They call them the Diamond Dogs
Find Zidler.
The girl's waiting for me.
That twinkle-toes Duke
took the bait, girl.
A patron like him, you could be
the next Sarah Bernhardt.
Do you really think l could be like
the great Sarah?
Why not? You got the talent.
You hook that Duke and you'll be
lighting the great stages of Europe.
l'll be a real actress, Marie.
A great actress.
l'm gonna fly away from here.
l'm gonna fly, fly away.
-Duckling, are you all right?
-Of course, Harold.
Thank goodness!
You certainly weaved your magic
with the Duke on the dance floor.
How do l look?
Smoldering temptress?
My little strawberry...
...how could he possibly resist
gobbling you up?
Everything's going so well!
I'll meet you in the red room
Unbelievable!
Straight to the elephant.
This is a wonderful place for a
poetry reading. Don't you think?
Poetic enough for you?
A little supper?
Maybe some champagne?
l'd rather just...
...get it over and done with.
Very well.
Then why don't you...
...come down here?
Let's get it over and done with.
l prefer to do it standing.
You don't have to stand.
Sometimes it's.... lt's quite long,
and l'd like you to be comfortable.
What l do is quite modern.
lt may feel strange...
...at first, but if you're open,
you might enjoy it.
l'm sure l will.
Excuse me.
"The sky...."
"The sky...the bluebirds...."
Come on. Come on.
l think....
There might be some shaking.
ls everything okay?
l'm a little nervous.
Sometimes it takes a while for...
...inspiration to come.
Oh, yes, yes.
Let Mummy help.
Does that inspire you?
Let's make love.
You want to, don't you?
Tell the truth.
Can't you feel the poetry?
Come on! Feel it.
Free the tiger!
Big boy!
He's got a huge talent!
-l need your poetry now!
-All right!
"lt's a little bit funny...
...this feeling inside.
l'm not one of those who can
easily hide."
ls this okay?
ls this what you want?
Oh, poetry.
This is what l want,
naughty words.
Naughty!
"l don't have much money,
but if l did, l'd buy...
...a big house where we both
could live."
Oh! lt's so bad!
-"lf l were a sculptor, then again, no."
-You devil.
"Or a man who makes potions
in a traveling show."
Don't, don't, don't!
Don't stop!
-"l know it's not much."
-Give me more! Yes!
-"lt's the best l can do."
-Naughty! Don't stop! Yes!
My gift is my song
And this one's for you
And you can tell everybody
That this is your song
It may be quite simple, but
Now that it's done
I hope you don't mind
That I put down in words
How wonderful life is
Now you're in the world
I sat on the roof
And I kicked off the moss
Well, some of these verses
They got me quite cross
But the sun's been kind
While I wrote this song
It's for people like you that
Keep it turned on
So excuse me forgetting
But these things I do
You see, I've forgotten
If they're green or they're blue
Anyway, the thing is
What I really mean
Yours are the sweetest eyes
I've ever seen
And you can tell everybody
This is your song
It may be quite simple, but
Now that it's done
I hope you don't mind
That I put down in words
How wonderful life is
Now you're in the world
Looks like he got the job!
l can't believe it.
l'm in love.
l'm in love with a young...
...handsome, talented duke.
Duke?
Not that the title's important,
of course.
l'm not a duke.
Not a duke?
l'm a writer.
A writer?
Yes, a writer.
Toulouse--
You're not one of Toulouse's talented,
Bohemian, impoverished proteges?
-You might say that.
-Oh, no!
l'm going to kill him!
There might be a small hitch.
-What about the Duke?
-My dear Duke--
The Duke!
Hide! Out back!
My dear, are you decent for the Duke?
Where were you?
l.... l was waiting.
Dear Duke, allow me to introduce
Mademoiselle Satine!
How wonderful of you
to take time out to visit.
The pleasure, l fear,
will be entirely mine, my dear.
l'll leave you two squirrels
to get better acquainted.
A kiss on the hand may be
quite continental....
But diamonds are
a girl's best friend.
After tonight's pretty exertions
on the stage...
...you must be in need of refreshment.
Don't! Don't you...
...just love the view?
Charming.
l feel like dancing.
l should like a glass of champagne.
lt's....
-lt's a little bit funny.
-What is?
This...feeling...
...inside.
l'm not one of those who can easily...
...hide.
l don't have much money...
...but if l did,
l'd buy a big house...
...where we both could live.
I hope you don't mind
That I put down in words
How wonderful...
...life is
Now you're in...
...the world
That's very beautiful.
lt's from Spectacular, Spectacular.
Suddenly, with you here...
...l finally understood
the true meaning of the words.
"How wonderful life is
now you're in the world."
And what meaning is that, my dear?
Duke!
Don't you toy with my emotions.
You must know the effect
you have on women.
Let's make love!
You want to make love, don't you?
Make love?
l knew you felt the same way!
Oh, Duke!
You're right. We should wait
until opening night.
Wait? Wait?
There's a power in you that scares me.
-You should go.
-l just got here.
We'll see each other every day
during rehearsal.
We must wait. We must wait
until opening night.
Get out.
Do you have any idea what would have
happened if you were found?
Satine?
Let's have a little peekaboo.
Right on target.
l forgot my hat--
Foul play?
Oh, Duke.
lt's a little bit funny,
this feeling inside!
Beautifully spoken.
Let me introduce you. The writer.
-The writer?
-Yes.
We were rehearsing.
You expect me to believe
that scantily clad...
...in the arms of another man, inside
an elephant, you were rehearsing?
How's the rehearsal going?
Shall we take it from the top?
-l hope the piano's in tune.
-Sorry, got held up.
Can l offer you a drink?
Oh, my goodness!
When l spoke those words to you,
you so inspired me.
l realized we had much work to do,
so l called an emergency rehearsal.
Then where's Zidler?
l didn't bother Harold.
Dear Duke, l'm terribly sorry.
Harold! The Duke knows all about
the emergency rehearsal.
Emergency rehearsal?
To incorporate the Duke's
artistic ideas.
Audrey will be delighted--
-Audrey left.
-What?
Cat's out of the bag.
The Duke's a big fan
of our new writer's work.
That's why he's so keen to invest.
lnvest? lnvest!
Oh, yes. lnvest!
You can't blame me for hiding...
...Christian away.
l'm way ahead of you, Zidler.
Duke, let's go to my office
and peruse the paperwork.
What's the story?
lf l'm to invest,
l need to know the story.
Well, the story's about....
Toulouse?
The story is.... The story's about....
lt's about....
lt's about love.
Love?
lt's about love
overcoming all obstacles.
And it's set in Switzerland!
-Switzerland?
-Exotic Switzerland!
lndia! lndia! lt's set in lndia!
And there's a courtesan.
The most beautiful courtesan
in the world.
But her kingdom's invaded
by an evil maharajah.
To save her kingdom, she has to seduce
the evil maharajah...
...but on the night of the seduction,
she mistakes...
...a penniless...a penniless...
...sitar player...
...for the maharajah and falls in love
with him!
He wasn't trying to trick her.
He was dressed as a maharajah...
...because he's appearing in a play.
l will play the penniless tango-dancing
sitar player.
He will sing like an angel...
...but dance like the devil.
Yes, all right.
And what happens next?
The sitar player and the courtesan
must hide their love.
The sitar player's sitar is magical.
lt only speaks the truth.
And l will play the magical sitar!
You are beautiful.
You are ugly. And you--
And he gives the game away, eh?
-Tell him about the cancan!
-The Tantric cancan--
--is an erotic, spectacular scene that
captures the thrusting, vibrant...
...wild, Bohemian spirit...
...that the whole production embodies,
Duke!
-What does that mean?
-The show will be a magnificent...
...opulent, tremendous, stupendous...
...gargantuan bedazzlement!
A sensual ravishment.
lt will be....
Spectacular, spectacular
No words in the vernacular
Can describe this great event
You'll be dumb with wonderment
Returns are fixed at ten percent
You must agree that's excellent
And on top of your fee
You'll be involved artistically
So exciting
The audience will stomp and cheer
So delighting
It will run for 50 years
So exciting
The audience will stomp and cheer
So delighting
It will run for 50 years
-Elephants
-Bohemians
-Indians
-And courtesans
-Acrobats
-And juggling bears
-Exotic girls
-Fire-eaters
Musclemen
Contortionists
Intrigue, danger
And romance
Electric lights, machinery
And all that electricity!
So exciting
The audience will stomp and cheer
So delighting
It will run for 50 years
So exciting
The audience will stomp and cheer
So delighting
It will run for 50 years!
Spectacular, spectacular
No words in the vernacular
Can describe this great event
You'll be dumb with wonderment
The hills are alive
With the sound of music
So exciting
The audience will stomp and cheer
So delighting
It will run for 50 years
So exciting
The audience will stomp and cheer
So delighting
It will run for 50 years!
But what happens in the end?
The courtesan and sitar man
Are pulled apart by an evil plan
But in the end, she hears his song
And their love is just too strong
It's a little bit funny
This feeling inside
So exciting
The audience will stomp and cheer
So delighting
It will run for 50 years
The sitar player's secret song
Helps them flee the evil one
Though the tyrant rants and rails
It is all to no avail
l am the evil maharajah!
You will not escape!
-No one could play him like you.
-No one will.
So exciting, we'll make them laugh
We'll make them cry! So delighting--
And in the end,
should someone die?
So exciting
The audience will stomp and cheer
So delighting
It will run for 50 years!
Generally, l like it.
Zidler had an investor...
-...and the Bohemians had a show.
-lt's the end of the century!
The Bohemian revolution is here!
You are a beautiful woman.
l love sex.
While the party raged upstairs...
...I tried to write.
But all I could think about
was her.
How wonderful life is
Was she thinking about me?
Now you're in...
...the world
Duke? I'm not a duke.
I'm a writer.
He wasn't trying to trick her....
It's about love.
It's about love...
...overcoming all obstacles.
I...
...follow...
...the night
Can't stand...
...the light
When will I begin...
...to live again?
One day I'll fly away
Leave all this to yesterday
What more could your love do for me?
When will love be...
...through with me?
Why live life...
...from dream to dream?
And dread the day...
... when dreaming...
...ends
How wonderful life is
Now you're in...
...the world
One day I'll fly away
Leave all this to yesterday
Why live life...
...from dream to dream?
And dread the day...
... when dreaming...
...ends
One day I'll fly away
Fly...
...fly...
...away
Sorry. l didn't mean--
l saw your light on
and l climbed up the--
l wanted to thank you
for helping me get the job.
Of course.
Yes, Toulouse was right.
You're...
...very talented.
lt will be a wonderful show.
Anyway, l'd better go.
We both have a big day tomorrow.
Wait.
Please wait.
Before, when we were...when we were...
...when you thought l was the Duke...
...you said you loved me,
and l wondered--
lf it was just an act?
-Yes.
-Of course.
lt felt real.
Christian...
...l'm a courtesan.
l'm paid to make men believe
what they want to believe.
Silly of me, to think you could
fall in love with someone like me.
-l can't fall in love with anyone.
-Can't fall in love?
-A life without love? That's terrible!
-Being on the street is terrible.
Love is like oxygen.
Love is a many-splendored thing.
Love...
...lifts us up where we belong.
Don't start that again.
-All you need is love
-A girl has to eat
-Or she'll end up on the streets
All you need is love
Love is just a game
I was made for loving you, baby
You were made for loving me
The only way of loving me, baby
Is to pay a lovely fee
Just one night
Give me just one night
There's no way
'Cause you can't pay
In the name of love
One night in the name of love
You craZy fool
I won't give in to you
Don't leave me this way
I can't survive
Without your sweet love
Oh, baby
Don't leave me this way
You'd think that people
Would have had enough
Of silly love songs
I look around me and I see
It isn't so
Oh, no
Some people want to fill the world
With silly love songs
Well, what's wrong with that?
I'd like to know
'Cause here I go again
Love lifts us up where we belong
Get down! Get down!
Where eagles fly
On a mountain high
Love makes us act like we are fools
Throw our lives away
For one happy day
We could be heroes
Just for one day
You, you will be mean
No, l won't.
And I...
...I'll drink all the time
We should be lovers
We can't do that
And that's a fact
Though nothing...
... will keep us together
We could steal time
Just for one day
We could be heroes
For ever and ever
We can be heroes
Just because I
Will always love you
I can't help loving...
...you
How wonderful life is
Now you're in...
...the world
You're going to be bad for business,
l can tell.
How wonderful life is
Now you're in...
...the world
How wonderful life was,
now Satine was in the world.
But in the Duke...
...Zidler had gotten much more
than he had bargained for.
Converting the Moulin Rouge into a
theater will cost a fantastic sum.
So, in return, l would require
a contract that...
...binds Satine to me...
...exclusively.
Naturally, l'll require some security:
the deeds to the Moulin Rouge.
My dear Duke--
Please! Don't think that
l'm naive, Zidler.
l shall hold the deeds. And if there
are any shenanigans...
...my manservant, Warner...
...will deal with it in the only way...
...you underworld show folk understand.
Satine will be mine.
lt's not that l'm a jealous man.
l just don't like other people
touching my things!
l...
...understand...completely...Duke.
Good.
Now that we have an understanding,
it appears that...
...you have the means to transform
your beloved Moulin Rouge--
--into a theater!
l shall woo Satine over supper tonight.
We will have created
the world's first...
...completely modern...
...entirely electric,
totally Bohemian...
...all-singing, all-dancing
stage spectacular!
The show must go on!
Yes, the show would go on.
But Satine would not attend supper
that night or the following night.
Mad with jealousy,
the evil maharajah...
...forces the courtesan to tell the
sitar player she doesn't love him.
"Thank you for curing me of
my ridiculous obsession with love"...
...says the sitar player, throwing money
at her and leaving the kingdom!
Brilliant! Brilliant!
A life without love?
That's terrible!
Yes. But the sitar player--
Wait! That's my part.
That's my part, Christian!
Don't you dare!
The magic sitar, who can only
speak the truth, says:
"The greatest thing you 'll
ever learn...
...is just to love
and be loved in return."
A picnic, sweet lady?
Oh, but we have so much work to do.
lf the writer can carry a basket,
you can both do it in my presence.
-So he falls from the roof--
-Yes, l know, l know. Don't tell me.
"The greatest thing you'll ever..."
Still at it, my sweet?
"...master...make...
...contract...."
l've so many lines. l've been
drilling them over and over.
For try as the Duke may,
it was almost too easy...
...for the writer and actress
to invent reasons to avoid him.
Mademoiselle Satine,
l haven't finished the new scene.
The "Will the lovers be meeting at the
sitar player's humble abode?" scene.
May l work on it with you
later tonight?
But, my dear, l arranged a magnificent
supper for us in the tower.
We can work on it tomorrow.
How dare you! lt cannot wait
until tomorrow.
"The lovers will meet at the sitar
player's humble abode" scene is crucial.
We'll work tonight
until l'm completely satisfied.
Dear Duke, excuse me.
l'm sorry.
Nice work, family!
Bright and early tomorrow morning,
we begin on Act Two:
The lovers are discovered.
Zidler.
My dear Duke, everything is arranged
for that supper in the tower tonight.
You can eat it yourself!
Her affections are waning!
lmpossible.
l know her work's important,
but she's always at it with that writer!
lf l don't see her tonight,
l'm leaving!
No, Duke! l'll insist
Satine take the night off.
All right.
Eight o'clock, then.
You'll come tonight?
Yes.
-What time?
-Eight o'clock.
-Promise?
-Yes.
Go.
Are you mad?
The Duke holds the deeds
to the Moulin Rouge.
He's spending a fortune on you.
Given you a beautiful new dressing room.
He wants to make you a star.
And you're dallying with the writer.
-Harold, don't be rid--
-l saw you together!
lt's nothing.
lt's just an infatuation.
The infatuation will end.
Go to the boy.
Tell him it's over.
The Duke is expecting you at 8.
If I should die
This very moment
I wouldn't fear
For I've never known completeness
Like being here
Wrapped in the warmth of you
Loving every breath of you
Why live life...
...from dream...
...to dream?
And dread the day....
How could I know...
...in those last fatal days...
Watch Movies, TV Series & Live Sports
www.admitme.app