Make an inventory of this rapid harvest.
No problem.
What's this?
Who did this?
Who else?
Your son Chengfeng.
Chengfeng.
Chengfeng is getting into trouble.
That half-hearted kid.
Where is he?
It's all good.
Look who is back.
Did you finish your task?
You're back.
Chengfeng.
It's all good.
Such a bad temper.
Can't you talk to your son nicely?
What do you want?
You call that work?
Those crops were hardly reaped.
Is that what they taught
you at the academy?
Besides, who told you
that you can ride him?
Look at your shoe marks
on my horse's belly.
You know he's off limits.
Report. Urgent message from Chief of Staff.
Upon receiving this message,
Commander Ma and you are
to reply immediately.
You ordered all horses to work the fields
except for your precious ride.
What else can I ride?
You've given him a task.
Why didn't you inform me?
Stop right there. Come back.
Stop right there.
Punk. You better stop.
Think you are tough?
Let's move.
Since May, Gen Okamura orchestrated a huge
sweep-up operation, unleashing his hounds.
Latest report indicated that on the 9th
we had traitors who defected to the enemy.
Our regiment's location
might have been compromised.
The commanders have ordered us
to halt harvesting and sabotage operations.
And break out of the encirclement.
Light machine guns.
Air burst.
Grenade launchers.
No heavy weapons.
Not quite right, keep listening.
Armoured units.
West side.
The planes are their vanguard.
They are smoking us out.
Inform every company
to withdraw independently.
Entire regiment is to rendezvous
at Ziya River by daybreak tomorrow.
Do you copy?
Gone deaf?
Copy that, Sir.
Grain in Ear.
Silent Shrike.
I told you it's just an air raid.
Japs don't tunnel.
Message from Chief of Staff.
Japs have discharged the dam.
We are not the enemy. Release.
- We are not the enemy.
- Put down the gun.
Put down. Not the enemy, put down your gun.
Don't touch my stomach.
Put her down.
The urgent message is that
Japs have discharged the dam.
Our only chance of crossing is
to detour via Dayin village.
Sons of bitches.
I want everyone accounted for.
Get their finger prints.
Every soul.
Take it. It's for the road, bro.
- No, thank you.
- There's more.
That's very kind of you, madam.
Take it.
Thank you, madam.
My man gave me the gun.
Around early spring he came
home and left the gun with me.
The name is Xiao Shuncheng.
He claimed to be from 23rd Regiment.
It's verified. Dachunzi
is a military spouse.
Been over 9 months.
Baby is due soon.
How's your neck?
It's alright.
Nasty scratch. Let me have a look.
It's nothing. I said it's nothing.
You deserved it for being mindless.
Another inch and you're dead.
What am I to do?
Your family affairs are not my business.
I was talking about these folks.
What are you talking about?
We don't have much time.
They'll be doomed
if the Japs get here.
The river isn't far, but
the path is mountainous.
Are we bringing them or not?
We'll bring them if it's possible,
but I don't believe it is.
52 people, most of
whom can barely walk.
I heard that the Japs have
left some villages untouched.
Perhaps they can hide underground.
You think you're smart
and the Japs can't find them like we did?
Exactly.
We can't just hope for the best.
Especially with military families.
They will be eliminated.
What are you blaming me for?
Am I being heartless?
Why are you yelling?
I'm not yelling.
Have I yelled?
Japanese armoured vehicles are on our tail.
Keep procrastinating
and we might as well let
Big Guy dig a larger grave
for them and us,
plus the horses.
Mom.
Whose child is this?
Listen to me. Bring a few more men.
What if you can't find the 3rd Company?
Bring Chengfeng along.
When it comes to intel-collecting,
he's better than either one of us.
You trust me with your child.
If anything happens to him,
how am I gonna tell you?
I'm already grateful that
Huang Rui is with me.
My marksmanship has no rivals
in the cavalry and the army.
You're almost perfect,
except for your bragging.
What's the bloody hurry?
Make haste.
Even if it's the last thing I do,
I'll steer this bull to the south.
When you have crossed
the river, send up a flare.
Wang. Stay safe and sound.
God is on our side.
Dachunzi tried every horse
and none was mountable.
She said they'll rock her baby out.
Can't even complete such a simple task.
You think I am not busy?
She lost her man.
What?
Her man is dead.
I didn't know what to
say when she asked me.
A while ago, at Raoyang,
the entire 23rd Regiment was wiped out.
You. Come here.
Can you take care of him?
Of course.
Sankui. Eat this.
Leave them to Big Boss.
Listen up, if you
want to live, follow us.
Big Boss.
Be careful. Don't kick his belly.
Who is Big Boss?
Do as you're told.
Obey all military orders.
Big Boss.
To my father, this horse
is more precious than I am.
Get moving, old lady.
Honey.
Our valuables are under the bed.
The Japs have eyes everywhere.
When I give the order, everyone
is to keep their mouth shut.
If you have to fart,
keep it inside your pants.
Let's go. Keep moving.
Enemy aircraft. Take cover.
Enemy aircraft.
Take cover.
Spread out and protect the civilians.
Not that way.
Come this way.
Spread out and protect the civilians.
Go. Quickly.
Hide underground.
Futing and Yupo.
Monkey and Jingguo.
Mount and shoot.
Yang and Long, prepare for ambush.
Erya.
Go.
Big Guy.
Wait till he takes the bait.
Grandpa.
I know. For your grandpa.
Big Guy. For your grandpa.
Grandpa.
All the other companies have
crossed the river except for 3rd.
No news about Commissar,
Huang Rui and them.
No news is good news.
Commissar must have
led them into the maze.
From a young age, I've never
been treated like he was.
What is this?
Mugwort.
Rub it over your neck wound.
Back in the Combined Arms Brigade,
there was this kid from Shanxi
and tetanus took his life.
He was about your age.
You think I'm afraid of death?
I fear that you are not.
I joined the army in 1925.
I've seen too much.
I was leading a recon platoon last year,
and on Mount Taihang I
encountered my first poison gas.
About half the platoon,
horses and men,
their bodies were covered with blisters.
My life was saved
by Big Boss's speed.
I am alive
because I'm always the first to charge.
When you wanted to join the army
your mom went berserk with me.
If you want to be a hero, I won't stop you.
But my son can
never be a casualty.
I chose to defend our country
but I feel guilty about your mother.
If you have to die, die after me.
Or else I'll be ashamed
to face your mother.
He peed on your hand.
You did the same at his age.
Nothing noticeable.
The Japs are finally quiet.
Our regiment has crossed the river.
- Any news of Commissar?
- None.
How about this?
I'll take a few men to search
for them with fast horses.
We'll return by daybreak.
I heard that. Count me in.
You.
Without me, how are you
gonna get any messages out?
I'll take the transmitter and
leave the receiver behind.
When you rendezvous with the
regiment, send up a flare.
When I see the flare I'll send you
a situation briefing immediately.
Let's seize this opportunity
while the Japs are taking a nap.
Commander.
No kicking of his belly.
Copy that.
What's wrong?
An emergency.
Once we use the transmitter
the Japs will locate us.
District Command demands
radio silence for all units
while operating in enemy-occupied areas.
Bloody Japs.
That's why we can't shake them off.
The Japs are betting big.
Looks like a lot of men.
We can't outrun them.
If we fight how
long can we last?
Given our firepower, we
might last for 30 seconds,
or perhaps just five.
Grandpa.
Anywhere beyond this
bend and we'll be made.
Bloody Japs.
We might die anyway.
I say we take some of them with us.
Get your weapons ready.
Hold on.
Radio guy.
Colonel. The cavalry's last
transmission was from these mountains.
Without my orders, nobody moves.
All units, forward.
Chao.
Shoot the flare.
What?
Shoot the flare. Shoot the flare.
Shoot the flare. Shoot it.
Good news at last.
They've crossed the river.
Halt.
Chengfeng's message.
Commissar and Huang Rui
were killed in action.
We
Regroup
immediately.
Colonel, we just intercepted
their radio signal,
which came from Yechenzuo village.
This flare is a decoy.
The real target is the village.
Move out.
What's going on?
Why are the Japs withdrawing?
Commander, you asked Chengfeng to
transmit when he sees the flare.
Everyone, get ready
to move out.
Keep moving.
Quickly.
Quickly, the villagers have arrived.
Mother, there are boats.
We're saved.
The boats are here for us.
Colonel, no more
Chinese troops to be found.
Thank goodness.
We're saved.
Thank you so much.
Go.
Our signal triangulation
was cracked by the enemy.
Colonel,
they've tricked us.
Looks like they have a death wish.
Chengfeng, don't try
to be like your father.
This battle is not yours to fight.
It's still undetermined
who'll be the first to charge.
Fire.
Stop.
Baby's coming out.
It's a boy.
Colonel, the Chinese troops
on the hill are defenseless,
we will eliminate them soon.
Release.
Enemy cavalry spotted at our rear.
Turn all cannons around.
Quickly.
Fire.
Stop the charging cavalry.
Stop them now.
All weapons free.
Fire at will.
Bastard.
They are coming towards us.
Their horses are too fast.
Hold the line. Don't fall back.
They're getting close.
They're too fast.
Charge.
I'm Luo Tong.
For honor and glory I fight the battles.
What do you want? Kid. Commander.
It's alright.
Here.
You are Sankui.
Mother.
What's wrong?
This is your child?
What's his name?
Chengfeng.
No running. Wait till I catch you...
Kid, this is not a playground.
I'll beat you up! Look
at the mess you made.
Get out!
An explosion!
Another explosion!
Hurry, if you're too slow, you'll miss it.
Get up there!
Quick!
Wait for me!
Get out of the way!
Can you see it?
I see smoke.
Come down!
Over there.
The data before the test run was fine.
I don't know what caused the explosion.
Let's send the debris for analysis.
Yes.
We must pinpoint the explosion point to
determine the cause of the explosion.
Then we must account for
the entire ignition process.
Cameras alone are not sufficient.
Next time I will inspect it
visually, if that's what it takes.
Master Yu,
I heard your son was in another fight.
With whom?
With Master Zhang's son.
Dont't worry about it.
Master, Take a break, please.
Smells good. We are having meat today!
Wow, meat!
Your loss if you don't eat some.
Own up to your mistake,
or you won't get to eat.
I won't eat then. I did nothing wrong.
But you got into a fight
with Little Four Eyes.
Look at him.
Clearly, he lost to Four Eyes.
He lost the fight.
I hit him first. Of course, I didn't lose.
Tell your mother that you are sorry.
Then you get to eat.
I won't.
Then I must teach you a lesson.
I will ask you one more time.
Are you sorry?
No.
Shush.
Are you sorry?
No.
You dare talk back to me! You're
not sorry for hitting someone?
That's enough. Let's eat.
You should have listened to me. You
could have avoided the spanking.
Let's eat.
Let's.
I know why my brother was fighting.
Brother Four Eyes said
Dad makes firecrackers.
Whoever makes firecrackers you
could have avoided the spanking.
Dad, where's the meat?
Stop hiding. Come out.
Here, eat this.
Dad, what exactly do you do?
Do you make firecrackers?
Of course not.
Then what do you do?
I'm a...
I'm a poet.
My job is to write
poems in the sky.
How do you write poems in the sky?
That's a secret.
Children aren't allowed to know.
I don't care what you do,
as long as you're not making firecrackers.
Of course I'm not making firecrackers.
If Big Brother asks again
whether or not we could die,
what do we tell him?
Just tell the truth.
No, that's too cruel.
I don't think he will take it well.
But, how can we avoid the topic?
Accidents happen.
From the first day of our
research on solid fuels,
since we knew that China
was developing from scratch,
and that it would take trial and error,
we've already understood.
What are you writing?
A poem.
A poem, you?
I told our son I'm a poet.
Let me read it.
It's not finished yet.
I'll show you when it's done.
Just a quick look!
If you're not working late today,
go to the village, see if
you can buy some meat.
Buy meat?
To satisfy our children's cravings.
I've been craving meat for a long time.
Then get more.
Wait.
The poem I wrote, see if you like it.
Brother, I'm scared.
Don't be.
Get up.
Shredded meat!
Go ahead.
It's delicious! Where did we get the meat?
A gift from your father's co-worker.
Where's Dad?
Where did you two go last night?
I will save a piece for Dad.
Where did you go, you and Dad?
We went to buy meat for you.
Be quiet!
I now call this meeting to order.
I'll speak first.
My dad hasn't come home in days.
Mom told me he has to put in extra hours.
I found it odd too.
My dad hasn't come home either.
My mom was crying.
Maybe he will not come back.
What does that mean?
It means he's gone to heaven.
So he won't come home.
Stop catastrophizing, you wimp.
You're ruining our meeting.
Stop arguing.
Rather than speculating here,
we might as well go investigate.
What do you say to that?
- Okay, let's go.
- Okay.
Let's go.
According to Comrade Shi Ruhong's report,
prior to his death,
plus the data analysis from this accident,
we have established that the
explosion happened in the engine head.
The modified propellant
formulation was not good enough.
We need to run the test again.
The heat insulation layer needs
to be partially thickened.
For our next test, we need
to reduce the engine speed.
All these could be major
causes of an accident.
Who are the comrades from the
propellant trimming workshop?
Do you think you could
improve the trimming accuracy
of the propellant surface to under 0.5 mm?
Can you do that?
Comrade Yu Kaiying.
Didn't I tell you to take some time off?
I can improve the
accuracy to 0.2 mm.
Where are you hiding?
Show yourself.
- Why are you crouching?
- Stand up.
What are you all doing in the factory?
Looking for my dad.
Me too.
What's your father's name?
Zhang Xiaoping.
And yours?
My father's name...
What's my father's name?
His father's name is Big Dummy.
What are you laughing at?
Stand still. Speak when spoken to
You... What's
your father's name?
Shi Ruhong.
Come again?
Stop going to there to
look for your father.
He doesn't work there anymore.
Then where is he?
What exactly does he do?
There's a thing called a Kongming Lantern.
You light a candle in the middle, and
the heated air inflates the lantern.
Then it can fly.
That's what your father makes.
But...
He makes something much much bigger.
Many times more impressive.
And it can lift very heavy
objects up into the sky.
That's how he writes his poems.
He promised to write one for me.
This is the poem I wrote.
See if you like it.
See you tonight.
Comrades. Three months from now,
the solid propellant engine
we are responsible for making
will be needed for a docking test
with the rest of the rocket.
Three months to go, comrades.
Gauge the propellant.
0.8 mm, Master.
This is a tough battle.
But, when we succeed,
we will have our
satellite in space.
0.6 mm.
Here's the poem your father wrote for you.
Just one line.
0.4 mm.
Here's another poem your
father wrote for you.
Get up.
It's raining.
Don't just stand there!
Close the window now!
They said there would be heavy rain,
those of us on overtime
were told to return home!
Dad!
Mom!
Brother!
Dad is back.
Where is he?
These houses can't
withstand heavy rain!
Dad!
Mom!
Everyone please stay calm! Don't panic!
They are sending people over to help!
Dad.
- Are you two ok?
- Mom, what took you so long? I was scared.
- I'm here now.
- Where's Dad?
Don't be afraid. Come here.
Stay here.
Okay.
Where's dad?
Your dad is working late.
Hey!
- Where are you going?
- Mom, don't leave me.
I'm not leaving.
Don't cry.
- Point the light in mom's direction.
- Okay.
Is my father dead?
Come inside. Close the door.
I won't come in until you tell me.
We will talk inside.
Tell me quickly!
Don't stand in the rain!
- Why won't you tell me?
- Come inside. We will talk inside.
What can't you tell me?
I've been going house to house.
All their fathers are back. Except mine.
Is he dead?
Yes, your father is dead.
You're lying.
My father isn't dead.
I want my father.
I'm your father now.
My father is a man, and you are a woman.
I can do what your father did.
My father writes poems. You can't.
Forget about poems. We need to battle.
My father can howl like a wolf. Can you?
My father spanks me.
You've never spanked me.
Don't make me.
Hit me then.
I don't hit you, huh? What about now?
It doesn't hurt.
- It doesn't hurt.
- Don't you talk back to me.
Mom, stop hitting.
I didn't hit you because I
didn't have the heart to.
Has your father really hit you before?
My father and my father before him.
Are both dead.
Mom, stop hitting.
They're both dead.
Does it hurt?
You are late picking up your son today.
What's the holdup?
Long story.
The test failed.
We will try the new formulation tomorrow.
I hope my son was not too much trouble?
He's a sweet boy.
Then I will take him home now.
Maybe let him stay the night with us?
He may keep you up.
He already sleeps over all the time.
I don't want to impose.
It's not a bother.
Plus, I'm counting on your son to take
care of our little one in the future.
Go home and get some rest.
Okay.
Good luck with tomorrow's test.
I will take it.
I have a favor to ask.
Could you help me
hide his death from the children?
Especially Big Brother.
It would devastate him.
His biological
father also died here.
Starting today,
could all the male
comrades avoid going home?
Tell your family that
you're working overtime.
Before the mission
is complete, We...
We must not let the children
know that their father is gone.
Master
Are you alright, Master?
Do you need a break?
We don't have the time.
The test is approaching.
0.2 mm.
Give me the number one blade.
Gauge it.
Okay.
Run!
Are you on a hunger strike?
There.
The poem your father wrote for you.
Now it's finished.
My father didn't write it.
Listen to me. You are
turning ten next month.
I want to start treating you as an adult.
Let's talk like adults.
Can we do that?
Brother, can this really fly?
I'll count down from three,
and we will let go, okay?
Okay.
Three.
Two.
One.
It's flying!
Mom. Please don't die!
Please don't die!
It's possible that I could die too.
You won't die.
The thing that your father made
is similar to this lantern.
Both rely on the fire in the
middle to fly to the heavens.
My job
is to make the fire.
But it's a dangerous job.
If something bad happens, I'll die too.
You won't die.
You never know.
In case I die,
would you regret
still holding a grudge against your mother?
In our family,
you're now the man of the house.
When Mom is not around,
you have to look after your sister for me.
Okay?
I'm sorry, child.
Your father and your mother
may not be there
to see you grow up.
Comrades.
This is our final test run.
We won't get a second chance.
Are we confident?
Yes.
Can we complete the mission?
Yes, we can.
Brother.
If only Mom and Dad had
lived to see this day,
they would be incredibly proud.
Their little girl who used
to be afraid of everything,
and now, she is an astronaut.
When mom passed a few
years ago, I made a wish.
I wanted too, to go up
there and write poems.
Comrade Commander-in-Chief,
Astronaut Shi Tiannuo
reporting for duty for this manned mission.
We're all set. Waiting for instructions.
Manned spacecraft Shenzhou has
entered the countdown phase.
Astronaut Shi Tiannuo is about to
embark on her first trip to space.
My children.
If I could,
I would tell you all the
mysteries of this world.
I would tell you about our
great mountains and rivers.
About the rising sun and setting moon.
Our honor and dreams,
frustrations and sorrows.
I would tell you, in making fuel,
we light up ourselves to
illuminate the dreams of others.
In making rockets we
give up what is ours,
to achieve a collective vision.
Life is to be used for a cause.
Death is affirmation of life
The vast universe
makes our death
so insignificant.
Tiny dust particles
are the beginning of the universe.
Our small steps today
are the beginnings of greatness.
And you,
my children,
give us, ordinary as we are,
the will to begin creating
a beautiful new world.
My Father
My father's name is Zhao Pingyang.
He's got a big head
and a chubby body.
Ever since I was little,
people have said my father
disregards his responsibilities
and always tries to find the easy way out.
But I disagree.
My father is good at learning new things
and has great computation skills.
A sofa in the furniture
store costs? 95.7.
My father thinks that's too expensive,
so he spent? 0.31
on a carpentry book
and drew up blueprints himself.
Then he spent? 8.5
on some scrap wood
and built a new sofa.
But then he ran into
yet another problem.
While moving upstairs
the sofa got stuck in the stairwell.
Others said his efforts were wasted
but my dad faced the challenge head-on
and came up with a brilliant idea.
Lift!
Up, up!
He made a pulley
and successfully
hoisted the sofa upstairs.
Let's go.
Watch out.
The sofa fit perfectly in our house.
My mom was particularly satisfied.
What is this?
The zig zag bridge at City God Temple?
Are you doing puzzles here?
In the end the fabric,
the springs and the tools
cost? 31.06 in total.
My dad said that by building this sofa
he basically earned? 64.64.
My dad is also warm-hearted
towards the neighbors
and approaches comrades with enthusiasm.
My neighbors fought over
splitting water bills.
So my dad installed individual
water meters for each family.
The monthly water bill
was reduced by? 0.72.
The installation cost was earned
back in just a year and a half,
which the neighbors were happy to pay.
And they even praised
my dad as a central figure
in the realization of the four
modernization developing strategies.
My dad cares for the people.
He took time out of his busy schedule to
go to rural areas
and visits farmers.
After thorough research my dad decided to
help them expand their
product distribution channels.
He was particularly supportive of
the duck eggs selling in
the production brigade.
One kilogram of duck eggs costs? 1.5,
and once transported to the
city it is sold for? 1.9.
15 kilograms each time,
minus 10 % in incidental fees,
and he could earn? 5.4.
The other day my dad was appointed by
his factory to attend the Canton Fair.
Unintimidated by neither
hardship nor fatigue.
He brought back 40 cute tropical fish
from Guangzhou,
which greatly enriched
Uncle Jiang's life after retirement.
My dad spent? 0.2 on each fish, which
he sold for? 0.5 to Uncle Jiang.
Subtracting? 1.7 for the fish tank and?
0.05 the tube,
this time my dad earned another? 10.25.
My dad is also strict with
himself and never wastes money.
It takes? 0.04 to make a three-minute
call on a public telephone.
He keeps an eye on his watch
every time he makes a call
and hangs up the phone
at exactly two minutes
and fifty-nine seconds,
refusing to spend an extra? 0.04.
Hello
Six Seven Eight
And so because of all these virtues,
my dad has become the most pupolar
person in our neighborhood.
He has told everyone that in the future
there will be phones without cords,
trains without wheels,
bridges over the Huangpu River,
and skyscrapers in Pudong.
Some of the neighbors don't believe him
and say he's speaking nonsense.
There is a saying
The duck is a prophet of spring
when the river becomes warm.
The duck what?
The duck prophet.
I see.
So you are this duck.
And so from that day on,
my dad was given a
nickname The duck prophet
The duck prophet is coming back.
Through his hard work,
my family has? 386.5
in savings now.
My dad was also appointed as
the sales manager at the 2nd
Traditional Pharmaceutical Factory.
Their product sales have since
continuously reached record-breaking highs.
I must learn from my
dad and train myself to be
a useful person to the people.
Zhao Xiaodong's
essay is lively and vivid,
which is something worth learning from.
Ms. Qian, He's bragging!
We're neighbors.
Since his dad was
appointed as sales manager,
the company's medicinal wine
hasn't been selling well at all.
If you don't believe me, just
go to his house and look.
His entire house is packed
with medicinal wine.
His dad has spent all their money
- on buying the medicinal wine
- Stop it
and their savings dropped into
the negatives a long time ago.
His dad was also kicked out
of their house by his mom.
Go live in your father's house
or else we get a divorce.
And now they're
about to divorce.
It's not true. You're lying.
Do you know who his father is?
Who is he?
There used to be a man who always sold
duck eggs in front of our school gate.
And that man is his father.
Embarrassed by his father,
Dongdong avoided him
every day after school.
I can pay for it, all right?
Duck prophet!
Yes!
Stop it!
Be quiet!
Put it down!
Mr. Zhao, I can understand that kids often
put their parents on a pedestal in essays.
But what kind of person would
you like Dongdong to be?
You can't let him solely
pursue materialistic goals.
He must also have spiritual pursuits.
You need to encourage him to
be more like Chen Jingrun,
someone who makes significant contributions to
our country even without sitting on a couch.
I never prevented him from
becoming more like Chen Jingrun.
Then what's the deal with
all the wine at your house?
This Ginseng Longan Wine is
produced by our factory - The 2nd
Traditional Pharmaceutical Factory.
It's made from a traditional
recipe with real ingredients.
But I'd like to sell it
in an untraditional way.
Comrade Duck Prophet,
as a sales manager at
a state-owned factory,
please don't focus your attention
on such crooked methods.
All the students are
laughing at Dongdong now.
Go home and do some self-reflection.
Put it in the bag.
That's Dongdong and his dad.
Dongdong and his dad.
Isn't that the Duck Prophet?
Dongdong, come here.
Dongdong. Hurry up, Dongdong!
Hurry!
Dongdong, come up quickly.
- Don't push. It's overcrowded already.
- Dongdong, hurry up.
- Just get off.
- Make some room.
Come on, come on.
- Dongdong. Dongdong, hurry up.
- Get off.
Dongdong.
What's wrong? Are you upset with me?
Did I embarrass you?
Yes, you did.
I'll behave better next time
and try to make you proud.
When is next time?
Next time is just next time.
Mom.
Let me do it.
Honey I'm so grateful for you.
Why did he bring you home today?
I passed by the school today, so I
picked him up and brought him home.
Honey. This is your favorite dessert.
- I'm not going back tonight.
- Cut it out.
You and your horrible wine get out of
this house together and go to your dad's.
What you just said isn't objective.
This wine is at the very least made from a
traditional recipe, with real ingredients.
How could it be horrible?
Plus, we already bought
a sewing machine,
which means our
life is pretty good.
How dare you say that?
Are you out of your mind?
If you hadn't promised to sell
thousands of bottle of wine in a year,
would your factory have
overstocked so much wine?
And as if that wasn't enough, you continued
to bite off more than you can chew.
As you know, this house
wasn't big to begin with,
but now we have got
neither money nor space.
I went to No.1 Food store on Nanjing
road today and convinced them
to sell our wine from next month on.
The distribution channel is alreadu opened.
Just keep bragging!
Do you think I'll still believe in you?
Let me tell you, Zhao Pingyang.
This is my last warning.
You must get rid of this
terrible wine within a month.
Either you drink it all or
pour it into the Huangpu River.
Does it taste good?
Don't worry. It's fine.
Your mom has more bark than bite.
Are you sure you can sell all the wine?
Are you bragging again?
How come you don't believe me either?
I've already come up with a solution.
But to implement this solution,
I need you to do me a favor.
What is it?
Little Fatty. Did you expose
Dongdong in school today?
Who told you my wine is not selling well?
It's... My dad.
I knew it was him.
I'm running around every
day doing actual things,
while your dad just smokes, drinks tea and
reads the newspaper all day in the office.
He's in no position to criticize me.
If I sell all the wine within a
month, you must apologize to Dongdong.
Otherwise I'll cut your big ears
off and have them with my wine.
Little Fatty's big ears are getting
even bigger. It's a sign of good luck.
Didn't I tell you to go home
and finish your homework?
Then why are you still here?
Go home.
Kicked out by your wife?
Absence makes the heart grow fonder.
What do you know?
You remember the lines, right?
Suppose your mom and I actually
get a divorce, what would you do?
Would you choose your mom or me?
Mom.
Listen, we're not
going to get a divorce.
Don't sulk. You must work with me after
getting on the bus. Did you hear me?
Oh my gosh! Buddy.
Please don't knock
over my medicinal wine.
Mister, mister.
Are you holding the
Ginseng Longan Wine?
Yes. It is. How did you know?
My grandpa is very fond of it.
He said there is longan,
Yu zhu and ginseng in it.
With real ingredients,
it not only boosts vitality
and nourishes blood,
promotes fluid production
and benefits the lungs,
but also relax muscles
and improves eyesight.
Since he's begun to drink this wine, my
grandpa has been eating well, sleeping well,
glowing with health
and jumping high,
as if he's suddenly ten years younger.
Really? Then you should definitely tell
your grandpa to drink more of this wine.
Where did you get this?
How much did it cost?
The usual price is? 30.
But I know someone from the
factory so I got it for only? 18
Then if my grandpa buys it from you,
could you make it a bit cheaper
so he can buy a bottle too?
In that case I'll be bankrupt!
But on behalf of the admirable
care you give your grandpa,
I'll make it? 16 for you.
Wow, that's a steal.
Then my grandpa must buy more.
Treasure!
What a Treasure!
Longan, Yu zhu, Ginseng,
with real ingredients.
If my grandpa wants to buy from
you, please just sell him a bottle.
Relaxes the muscles
and improves eyesight.
Mister, please sell it to me.
I need replenishment too.
- Boosts vitality and nourishes blood, - promotes
fluid production and benefits the lungs.
Mister I'm begging you to sell me this.
Mister.
You are a living Lei Feng,
sacrificing yourself for others.
Our whole family will remember
your kindness forever.
Oh my gosh!
Is this the legendary
Ginseng Longan Wine?
Eat well.
Sleep well.
Jump high.
Leap far.
Glow with health.
Jump high.
Do you want some?
No.
Mister, I must criticize you.
Don't you think it's very selfish of you
to not sell me any of the wine?
Honey, should we buy two bottles
of the wine for your dad?
It's too expensive.
It will make your dad happy, which
means you won't beat me again.
I'll take two bottles.
Duck Prophet.
I've been watching you for quite a while.
When was your son adopted by others?
How did I not know?
I can't believe you called him mister.
Why don't you call him comrade?
Comrade, please don't be fooled.
This guy is
the sales manager at a
pharmaceutical factory.
And this boy is his son.
What they're trying to
sell is in very low demand.
It's not!
There's nothing wrong with the quality.
Nonsense.
We have everything we need, right?
Yes.
Comrades,
are you working for the
Shanghai TV Station?
Are you doing news reporting?
We're going to film the retirement
home for the Double Ninth Festival.
What a coincidence!
I work for the 2nd Traditional
Pharmaceutical Factory.
We're also going to visit the elderly
at their retirement home for
the Double Ninth Festival.
Could you film our visit as well?
Sure.
Cut.
Good.
You done?
Done.
Director, could you
film one more shot
of me opening the bottle
and the elderly drinking the wine
and their satisfied smiles?
No. No.
This is not how we do news reports.
Then could you take one more close-up shot
and make sure our brand
logo is big and clear?
Close-up?
Do you have any idea how much it costs
for a 10-second shot?
How much?
Enough to buy 25 kilos of pork belly.
Our factory can pay for it.
It's not something you can just pay for.
We are not making an advertisement for you.
Advertisement?
What is an advertisement?
Mr. Feng,
the elderly performing Tai Chi are ready.
Young Comrade, what
is an advertisement?
An advertisement is
a very short film broadcasted on TV,
aimed at promoting and selling products.
That's great!
It suits us.
Can we film an advertisement?
We don't have that
in China only abroad.
Our TV station never broadcasts ads.
Never before but never
in the future either?
I'm not sure.
But there are articles
about this in the paper
and our leaders are discussing it too.
Well how about
if I hire you to make an advertisement,
would you do it?
I could.
But you'll have to pay for it.
Either way Mr. Feng won't agree to it.
I'm not asking Feng.
I'm asking you.
May I have your name please?
You can call me Xiao Ma.
Director Ma.
Advertisement?
Do you know anyone who's
made an advertisement before?
I've talked about it to a
senior staff at the TV station.
According to reliable
sources, it's probable that
they'll start broadcasting ads soon.
We must seize this opportunity.
It could be the first TV
advertisement in China.
Manager Zhao, I have
a TV set in my house
which I watch everyday.
But I have never seen
anything like you described.
Do you think I'm
stupid enough to pay for
something I've never seen before?
It won't cost very much.
Stop talking.
We now have an abundance of wine in stock
just because I believed
in what you have said.
Please think about some
practical solutions.
Don't shoot for the moon.
Do you drink this wine?
I don't drink wine.
Do you think I can drink it all?
Do you know what an advertisement is?
What is it?
You don't even know what
an advertisement is.
Dongdong, please listen to me.
Your mom has demanded that I sell
all the wine within a month, right?
There are only 15 days left as of today.
So you have to help me get
the key to the wooden chest,
and take out the household
registration booklet inside,
in case your mom is going
to divorce me in a rage.
I don't think you actually want
the household registration booklet.
You just want me to steal my mom's
money for your advertisement.
My boy is smart indeed.
It's not stealing but simply borrowing
your mom's money to make an ad.
When the advertisement is done,
our family will also be secured.
Dongdong.
This is the only money we have left.
Mom will definitely divorce
you once she finds out.
I know.
Do you remember what I said before
The duck is a prophet of spring
when the river becomes warm.
It is only because the duck
isn't afraid to go into the river
that it is able to feel
when the water becomes warm
and able to capture fish.
Always be
the first duck brave enough
to jump into the river.
But I feel we're already in the river.
Right,
Then do you dare to be a brave duck?
Yes.
My good boy.
Mom, give me the key.
Where's yours?
I left it home.
Why didn't you leave yourself home?
Finish your homework first
and don't mess around.
OK.
Today is my first date with Zhao.
He's a good guy.
It's the happiest day in my life.
Have another pork chop.
I've already figured out the story.
A minute and a half in total.
The story will be about
a family of three that goes to a store
to buy the Ginseng Longan Wine
as a gift for their grandpa,
who is very satisfied
after drinking the wine.
Manager Zhao, thank
you for the noodles.
But this is very difficult.
You asked for money
which I got now.
Even if I could
get a hold of the camera by using
news reporting as an excuse,
what about the film negatives?
It requires four leaders' signatures
to get the negatives.
Then we'll buy some.
Have you seen a store
that sells film negatives?
It's not something you can just buy.
Without a letter of introduction,
you can't even hire
actors or book filming locations.
Just forget it.
Xiao Ma,
Director Ma.
We had a deal.
You can't just give up now.
Come on, think about it.
If the advertisement is well filmed,
then you would be the first TV ad director
in all of China.
The first one.
The progenitor.
The founder.
I'll take care of the film negatives
and the actors.
You just let me know what your
requests are for the filming location.
It should be a place with grandeur.
Yes.
Style.
And a feeling of
natural and harmonious.
Then we can do it in my house.
Waiter, another bowl
of noodles please.
Got it.
The unexposed head of negative reels
are supposed to be discarded,
but I think it's quite a waste,
so I've been keeping them for years.
Luckily, they're long
enough for your short film.
They're already spliced together.
Here you go.
Thank you.
How dare you come here?
The fish you have sold me last time
turned upside down within a few days.
Not even.
They died on the night we bought them.
Give my? 20 back.
I will give you? 30 and
you can keep the change.
Just do me a favor.
Look.
You'll have the opportunity
to be on the cover.
I've already told you Zhao Pingyang.
I've never thought about
becoming an actress.
You're such a beautiful lady.
It'd be a shame if you
don't go into acting.
You should come too, Xiao Mei.
I'll make you a movie star.
On your birthday
we're going to film at the
drugstore in the morning
and at our house in the afternoon.
What I'm sayning now is very crucial.
You have to let your mom take you out
to Nanjing Road and stay there for 6 hours.
You can't come back home
until the time is up
It's all or nothing.
This is called luring the
enemy away from their base.
What are you looking at?
Nothing.
Hurry up!
Everyone must move quickly.
We've only got 6 hours in total
to film the rest of the shots.
We must remember the original
location of all the furniture
and put everything back after we're done
My wife must not spot any difference.
Dongdong, it's
your birthday today.
I'll let you have
anything you want.
Mom.
I want to have some pork mooncakes.
Sure.
The line is so long.
Let's go.
A long line means the
mooncakes must be yummy.
I want to have some pork mooncakes.
If there's no line, then it's not yummy?
Let's rehearse it first.
Ready.
Action!
Father, this is a
present for you.
Ginseng Longan Wine.
May you be healthy,
live long and prosper.
Cut.
That's too pompous.
Oh.
Be lifelike.
Be natural.
Oh.
Ok?
I got it.
Be more lifelike.
Sorry.
Right.
Let's do a first take.
Rolling.
Action!
Dad, This Gingan
Lonseng Wine is for you.
Sorry I mispronounced words.
Cut.
Why did you look at the camera?
I'm sorry.
Don't be nervous.
You make mistakes more easily when nervous.
Take a deep breath.
Adjust my relaxing.
No. Adjust my breathing.
Just relax.
Rolling.
Action!
Dad, This is a father for you.
Don't buy this. Let's go.
Mom, I'm still hungry.
I'm exhausted.
Stop eating.
Mom, I'd also like
to go to the cinema.
Which film do you want to watch?
Manhunt.
You've already seen it
six times with your dad.
Then I want to see Mistress Xiang Lin.
Do you have any idea who she is?
I think She looks
like my grandma.
Let's go.
Your grandma?
Dongdong.
Watch the car.
Cut.
This shot is done.
Let's do a close-up.
Move the light.
Director, how
many shots are left?
Quite a few.
Come on. Be quick.
Mom, I'd like to
watch the film again.
Why do you like this film so much?
Let's go home.
Let's go.
What's wrong?
Mom, I have a stomachache.
Where?
Here?
Yes.
Look at you!
You ate so much it's no
surprise you have a stomachache.
Does it hurt here?
Yes, it does.
Take it easy.
What about here?
Yes.
It's quite serious.
You'll need a few
acupuncture treatments.
Acupuncture.
Mom, I suddenly feel fine.
What's the matter with you?
That's weird.
Oh well I just farted.
That is weird.
The light is too dim now.
Change it to a brighter light.
Quickly.
I think it's fine.
No. It's not.
We're running out of time.
Little Fatty is coming back soon.
We don't have much time. Let's start.
You are so annoying.
Absence makes the heart
grow fonder everyday.
Boosts vitality.
Nourishes blood.
A good wine.
Good.
Cut.
This shot is done.
Now let's take the last shot.
Great.
My wife is sick in bed.
Are you guys setting up this search...
setting up this searchlight
to illuminate her?
That's despicable.
Stop what you're doing.
Sorry. Mr.Fatty.
We're making a film.
That's none of my business.
But you must not disturb your neighbors.
And we're neighbors.
Please don't be upset.
Cut the nonsense!
It really doesn't hurt?
No.
Little Fatty, Why
are you sitting here?
Dongdong, My parents
didn't let me stay home.
Can I go to your house to
watch the film being shot?
What film?
What's going on?
Fake!
Even the vase is fake.
You filmmakers always
deceive audience with fake things.
Shame on you.
Mr. Fatty. Calm down.
Please don't be mad.
Stop talking!
I won't allow you to
continue filming today.
Just give me five
minutes for the last shot.
I won't even give
you one second.
Stop filming!
I won't allow it!
You can wait for the sun.
Mr. Fatty!
Get out of the way.
Mr. Fatty,
I bought this blanket when
Zhao and I got married.
I've never used it.
Are you satisfied now?
Can you please give him
five minutes to finish filming?
Can you?
Put the flowers in the vase.
I have something else to do.
Then let's continue filming.
Back to your positions.
(Three Months Later)
Then we'll follow your instructions.
Xiao Ma.
President.
I heard that you've made an ad?
Yes.
Our TV station has been thinking about
launching an advertising business.
Show me your ad.
Yes, okay.
President,
do we need to report
this to the leaders
and ask what they think before we proceed?
Just in case.
I'm afraid we might be accused of
making mistakes regarding principle.
What mistakes?
It already passed the conference vote
to expand enterprise production,
increase economic efficiency,
and improve people's living standards.
Those are the biggest principles.
Don't worry.
I'll take responsibility
if anything bad happens.
I'll fetch it for you.
OK.
Don't try to fool me.
I've made films before too.
Dear audience,
today is Sunday 28th of January 1979,
the first day of the first lunar month.
The following is the main
content of the news program
Today is the 37th day after the closing of
the Third Plenary Session of
the Eleventh Central Committee.
Cadres and masses from all walks of life
organized spontaneously to
study the Communiqu? Of the Third Plenary
Session of the Eleventh Central Committee.
Tell Dongdong to stop watching TV.
He sits there waiting for the ad everyday.
Dongdong, stop watching TV.
This wine won't
sell well anyway.
I'll take two bottles to your grandpa's
to celebrate the New Year.
When will the ad be broadcasted?
Probably never.
I have no idea.
Do you think I'm useless?
Next time you write an essay,
feel free to write
whatever you want about me,
all right?
Are you ready?
Let's go.
Put on your sweater.
OK.
Turn off the TV, Dongdong.
Zhao Pingyang,
grab a few more bottles
of wine for you dad.
Don't waste good wine.
Dad, mom, come and watch the ad.
Come.
Where?
Dad, this present is for you.
Ginseng Longan Wine.
May you be healthy,
live long and prosper.
Ginseng Longan Wine.
Boosts vitality.
Nourishes blood.
A good wine for
family and friends.
Give Ginseng Longan Wine as a present.
This Ginseng Longan
Wine is really hard to get.
It's so hard to buy this wine.
It's so hard to buy.
Good product. Be quick.
I told you it's hard to get.
Over there.
Hurry up.
Hello comrade.
How's this wine been selling today?
Very well.
Almost sold out.
Usually just few people purchase it.
But for some reason, today
everyone's here to buy it.
That's because of
its traditional recipe
and real ingredients.
That's true.
I remember now,
something my dad once said to me.
Dongdong,
I believe that
you'll become a successful person one day.
But it's at this momment
that I can finally believe what my dad said
was true.
My father
was perhaps indeed a duck prophet.
Dad, this present is for you.
Ginseng Longan Wine.
May you be healthy,
live long and prosper.
Ginseng Longan Wine.
Boosts vitality.
Nourishes blood.
A good wine for
family and friends.
Give Ginseng Longan Wine as a present.
Since then
advertisements have reached
every family in China
and have become a part of our lives.
My dad was not only the
first advertiser in China,
but also one of the first
people who bought stocks,
used mobile phones,
and bought commodity housing in Pudong.
What others regarded as
his daydreams turned out
all to be true.
Many said my dad
was the duck prophet,
a miraclulous man,
able to predict the future.
I only finally understood when I grew up
that he is not the miracle,
but ourselves.
Later, I became an engineer.
In 2016 I led my team to
build the tallest building in China:
Shanghai Tower.
There are 285 commercial
buildings in Lujiazui
with 43,000 companies inside.
Our generation is also
creating a new world
full of hope.
A bright new world.
Son.
What are you writing?
What's the height of the
Shanghai Tower that you designed?
632 meters.
Is it the tallest in China?
It's the second tallest in the world.
Why are you writing it down?
For my essay.
The title is My Father.
Dad, mom,
are you looking through
the binoculars again?
Your dad has looked
over 100 times.
That red roof used to be our old house.
I know.
I found it a long time ago.
Well, this building you designed
is absolutely amazing.
Like I said before,
The duck is a prophet of spring
when the river becomes warm.
Always be
The first duck that dares
to jump into the river.
That's right
I'm sorry!
I will never do that again.
Where has gone the hot water?
Mom, it was my fault.
I was half way in my shower
when the hot water ran out.
How dare you to take apart
the water heater, huh?
Sorry.
The fan
The hair dryer The
vacuum cleaner Besides,
What are these?
I was wondering why all
the appliances in our house
keep breaking and breaking after repairs.
Now I see.
If there is one thing in this
house to be fixed, that is you.
Kid,
say goodbye to your plane.
You are not taking apart the appliances;
you are tearing our
mother-son relationship apart.
Mom.
The ceiling light fell off by itself.
I didn't do anything!
As if it doesn't want to
live, like the way you don't.
Listen, let me explain.
For a static object,
if an external force is
greater than the friction,
it naturally moves.
And that external force
might be the gravity
or some unknown, mysterious force.
The force is neither
unknown nor mysterious.
Let me show you.
Aren't you familiar?
Is this the force you are referring to?
Is it mysterious?
The ball is mine.
Yours?
Can you guys keep down
your construction noise?
It shook off our ceiling light.
My mom thought I did it.
See the works of her spank.
Generally speaking,
mothers spank for guiding ways.
Then, can you see the
ways my mother is guiding?
Your mother lost her way.
Forget about it You
should apologize right now.
Your mother spanked you.
You should tell your mother to apologize.
Give back the ball.
Xiaoxiao, stop dragging your feet.
You are getting late for school.
Don't think about getting your ball back.
Fanfan, the teacher said that
Empress Dowager Cixi was buried
with a priceless jewel in her mouth,
the luminous pearl.
Yeah, so?
It is right here.
Didn't the teacher say that
it was lost long time ago
in some foreign countries?
You know, my dad is a special agent,
and he brought it back.
If you like it,
I don't mind if you play it for some days.
You, big liar!
Come, everybody.
Xiaoxiao said this luminous pearl
belonged to Empress Dowager Cixi.
Empress Dowager Cixi?
Must be a fake.
Getting things from Empress Dowager Cixi,
your dad must be
an imperial eunuch.
Rebound. Your dad is an imperial eunuch.
Bounce back. Your dad is an eunuch.
Xiaoxiao's dad is a special agent.
Don't believe him.
Few days ago, he just said
his dad is Yao Ming's coach.
Don't believe a word of it.
Isn't his dad an astronaut?
He changed his job because of acrophobia?
I still keep some lunar
soil that Xiaoxiao gave me.
He said his dad's a scientist.
Why haven't you inherited from him?
Are you the real son of your dad?
Wang Mingtu.
I've been putting up with you for too long.
I'm Jackie Chan!
I'm Jet Li!
Stop!
Jackie Chan, sit down; Jet
Li, go back to your seat!
Watch out!
Watch out here!
Looking for cars?
Come on in.
Come, sir. This way.
You sure you want to bring in this guy?
Remember,
never judge a person's
purchasing power by his looks.
Get the swipe machine ready!
Sir, Sir, the first time
that I saw this car,
I was as excited as you.
You must be a pro.
You first check the chassis
when looking for cars.
I know the chassis is awesome but
we can't just keep staring at it.
Here.
The boss sits in the rear. Give it a try.
Sir,
we offer different
types to fit you the best.
Ranging from hundred
thousands to millions yuan,
our cars cover almost all purposes,
whether it is for family, business or...
Yes! That is the exact
expression that I'm looking for.
You perfectly illustrates
the mind-blowing luxury experience
that is beyond the description of words.
This car, features
the most advanced
battery technologies in the world so far.
It has the amazing charge efficiency.
Indeed amazing.
Why is it out of battery?
Emm...
Sorry, sir.
This car might not have been charged.
How about we switch a car?
Sure.
Let me open the door for you.
What just happened was a pure accident.
The battery in this car
undoubtedly has strong
cells, high charge rate,
and wonderful capacity.
Power-off?
Why is it dead again?
Where has the power gone?
Tomorrow is the Parents' Day.
You gonna have your mom come again?
Your mom did nothing but
cracking sunflower seeds.
It will be nice if your dad could come.
I wanna see your dad.
Xiaoxiao, where are you going?
Give me back the ball.
Look, is he Xiaoxiao's dad?
He looks like a homeless
Can I hold your hand for a second?
Like a homeless I
will go with my dad.
Wow, you found my school.
Here's the ball.
What's wrong?
Water...
Not waterproof.
What's wrong with you? Tell me, quick.
Freeze.
I know you are a robot,
and you are not waterproof.
Let me ask you.
Robots should look like me.
You look way too human.
Double chin, potbelly,
what are these for?
The adipose layer cushions the body
and protects core parts.
What is this?
Why do you want it back so badly?
Are you grilling me?
No, I'm helping to dry you.
I want to save you.
Only by using it can I go back to 2050.
You came from 2050?
Scientists are performing a
time travel experiment on me.
What is it like in 2050?
Are there more people or
more robots on streets?
Can cars fly?
What energy sources are used?
I don't know either.
I was just off from production line
and they brought me here.
What are you advanced robots able to do?
Don't harm me.
And I won't harm you.
Don't worry.
I can't attack humans.
You scared me to death.
Why don't you tell me earlier?
Wow.
Here's the thing:
Tomorrow is the Parents' Day.
If you come with me,
I will give you back the ball.
How's that?
Even my mom has never seen these.
You made all these?
Yep.
My dad studies artificial intelligence,
and I might get it from him.
This will be the finale
project for tomorrow.
Can you help to take a look?
How to make higher and further flights?
I can't help,
but I can take a look.
You don't know my mom's temper.
If she sees this plane,
she will throw it away.
Every day, she forced me to
practice Mathematical Olympiad,
English speaking, and
ancient poems recital.
All those naggings keep
going on and on and on.
My head is about to explode.
Then, why haven't you?
Mom.
You can't hide a plane that big.
Come here.
Who's this?
He is Xing Yihao.
The blind date that Ms.
Wang arranged for you.
So, you are into cosplay.
Which character are you?
Son,
go play.
Mom, I... Play now or never.
Let's chat.
My bag, please.
As you can see,
I have been a mom and a
dad for all these years.
Every now and then, I'll
have to handle some liquor.
And I don't want him to see.
So I thought about hanging out here
till I am sober.
Now that he has grown up,
and the hardest time has passed.
Please go and tell Ms. Wang
that don't arrange blind
dates for me anymore.
Besides, a man of this quality
is definitely not my thing.
What happened to his father?
Ms. Wang has not told you about that?
They clicked?
His dad studies artificial intelligence.
He always says, To make dreams come true,
you will have to go through
failures thousands of times.
Five thousand times of failures
will carve out his great
technological product.
However it turned out that only
after the fifth try, he passed away.
I'm sorry for your loss.
He was gone too soon.
The boy got it from his dad,
fiddling with all these.
I was just afraid if he
fell behind his school work,
and still he is not cut out for that.
His dad's dream
is to enable machines
to learn autonomously.
But you are turning you child
into a machine that can
do nothing but study.
Fly higher.
Indeed.
I can't let my son live in good times
but without a good mom.
Alright.
Hang in there.
I'll go home.
Ma Daiyu.
Two more rounds?
Nope,
I'm sober now.
Boy, let's go home.
Take the plane
Ok
I wish you could come tomorrow.
When you enter the school later,
try to be cool, OK?
Absolutely
Look at that!
Roasting under this big summer sun,
he wears layers without sweating.
How frail.
He is cosplaying Leon
With that speed,
I could hit the target before he knows it.
Mom.
Oh my boy.
I was heavy-handed
Do not tell your dad about this.
Ah, my boy
Please stay there, I
will come downstairs.
Fretting?
If I walk like this, you fret, right?
Move quickly,
or the Parents' Day would be over soon.
You already are the center
of attention for kids.
You don't need to dress up this formal.
Though it's the first time we meet,
I have already heard a lot about you.
You have been through so
much hardships these years;
I taught them about going to moon,
you brought back the lunar soil;
I taught them about Cixi,
you brought back the luminous pearl;
Have you been in contact
with the aliens recently?
Despite all the hustle-and-bustle,
remember to spend more time with your kid.
Come on!
Come and defense me.
Come on, Yao Ming's coach.
Three shots in a row.
Three shots in a row, can you?
Excuse me.
Let me introduce myself.
I was a former
second-level athlete.
Sorry for you
Come, show around.
My dad was a foregone
second-level athlete.
Come on.
Can you do that? Go for it.
Have a try
There, there. Follow me.
Pose like this, Yao Ming's coach.
Dad, you scored!
You scored!
Dad.
My dad scored!
Xiaoxiao's dad is amazing.
My dad won! My dad scored!
Dad, try another one.
I want to eat dumplings.
Here.
Come on, come on Dad, I'm hungry
I'm hungry Dad
I'm hungry I am truly hungry
It's not yet lunch time.
Dad, I'm hungry
Ready?
We are coming last in the race.
Try harder.
Wouldn't it be too fast if I do?
As long as we race fast.
Cheeky wins.
Speed up.
Straight up your waist.
Go, Xiaoxiao!
Xiaoxiao! Go, Xiaoxiao!
I won! I won!
Why don't you smile?
I don't know how.
I will show you, like this.
Teacher, I applied
principles of aerodynamics
to make a glider.
How impressive, Yihang.
I'm so proud of you.
Thank you for your encouragement.
Teacher, I got inspired
for making this plane
because my dad irons my mom's clothes.
No, the opposite.
It is powered by steam
to provide perpetual fuel.
Teacher, cleared for departure.
Departure approved.
Dad, the power is gone.
What can help it fly?
Damn, your dad.
It's a bionic plane.
How wonderful, Weiwei.
You see, in science, we
must keep our integrity.
Although there were ups and downs,
you got to advance forward.
Understand?
I'm sorry, Weiwei's dad.
What a coincidence.
Mine is bionic too.
Yours is not bionic.
Yours is bio-release.
Bionics eat this?
I intended to buy this pigeon
to simulate a bionic plane.
I didn't expect this. I was simple minded.
Time is so limited
that I just made a remote control.
Go, Da Cheng.
Alright.
Xiaoxiao,
can your stuff fly or not?
Yours are just toys.
Mine is a real plane.
It hovers vertically like an helicopter,
and speeds up like a fixed-wing aircraft.
Teacher, it combines
the merits of both types,
and is forged as a new type of aircraft.
It's on fire!
Don't gather around.
Turn off, please
Xiaoxiao's father,
please take the kids away
It caught fire.
The plane was shot down.
My plane flew nicely last night.
My dad was there too!
If you don't believe, ask him.
Surely your dad speaks for you.
Last night,
I didn't actually see that.
I couldn't take my eyes off your mother.
Even if it flew last night,
it fails to do so now,
proving that it's just not good enough.
You failed.
It failed to fly.
Why are you here?
I brought back the airplane for you.
I don't need it.
To make dreams come true, you will have
to go through failures thousands of times.
Five thousand times of failures
make a great product like me.
You should follow your
father's path to move forward.
How can you give up your
dream after only one failure?
At least your dad tried five times.
Who gave up dreams?
I gave up on you.
You could have vouched for me.
But, instead, you didn't
trust me on one hand,
and accused me in front of
the crowds on the other.
My dad would never do that.
Since he's gone,
I think about him every day.
The reason I did all of these is to figure
out why his study is so important for him,
even leaving my mom and me behind.
Ever since I met you,
I thought my dad was back.
But I was wrong.
You are a cold-blood machine.
You don't have feelings at all.
Go away. You don't deserve to be my dad.
Xing Yihao
Somebody help!
Help! Help me drag him up here!
Aren't you leaving?
Who told you to come back?
Last time I missed the plane's flight.
I want to see it before leaving.
Did you see it then?
I saw...
I saw you paddling in the water.
It's time for me to go.
Please don't go.
Could you stay and be my dad?
Just between you and me.
I'll protect you.
I will never let you get close to water.
I have to go back
to prove that the experiment is a success.
But I don't want you to go.
If you really need to go,
can you take me with you?
I will go home right now and pack my stuff,
and bring my mom too.
If I stay any longer,
I will never be able to go.
I'm sorry.
I missed this time again.
But I'm sure it did take off.
Xiaoxiao,
You can!
Could you please stay?
Xiaoxiao,
help me put it in.
Look at this.
You guys made him travel to the past.
Thus we see the future.
I'm here to announce,
the first time-travel experiment by mankind
was a complete success.
Nice to meet you again.
Thank you for giving me
an unique childhood memory, dad.
YOU made me.
YOU are my dad.
Wow, what a big hand-made rocket!
That's my son.
Which one?
That one.
Ready to go?
Yes!
Go, my boy!
Don't hurry.
Son, take your time.