Christmas in Beverly Hills, California.
A time when everyone thinks
only kind, tolerant, generous thoughts.
- I went looking for you.
- What, what, what? What is it Mushy?
- I went to the house looking for you.
- Why? What happened?
Nothing happen, I thought
maybe you needed me for something.
Heart attacks, that's
what I need all of you for.
Phoenix, Arizona calling Mr. Acebos.
Hello? Yes, yes operator, speaking.
Mr. Ocean doesn't answer?
Still doesn't answer and Mr. Foster?
Of course, keep calling.
They got to come in sometime.
- Hello? Jimmy, are you in yet?
- You don't even expect me.
Sorry operator, Mr. Foster is out.
Yeah, so is Mr. Ocean.
I made a cardinal rule not to answer the
telephone during the month of December.
That's crazy, why?
Because one December, only
time I picked up the phone they...
sent me out in the snow
to play with my little friends.
That was at the Bulge.
Clowns they got to be.
I like clowns but they should be funny.
It's a clown's business being funny.
And I ask you...
what is funny about going
to the pokey for 10 years?
To me in all sincerity, nothing.
Greed, yet that's exactly
where we'll be unless every...
bit of time is checked and checked.
One more question, inform me frankly.
What have I done to earn contempt?
Why should I be treated
like I'm stupid and there are smart?
That's right, was
your scheme in the first place.
So was the Hialeah racetrack job,
Hegel's supermarket and the
hit switch on Nelson's Armors cars.
All my inspirations.
There isn't a man in
the country with my reputation.
So, why don't those fellows respect me?
Maybe because you
don't do nothing, just get ideas.
I just get ideas.
If you're not careful
Buddybosch, she'll rub you out.
Acebos, he's insistent.
This is a recording,
you dialed the right number.
Now please hang up and don't do it again.
- Where were we?
- Right here.
That man is going to flip.
Well, he sell us into
the deal, let him sweat.
He didn't silver tongue you
for long, 30 seconds if he take a few.
You couldn't expect me to turn down a nice
conservative business opportunity like this.
- Especially where is no risk factor.
- I wouldn't have anything another way.
- And it's time we looked up Vince Massler.
- I saw him, he doesn't want in.
- Why not?
- Beats the hell out of me, sergeant.
I took him by the ears and dragged
him from Solano to Siegfried line.
And I may have to do it again.
Maybe this time he'll come gently.
Alright girls, time for your nap, beat it.
- Hey.
- See you later.
- Get up, lover boy, get up, get up.
- You're a spoilsport.
San Harmon is coming in the 3 o'clock,
shouldn't I go down to the airport?
I sent Steffans to the airport.
Everything to the last minute.
This Harmon should've
been in the scam weeks ago.
The whole crew should.
What about this Sam Harmon?
Why all the way from
Hawaii, he was so special?
And who says he can be trusted?
Sam Harmon is Ocean's closest friend.
- Another closest friend?
- Yeah.
- What about Foster?
- Before Foster, from way back.
We were all in the commandos
together and Ocean save Harmon's life.
Hey Sam, Sam Harmon.
Alright, that takes care
of me. Now, let's get to you.
George Steffans. Curly, Curly Steffans.
Curly, of course, I'd know you anywhere.
You haven't changed
either, you look great kid.
Hey listen, is Danny really going to go
through with this commando raid?
- Just like the old days.
- Who is this Acebos guy? What is he?
Planning division, he
dreamed it up. Not the tactics though,
Jimmy and Danny workout the coordination job.
What is he, a con?
- Leavenworth.
- Where Danny meet him?
Who knows?
A racetrack, a nightclub, Disneyland.
- Same old Danny.
- Yeah, he likes action.
- Still married?
- Yeah, but he's not working at it.
That figures. Soldier, fatigue detail.
Put this footlocker in my car,
Hold it.
What can I do for you?
- I would like to see the proprietor.
- You're looking at him.
- Well, doesn't Tony Bergdorf own this shop?
- Not anymore.
Can you tell where can
I find him? I'm a friend of his.
That's him, that's me.
I'm afraid what I'm
going have to tell you isn't a...
very nice thing to hear, he's in prison.
- Shorty Bergdorf?
- San Quentin.
- Won't you tell me were can I find his wife?
- I have her address here some place.
If you excuse me,
I'll get it for you in a minute.
May I use your phone
for a long distance call?
- Long distance?
- I'll have it reverse.
- Alright.
- Thank you.
- Hello.
- Collect call.
- Yes operator, I'll take the call.
- Go ahead please.
- Hello Corneal, it's me Mushy.
- Forget, it's not Phoenix.
This is Acebos, go ahead Corneil.
Tony Bergdorf is in
San Quentin, doing from one to five.
He's in prison, the electrician.
Our master electrician is doing one to five.
Make it a little short, will you please.
Here we are Miss Allenby.
Oh, thank you so much Mrs.
Bergdorf, Mr. Allenby will be so pleased.
- They're our very own children, you know.
- Oh, I know.
- Goodbye.
- Goodbye, thank you so much.
- Mommy is so pleased to have you home.
- Gracie...
Roger Corneal...
- Oh, where the world did you come from?
- Been a long time, how are you?
It's been a lifetime.
Was our first anniversary, wasn't it?
You remember those
rum drinks that betrayed us?
I haven't had rum since.
Oh, those were the old and
golden days, weren't they?
- You know about Tony?
- Yes, it's a shame.
He's getting out tomorrow morning.
Tomorrow? I thought
they gave him one to five.
Yeah, they did but they gave
him an amnesty, I don't know why.
- Oh, that Danny, always a step ahead.
- Pardon?
Oh, I'm just mumbling.
Will you have Tony call me when
he gets home? Tell him to call me at...
He won't be coming home, that's all finished.
Oh, I didn't know that.
Well, won't he see the kid?
Oh yes sure see Timmy, but he'll see
him in the Peninsular military school.
In the presence of Major Taylor.
- Can I use your phone Gracie?
- Sure.
Oh look Rog, I just
can't ignore the possibility of...
of him being a bad influence on little Timmy.
This time it must be Ocean.
- Hello.
- Mr. Corneal call...
- Who?
- Mr. Corneal.
- Corneal again.
- Will you accept the call?
- Yes, I'll accept the call.
That man sure likes telephones.
Come on in boys, I'll be right with you.
Hey Sam, get them up, get them up.
You look great. Is that what
a diet of wahines does for a guy?
- You get them up now.
- Come on, shoot one in there.
Fellows, I can't hear.
Hey Mushi, you look
almost human, you quit fighting?
Yes Sam, I'm running out of scar tissue.
Yeah, hold it a minute, Corneal.
Avail yourself of my hospitality Mr. Harmon.
Scotch.
- Yeah.
- Tomorrow morning.
Tomorrow morning?
Yeah, wait, wait. Yes, proceed, proceed.
- Just listen.
- Sure, I'm listening.
And I'm a very happy man.
No, no, I said I'm a, never mind,
never mind, go on. Thanks, Corneal.
It's excellent what you did,
yes, excellent, yes. Goodbye,
Another crisis lived through.
They're letting Bergdorf
out, giving him an amnesty.
Some joke.
I bet Ocean knew it all
the time but he wouldn't tell me.
No, no, he wouldn't. He's got to torture me.
Eat my heart out, he likes it of you, tutti.
You're not make yourself
popular knocking Danny.
Who's knocking him?
I love him, I respect talent.
All I'm asking is he should love me a little.
Too tough, don't ask.
How about that, fellows?
A little hand for Lolita.
And now a sweet bundle from
Texas, sweet as chocolate candy.
The tantalizing, Honeyface.
Sorry about the interruption
boys, I got a job to do.
What's the word Vince,
we got to catch a plane?
Danny, I never figured you'd go this route.
Vince, the plan is
foolproof take my word for it.
You know I lie to girls.
But Tim, if is so fool proof why
hasn't somebody done it yet?
Same reason nobody is gone
to the moon yet, no equipment.
And we're equipped, it's going to be a
military operation executed by trained men.
Why waste all those cute little
tricks that the army taught us...
just because its sort of peaceful now?
You remember a little bit
called Operation Gold in Oran?
Do I? Eleven of us on
a beach with a rubber boat...
and six million in gold bars.
- We should've buried them.
- No shovels but we got shovels this time.
What do you say Vince?
I can't do it boys,
I got my wife to think of.
- Think of her rich.
- Think of me dead.
Stop talking like a kid.
You went through the
whole war without getting dead.
Why suddenly should
you get dead in peacetime?
Vince, you're indestructible.
I'm sorry folks, I'd go along
with you in a minute, but my wife...
- When she come on?
- She's on.
Is that her?
- Yeah, why? What are you thinking?
- She's a very lovely girl.
Honeyface, I'd like to grab you, take you
home and spread you on my waffle.
Its only two of them.
First he comes around begging for a
job, now he's duping pay customers.
- Let's get the bum out.
- Ok Al.
- Now?
- Now is the time.
- What's matter with you boys?
- Hold it pal.
Hey, what's the big idea?
- Oh, stop it.
- Go that way.
- Come on boys.
- Voila.
I didn't figure to come across a
pierce set brawl like this so far in land.
You still want me Danny, I'm in.
Alright, you're in. Could be a little itchy.
I don't care, I'm tired of having
those bums yelling at my wife.
I don't want her have to
take it one more lousy night.
Neither do I, Vince.
Now, take that.
- Oh, shucks Danny.
- How cut out the gun's smoke dialog?
This a plane ticket.
Now, when you get up there...
Go to this address, ask for Josh
Howard, he'll tell you what to do.
- Josh Howard is in with you?
- Yeah.
- I feel better already.
- Good.
Heard anything about Louis
Jackson? Where he might be?
- Salt Lake City last I heard.
- We heard that too.
- Ok, we'll see you in a couple of days.
- What I may tell my wife?
- Tell you love her.
- That will hold her for a couple of weeks.
It's fun time Jimmy boy. I'll give
him a party, you make the drinks.
Hello, Jimmy Foster here are you there?
How can you do this to me?
You, I relied on, I had confidence in you.
From the other one I knew what to expect.
He's hopeless, hopeless, undisciplined.
That's why I sent you with him.
Hello Spyros, how are you?
Get away from that phone.
I won't talk to you. I won't...
I won't, all you know is to give
me heartache, better get shot.
Spyros, I got good news and bad.
Don't tell me the bad, bad news I got
plenty, all I want. Just tell me the good.
We're leaving Phoenix.
They're leaving Phoenix.
Danny darling, that's wonderful.
Oh, why didn't you tell me the first place?
Alright, now tell me what's the bad news.
We're going to Salt Lake City.
They're going to Salt Lake City.
Well, say hello to your father Timmy.
- Hi.
- Hello sir.
Don't I get a kiss or are
you grown too old for that?
Sorry sir.
Your clothes smell funny.
- I came from a faraway place.
- I know sir, Japan.
That's right, Japan.
I didn't stop to change
because I was afraid I'd miss you.
- Miss me sir?
- Yeah, don't you go home on weekends?
I do sir, but mother said you'd come
to see me and then I had to stay.
Oh, I'm sorry if I spoiled your
weekend with your mother.
But maybe you and I
can do something together.
Maybe we can go to a movie
and have some ice cream, eh?
How would you like to go to a football game?
- Oh, I would like that sir.
- Good, I'll call for you next Saturday.
- Yes sir.
- Right?
Dad.
- You won't forget Dad?
- No, no Timmy, I won't forget.
Merry Christmas Dad, I made it myself.
Well.
- Wait a minute, Corneal, Roger Corneal.
- That's me.
First man in the 82nd to be fined
for fraternizing with the Fraulein.
And the first man to greet
me in graduation day, how come?
I saw Grace, your kid glad to see you?
- Yeah, look what he made me.
- What's that? Beads?
No, it's Japanese abacus,
you can add and subtract on it.
- Oh, that is clever.
- Yeah.
Grace told him I was in Japan, she
couldn't tell the kid where I really was.
- No, I guess not.
- How things with you?
We need a master electrician.
- Who's we?
- Our old outfit.
- You mean Jimmy Foster and...
- Danny Ocean, Sam, Josh, all of them.
How they all got together? What's up?
It's a reunion.
We have been getting things ready for weeks.
- Sounds like a whale of a party.
- Bigger than Anzio or Raimac.
Only this time you won't
get paid in invasion money.
- It'll be the real long green, stacks of it.
- Oh, hold it.
Sounds like the kind of reunion that
can put me back in the Calendar Hall.
Tony. Tony.
Hup, two, three, four.
Tony?
You don't get rich if
you don't take a chance.
Look Rog, the last joker who fed me
that line was a wholesale jeweler.
He wanted me to short circuit his
burglar alarm so he can rob his own store.
It worked out fine, he got sixty grand, I
got one to five and I lost my wife and kid.
And the funny part of it
I thought I was doing it for her.
She always wanted a white fox stole.
This time it'll take you one
to five just to count your loot.
No, sorry Rog, I got
things to do in the outside.
And I'm going to stay there.
Besides, if I went in on it, you'd
be licked before you started.
I'm hard luck, I used
to be unlucky only for myself.
Now I'm unlucky
for everybody, see you around.
Didn't you get medical
attention on the penitentiary?
- Yes sir.
- Then what made you come to me?
When I was leaving Dr. Griffin said
I ought to see a specialist right away.
He made the appointment for me.
Look doc, give it to me straight.
Is it the big casino?-
I can't tell until
I've seen the biopsy report.
What if the report says it is? How long?
Well, I...
How long doc?
What do you say Tony?
You can still change your mind.
Will my cut be big enough
to send the kid through college?
Big enough to buy your kid a college.
- Come on Josh, your turn.
- Alright.
♪ Some day I'll have me a chauffeur... ♪
♪ And a block long limousine,
Eee-O-Eleven. Eee-O-Eleven. ♪
♪ Someday I'll have me a penthouse.
Stacks and stacks of folding green. ♪
♪ Eee-O-Eleven. Eee-O-Eleven. ♪
♪ It's all a state of mind,
whether or not you'll fine. ♪
♪ That place down there
or heaven, in the meantime. ♪
♪ Eee-O Eee -O. Eee - O-Eleven. ♪
♪ Eee-O - Eleven. Eee-O -Eleven. ♪
♪ It's all a state of mind,
whether or not you'll fine. ♪
♪ That place down there
or heaven, in the meantime. ♪
♪ Eee-O Eee -O. Eee - O-Eleven. ♪
♪ Eee - O-Eleven. ♪
Vince, Vincerinio, how are you?
You're a tough guy to catch up with Josh.
Trash is where you find
him, you got to fallow this lead.
What happened to ball-playing? No hit?
No see remember.
You know, when I got out of the Army the
only club that was open was down South...
no spot in the outfield spot.
Could you imagine how I would've made
out, a one-eyed third baseman in Mobile?
I always leveled with you, didn't I Josh?
Well, I'm stringing along
with this operation but I'm scared.
And it's no panic, just is this little
something gets me up in here.
That's the only way to be, makes you careful.
Look Vince, the brave ones
don't come home, you stay scared.
Yeah, you were always guys didn't want any
brave ones on patrol with you, weren't you?
That's simple enough, in my book,
bravery rhymes with stupid and still does.
Yeah, you were some yellow belly, imagine
the damn fool Army giving you the DSM.
I know, don't think I
wasn't scared the day I won that.
And do me a favor, will you? No even
mention it know because my knees...
start to shake all over again.
How come this operation
of Danny's isn't make you shake?
It does.
A million bucks apiece, I guess
you figure the odds are right?
Vince, baby boy,
the way I figure it is like this...
The 11 of us cats
against this one little city.
We're an overlay.
- Ok little pal, I'm ready for the briefing.
- Then step into my office.
♪ I've sunshine enough to spread
It's just like the fella said... ♪
♪ Tell me quick, ain't love a kick,
in the great kick in the head? ♪
- Sam Harmon.
- Merry Christmas Mrs. Ocean.
What are you doing here?
Hey, you better stop getting prettier
every day, you'll turn into a monopoly.
I asked you a question, why are you here?
Well, I got scared I'd gets two shorts from
all those leis hanging around my neck.
- Same sweet talking Sam, Danny still in bed?
- No, not exactly.
- In the hospital, see?
- Oh, no, no.
Because some doctor called the place
I work and said Danny is very sick.
- Frankly, that doctor was me.
- In fact the message said he was dying.
I wanted to make sure you'd come over.
- Dying was the touch that gave it away.
- You knew it was a gag?
It's the sort of stunt Danny usually
pulls when he wants to see me.
Why you come over if you knew was a gag?
Oh, it's Christmas. I have a
present for him, simple as that.
Now what's your excuse?
I was wondering what it is, I come to the
conclusion it must be love, mother love.
I'll consider mistress, play thing, toy for
a night but I refuse to be your mother.
- And that's out.
- No, you got it all wrong, I'm the mother.
I just don't like you and Danny busting up.
Yeah.
We're sort of eye to eye there.
I'd like to straighten him out.
No Mother, he's the
only one that can do that.
What happened to your marriage Bea?
It drowned in champagne.
With both of you on cloud nine,
I didn't think it got boring out there.
Boring, no.
I just woke up one morning and realized
there's nothing of any prospect, thin air.
So I got off at the next
mountain, walked down, got a job.
Danny didn't like that very well.
And a little later I left him.
How he feel about that?
Oh he, he wants me back, but not
enough to give me what I want.
Such as?
I want a life that doesn't
depend on the color of...
a card or the length of a horse's nose.
Danny ran into a little bad luck, eh?
If only he had.
A little bad luck might've made him realize
what things may mean when you earn them.
We didn't have a home Sam,
we had a floating crap game.
That's no life, it's a
way of running away from it.
- I better be going.
- Danny will be here any minute.
I have a job to get back to.
I don't really want see him
anyway Sam, there's no point in it.
Danny is not the only one who's running away,
Don't hack at me Mother, his luck is
bound to run out one of this days.
When it does, if he
still wants me, I'll be around.
- Hello Danny.
- Hey Bea, wait a minute.
- Hold it.
- Down please.
Oh, that make it, I came in with a fellow.
A fickle fellow, you stick
with me lieutenant, I'm sincere.
I got great news for you.
- Auburn beat Alabama by 12 points.
- No, this is important, honestly.
Hold it, come on back upstairs
at least for five minutes.
- No Danny. Down please.
- Up, all the way.
The Sky-room is not open
yet, there's no one serving.
- Fine.
- Why do I always give in?
Not like not starting another round.
Now, I'm out of training.
- It's a truce, peace talk, so help me.
- You always start that way.
Now, just sit there and don't interrupt me.
I got a very big deal
going on, lots of chips, carloads.
- That sounds familiar.
- That might be so but this time it's true.
Oh good, I'd like to have rich friends.
This is one of its friend that
wants to spend a bundle on you.
- Gee, thanks.
- Ok, that's settled.
On January 2nd, I'll pick you up
and we're going to hop down to Rio.
You're serious?
- I honestly think you're serious.
- Yes, of course I'm serious.
- A week's trip to Rio.
- Yes.
Oh Danny, what a prize you are.
The only husband in the world
who proposition his wife.
Well, I married you once and
it didn't work out to well, so...
- what's wrong with a little hey-hey?
- Nothing, nothing at all.
I'd never knock it as long
there is a little love involved.
- You mean there isn't?
- On your part, not much.
There's only one thing
you love Danny, that's danger.
Cliffhanging.
You can never love a
woman like you love danger.
And as long as you're luck goes
up you'll stay in love with danger.
As long as it keeps coming up heads.
Let's say you're right,
let's say you're absolutely right.
- But remember I did not invent myself.
- What's that suppose to mean?
That's mean I do not own the patent.
And I can't change it any
more than you change yours...
and anyone who says he can is a liar.
I didn't expect you to be perfect
just because I fell in love with you.
- Going down.
- Just a second.
And it wouldn't hurt you
to give me the same break.
I don't expect you to be perfect,
I want you to be my husband.
- Going down.
- Where they serve the drinks?
- To the bar.
- James.
- Hello there Sam.
Don't stop, I'm just calling Mother.
♪ Sure, I love the money
that shines in your hair... ♪
♪ And the brow that's all
furrowed and wrinkled with care. I... ♪
♪ Kiss the dear fingers, that hold all that
dough all that blessing and keeper... ♪
♪ Tell your mother... ♪
- Hello.
- Mrs. Restes' residence.
- Is it Mother there?
- Oh yes Mr. Foster.
- Oh, it's my Jimmy, my innocent.
- Another innocent touch.
- Jimmy, where have you been?
- Oh, here and there.
Oh, it was wicked of
you not at least to have telephoned.
- We've been home 3 whole days.
- What you mean we?
We? We means your poor
lonely mother and Mr. Santos.
I wrote you about him, I think.
He's been very kind to me
and he's a financial genius.
- Just what I always hoped you'd be.
- Yes Mother. Speaking of finances...
- Could you let me have some more?
- Some more what?
Money. M - O - N - Y.
- E.
- Yeah, M - O - N - E - Y.
Oh yes, of course darling.
If you tell me what you want it for.
I plan to paper the walls with it.
Oh Jimmy, shall I try and take an interest
in your affairs just snap my head off.
Oh mother, how do I know
what I'm going yo spent it on?
It just goes, you know what I mean?
Oh, you mean spending money.
Oh, why didn't you say so?
I was afraid you might be
considering some foolish investment.
No Mother, nothing foolish.
Alright darling, hurry
over and bring me a big kiss.
- I want to see my big tall boy.
- Yes, yes Mother, I'll be there around 5.
What a way to make a living?
Alright Sam, let's have
a quick briefing on Hawaii.
Hawaii? Oh, great sunsets.
Only one a day but they're working on it.
Weather good enough
to get me up in the daytime?
Sometimes it rains, sometimes the sun is out.
And how about the women?
Oh, speaking of women,
did you take a good look at Bea?
No really, no.
The play went around the other end.
- She's still in love with Danny, you know..
- And what's the problem? He's up too.
- Yeah, I'm worried about him.
- Worried?
- Maybe you mean is the project worries you.
- Can be part of it.
You trying to salt the
clouds, maybe spoil the picnic?
Jimmy, what do you need this picnic for?
If you want money all
you have to do is yell for Mother.
You haven't met Mother, have you?
No, but I gather she's very generous.
Generous to a fault.
Especially when it comes to husbands.
She only had five.
Oh, that must left you
pretty much out in the cold, eh?
No such luck.
Would you mind spelling that out?
I had so much mother love,
you'd thought I was quintuplets.
She wouldn't let me out of her
sight, everything was done for me.
After the war I tried to break away from her.
Plenty of money is a hard habit to kick.
That's why I;M going to our picnic.
- Well, the Hawaiian hotshot.
- Hi Danny.
Hello Sam, how are you?
Oh, same as always, I move, I breath, I seem
to feel the thrill of life along the keel.
You sound like a ferryboat.
I'm not a ferryboat, I'm a very manly slope.
Where I go people stare
at me in at dumb admiration.
And what happens when they speak?
And never mind that, let's get back to
where you ask me how I was, I was fine.
Will you get Spyros on the phone?
You know something?
I think the only reason why I got into
this caper so I could see you again.
Sounds like a hell of a price
and I agree with you, I'm worth it.
It is in time for the jokes.
For you Mr. Acebos, very important.
- Hello.
- This is the Los Angeles County morgue.
Los Angeles County morgue. Yes?
We have a couple of men down here...
one is well muscled and the
other one is rather slender build.
Oh my goodness, my...
These two young fellows
were traveling mighty fast...
in an automobile, look like their try
to keep an engagement somewhere,
Their names are...
Never mind, never mind
their names, I know, I knew them.
Would you be willing to identify them?
I'm willing. I'll, I'll
come down, I'll be right there.
Oh my goodness, yes.
And what is your name please?
Just ask for Detective Lieutenant Brannigan.
Detective Bra...
How did he get my name?
Let's saddle up, let's go.
I finally caught up with you,
where you've been for days and days?
And what you doing back with your wife?
I know she was here, in this hotel
with you, not more than an hour ago.
You're two-timing me,
and I'm warning you Danny Ocean.
I'm one girl you can't treat this way.
I won't be pushed around and neglected.
- What exactly you plan to do about it?
- Plenty, I'm going to do just plenty.
- Isn't it about time you got started?
- Now wait a minute big buster...
No, you wait a minute and
listen to me very carefully my dear.
I picked you up at
the Biltmore Bar because I...
thought you were attractive
and I had nothing better to do.
And I made a pass at you
for the very same reasons.
Now, I don't know what's your reason
were but nobody twisted your arm...
made you any promises.
So what is this act? Not outraged virtue.
You really are a rat.
Why don't you let it go Adele?
I know all about the guys you had on a
string, you told me about it, remember?
And why you treating me
this way, I didn't do anything.
Neither did I, so why
don't just say goodbye nicely?
Surely. And maybe I should say
thank you, for being humiliated.
Well, put this in your pipe.
One of these days I'll
break your back, I swear it.
- Is a good thing she doesn't pack a knife.
- How do you know she doesn't?
To the morgue.
You...
You low, miserable...
I cry but not for you or you or you.
For my money you could drop dead.
I think he's mad at us,
let's go back to the hotel driver.
You stay right here.
You, come out of that cab.
So I'm mad, I'm entitled.
Ok Spyros, we accept your apology.
No phone call.
With all these jokes for
messages maybe you forgot...
to call everybody they
should be here for the meeting.
No, not at all, I just wanted to check
on you to see if you're still alive.
Me alive?
Well, you know how it is? You so apoplectic.
My health is my greatest
virtue, every day I do exercises.
No, everybody is going to be
here at 9 o'clock for the meeting.
Yeah, then you can entertain us by doing
some these deep knee bends push-ups.
- Good evening.
- Evening Marie, my mother at home?
She's expecting you
Mr. Foster but she's upstairs.
Thank you.
- Oh, you must be Jimmy.
- That's correct.
Your mama be down
in a minute, I'm Duke Santos.
I'll wait in here.
Must be a funny feeling meeting a total
stranger who's going to be your stepfather.
I mean, I think it's only natural
if you resent me a little.
Then you won't mind if I don't call you Dad.
Duke is Ok.
Oh, it's the engagement
ring I bought your mama.
That's nice. Zircon, isn't it?
- Zircon? That's a diamond.
- Oh, I'm sorry.
You probably thought it was
a Zircon because it's so big.
It isn't too big, is it? Your
mama is got an wonderful taste.
Has she?
Alright, rich boy.
You want it that way, you got it.
Let's see how fat you get tangling with me.
No, I know your record
Santos and your connections.
A lot of loot and a rough guy to cross.
But I still reserve the right to dislike you.
Well, sure, sure.
A man marries your mama, like I said,
it's only natural, takes a little time.
But you find out I can be a pretty good Joe.
Yeah, I'll tell the FBI.
They're not looking for
me anymore, I'm clear now.
That's one point for Mother.
Easy for you to
look down on people, isn't it?
All this ever since he was a baby.
You ever make a buck yourself?
No, but I have plans.
Know what I had when I
was a kid? A lot of nothing.
Nobody to help me either.
Now I got a lot of everything.
Got a lot of years too and a sick stomach.
Proves that my way is better.
- What way?
- Choose rich parents.
Yeah, you bet that's better.
My folks are so poor I used to walk
New York barefoot winter and summer.
One day I'm swimming in the East river...
when I come out I seen
a row of shoes in the wharf.
One pair brand new, I put them on, they fit.
Then some kid yells, hey them
is my shoes, so we fight. I win.
It's been that way ever since.
Fight, fight, all the time.
- And you always win?
- Sure, I got the guts.
Like you when you was in the
82nd Airborne, your mama told me.
You know, I've often wondered if
I'd have the guts to jump out of a plane.
Only for money or if I was young.
You got to be young to do anything.
Come on, loosen up.
Have a drink to my wedding.
Why not?
- Soda?
- What about you?
- No, not me, I told you, delicate.
- Come on Mr. Santos, fight, always fight.
You got the guts, you look at me win.
- Yeah, but...
- What's the matter? Run out of guts?
- Darling, at last.
- Hello Mother.
What's wrong with Duke?
He'd a slight attack of courage.
We had a drink to your wedding.
He knows he can't touch it, poor darling.
Yes, so he told me,
was naughty of me, won't me?
Indeed it was and not
congratulating me is naughty too.
Oh, I'm sorry. Bon voyage.
Oh, I know must think you that
I'm on a marital merry-go-round...
trying for all the brass
rings but this time is different.
You can say that again.
Oh, I realizes his
background is impossible but...
please don't judge
him from that point of view.
Oh, what view do you suggest mother?
- A woman's.
- Oh, I find that highly impractical.
You can understand if you try.
Since your father died Duke Santos is
the only man who's ever needed me...
really needed me, no, not my money.
Alright alright, I won't be critical.
And now speaking of money...
- Here it is.
- Thank you.
A woman loves to be needed Jimmy, Duke
is the most important thing in my life now.
Outside of you of
course, so please be nice, eh?
As soon I get back to town I'll butter
him up, tell him I'm sorry I needled him.
Oh, but where are you going?
I, I'm going skiing with, with
Danny Ocean, with the square ballet.
But you won't miss the wedding?
Mother, have I ever
missed one of your weddings?
Yes, the first one.
- Bye.
- Bye darling.
It's after 9, everybody
is here but this Jackson.
Shall we start the meeting without him?
Lack of organization, it's a poison, it
poison enterprise, kills it dead, dead. Dead.
You know, all point in having money, is
so that other people know that you got it.
I want to get me a big 50 foot
Chris-Craft and not even put it in the water.
Just going to leave it in my driveway...
maybe give it to the
mailman or somebody like that.
Well, that's sound real stupid like,
why don't you use it to improve yourself?
I don't need no improving,
I'm alright the way I am.
Gin.
Can understand that, I played it like a god.
Well, don't you finish
the sentence, how many points?
They get 10 points.
Why don't you guys be smart?
Won't you put your loot in with me, eh?
You know what I'm going to do with my money.
I'm going to produce my own pictures.
I got to listen to all this,
they're rotting my brain.
So where is this Jackson?
Where's some sort of organization?
Don't panic, will you?
You know, it's a good idea.
Take a couple of hundred big ones
and do something for world peace.
Like buying out the Miss Universe contest.
Get rid of all the parade and all that jazz.
And just sit around and
talk to the girls, one by one.
Find out how things are in Sweden.
Or invite them for a weekend to New Orleans.
- Ramos gin fizz's, oysters Rockefeller...
- No, I don't like that good well approach.
Use your loot right, you can order
them to New Orleans for the weekend.
- You like to explain that professor?
- Very simple, by turning money into power.
I go buy me some votes and go into politics.
Hey, that's a good idea big boy.
You'd make a good notary public.
He'd make a better coroner.
One of laughing coroner.
- I'm going into going in politics.
- What's going to be your platform Big Sam?
Repeal the 14th and 20th amendment.
Take the vote away from the
women, make slaves out of them.
Hey now, that's
something is real constructive.
- Hey, will it cost much?
- Oh No, we'd have the price controlled.
No inflation on slaves,
Vote for Sam Harmon,
help stamp out mental health.
- You got a better platform?
- Sure.
Pay off your own party,
settle for an appointment.
Yeah, that's real deep thinking. Gentlemen,
I'd like you to meet our latest senator.
What a terrible thought.
Why don't you become an ambassador, you
could be a big men some foreign country?
Make that a little foreign country,
we don't want a big enemy.
Yeah, little country like Andorra.
- Or Pomona.
- What about Little Rock?
Hey fellas, you have any idea how
much money a man can steal...
if he was something like
Commissioner of Indian Affairs?
That's what I'll be,
Commissioner of Indian Affairs.
- That you'll never be.
- For what.
Because I'm going to be secretary of
the interior and I won't appoint you.
- This commissions is a snobbish idea.
- -You won't?
No, I won't.
Certitude, my dear fellow, went
out with equestrian statuary.
- Now, what kind of language is that?
- Beats me, that's not on me.
I don't know, but If you ask me,
I think that cat is a spy there.
So where is this horse-wrangler? 9:30.
Still running around Salt Lake City
I'll bet, saying goodbye to his wives.
- And his horses.
- Yeah.
Up and down after up and down.
And the houseboy's night off yet.
- Mr. Acebos?
- Who's asking?
He is, you know him?
Oh Jackson, Louis, my boy, I...
What's wrong officer?
Louis, you did something?
Oh no sir, he didn't do anything, we just
want to be sure he got in the right place.
That's the Beverly Hills police for you, the
best in America, they pro, protect us...
night and day, thank you officer.
Thank you, good night. You, you're crippled.
Oh, no, it's not well,
that's the way we found him.
- Good night.
Oh Louis my boy, come in.
I couldn't be in error...
I couldn't be in error, could I?
Your name couldn't be otherwise than Jackson?
No, I reckon that's my name partner.
Don't please tell me why you had to
come in such a pitiable condition, don't.
Suits me Mr. Acebos.
- Hello Danny.
- Hello cowboy.
What took you so long?
You come on a horse back?
Hot damn, what a foxhole? Howdy, you all.
- Hello, Josh.
- How are you?
- Good, great.
- Hi.
So what's for you to be funny of?
You should be ashamed of yourself.
Enticing a broken armed man
into a project of such precision.
You know what your problem is? You
underestimate people, Louis, grab it.
But...
What's, what's with the broken arm?
Why shucks Mr. Acebos? Is all healed now.
You knew this, you Dracula, you
want to worry me into an early grave.
Lieutenant, brief your group.
Anyone not at ease, get that way.
Some of you already have a general
idea the plan of this operation.
Before I give you the full picture, I
want to point out that everyone turned up.
Not one goof off.
I say this is a hell of a good sign.
Lieutenant, I think you and the sergeant
ought to be very proud of yourself.
And you give us the good news,
how about the bad news?
Sergeant Ocean.
This is our objective. Las Vegas, Nevada.
Mission? To liberate millions of dollars.
Now these are the 5 casinos we hit.
Sahara, Riviera, Desert Inn,
the Sands and the Flamingo.
H hour is New Year's Eve.
Units involve, special combat teams made
up of former members of the 82nd Airborne.
Just for curiosity, how did you figure
this is a job for old paratroopers?
Why you didn't just
get some regular heist guys?
For the best of reasons Mr. Harmon.
A man with a criminal record can't get
near Las Vegas, might less the casinos.
I guess that lets me out.
Don't be ridiculous, you're no hoodlum.
You got no connection to the underworld.
Hoods always mix with other hoods.
Where there're hoods, there stool pigeons.
But with us, no stool leads, no leaks.
Now you five guys working
on the hotels, which hotels you in?
- Flamingo.
- The Sands.
- Desert Inn.
- Riviera.
Sahara.
Now, there'll be 5 more men working as
floaters with you inside guys as 2 men teams.
Sam, you've been in Vegas many times.
Give me a rundown on exact
action takes place New Year's Eve.
Come midnight they go nuts.
Everybody kisses anybody.
Then because they just met each other, they
sing Should auld acquaintance be forgot.
How long you figure take to sing that song?
Oh, I don't know, about...
One minute and 38
seconds exactly, we timed it.
Now, one minute and 38
seconds after midnight we black out...
the whole town and hit
the 5 casinos at the same time.
Sahara, Riviera, Desert Inn...
the Sands and the Flamingo.
Nobody will even see us.
- You got a question Tony?
- How you figure to black out a whole town?
Let me ask you one, what happens
if you knock out one of these towers?
You'll get a short circuit as
soon as the cable touches the ground.
It's interesting.
Reimer and Josh are the
demolition men, what's my job?
We need you to open the doors for the
cashiers' cages for that where the loot is.
Now, those doors are controlled electrically.
The cashier can open them
by pushing a button from the inside.
But if the button is on the inside
I can't push it from the outside.
But that's exactly where you
going to push it from, the outside.
Now, every casino is got an auxiliary motor
That generates enough power to light up...
the gambling tables and cashiers'
cages whenever the main cable fails...
which happens quite often.
The auxiliary motor kicks in automatically,
20 seconds and they're back in business.
Except they won't quite be back
in business on account of you Tony.
Now, let me ask you a question...
What happens if you cross
the wires that operate lights...
with wires that open the cage doors?
Well, when the auxiliary motor
kicks in, instead of the lights going on...
- the doors of the cages will click open.
- As simple as that.
Yes, in theory, but to be sure I have to
study the main switch box in each casino.
Oh, but you will, you will.
- Is this the only road in or out Vegas?
- Yeah, that's route 91, why?
Oh, I remember reading
about this guy in Perth.
Is this going to be
another of your long stories?
- Who cut up his grandmother.
- Cut up his grandmother?
Come on fellows, let him talk.
Who cut up here
grandmother and mailed her out of town.
Everything went find
until he ran out of stamps.
Which proves something very crucial, right?
Now, wait a minute, there
Pete is got a very good point.
Now, getting you missing as though is
wanting but getting out of town is another.
- Yeah, that's where Josh comes in.
- I was wonder.
But don't wonder. He's the
main cog, if he goofs, it's over.
- What's wrinkling you Curly?
- How long can we depend on a staying dark?
- 10, 15 minutes.
- It's not much time.
It's plenty of time if everyone
does what he's suppose to do.
Danny is right. You should all
move like clockwork, seventeen jewel.
Boys, I wanted you should think
of this as a full fledged battle.
Leap into it with same high pride hearts...
that got you across the Rhine River and...
other historical places.
Just think, think how proud all the big
brass in the Pentagon would be, would be...
knowing that their labors made
this, this beautiful operation possible.
You know, I think they all sit right...
down in the officers' mess
and have a good cry from happiness.
Even I myself am little bit tempted.
- Any further questions?
- Yeah, what's your job Acebos?
Yeah Mr. Acebos, what you all going to do?
Our modest friend here is a known felon.
They take one look at him
up in Vegas and we're kaput.
- That's it.
- Any more questions?
- Comments, anybody worried?
- I got a suggestion.
- What is it Sam?
- Forget it.
- Forget? Why...
- The whole deal, forget the whole deal.
And believe me, I'd like to swing
like the rest of you guys, but...
you haven't got a plan
here, you got a pipe blow.
Is this another of your
morbid jokes Danny, you sadist?
- What's wrong with our story Sam?
- For one thing, 15 years.
This ain't a combat
team, it's a long night meeting.
Any of you lairs want to claim
you're half the man you were in '45?
Can you run as fast? Can you think as fast?
Can you mix it up as good
you used to? Well, I sure can't.
And Danny, if you want to try and
catch lightning in a ball you go ahead...
but don't try and catch yesterday.
Old times are only good when you've had them.
Sam...
some guys grow old without turning chicken.
Did you hear about it?
Ok, Lieut Lionheart, I grant you're brave.
But the question now is, how dumb are you?
I'm the only one here that knows Las Vegas.
Why don't you guys believe me when I...
tell you the percentage is always
with the house? With the house.
The percentage is with the people
rigging the game and in this case is us.
- Deserter under fire, a traitor.
- Oh, shut up or I'll step on you.
You can't let him walk out like
this, it disrupts the entire plan.
Maybe you got an idea on how to stop him?
- He owes you, you saved his life.
- And I'm trying to save his life.
Sam.
Thank you Danny.
You don't owe me a thing Sam,
and you're entitled to your opinion.
Anybody agree with him?
What about you Josh? You got brains.
Yeah, I got brains Sam,
but I got to go with Danny.
Well, at least it only
leaves us one man short.
One man short? Oh, that's nothing, nothing.
Danny darling, just run a want ad.
This means we have to leave out one of the
casinos, which one you think it ought to be?
By way, way, hold it, hold it.
Nobody is walking out.
So I can't talk you guys out of it, I can't.
I'm certainly not going let you boobs,
trying pull this job without your best man.
So go ahead, let's me have it.
When do we blow this mausoleum?
Cuckoo.
The day after tomorrow
gentleman, we'll be in Las Vegas.
Happy New Year.
You spray the stuff on your shoes yet?
I did, but that infrared paint you
gave me isn't ready for the public yet.
- I can't see a single footprint.
- Of course you can, try this.
Still nothing Danny must be off his rocker.
Cool it. Put these on. Go ahead, put them on.
Now look.
Wow.
I got an extra can of this jazz.
I want you to do me a
favor, don't be stingy with it, Ok?
- Hey.
- What?
They ought to mix this with dames makeup.
It would make for interesting midnights.
Yeah, I'm hipped.
One, two, three, four. Two, two,
three, four. Three, two, come on kids.
Hup, two, three, four.
One, two, three, four. One...
Hey, kill it, kill it. Go on,
Helen, get in there, take her place.
You got a tough job.
Why so many barrels?
I don't know, is a whole of dinners, when
is a la carte, then we get sensible garbage.
We'll have none of that.
- Sorry.
- Hi you.
- Oh hello Mr. Skelton.
- So you remember me, eh?
- I remember what you told me too.
- What I told you?
Oh, about putting limit on myself? But
you don't take that seriously, did you?
You said you'd break me like a dry twig
if I cashed another one of your checks.
Oh well, don't pay any attention to that kind
of talk, is all solid flab, you know, eh?
I actually haven't got the strength
to pull a wing over a dead bee.
- Here cash the check.
- No use arguing.
- We won't let you exceed your limit.
- Oh, this is unbelievable.
Get a load of this guy, the way he acts
he thinks we're going to stick up the joint.
- We wouldn't do that, would we?
- No.
Ridiculous, cash the check.
Please Mr. Skelton,
this gentleman is waiting.
Like a tree, buddy
boy, I'm standing right here...
like an leafy elm until you
cash that perfectly good check.
You ought to be a little more careful.
You know, I may hit a
lucky streak and win this casino.
It can happen you know,
the whole joint could be mine.
Then wonder what cashier's
little old nose would be out of joint?
- Let me tell you pal.
- Oh, no guts, eh?
- Had send for Wyatt Earp little fat brother.
- It's Ok.
Watch my arm, that's my old slot machine arm.
Silver dollars please.
- Coffee please.
- Could you light me up please?
I had the key made, be
careful with it, cost me two bits.
I hope somebody is keeping an
eye on all this reckless spending.
- Here's, here's one for the Sahara.
- Right.
♪ How lucky can one guy be?
I kissed her and she kissed me... ♪
♪ Like the fella' once said,
ain't that a kick in the head? ♪
♪ The room was completely black,
I hugged her and she hugged back... ♪
♪ Like the sailor said, quote,
ain't that a hole in the boat? ♪
♪ My head keeps spinning,
I go to sleep and keep grinning. ♪
♪ If this is just the beginning,
my life is going to be beautiful. ♪
I've sunshine enough to
spread, it's just like the fella' said... ♪
♪ Tell me quick,
ain't love a kick in the head? ♪
♪ Red that's a kick in the head. ♪
♪ Ain't that a hole in the boat? ♪
♪ My head keeps spinning,
I go to sleep and keep grinning. ♪
♪ If this is just the beginning,
my life is going to be beautiful. ♪
♪ She's telling me we'll be wed,
she's picked out a king-size bed. ♪
♪ I couldn't feel
any better or I'd be sick. ♪
♪ Tell me quick, oh ain't love a kick? ♪
♪ Tell me quick, ain't
love a kick In the head. ♪
You look like you
getting a combat fatigue girls...
you've been up on that line a long time.
- Everything alright Joe?
- Like tulips in July Mac.
- You want to get a split, don't you?
- - Come on Josh.
- I can do it if you cool it just a second.
- Be sure you let go of the ball hard.
- What you find out last night?
- Casinos don't like to be robbed.
It's a pretty narrow minded aptitude,
Go right wire-crossing work?
Technically yes,
technically everything works.
How long will it take you to rig them?
Oh, 5 casinos, 15
minutes each, that's 75 minutes.
Traveling time 25 minutes,
that's an hour and 40 minutes.
And that's when I'll rig them.
One hour and 40 minutes before we get.
- Can't you preset them so it's ready?
- Can't take the chance.
If the main cable should
fails legitimately, those doors...
spring open like a set of false thief.
- Did you pick a tower?
- The biggest.
Josh will give me a hand.
What about the Sahara?
One security cop really got me
bugged, the guy sits in front of the cages.
Must've arthritis or something,
sun of a gun, he never moves.
A left hook will keep him that way.
- Sam?
- Steady as down country loving.
Good boy.
Louis, what about the Desert Inn?
Why, it'll be just as easy
as riding a stuffed horse.
- How's that?
- It'll be as...
Just forget it.
- Jimmy?
- Flamingo is all set.
What about the Sands?
Smooth and level.
Alright, nobody carries
identification until the job is done.
Everybody got an
inside job, you go back to work.
The rest of us will wait
outside, mingle with the crowd.
Stand in front of your respected
casinos until Jimmy and I contact.
What are we going to do with our self
till we hit? We have all today and tomorrow.
Hey, I got an idea, therapeutic idea.
Forget it. No, no.
Today Tonight and all day tomorrow
we rehearse and keep rehearsing until H hour.
- Transportation?
- Have no fear, little Josh is here.
- Let's go, Mushy is up.
- Come on, you make it.
- I never bowled in my life.
- Fake it.
- Do we have time for another show?
- What about the lounge at the Sands?
- That's a good idea.
- Yeah, it's my lucky spot.
Someone you know?
I just thought that I recognized
somebody I know from the profession.
Yours or his? Come on.
- Well, well, well.
- What are you doing here?
Same thing you are, cheating.
Ah no, you got
me wrong, I'm here on business.
I expect my party any minute.
I'd like to see her
and I'll bet your wife would too.
Now, you don't understand,
I'm all alone, cross my heart.
I hope you die.
Take your hands off me or I'll call that cop.
Let's not panic.
When you realize how wrong you are, use that.
Hello?
Mrs. Ocean? This is a friend.
I'm calling from Las Vegas.
I just think you'd be interested
to know that your husband...
is up to in Vegas.
That's funny, I was taught that creature
like you always rattled before they struck.
- And I didn't hear a thing.
- I thought I was doing you a favor.
- Sorry I disturbed you.
- No Malicious, I'm not disturbed.
When I learn Danny has
an enemy as venomous as you...
it just makes me love him a little more.
Call me anytime, love
to have you waste your money.
Happy burial, dead dog.
- Are you all ready Pete?
- Just a second.
- What time is it set-up?
- One minute, 38 seconds past midnight.
- It's five after 6.
- Right.
One minute and 38 seconds past 12 o'clock.
Big Daddy and then happy New Year.
Happy New Year, come on, let's go.
♪ Live, live, live until I die. ♪
♪ They're going to say What a guy,
he's going to play for the sky.. ♪
♪ Ain't going to miss a thing,
I'm going to have my fling... ♪
♪ I'm going to
live, live, live until I die. ♪
♪ The blues I lay low, I'll make them stay
low, they'll never trail over my head. ♪
I'll be a devil, till I'm an angel,
♪ But until then Hallelujah. ♪
♪ Going to dance, dance, dance, going
to fly, I'll take a chance riding high. ♪
♪ Before my number is up, I'm going to fill
my cup, I'm going to live, live, live... ♪
♪ Until I die. ♪
- Good evening Mrs. Restes.
- Oh hello.
- Nice to see you, happy New Year.
- Same to you.
You know, Las Vegas is like Paris a way,
you always run into people you know.
- And usually wish you hadn't.
- My sentiment is exactly.
Excuse me a second, will you honey?
I want to go bar side a minute.
- Oh, I adore running into old friends.
- It's certainly our pleasure.
- Is Jimmy joining us?
- Ah, poor Jimmy..
No, he's shivering in Squaw valley.
- But he's here.
- Here, in Vegas?
Here at the Flamingo, I saw him last night.
Oh dear, don't tell me
he broke something skiing.
Nothing that showed.
Oh, why would he tell
me he was going to Squaw?
Oh, I'm stupid, it's simple.
He ran into some jiggly little
number who was Vegas bound.
Jiggly little number isn't the way
exactly I would describe Danny Ocean.
More like a well mannered shark.
Twenty five dollar chips please.
Tony, it's me Steffans Tony...
You nuts? Get away from here.
It's say after 11:30,
you think you'll make it?
You know soon enough.
Ok, I'll see you at the blow off.
♪ I couldn't feel
any better or I'd be sick... ♪
♪ Tell me quick. Oh, ain't love a kick... ♪
♪ Tell me quick,
ain't love a kick in the head? ♪
I thought he said it was a, a lady's
drink, I think he meant a lady horse.
He meant one at a time honey.
Lucky I can hold my liquor very fortunate.
You can get to the room
by yourself, can you honey?
I got a date in the casino, here's your key.
You're wasting, wasting your time with
that Clyde honey, he's a loser, he's a loser.
Oh, I'm so drunk I don't think I
could lie down without holding on.
Get her out of here.
Here you are Missy, happy New Year to you.
It so happens that I do not
know who you are my good fellow.
Oh well now, who do I have to be
to wish you a happy New Year?
Ricky Nelson.
I used to be Ricky
Nelson, I'm Perry Como now.
No, you're not, you moved.
Smart girl, smart girl. Now, about this
night air, let's get in out of it, come on.
- Come on.
- Is it New Year's yet?
Too close for comfort, come on.
I hate it too, I hate holidays.
Do you like the holidays?
Hey, give me a little kiss, how about it, eh?
Sound idea, it's good talking. Yeap.
- Right there and I'll be there in a minute.
- And I'll wait for you.
You know something? I think I kiss better
when I'm drunk than I do when I'm sober.
- Some other time.
- Where you going?
Oh, after all that we've meant
to each other, I must leave you.
- Hey now, this is a dirty deal.
- Our first quarrel.
- I don't fit into your picture?
- From here on in you don't sweetheart.
- Good night.
It's Ok man.
It's Ok, it so happens
I'm very much in demand.
Maestro, if you please.
Ladies and gentlemen, it's almost midnight.
So pucker up your
lips ladies, 20 seconds to go.
20, 19, 18, 17, 16...
15, 14, 13, 12, 11...
10, 9, 8, 7, 6...
5, 4, 3, 2, 1.
Happy New Year.
Lights, lights.
Darn that cable,
it's the second time this month.
Stay where you are, the
lights will be back on any minute.
Once more George, from the top and
keep playing until the lights come on.
Oh, pardon me, wrong girl.
Douse those lights. Now sing loud and clear.
Sing louder.
With the music now,
when shouldn't it be forgot?
Blow out the candle. Blow.
Alright now, sing.
It's a party, loud and clear.
Do what he says Charlie, trick or treat.
You too, let's make it a duet.
Little louder.
We've been hit.
- We've been tapped.
- What?
We've been held up, robbed.
Give me the sheriff's office, hurry.
- Hello.
- Sheriff Wimmer?
Yeah, this is sheriff Wimmer speaking.
- Flamingo speaking, we've been tapped.
- What? We'll be right over.
The Flamingo, roll cars 620, 622 and 624.
You can roll some more,
they just knocked over the Sands.
Happy New Year.
- How it come off?
- Like a charm.
Same here, fantastic.
Attention all cars,
cover all entrances and exits.
Sands, Sahara, Flamingo,
Desert Inn and Riviera.
Check everyone who leaves.
Don't you get a look
at them? Any kind of them?
What? In the dark?
I see, it was dark, don't
you hear anybody say anything?
- Yeah, he said we should sing.
- He said you should sing.
Ladies and gentlemen, this is Don Murphy...
speaking for station
KLAS-TV, here in Las Vegas, Nevada.
We're standing in front
of the famous Hotel Riviera.
In just a few moments, you'll hear
some reports of this fantastic robbery...
from the spot eyewitnesses.
Yes, do you have something you want to say?
Say, do me a favor, if you going to
interview people, pick elderly couples.
Some of the others don't
always belong together.
- Don't look now, it's little old me.
- Hoops, how your action go?
If it were any easy, I
might ashamed to take the money.
Good boy, get lost now.
Cars 305 and 309, reinforce roadblocks
extending to Barstow, acknowledge.
Get a rundown on every train leaving
Vegas, passenger and freight, east and west.
Things went too easy.
Tony.
Never the luck, never the luck.
- Tony.
Ok folks, get back. Ok.
- Call for an ambulance quick.
- Ok, but this guy is dead.
Look Danny Tony is just
another guy died in the street.
- Lot of guys die in the street.
- Sure they do.
Happens all the time.
- No sweat.
Yes, I heard you,
check all out going flights.
Car 306, 306, come in please.
I want every piece of luggage examined.
306, proceed with plan 22. Over.
Ask them, they don't
cooperate, fine, let's find out why.
- I haven't a man to spare and we can do it.
- What you mean you can't do it?
- How it go?
- Smooth as a peeled egg, how about you?
Well, things happen can break you up,
things you don't expect, you know.
- Like what?
- Tony is dead.
Bergdorf?
Heart attack, I guess,
he drop crossing the street.
- Cops got to him before we did.
- They'll check up on him.
Sure they will, what they going to find?
Nothing, nobody will ever know.
Yeah, no one but us.
Don't hit me on the head with that,
will you? I'll tell the other men about Tony.
Maybe by tell them, they won't panic.
Meantime the plan remains the same.
The money stays where it is until the heat is
off, nobody takes out until we get a word.
Maybe you better go back
to your job, I'll contact you later.
Ok.
He's taking it hard.
Yeah, long time since
he lost a man in combat.
Is it true somebody
stole millions of dollars?
Oh yes ma'am, but there's still some
left. Would you move along please?
The sheriff's office and the State police...
have assured us we're going to have
a round down and capture by morning.
Thank you very much sir.
And there you have it.
Millions of dollars are missing,
stolen by an unknown number of men, but...
at this very minute they're being tracked
down as they skulk through the night...
down dark roads and lonely alleys where
the long arm of the law is reaching out.
- Happy New Year officer.
- Yeah, Happy new year.
Say, what's going on before leaves Santa?
Will you get this
garbage truck on out of here?
I'll be glad to do that there.
Happy New Year.
Oh, my goodness.
He Danny.
Before I'll tell you why I called this
meeting, I want to get one point straight.
We're not the sole owners of our casinos.
We all have partners that
we have to answer to, right?
- You can say that again.
- Mine are coming after me with a robe.
Mine are not too happy either.
But they gave me a free hand
to make the best deal I can.
What deal? For what?
To get our money back. Now, how about it?
You boys empowered to make a deal?
- I am.
- I am too.
Good, Duke Santos is coming in to see us.
- Duke Santos?
- Just doesn't figure.
If Santos wanted to pull a
robbery, he had his lawyers do it.
Yeah, I know the firm.
- Yes?
- Mr. Santos.
Send him in please.
I don't know how you fellows feel
about it but I'm glad he's interested.
- Mr. Santos, my name is Strager.
- Glad to meet you Strager.
I want you to meet some of my friends.
Mr. Brice Mr. Gillette,
Mr. Freeman Mr. McCoy.
- Hi.
- Won't you sit down?
We were just talking, saying how
mighty happy we are to get your call.
It's our first ray of sunshine.
Don't worry, I'll get
your money back for you.
You heard that fellows, our trouble are over.
Mr. Santos doesn't make
a promise he can't keep.
- No doubt about it.
- Good deal.
- First time I relax today.
- How much is it going to cost us Mr. Santos?
Oh, let's say I wanted a third and...
you fellows beat me down to 30 percent.
Ok?
And if he doesn't deliver, he gets nothing.
- That right?
- Naturally.
Oh, I'll certainly go for that. Our insurance
won't even pay 20% of what we lost.
Neither ours, but that's
a whale of a finder's fee.
I'd say that all depends on
what the finder is looking for.
- Ok, I'll go along.
- Me too.
So will I.
Alright, but how about taking
some of it in chips Mr. Santos?
We would like a chance to win it back.
Would you now?
Ok, you got it.
For 30 percent of what they took
out you joint, call it, heads or tails.
No, no thanks Mr. Santos. I got partners.
They wouldn't want me to make a
bet like that without consulting them.
So if you can put up, what do you do?
- Shut up and that's what I'm doing.
- Good.
I'll expect the cooperation
of the local sheriff.
- You'll arrange it for me?
- Consider it done.
Mr. Santos...
- may I ask a question?
- If it's the right one.
We know you're not getting
involved in this because of the dough.
What's your real reason?
Well Frankly I'll tell you.
Whoever pulled this job, he shouldn't
have done it while I was in town.
It's embarrassing.
- You call the sheriff for me?
- It will be taken care Duke.
- The report on Bergdorf.
- Who?
The dead man we brought in last night.
- The guy got a Silver Star, Purple Heart.
- Sheriff Mr. Strager on three.
- Yes Mr. Strager?
- We made a deal with Duke Santos...
- Duke Santos.
- We get our money back, I told you.
- Good, I'm very pleased for all of you.
- He's at the Riviera, talk to him.
Sure Mr. Strager.
Of course, I'll talk to him.
Locate the dead's man
wife, tell her about her husband.
Pump her, she may know something.
I'll be over to Riviera with Mr. Duke Santos.
- Call me if you find out anything.
- Ok skipper.
Come in.
- Hello?
- Mr. Ritsik doesn't answer.
Joe Ritsik don't answer?
Operator honey baby,
darling, you're wasting my time.
I don't want to know about
guys who don't answer.
Try the Terre Haute Cad Manny
Ruditski or Willy Henshaw in Detroit.
Yeah, he's listed, so is Fred
Cusik in Palm Beach. Try them all.
I'll do my best.
Thattagirl, now get me
some numbers that answer, will you?
- Mr. Santos, I'm sheriff Wimmer.
- Nice of you to drop by so soon sheriff.
Sit down.
I guess you understand
my position Mr. Santos.
We're all grateful for your cooperation...
but I want to warm
you, don't cut out on your own.
Whatever I get goes straight
to you, I'm a great collaborator.
- So what's new on your end?
- Not a clue.
We had a net over the highway
3 minutes after we got the alarm.
If that mob got out it was only by seconds.
So they made it by seconds it
don't count? They get disqualified?
Only shows they're
a highly professional outfit.
- Is there another kind?
- Now look mister Santos...
Alright alright Sheriff,
don't get your feathers ruffled.
Mr. Strager says your sources
can check any outfit in the country.
You bet your boots they can.
- Hello?
- Duke is Manny.
- Yeah Manny, what you hear?
- Nothing, nobody got a smell.
Nothing? Not a smell?
What's this nothing gotten? You
keep nosing around till you do get a smell.
Takes time, you know how it is.
You got to give it a little time.
- Hello.
- Sheriff Wimmer please.
- Just a second. It's for you sheriff.
- Thanks.
- Hello.
- This is Joe.
- Yeah Joe.
- I talked to Bergdorf wife.
- Good, does she know anything?
- She hasn't seen him.
She hasn't seen him? Not
the whole time he was in prison?
But she's coming
to claim the body, isn't she?
- Yes, she's claiming it.
- Good.
Yeah, she can take it back to San Francisco.
Turn him over to Cohen's Mortuary.
They'll ship him out for here, good bye.
What was that about all about?
Old guy drop dead last
night, right in front of this hotel.
Quite a hero. Purple Heart,
Silver Star, served with the 82nd Airborne.
Say with the 82nd Airborne?
Yeah, served in San Quentin too.
Well, I got to get back to the office.
So long Mr. Santos, keep in touch.
And is it vice versa sheriff?
Now that we understand each other, certainly.
So long sheriff, you'll hear from me.
- Hello.
- Mr. Henshaw is not expected soon.
Well, never mind
operator, Ill call him later.
Oh, don't make any more of
them calls for about an hour.
Mr. Cohen?
No, I'm Mr. Kelly Mr. Cohen
is my associate, he's occupied.
- May I be of some service to you?
- The sheriff had sent over a body?
Yes, a Mr. Bergdorf, must've
been a fine looking fellow in life.
With the compliments of Mr. Jack Strager.
I'm helping him with the
investigation of last night's robbery.
- A shocking thing.
- Yeah.
Well anyway, if somebody
shows an interest in the late...
Bergdorf Jack want that
you should call me right away.
My name is Duke Santos. I'm at the Riviera.
And you can tell Mr. Strager
he can depend on us Mr. Santos.
He said he could, yeah. And Mr. Kelly please,
not a word about this to anyone, eh?
Not even to Mr. Cohen.
But Fred it can't be a job this big is pulled
and nobody in the world knows who did it?
It's what we got, but we're digging so far.
- There ain't a single break?
- Not a break, nothing.
Ok Fred, keep listening.
- Hi honey.
- Hello darling.
Excuse me messing in, but this is
the first opportunity I've had.
Hello operator, get me the Flamingo please.
I had a date with Adele but as usual she
was late, poor Duke you must be starved.
I got other problems besides
food, I can't have lunch with you.
Oh, but darling I
asked some friends to join us.
Well, that's great, you won't be lonesome.
Look, make it quick, will you? I got a
lot of important calls coming through.
Hello Flamingo? I'd like to
speak to Mr. James Foster please.
Who did you say?
Oh, didn't I tell you? Jimmy is at the
Flamingo, he didn't go to Squaw valley.
Operator, if his room doesn't
answer please have him paged.
Wouldn't you think he'd call his own
mother? He knows very well I'm here.
Wait he hits the crap
tables, you'll hear from him.
Yeah, the only time he give a
thought is when he needs something.
Oh, what he see in that vulgar little Danny
Ocean and all those other Army cronies?
They hold more meetings
than the American Legion.
- I'm paging him.
- Yes operator, I'll wait.
They having a meeting here? Then why
he say he was going to Squaw valley?
I don't know but Adele told
me he was here and and...
Ocean is with him and Heaven
knows how many other ex-Army pals.
Foster, Ocean and Bergdorf All 82nd Airborne.
Yeah, I wonder what they doing here.
Maybe it's the anniversary
of one of their commando raids.
The Little Scorpions.
Very well, it's all very mysterious.
- Hey, what you doing?
- Not any longer it ain't mysterious.
- Hello operator?
- Yes sir?
Cancel all the calls I put in.
Yeah, cancel them all.
No wonder I couldn't find out nothing.
A work of art, a real work of art.
- But darling, what you so excited about?
- This honey.
- The robbery?
- Yeah.
Duke, don't tell me you
had anything to do with this?
No, no, relax sweetheart, I'm clean.
But I know who pulled that job.
- You do?
- Yeah.
- But shouldn't you tell the police?
- Oh, no.
And you want to know why not?
Because I love you too much.
May I learn what's so amusing?
Your Jimmy, your innocent.
Oh, I knew he had guts the minute I met him.
Please, Duke.
Sweetheart, this job was cooked
up by Jimmy and his soldier boy pals.
Oh but, but that's ridiculous Jimmy
has all the money he could spend.
Why, why would he rob anyone?
Hitler had Europe.
Why did he want Russia too?
Oh, you can't compare my Jimmy with that
monster, why, he actually fought Hitler.
He and his paratroopers overran Germany.
Yeah, but last night him and his
paratroopers overrun a hunk at Las Vegas.
Oh, it's a real shame that boy wasn't born
poor, what a career he could've had.
- I think you're serious.
- That's right honey, they hijacked the town.
Jimmy and his little paratroopers, well,
this won't take long. I'll see you at lunch.
- Want some lunch?
- No, you go ahead, I may not eat for weeks.
Hello Danny. Hey, nice room you got here.
- I don't think I know your friend.
- You don't know me either.
Sure I do, I'm a pal of Jimmy Foster's.
I know some of your other buddies too.
Like Tony Bergdorf.
Poor Tony died, you know.
It's too bad, his wife is
coming over to claim his body.
Yeah Tony is going home in a pine box.
Yes, a beautiful job you
boys pulled, a real work of art.
- You a cop?
- Me? Duke Santos, a cop?
I only wish I was in on it with you.
Oh, I envy you, your youth.
You're not get any younger
hanging around here, what do you want?
If you guys had been pros,
I had put you out of business.
But new talent needs
encouraging, I want half.
- Half of what?
- You tell me, you got the money.
You talking on a dead phone Charlie.
Well, suit yourself, there's a
live one at the sheriff's office.
So you are a cop?
No, I made a deal with the casino
owners to get their money back for them.
And now you're ready to double cross them?
Well, they only going to pay me 30 percent.
You're going to give me 50.
- Playing both ends from the middle.
- Sure, I can't lose.
You've already lost.
- The money is sent out of town, long gone.
- If you're here, the money is here.
We couldn't make a deal with you if
we wanted to too many people involved.
So talk to them.
That's to take a little time.
I'll give you till tomorrow.
I know you won't try anything cute.
50% of something is
better than 100% of nothing.
One o'clock tomorrow, here.
By-bye.
Hold it.
What's your relationship to Jimmy Foster?
I'm going to marry his mama.
Tell me? Jimmy sold us out.
Your best friend sold us out.
You believe that? You want
the facts tattooed on your nose?
I'll admit I don't like Foster, much that
now we found out he's turned canary.
You got to stand up for the slob.
You always have to be different.
- Always on the opposite side.
- And you always have to jump to conclusions.
What do you think the others are
going to be jumping to when they find?
Just a minute, let me ask you one question.
Does Jimmy know where we hid the money?
You know it.
Eh? Then why he isn't tell Santos about and
go out and pick it up and split it with him?
Eh?
- Go ahead, right on the chin.
- Yeah, forget about it.
I've been making a couple of mistakes myself.
Oh Jimmy Jimmy Jimmy.
Oh, mother what is it? I
came as quickly as I could, you ill?
You fool, you complete utter ass.
- Oh, that's good, you're not ill.
- I could slap you face roar.
Oh, what is it? Mother's Day? I forget?
You dare to be sarcastic after what
you've done? No, it's not mother's day.
But how you plan to celebrate Mother's Day?
Perhaps you and you're
kin soldiers will rob Fort Knox?
What's that?
Well, after stealing
all the money in Las Vegas...
that's the next logical step for a maniac.
- But how in the...
- Amazed, aren't you?
You probably thought you
had committed the perfect crime.
- You moron, I could die.
- Mother, who's been talking to you?
- Duke, he knows all about it.
- But that's impossible.
I mean, why would
you believe what Santos says?
Because you're an
amateur thief, he's a professional.
Oh please, don't try to lie.
Your face gives you away.
- Even as a liar, you're an amateur.
- Where's Santos now?
He's going to see your confederates
to take the money away from them.
Now he's going to get mixed up in this too.
Oh Jimmy Jimmy, how
could you treat me this way?
I think now is a nice time to tell him.
I owe an apologize, I thought for
a minute you blew the whistle on us.
But Clarence Darrow
here, he proved otherwise.
What do we do now that Santos knows?
Wish I knew, I just don't know where to
bind and we haven't got much time left.
I got an idea.
Come on, I'll paint you a picture on
the way out. Come on Clarence.
What's so funny?
I knew this color would
come in handy one day.
- Oh, Josh.
- Yeah?
- How you get this stuff off?
- What I usually...
Hold it, you count it
when it get to San Francisco.
It's for Tony's widow and
he's kid, it's only 10 grand Danny.
Good boy Josh,
I should've thought of that myself.
- Operation Pine Box.
- Danny? The widow just arrived.
I figure she'll ship the body
to San Francisco on the 11:40.
It's the only train today, they
got plenty of time, over an hour.
Ok, you stay with her.
We'll phone the others.
- Operator?
- Operator, get me Dudley 26969.
- Vince Massler.
- Vince...
watch the 11:40 Tony may go out on it.
Mr. Santos will get his.
Sorry to keep you
waiting ma'am, I'm Mr. Cohen.
How do you do?
I came to make arrangements to ship my
husband's body back to San Francisco.
Oh yes Mrs. Bergdorf, may I?
May I ask Mrs. Bergdorf,
in my professional capacity...
are you a woman of means?
Oh, no.
No, my husband, my
late husband left me $10,000.
I received it this morning.
But that's all I have and I'd like to
keep that for my son's education.
I understand, now...
- if I may make a suggestion Mrs. Bergdorf?
- Of course.
The services in Las Vegas are no
different from the same rites San Francisco.
Your late husband was a war hero.
And we have a chapter
of the American Legion here.
The legionnaires will be
happy to serve as pallbearers.
Why waste money on needless transportation?
- Well, I guess you right Mr. Cohen.
- Good, good.
- Danny?
- Yeah Corneal?
Something is going on in
there, but I don't know just what.
- You mean the box hasn't left yet?
- No and I don't think it's going to.
- Why not?
- A bunch of legionnaires just showed up.
Must be they're going to attend the services.
So looks like the widow is
going tot Tony here in Vegas.
Ok, you wait right there.
'll round up the boys, we'll be over.
- Hello, who is it?
- Kelly of Kelly and Cohen Morticians.
You asked me to call you if something unusual
happened in regards of out client Bergdorf.
Bergdorf? Yeah, go ahead.
Well, about a dozen men arrived to attend
the services which are being held in our...
beautiful chapel which serves
all denominations, faiths and creeds.
Yeah, yeah, skip the commercial, will you?
These men don't look like the usual mourners.
Mr. Santos is something else.
I made a discovery in the
waiting chapel that's most unusual.
I could call it incredible.
Mr. Santos, I will call it incredible.
- What is it?
- A money band, a $10,000 money band.
Which lying by the coffin and it
certainly wasn't there last night.
- By the coffin, eh?
- Right beside it.
I, I hardly know what to think.
I do. I'll be right over.
How do you like that? A dead
delivery boy, cony characters.
We are gathered together
today to pay honor and tribute...
to the memory of Anthony Raymond Bergdorf.
At such a time as we all together fitting
that we recall the psalm of David.
The Lord is my shepherd, I shall not want.
He maketh me to lie down in green pastures.
He leadeth me besides still waters.
He restoreth my soul.
He guideth me in the paths of
righteousness for his name is sake.
Yeh, though I walk through
the valley of the shadow of death...
I will fear no evil, for thou art with me.
Thy rod and thy staff, they comfort me.
Thou preparest a table before me
in the presence of mine enemies.
Thou anointest my head
with oil, my cup runneth over.
Surely goodness
and mercy shall follow me all...
- What's that noise?
- The Lord forever.
The deceased is being cremated.
Verily, verily, the Lord giveth
and the Lord taketh away.
Earth to earth, ashes to ashes, dust to dust.
In sure and certain hope
of the resurrection unto eternal life.
The Lord lift up His face upon you...
and give you peace, this day and always.
Amen.
♪ Show me a man without a dream.
And I'll show you a man that's dead.. ♪
♪ Real dead. ♪
♪ Once I had me a dream but
that dream got kicked in the head. ♪.
♪ Dream dead. ♪
♪ Some Judge is up to say
I'm putting you away... ♪
♪ For four score years
add seven in the meantime... ♪
♪ Eee-O-Eleven, Eleven. ♪
♪ Eleven. ♪