♪ Of all the boys I've
known And I've known some ♪
♪ First met you, was lonesome ♪
♪ You came in sight
And my heart grew light ♪
♪ The world was new to me ♪
♪ You're swell ♪
♪ I'll admit you deserve
Expressions that fit you ♪
♪ Racked my brain
Hoping to explain ♪
♪ The things that you do to me ♪
♪ Bei mir bist du schön ♪
♪ Again and again ♪
♪ Means you're the fairest
In the land ♪
♪ I could say bella, bella ♪
♪ Even sehr wunderbar ♪
♪ Each language only
Helps to show ♪
♪ How wonderful you are ♪
♪ I've tried to explain
Bei mir bist do schön ♪
What do you know, boys?
Hey, Papi, get over here. I got
someone I want you to meet.
Roland Legrand.
Caught this fuckin' goat singing
like a canary to the police.
This is what happens when you cross me.
Get this piece of shit
outta here.
So, what do you got
for me?
Piece of cake.
Just like you said.
You pocket any
for yourself?
Yeah, just a couple
of big ones.
You sure got
some balls on you.
You try to hustle me,
and I'll cut 'em the fuck off.
Good for 10,000.
♪ Zulu man is feeling blue ♪
♪ Hear his heart beat
A little tattoo ♪
♪ Diga diga doo, diga doo doo ♪
♪ Diga diga doo, diga doo ♪
♪ You love me and I love you ♪
♪ When you love
It's natural to ♪
♪ Diga diga doo, diga doo doo ♪
♪ Diga diga doo, diga doo ♪
♪ Well, I'm so very
Diga diga doo by you ♪
♪ By nature ♪
Did you have
a good night?
- Yep.
- At least you did.
Maybe this'll
cheer you up.
Take it.
It's for you.
A couple of the big ones
for us.
You're crazy.
- Where you goin'?
- Castili doesn't want me leaving early.
To hell with Castili.
Let's go have some fun.
Turn that frown
upside-down.
I know you
wanna have some fun.
I love you.
Say that again.
Slower.
I...
love...
you.
I want a house.
In the countryside,
like where you grew up.
You make it sound so nice, riding
your little horsey around.
Let's go today.
How am I gonna earn
in the country?
There's nothing to steal.
We'll get jobs.
I made more last night than most
people in the country make in a year.
Gimme six months.
I'll be making more money
than Castili and all those bums.
Hey.
I don't want to wait
six months.
I'm here for the rent.
All right.
I'm comin', I'm comin'.
- It's him.
- What the fuck?
You're under arrest for
the murder of Roland Legrand.
What are you talkin' about?
Well, he was murdered last night.
A witness identified you.
The pimp,
Roland Legrand.
You know him, right?
- You got the wrong guy, pal. I was with her all night.
- Come on. Let's go.
- All right. Let me get dressed.
- No, no, no, no.
We got some stripes at the
station for you, pretty boy.
This is bullshit.
- I didn't kill anyone.
- You can't do that.
- He was with me!
- Nennete, relax.
- They got nothin'.
- Nobody believes a whore.
- Nennete!
- Get back in your room.
Honestly,
I'll be back in no time.
- Papi! Papi!
- Don't worry. Don't worry.
Papi!
He didn't kill anyone!
He was with me!
Step away from the bars!
I can't believe they gave
you a life sentence.
You need to appeal.
Appeal what?
Nennete,
this is a frame-up.
They're all in on it.
I just need to concentrate
on breaking out.
Okay.
First thing I'm gonna do when I get
back is kill that lying rat witness
and anyone who has anything
to do with this.
- Calm down.
- All visitors have to leave!
Nennete, you need
to forget about me.
Don't say that.
I love you.
- Time's up, lady.
- Papi, I love you.
Come on. Come on.
Come on.
- Come on. Come on. Come on!
- Get your hands off me!
Papillon, right?
They fucked you good, huh?
Framed you
for murder.
Say you're one hell
of a safecracker.
I'm more of a smash-and-grab
guy myself. Name's Julot.
Got any money?
No?
Get some. You'll never
escape without it.
Keep goin', keep goin'.
Let's keep goin'.
- Next. Move forward.
- Next, come on!
- Let's go, let's go.
- Next.
- Line up.
- Go to the end.
Come on. Move along.
- Stay in line.
- Hey.
- Perhaps I could speak with your supervisor.
- Sure.
Whatever you say.
Louis Dega.
Guy's a millionaire.
Busted making counterfeit
defense bonds.
- Won't last long.
- Next.
Every con in the prison will wanna cut
him open to get the money he's carrying.
Next.
As of this moment,
you are the property of the Penal
Administration of French Guiana.
After serving
your full term in prison,
you will remain in South America
as workers and colonists for a period
equal to that of your original sentence.
This is for the greater good
that is French expansion.
As for France...
she has disowned you.
She has rid herself
of you... altogether.
Forget France.
Now dress yourselves.
Are we going to hell?
Look up. Just keep walking.
Mr. Dega.
Your appeal is
in a few weeks.
Be strong, Louis.
I love you.
You'll be home
before Christmas.
Dega. Mr. Dega, here.
Look this way. Mr. Dega.
Sixty-nine, 70.
- That's right.
- Move it!
That's enough.
Pick your feet up.
Hey, Julot!
All right, pair up.
- Hey.
- Take the corner.
Looks like Dega's
making friends already.
Julot, make sure
no one takes this hammock.
Hey.
I saved you a spot next to me.
You got a lot of eyes on you.
I can keep you safe.
All I need's enough money
for an escape.
Won't be cheap,
but you'll be safe.
Said the scorpion to the frog.
We're all scorpions
in here, pal.
I think I'd be better off taking my chances
setting up in front of the guards.
Wouldn't you agree?
You seem like the kind of man
who can make up his own mind.
You're a good judge
of character.
Have a good night.
Yeah, you too.
Hey.
Me and you, we should team up
for an escape.
If I get caught in some half-assed
escape, I want it to be my mistake.
Settle down now!
Shh.
I know you hide your money
in your guts.
Upper deck.
Move it back.
Back, you.
Back. Back up.
Get him outta here.
The animals can clean up
their own mess.
Come on. Get rid of him.
Show's over.
How'd you sleep last night?
Smells like freedom.
What, you've heard of someone
escaping the prison?
Doesn't mean
it can't be done.
I have trouble seeing hope
in hopelessness.
That's why I need
a man like you.
I've reconsidered your offer.
Keep me alive until
I'm set up on the island,
I'll underwrite any escape
you care to arrange.
All right.
And when the time comes,
you're not comin' with me.
I have no intention
of escaping.
Unlike you,
I enjoy being alive.
My wife's working
on my appeal.
I'm confident
I'll be home by Christmas.
A fellow optimist.
Four.
Two.
Look what the fuck you did!
Get the knife!
Come on!
I'll kill you!
Steam! Turn on the steam!
Fuck you!
Come on,
come on, come on.
Get back!
Strip and line up, you fuckin'
animals, or it's the steam again.
Strip down!
Gimme the fuckin' knife.
- Move it!
- Come on. Line up back there!
Let's go! Strip down!
- Come on, come on.
- On your feet.
Line up back there.
Strip down.
Strip right up.
Hands. Hands out.
- Everybody, hands out.
- Everyone, let's have your hands out.
Let's see.
What you got?
Get him to the infirmary.
Let's get this
piece of meat outta here.
- Show me your hands. Let's see.
- Turn 'em over.
You.
This one's been fighting
for sure.
Take him to first class.
Come on. Come on!
Time to go.
First class, let's go.
Try and behave, ladies.
You should have finished him.
I don't want to kill anyone.
I'm gonna get myself sent
to the hospital.
Let me know if a guard
looks this way.
- Do not stop!
- Get a move on!
Shh.
Move it, now! You two!
- Move it! Move it!
- Crazy, Julot.
Go that way! You go this way!
You two, come on down.
Form a line.
Form a line, I said.
Form a line. Go ahead.
You two, you stay here.
Go back in line.
Move.
Move it! Come on!
That way!
Come on! Move it!
Come on.
I said move it, goddamn it.
Get up. Get up!
- Come on.
- Move along! Move along!
Eyes straight.
- Come on. Move it.
- Move it!
- That way.
- Down the ladder!
- Over there. Come on.
- Faster!
Move it. Move it!
- Come on now.
- Come on. Move.
Don't be looking at me
like that.
- Come on. Move.
- You too.
Move along.
Guys, get him up!
My fucking leg!
My leg. My leg!
That's enough.
Break it up. Break it up.
- Move it!
- Move. Back to the line.
Move, move.
Raise your hand
if I call your name.
Augustin.
- Barba.
- Come on now. Stay in line.
Bellaire.
Move along! Over there.
Lofton.
Navarrone.
Move out!
All right, come on.
Move it.
Keep moving!
Prisoners, halt!
Open the gates.
March.
I know many of you at this very
moment are thinking about escape.
Feel free to try
whenever you like.
We'll be happy to shoot you.
If, however, you should
avoid that mercy,
there are two guardians
who are always on duty...
The bush, where the best thing that
can happen to you is starvation.
Or you could choose the sea,
where sharks too, I assure
you, are always hungry.
If you manage to survive
your first attempt,
you'll get two years
in solitary.
Second attempt,
five years in solitary,
followed by a life sentence
at Devil's Island.
If you commit murder...
you'll be executed.
That's all.
Move. Move.
Jesus Christ.
Take the corner.
Hey, keep your eyes open
and don't move.
Hey.
Who decides what work
we get assigned to?
- Excuse my ill-mannered...
- I thought I told you not to move.
He has yet to be tamed.
And you're obviously a very
important, very, very busy man.
I'm just the turnkey.
We're looking for someone
to ensure we're assigned
the right sort of work
in the morning.
It'll cost you a thousand.
I don't think so.
No, now that seems
entirely too high.
Sir, I think we started
off on the wrong foot.
I think a thousand
is actually fair.
Now, is there a selection
of work you have...
Attendants at
the hospital.
And for a thousand, you can
throw in a pouch of tobacco.
- And a notebook.
- A notebook?
- I'm an artist.
- You're a forger.
And you're a safecracker, a profession
of which I thoroughly disapprove.
- At least I'm an honest criminal.
- Hmm.
Hey. I'm gonna need that
right now.
I mean, right now.
Excuse me.
I think you need to go
to the bathroom.
Yes, of course.
If you'll excuse me,
gentlemen.
Where you goin'?
I've never
been here before.
Toilet's there,
princess.
What animal but a man keeps his
only means of survival up his ass?
Something bit me.
We got a runner!
- Lockdown!
- Lock it down!
- Which barracks?
- No, he broke out the hospital.
- Just one.
- The hospital?
Lock down
your barrack.
- I'll bet that's Julot.
- Lock it down!
Son of a bitch
didn't waste any time.
You see?
It can be done.
Lock it down! Into the jungle.
Stand down.
Route Zero.
My friend and I need to be
kept together at all times.
Set these two up
in the hospital.
And it'll be a few days before I'm
well enough to do any sort of...
Don't push it.
Both of them,
Route Zero.
Mr. Dega, stop.
I know you.
Do you know me?
Yes.
Yes, of course, sir.
You're the deputy
warden, sir.
My sister's husband
was arrested
selling counterfeit defense bonds you
furnished him with in Marseilles.
Dega is a very common name
in Marseilles.
- Santini.
- Yes, sir.
This one goes straight
to Route Zero.
Take him away.
Wait.
Take him too.
We try not to separate
old friends here.
Get them to Route Zero.
Move.
What is Route Zero?
Stand clear!
Your other round!
I don't feel so good.
Watch it now!
It go...
It goes in the cart.
Move along.
You do a lot
of talking.
- I do?
- Yeah. Stop that.
It passes...
It passes the time.
- Get outta my face. Get outta my face.
- You take the bigger rock.
You get into a fight with
him, I'm not protecting you.
If your wife was here...
you were in Paris
with all that money,
how much would you pay
to get her back?
Everything I have.
How much would she pay
for you?
You're a real optimist.
Little man. Little man.
You need to put some weight in.
You can push harder
than that. Come on.
Trust me, he can't.
Trust me,
he has to.
Come on! Push it!
- Push it!
- Pick up the pace.
I have... I have diarrhea.
What you want me
to do about it?
No, you don't understand.
I lost the money.
What's the holdup?
What the hell are you doing?
- What?
- Stop shitting around.
- You'll get us all killed.
- You mind your own cart.
The little guy is making more
work for the rest of us.
- Mind your own business.
- Break it up. Break it up.
What are you doing?
Get up.
Get up! Get up.
- On your feet.
- I can't.
Pick him up.
Come on, pick him up.
Put him in the cart.
Back to work.
Move your carts.
You had one job to do.
You couldn't do it.
My body's in revolt.
Where is it now?
Where do you think?
I should have known better
than to trust a thief.
I can't steal
what's already mine.
As soon as we get back to the
barracks, you're taking it back.
And you're gonna hold onto
it this time.
I don't care if you have
to sew your ass up to do it.
I'm sorry.
I may have prematurely judged you
with an unworthy degree of suspicion.
Well, don't propose yet.
I just don't like
carrying things in my ass.
Mmm.
He's dead.
- He's dead!
- Shut up, birdie.
Are you stupid or what?
We share his ration.
Here.
So you got yourself a boyfriend, huh?
You were in the navy?
What do you think?
I thought maybe
it meant "jailbird."
Swallows.
It stands for hope.
First thing you see
when you reach land.
- I know.
- Yeah? How come?
You were in the navy?
Eighteen months.
Followed by six in the brig.
Didn't suit me.
A butterfly.
So you're a thief now?
Guess that didn't
suit you either.
We should go sailing
sometime.
You got a boat?
Can you get any
of that?
Maybe.
Well, let me know then.
Your boyfriend's
got trouble.
Give me your money, or you
and your friend will die.
- Is there trouble?
- I was talking to your bitch.
Now you're talking to me.
Work it out in the barracks!
Break is over.
Get in line!
Forward march.
Line it up.
Line it up!
Stop. Stop!
Turn around. Eyes up front.
Come on.
You know better than to truck your
ladies through here after a rainstorm.
Yeah.
Can you help me out?
I'll make it good for you.
Get the girls up here.
Come on.
Watch out.
Watch out...
Hey.
Can you hear me?
How much to take me
up the coast?
Don't be stupid.
I'll give you 2,000.
Guard!
Don't turn me in,
for Christ's sake.
4,000.
What's the problem?
Just wanted to know which girl
I should send to repay you.
One that hasn't
caught anything yet.
My boat is on the other
side of the river.
I'll be there for
three more days.
It's 5,000.
You're a goddamned thief.
- The guards are coming.
- Don't fucking touch me!
I didn't know
it would be like this.
I'll be dead long before
my appeal.
I need to go with you.
That wasn't part
of the deal.
Yes, I realize that, but I
still have to go with you.
You ever sail a boat?
Spend any time at sea?
Yes, I have spent a
number of days at sea.
I was locked in a cage
for most of them.
But I think I understand
the concept well enough.
You can't come
with me, Dega.
You should call me Louis.
Keep it moving.
Get 'em in line.
Stand straight!
Down on your knees.
Take off your hats
and cross your arms.
At the moment of execution,
you're all to bow your heads.
A man stabbed two guards...
one of whom died this morning,
leaving two children
without their father.
And for what?
So he could go on a run
through the jungle.
Thank you
for coming!
Watch me go to hell!
Prisoner ready.
Keeping you is no benefit.
Destroying you is no loss.
You.
Pick another inmate.
You carry the body.
Go get
the boat ready.
He's gone.
It's just
flesh and blood.
Why are you stopping?
What are you doing?
Move.
I said, what the hell
are you doing?
Get up.
You get up,
you little worm.
Get your ass up.
You little worm.
Oh, shit.
Stop! Hey, stop!
Hey!
We've got a runner!
He's heading north.
Papi.
- Papi?
- Heading north now!
Papillon!
Check the tree line.
Hey!
Pick him up.
Come on. Come on.
Oh. You're a good man.
Yeah, I'm a good man
that wants his money.
Look, I don't have it.
Not with me.
But I'm gonna make it
worth your while.
I got a lot of money in Paris.
I'll give you
everything I got.
Hmm.
Even if you had the money...
the warden will pay us double.
Son of a bitch.
You're lucky
that guard didn't die.
Otherwise, you would
have met the guillotine.
Now you'll be transferred to
the island of Saint Joseph,
where you'll serve a two-year
sentence in solitary confinement.
There's no
rehabilitation.
We know that's useless,
so we do our best
to break you.
Strange things
happen there.
Especially to those
who cling to hope,
because there is no hope
on Saint Joseph.
Just silence.
You heard the warden.
Silence must be observed
at all times.
Thought you grew wings,
didn't you?
Grab him.
I'll teach you to be quiet.
You make another peep...
you might not survive
your time here.
Huh.
Come on. He's crazy.
Come on. Come on.
Enjoy your next
two years here.
Dega.
Hold on.
Need to check that.
What is that, hmm?
Somebody paying you to bring this
shit in here? Son of a bitch.
Huh? Who's paying you?
Who's paying you, you son of a bitch?
No!
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa! Whoa!
Jesus!
I think you killed him.
Get that body out of
here and clean up the mess.
What the hell
were you thinking?
No wonder you haven't
broken yet.
How long has it
being going on?
You may speak.
Who sent you
those coconuts?
If you don't fess up...
I'll put you on half rations.
You're choosing another
man's life over your own.
Put him on half rations.
I brought you some soup.
It's got meat in it.
Just tell me his name.
Tell me his name.
You think a person knows
when he's going mad?
Or you think
it's blissful ignorance?
'Cause you're about
to find out.
Put him in darkness for the
remainder of his sentence.
Or the remainder of his life,
whichever comes first.
Six.
Two.
Twenty-four.
6-2-24.
This is a good escape.
Is he still alive?
Two years are up.
I know that some of
you, at this very moment,
are thinking about escape.
Feel free to try
whenever you like.
We'll be happy
to shoot you.
However, should you
avoid that mercy,
there are two guardians
who are always on duty.
The bush, where the best thing that
can happen to you is starvation.
Or you could choose the sea,
where the sharks too,
are always hungry.
If you manage to
survive your first attempt,
you'll get two years
in solitary.
Second attempt is
five years in solitary,
followed by a life sentence
at Devil's Island.
If you commit murder...
...you'll be executed.
That's all.
Papi.
I wanted to come sooner,
but I was afraid you
wouldn't wanna see me.
I'm sorry.
It's my fault you're here.
As you predicted, um,
my appeal's run into
some problems.
But my wife's doing very well.
She recently married my lawyer.
Well, to hell with her then.
You son of a bitch.
I thought you'd gone
simple on me.
That's the idea.
You know you'd have had
a much easier time
if you'd just given them
my name.
It's not like
I didn't think about it.
I just know how goddamn
delicate you are.
Mm.
I fear under
similar circumstances
I would've fared
differently.
I don't know how you made it.
I just got used to the silence.
If I ever get out...
I'm gonna live
a different kind of life.
This Sunday, the warden will be
showing a film in the courtyard,
entertaining some
local politicians.
It'll be loud.
The guards will be doing
double-duty, spread very thin.
This is your best chance.
Can you get a boat?
No.
What about Celier?
Is he still here?
Unfortunately, yes.
If he can still get a boat...
do you have enough money
to pay for it?
Well, I might, but then
he'd wanna come with us.
Us?
Us.
All right.
But we still need a boat.
You leave now!
Leave!
Get out!
Get out! Leave!
- This man's mad!
- Go!
- Get out!
- He's out of his mind!
No!
No, no, no, no!
- No!
- He's out of his mind!
Help me!
Come, Papi. Here.
Come on, come... Calm down, calm down.
Let him go.
Let him go!
It's okay, it's okay.
Shh, shh.
Bring me some pills.
Come on.
Take one.
Bring me some water.
Swallow.
It'll be okay.
Lights out, ten minutes.
Oh!
Shh, shh.
- Get off of me.
- Just relax!
- Leave me!
- Relax.
Get off! I will never
let you fuck me.
Shh, shh.
You will soon, if you
know what's good for you.
Hey.
Hey, I just wanna talk.
- I'm not a goddamn whore.
- That's not what I want.
Yeah, everybody says that
until they do.
Trust me, I don't.
I got a different proposition.
If you repeat one word of this,
it's not gonna be good for you.
- I don't wanna know then.
- Maybe you do.
Look, I'm puttin'
something together.
This Sunday.
We got room for one more.
I have nothing to offer you.
I need you to distract
that turnkey.
Get him to come in here at a
certain time, keep him occupied.
If I do that,
your plan better work.
It'll work.
It's not gonna be easy.
Can you handle yourself?
You were framed
for murder, right?
Well, nobody framed me.
That's Celier.
He's gotten us a boat.
Let's see the arm.
Infected.
Good job.
Papi!
You skinny son of a bitch.
Good to see you.
What'd you do
to your arm?
I had to cut myself
to get in here.
- It still work?
- Yeah, it's nothing. Don't think about it.
- I can still kick your ass.
- Can we hurry this up? I have to get back.
Birdie, can you
shut up for once?
This is Maturette.
He's our fourth.
Oh, yeah?
- You know how to handle yourself?
- Yeah, with a knife.
- All right, take it easy.
- Feisty little one, huh?
- You all set?
- Yeah, I'm set.
I got a guy that's
hiding a boat on the bank.
It's upriver a ways.
From there, it's a straight
shot to the ocean.
But we need
half the money now.
What about you?
When the film starts, we'll go
through the warden's building.
I'll have a key.
We got a plan.
You all right?
No.
I'm not sure
we can trust him.
Look at him,
he's unpredictable.
He's like a caged animal.
We're all animals
in here, pal.
He'll be fine.
He needs the money now.
Here.
It's the sedatives
they gave me.
Get 'em in the guards' coffee.
We'll do the rest.
I have to get back.
Hey.
You're doin' good.
- Hey.
- What do we have here, huh?
Go to hell.
Give me those back.
He's gonna fuck up
our plan.
It's gonna be fine.
What the fuck are you doing, man?
All right!
That's enough!
Break it up!
He does the warden's books.
I had to figure I'd know
how to throw a punch
considering how often
my father used to beat me.
Yours too?
My parents are school teachers.
See ya tonight.
Anisette for the warden.
The best you have.
Just give me the bottle.
Here's two or three.
Would you gentlemen
like your coffees freshened?
Bring it on in.
Compliments of the warden.
Wow.
Very nice.
Here.
If we kill someone and this goes
wrong, it's the guillotine.
No one dies.
Give me another one
of them.
All right.
Dega!
Where are you going?
The warden.
Now!
Stop!
Shh, shh!
What was that?
I'd better go check.
It's working.
Oh, man.
We're too early.
Hey, got a light?
Yes, of course, sir.
Oh! Oh!
Okay, go inside.
Everybody, go inside.
Come on.
- Come on, darling.
- Fuck.
- That's our way out.
- No, no.
What's he doin'?
- Power's off!
- Fuck!
Papi, we gotta move.
We can't stay here.
We wait for Dega.
Forget about Dega!
He's not reliable.
And you know it!
Let's just go.
Come on.
You wanna go?
Go.
You with me?
Uh, yeah.
Open the gate.
What's wrong with you?
Ha! I stole the keys to get
us up to the central walkway.
We can take that
to the guard tower.
As long as the lights stay off,
they won't see us.
And then we jump?
You got a better idea?
Come on.
Come on!
Go, go!
Guard the wall!
You! Take me
to the south wall.
Yes, sir!
Oh, shit.
All right.
Come on. Let's go.
Easy.
You all right?
Let's go!
Come on!
Go, go, go.
Jump!
Come on!
They're gonna see you!
Jump!
Come on!
Shit!
Hey.
It's broken.
- Leave him.
- He's got the money.
Aah.
Maturette, help me.
Christ!
All right, come on.
Let's go.
Come on.
How much further
to the boat?
You're slowing us down,
Dega.
Come on.
We've got to move faster.
Don't take another step.
You're not takin' me back.
That depends
if you have my money.
Hey.
Papi.
It's okay.
This is my guy
with the boat.
Where's our boat?
It's a ways up the river.
Want me to take you
there, pay me.
Or fuck you.
This is all I have left.
Let's keep that between us.
Enjoy your freedom!
Fuck! What kind of
shit boat did you get us?
Shut up, Dega!
You're lucky to be here.
Keep bailing!
Get it outta the boat.
I'm trying.
Don't throw it at me, Dega.
Goddamn it.
- Throw it in the water!
- I'm throwing it at the water.
- Maturette!
- Yes?
Check the tiller.
I got it,
I got it.
Papi.
This boat can't hold all of us.
You know it.
We need to lighten
the weight.
He's gonna die anyway, Papi.
Nobody needs to die.
Fuck!
It fell off!
- Fix the tiller!
- It's broken.
Fix the tiller!
Move!
Come on.
Here, take this.
Take this.
Maturette, help me.
This storm is
gonna sink the boat.
We need to act,
and we need to act now.
Just let me get
the boat ready.
Did you lose your mind?
Huh?
You wanna die
because of this guy?
Nobody needs to die.
Well, we can't all live.
Dega, he's dead weight.
How much money you have?
He doesn't have any money.
He doesn't have any money?
You hear that, Maturette?
They've been lying to us.
You wanna die for him?
That makes it
two against one, Papi.
Step aside.
You don't need to do anything.
Step aside, Papi!
I'm not gonna die
for that guy.
Last chance, Papi.
Step aside!
I don't know about you,
I'm going home!
Stop!
Enough!
That's enough!
That's enough.
Enough.
Welcome.
I was traveling
with two other men.
They are
being cared for.
Where are we?
This is Colombia.
We know where
you've come from.
But you need only repent.
Allow God back
into your life...
and you'll be forgiven.
You should go
and wash yourself.
Then come
and pray with us.
We need to keep movin'.
They know
where we came from.
Our deal is done.
I told you
we couldn't trust him.
I'm leaving.
With or without you.
Good luck.
Papi!
We made it!
Papi.
It's paradise here.
Yeah, but it's not home.
Not for me, anyway.
Good luck, Maturette.
We're leaving.
Now.
Come on.
- Aah!
- Papi!
Maturette!
Repent.
If you are truly sorry
for what you have done,
then you have
nothing to fear.
God will watch over you.
You came back.
Come on, Papi.
I had to come
and see this for myself.
Few men survive
five years in solitary.
What were you
living for?
'Cause I don't think you're gonna
find it where you're going...
Devil's Island.
Now, what's the son of two school
teachers doing in a place like this?
Well?
What do you think?
I've had five years
to work on it.
The warden wasn't very happy
with my disobedience.
So he sent me straight here
to Devil's Island.
Let's get some food in you.
Rise and shine.
Come on.
There's work to be done.
Can we get to the ocean?
I know what you're thinking.
But even if you survive
the fall...
you'll never survive
the ocean.
Hmm?
It's all about the waves.
What?
What are you talking about?
What do you think
I'm talkin' about?
Oh, go back to bed.
That's suicide, not escape.
No. Listen.
All we need to do is build a
raft and get it to the ocean.
The tide will take us
straight to the mainland.
Just come and see.
Come and see!
See?
We ride the current
to freedom.
I'm a little concerned about your
ability to protect me right now.
Don't worry. The fall
will probably kill us.
Let's tie these together.
I need to stay.
What are you talking about?
For the same reason
you have to go.
I belong here.
It's okay.
It's good.
Go on now. You don't wanna
waste any more time.
Louis!
I made it,
you dirty little forger!
Whoo!
Whoo-hoo!
Thank you.
Sir?
Your water.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
I'm surprised
you risked coming back.
I'd read
the statute of limitations.
You're still a wanted man.
I won't be here long.
My home is Venezuela now.
But it's important
that my memoir
be published here...
in France.
My wife convinced me
to write it all down...
while I'm still young enough
to remember.
So is this really your story?
It's the story of
a lot of men.
Subtitles by explosiveskull