Hey, son!
This is where you wanted off.
Well, thank you, sir.
Thank you for the hitch too.
I've ridden them lots of times
when I was your age myself.
What do you want here?
A friend of mine lives here.
His old man's a big shot
in the grain business.
Real rich.
- Honest.
- Sure!
The governor's an old
sidekick of mine.
That's how I got this job.
Millie!
Does it make your mouth water?
It's beautiful, Mrs. Potts.
Thank you, dear.
Ma'am?
Yes?
About your yard, ma'am.
I could rake it up
and burn your trash for you...
...or any other job needs done.
My gracious!
Nobody works today.
It's Labor Day!
Are you hungry?
I guess my stomach didn't know
it was Labor Day, ma'am.
You just stop being embarrassed.
Come in and have breakfast.
- Not unless I clean up your yard.
- All right, but after you eat.
Come on, get in the house
and get something to eat.
Madge!
Dry your silly hair
over somebody else.
Why don't you read your silly book
under somebody else?
My, it's hot and still today.
It looks lovely, dear.
I wish it didn't
take so long to dry.
I think, one summer
I'll cut it short.
Madge!
She's just talking.
The way she primps and fusses...
...somebody'd think
she was the Queen of Sheba.
Well, if you fussed a little...
...maybe you'd have a date
for the picnic today.
I don't want any of these crazy boys
to take me anywhere.
Beggars can't be choosers!
Madge, that's mean.
There'll be dancing tonight.
Millie ought to have a date.
All she has to do is
dress up and act decent.
I will dress and act the way I want.
Anybody mind if an old maid
schoolteacher joins their company?
Morning, Miss Sydney.
Come out and join us, Rosemary.
- Mail in yet?
- It's a holiday.
Oh, that's right.
I forgot.
Thought there might be a letter
from that man I met...
...at the high-school dance
last spring.
He's been wanting to
marry me ever since.
He was a peck of fun.
But I don't have time for any of them
when they get serious on me.
You schoolteachers
are mighty independent.
Shoot!
I lived this long without a man.
What's to keep me
from getting on without one?
What about Howard?
Howard Bevans?
He's just a friend-boy...
...not a boyfriend.
I'll bet you never had cherry pie
for breakfast before, did you?
No, ma'am.
I never did.
I'll get started on your yard now.
You had such a big breakfast.
Wouldn't you like
to rest for a while?
No, ma'am.
Work's good for my digestion.
I was figuring to look up
this friend of mine that lives here.
I was in college with him...
...some years back.
You look like a college man.
Well, thank you, ma'am.
I don't suppose you'd know him.
His name's Alan Benson.
Alan Benson!
Why, of course!
He visits one of
the girls next door.
What do you know!
It's right around here.
It'll be awful hot in that jacket.
You better take it off.
My shirt's awful dirty, ma'am.
I'll wash it for you.
You think anybody'd mind?
Of course not. You're a man!
What's the difference?
Helen!
It's my mother.
She lives upstairs.
She's an invalid, you see.
She's very old.
Sure. Older people take a lot of care.
Helen!
All right, Mama.
I'm coming.
I'm coming!
Working over there
naked as an Indian!
Who's naked as an Indian?
Who does he think is interested?
- Good morning.
- Hey, Bomber, you stupe!
You want to knock the house down?
Go back to bed, will you?
Go blow your nose!
Tell your pretty sister
to come out.
It's no fun looking at you,
goonface!
You take that back,
you dirty little pest!
Look at goonface!
She fights just like a man. Oh, boy!
One of these days, you'll come here
and I'll shoot you, so help me!
Morning, Madge.
Hello, Bomber.
A bunch of us guys...
...are chipping in on a hot rod.
I get it every Friday night.
Well, don't expect to honk the horn
and have me run out.
If a boy wants a date, he can
come to the door and ask if I'm in.
Alan Benson sends her flowers
every time they go out.
I can't send you flowers, baby, but...
...I can...
...send you.
Let me pick you up some night
after Benson brings you home.
Will you stop being ridiculous?
I've seen you riding
around in his convertible...
...like you was a duchess.
Why do good-looking girls
have to be so...
...stuck on themselves?
I am not stuck on myself.
Let me pick you up some night
after Benson brings you home.
Bomber, will you let me alone?
Give a guy a break!
On your way, lover-boy.
Who are you?
What's that matter?
I'm bigger than you are.
I'm late on my route!
Go on.
Go peddle your papers!
Drop dead!
Hi.
Hey, you working for Mrs. Potts?
Just doing a few odd jobs
in the yard.
- She give you breakfast?
- Millie, stop it.
I need you girls to help me
with the picnic sandwiches, so...
Is there something you want,
young man?
Just loafing, ma'am.
This is a busy day for us.
We have no time to loaf.
Are you the...
...mother?
Yes.
Come on, Millie.
Madge!
Come here!
Come here a minute.
He knows Alan!
Isn't that nice?
I've never been to Kansas before.
Maybe you can tell me
where Benson lives.
He lives on the
other end of town.
Ask anyone over there.
Alan's father is an elevator man.
He owns all those big grain elevators.
See you.
Nice chip, Dad.
Keep your head down, son.
Follow through.
Benson?
Hal Carter!
Kid!
Well, where did you come from?
Oh, around.
You old son of a gun!
Of all the people in the world!
Hey, now. Watch it! Watch it!
Remember how we used to
wake up that fraternity?
Do I?
Who's Winkin'...
...Blinkin' and Stinkin'?
Dad, this is Hal Carter.
Yes, so it is.
I remember you
on the football field.
Thank you, Mr. Benson.
You still look able
to dodge a few tacklers.
You look pretty fit yourself, sir.
Well, I try.
I try.
Great guy.
- When did you get into town?
- Early this morning.
Imagine living in
a place like this.
Why didn't you come
to see me first thing?
I didn't want to walk in on you,
looking like a bum.
I thought I'd scrounge around, get me
a little change and pick up a new shirt.
That wouldn't have made
any difference.
Hal Carter!
Where have you been all these years?
I was working back home...
...in the filling station.
- Then I was in the Army.
- Yeah? How long?
Till I got out.
I heard you went to Hollywood...
...to become a big movie hero.
I was going to have a big career.
They were going to call me
"Brush" Carter.
What happened, "Brush"?
This babe told me they'd have to
pull out all my teeth...
...and get me new ones,
so naturally...
Wait a minute. What babe?
The babe that got me the screen test.
She wasn't exactly a babe.
She was kind of beat-up, but...
...not bad.
Same old Hal.
Aren't you glad to see me?
Well, sure.
How about lending me a razor?
Okay, go on now. Fill me in.
After I left Hollywood...
...I took a job on a ranch in Nevada.
You'd have been proud of me.
In bed every night at 10...
...up every morning at 6.
No liquor, no babes, no nothing!
I even saved up 200 bucks.
Then I got rolled.
Rolled? You?
I was...
...hitchhiking my way down to Texas...
...on a big oil deal...
...when two babes pull up...
...in this big, yellow convertible.
One of them slams on the brake
and hollers...
..."Hey, beefcake! Get in."
So I...
...got in.
Benson, it was crazy.
They had a shaker full of martinis
right in the car.
- Remembering old times?
- Oh, yes, sir. Oh, no, sir.
I'm due at the club, Alan.
Join me later if you wish.
I've got a date, Dad.
Same young lady?
Of course.
Delighted to have seen you.
It's mutual, sir.
Great car.
Go on. Now tell me
what happened exactly.
You know me.
- I'm an agreeable guy.
- Sure.
So when they park in front of
this tourist cabin, I said:
"If I got to pay for the ride,
this is the easiest way I know."
So we got busy...
...on the martinis.
They must have thought
I was Superman.
Nothing like that
ever happens to me.
So then I said...
..."Okay, girls, party's over.
Let's get going."
And one of them sticks a gun
in my back and says...
..."This party's going on
till we say it's over, Buck."
You'd have thought
she was Humphrey Bogart.
Wait a minute. Then what?
So finally I passed out.
When I woke up, the dames were gone
and so was my 200 bucks.
I went to the police.
They wouldn't believe me.
They said my story was wishful thinking.
How do you like that?
I'm telling you, Benson...
...women are getting desperate.
Be awfully nice to
be married to Alan, Madge.
Better get busy.
Busy?
A pretty girl doesn't have long.
Just a few years.
Then she's the equal of kings.
She can walk out of
a shanty like this...
...and live in a palace.
If she loses her chance
when she's young...
...she might as well throw
all her prettiness away.
I'm only 19.
And next summer, you'll be 20.
And then 21, and then...
...40.
You don't have to be morbid.
Is this a private party I'm crashing?
Oh, no.
I won't be back
for lunch, Mrs. Owens.
There's a welcome-home party
at the hotel...
...for the new girls on the faculty.
My, isn't that scrumptious!
You'll be the belle of the ball, Madge.
You look nice yourself, Miss Sydney.
It's the new fall outfit.
You schoolteachers
certainly have nice things.
I got it in Kansas City.
Paid $22.50 for the hat.
Good land! You let your daughter
read filthy books like that?
- Filthy?
- What are you reading, Millie?
The Ballad of the Sad Cafe.
And it's not filthy.
It's wonderful.
Somebody wanted it
banned from the public library.
It's on the reading list at college,
and Alan Benson loaned it to me.
Oh, dear.
What is a person to believe?
Well, those college professors
don't have any morals.
Bye, now.
Madge, let's get at this dress.
Everybody around here gets to
dress up and go places except me.
That's because you're not
interested in boys.
You'd think all boys cared
about was what somebody wears.
They do care about
how they look and act, though.
And how they smell
a lot of the time.
Girls, don't fight!
La-dee-da!
Madge is the pretty one.
But she's so dumb, they almost had to...
...burn the schoolhouse
to get her out of it.
That is not so!
You have to work in the dime store.
Bomber was right. You are a goon!
You slut! You take that back or
I'll kill you! Take it back!
Hello, girls.
Lovely morning, isn't it?
- Mother!
- Take it back, Madge!
Girls! What will the neighbors say?
Nobody can call me "goon"
and get by with it.
You've called her worse names.
It doesn't hurt, what names I call her.
Madge is the pretty one.
Names don't bother her at all.
Poor Millie!
All I ever hear is "poor Millie"!
Poor Millie won herself a scholarship...
...for four whole years of college.
A girl like Millie...
...can need confidence in other ways.
With Alan...
...you'd live in comfort
the rest of your life.
Charge accounts at all the stores.
Automobiles and trips.
And you'd belong to the country club.
I don't feel right with those people.
Why not?
Your grandfather was in
the state legislature.
You're as good as they are.
When a girl's as pretty as you are,
she doesn't have to...
What good is it just to be pretty?
What a question!
Maybe I get tired of
only being looked at.
You puzzle me when you talk that way.
Does Alan ever make love?
Sometimes we park the car
by the river.
Do you let him kiss you?
After all, you've been
going together all summer.
Of course I let him.
Does he ever want to
go beyond kissing?
I'm your mother!
These things have to be talked about.
Do you like it when he kisses you?
Yes.
You don't sound very enthusiastic.
What do you expect me to do?
Pass out every time Alan
puts his arms around me?
No, you don't have to pass out.
But there won't be many more
opportunities like the picnic tonight.
It seems to me you could at least...
What?
Nothing!
That dress is to be worn
only to parties. Do you understand?
I don't want to have to remind you.
And another thing...
...I want you to stop picking on
Millie all the time!
Poor darling.
Oh, don't.
Do you love Millie more than me?
Madge, of course not.
But sometimes you act like you did.
Don't say things like that.
Listen to me.
When you were born...
...we didn't know how to
hold in our joy.
We laughed...
...and we cried.
We planted that elm tree
in the back yard.
When you got older, your father
carried you on his shoulder...
...for all the neighborhood to see.
And when Millie came...
...it was different.
Your father wasn't home
a lot of the time.
He'd found other things.
Then he walked out of the house
and never came back.
If I ever seem to favor Millie...
...maybe it's because I want
to make it up to her.
All those golden years you had
and she didn't.
I was just remembering you at school.
How you always
had things under control.
Who, me?
You never cut classes...
...understood the lectures...
...took notes.
The hero of the campus,
and he envied me.
Yeah. Big hero.
Between the goal posts.
It finally happened, kid.
Your father?
He went on his last bender.
The police scraped him up
off the sidewalk.
He died in jail.
I'm sorry to hear that, Hal.
You wanted to see them.
There they are!
Mr. Benson!
Hello, Mike!
You're not working today?
Have to. Got a backlog.
Come on.
They're loading.
What do you say, Red?
Hello, Alan.
The wheat comes down
through that spout.
All the way from the top.
- It must come down like a ton of...
- It does. Come on.
- I'll give you a hand, Red.
- Thanks. I can use a hand.
Tie it up good, now.
If these things ever get loose,
they can be mean.
I worked with the boys here one summer.
I was a wheat scooper.
No kidding.
Dad wanted me to learn the business
from the bottom up.
I guess that'll hold it.
- All set?
- Okay, ready to go.
Watch this.
I'll push a button.
Hey, Hart!
How you doing, Charlie?
What's this thing?
It's the man-lift.
Go on! Get on it.
Go on! Don't be afraid.
This is great!
Watch your head.
- You own all these?
- The corporation does.
That one too?
That's their newest one.
That holds 10 million bushels.
That's a lot of biscuits.
You know...
...what I was hoping was that...
...you and your old man...
...between you might be able to
fix me up with a job.
Sure.
These companies can always use men.
I'm sure Dad can do something.
Maybe...
...something in a nice office
where I can wear a tie...
...have a sweet little secretary.
And talk over the telephone...
...about enterprises...
...and things.
I got to get someplace in this world.
I just got to.
Sure.
But...
...before you get to be president
of the company, you'll have to be...
...a little patient.
That's something I gotta learn.
Patience!
- Come on.
- Where are we going?
We're going swimming.
- With a couple of girls.
- A couple of girls?
Wait till you see mine.
She is unbelievable!
I know. Her name's Madge.
Absolutely and positively
the cutest thing I ever saw.
He's all right.
All right?
lmagine him on a cold and rainy night.
He's going to the picnic with Alan,
and he's taking me.
He's taking you?
After the picnic tonight...
...let's get away from the others.
All right.
We'll take a boat out on the river.
Come on, kid.
Let's show them how to swim!
On your mark, get set...
...go!
"Come on, kid.
Let's show them how to swim."
Big shot!
Bomber, don't be forever a creep.
I want to find out something.
I want to find out if
you look real in the moonlight.
Don't say that.
Why not?
Because I'm real, all right.
It doesn't matter
whether you are or not.
You're the most beautiful thing
I've ever seen.
What's on your mind?
I don't know if it's a good idea,
me going on this picnic.
Why not?
You're taking Millie.
I've never been on a picnic.
What are you talking about?
Everybody's been on a picnic.
Yeah? Not me.
When I was a kid,
I was too busy...
...shooting craps
or stealing milk bottles.
You went on the steak fries
in the fraternity, didn't you?
And you know what
they turned out to be.
This picnic won't be that primitive.
How do you talk to boys?
Why, you just talk, silly.
How do you think of things to say?
You just say whatever
comes into your head.
Supposing nothing ever
comes into my head?
Why ask me all the questions?
You're supposed to be
the smart one.
What do you think of her?
Who?
My girl!
Not bad.
Not bad?
She's the prettiest girl in town.
I bet you they announce tonight
she's going to be Queen of Neewollah!
Nee-what-a?
Neewollah!
It's Halloween spelled backwards.
They have this big
coronation ceremony every year.
Madge should have been Queen
last year. She had 400 votes.
- Only this other jerk...
- Stop it!
- What have we been talking about?
- I don't know.
Get away from this wall.
You're liable to get educated.
Millie, stop it!
I can't see anything.
We brought home your wayward girl.
Welcome back, Irma. Rosemary
told me you've been in New York.
Whatever she says,
I didn't disgrace myself.
Mrs. Owens, this is
Christine Schoenwalder.
She's taking Mabel Fremont's
place this year.
In Feminine Hygiene.
I'm delighted to know you, Christine.
Howard phoned.
He did?
How do I look?
Now tell me the truth.
You look very nice.
Feel sort of funny, though.
You think he'll like me?
I don't really care anyway.
I just wonder.
Bye!
You better hurry if you're going
to change. Howard'll be here soon.
Shoot!
It doesn't take me any time
to dress for Howard.
Hey, Hal! Here.
Try this.
Can you imagine that?
Alan's brought two cars!
Here's your date, Millie.
Hey, kid! Look at you!
I've decided to go along too.
My best girl!
Romeo, you've met Mrs. Owens too,
you know.
Oh, sure. She's the mother.
I'm coming too, Rosemary.
This is Miss Rosemary Sydney.
Miss Sydney teaches
in the high school.
I'm an old maid schoolteacher.
I have every respect
for schoolteachers, ma'am.
It's a lot of hard work
and not much pay.
If the men will take
the baskets out to the cars...
And there's a big tub of ice,
but I don't think...
I'll handle that, ma'am.
I'll help.
Be careful. It's very heavy.
Here we go.
Look at him!
He carries that old washtub...
...as if it was
so much tissue paper.
Here, let me help.
It's him!
Who?
It's Howard.
If he's been drinking,
I'm not going with him.
Hold it, Hal.
I want you to meet Howard Bevans.
Hal Carter.
Pleased to meet you, sir.
Same here.
Hey, Millie's a good-looking
little lady.
I never realized that before.
He's right, kid!
I've been telling her that
for years.
- Is there anything else, ma'am?
- Thermoses.
Thermoses, coming up.
Howard, I'm going along too.
That's fine.
Howdy, ladies.
Alan, I think you better
hurry Madge up.
Say, Delilah?
- Go on up.
- Coming.
You sure look nice, Rosemary.
It seems to me you might at least
have left your coat on.
It's still too darn hot...
...even if it is September.
How are things across the river?
Business is fine.
Back to school.
Everybody's buying.
Bride and groom!
Everybody look. Bride and groom!
It's a picnic.
Why did you wear that dress?
I don't know, Mom.
I just put it on.
I never could wear
another fellow's clothes.
I'm kind of beefy
through the shoulders.
I should have all
my clothes tailor-made.
Nobody'd mind if you took it off.
Yeah, look at me. Eh, Rosemary?
Nothing like being loose.
We'd better hurry.
All the tables will be taken.
- I'll race you to the car.
- Roger.
On your marks.
Get set.
Go!
Ready?
See you there!
How did a boy like that
ever get into college?
On a football scholarship.
But he was in your fraternity.
Don't those boys...
...have a little more breeding?
Maybe.
But fraternities like to
pledge big athletes.
Hal could have been an all-American.
If he'd only studied.
He flunked out his third year.
And on this farm he had some pigs
E-l-E-l-O
With an oink- oink here
And an oink- oink there
Here an oink, there an oink
Oink- oink everywhere!
Old MacDonald had a farm
E-l-E-l-O
Here's one my old man taught me.
Old MacDonald had a farm
E-l-E-l-O
At first, I couldn't stand...
...the way he bragged
and swaggered either.
Then we shared a room,
and I got to know him better.
Is he wild?
Not really.
Does he drink?
A little.
After all, Millie's only a child!
Now, Flo.
Don't be an old poke.
A picnic isn't a picnic
without a little drink.
Put that bottle down
where you found it.
Old poke!
What if somebody saw us
from the school board?
I'd lose my job.
Honey, why do you think
I drove down this street?
There isn't a soul in sight.
Come on, honey. Be a sport.
Have one little one.
Just for me.
If I have one,
will you stop coaxing?
Just the same, you ought to be
ashamed of yourself.
Oh, kids!
That looks like a lovely spot.
Yes! That's just fine.
That's enough of you kids.
That's all the swan boat will hold.
Going to run all night
Going to run all day
Dancing tonight will begin
at 8:00.
The music will be provided by
Ernie Higgins and His Happiness Boys.
Don't overdo it!
I hear
The gentle voices calling
We are putting in the haystack...
...$125...
...in nickels, dimes and quarters.
All the world is sad and dreary
Everywhere I roam
Attention, everybody! Attention!
A child has been found.
He says he has no name.
Anyone missing
a child with no name...
...can claim him here
at the pavilion.
Get your partners
for the trained-seal game.
No, ladies.
You've got to have a man.
I've got one!
I'll get my pants dirty.
Now, Howard, we're going to play.
Kneel down!
The object of the game...
Men, put your hands behind your back.
Ladies with the jar rings,
ring the lollipop sticks...
...in the fellow's mouth.
Hal! Catch it!
While my little one
While my pretty one...
...sleeps
Faster!
Go on!
Come back here!
And it is proper...
...that this holiday
known as Labor Day...
...be set aside...
Hey, Hal, look at the mutt!
That dog ate up our food.
No, no!
Leave room for the cake.
I've never had so much fun
since Grandma caught...
Since ever.
How about it, kid?
We'd have won that
three-legged race if I hadn't...
...let you down.
Millie doesn't go in much for sports.
She cultivates her mind.
I wasn't taking anything
from her there, ma'am.
She's got a...
...splendid mind.
Come on, both of you!
Cut it out!
You ought to come to Halster someday
and see my shop.
Notions, novelties, school supplies.
You too, Alan.
It's right across the big river.
We'll be over, sir...
...as soon as we can fit it
in our schedule.
You can't miss it.
The store right next to the bank.
I live right upstairs.
Only one big room, but it's big
enough for me and my 21 -inch TV.
Where did you ever get those boots?
My old man left them to me
when he died.
He had a very big foot.
Is that all he left you?
Just a pair of boots?
He used to sit on
the bed at night and I'd...
...tug them off him.
And he'd say:
"Son...
...the man of the house has
got to have a pair of boots...
...because he's got to do
a lot of kicking."
Then he said:
"Son...
...there'll be times
when all you've got...
...to be proud of is
the fact that you're a man.
So wear boots so people know you're
coming, and double your fists up...
...so they know you mean business
when you get there."
My old man, he was a corker.
Hal's shy of people
before he meets them...
...and then you can't keep him still.
What line of business you in, son?
I'm about to...
...enter the grain business, sir.
You see...
...my old man was no aristocratic
millionaire or anything, but he had...
...some very important friends.
Some very big people...
...in their own way.
And one of them was
always after me...
...to take this position with the...
...oil company down in Texas and...
Dad and I found a place
for Hal scooping wheat.
Yeah, I've decided to
start from the very bottom.
I sure do appreciate Alan
and his old...
...his old father...
...giving me this opportunity.
A young man coming to town
has got to be a good mixer.
Wouldn't it be nice if he could join
the country club and play golf?
He won't be able to afford that.
The bowling team's a rowdy gang.
There's a young man's Bible class
at the Baptist church.
I learned something today.
And it's that there comes a time
in a man's life...
...when he's got to quit
rolling around like a pinball.
Maybe...
...a little town like this is...
...the place to settle down.
Where people are...
...easygoing and...
...sincere.
Hi.
I'm sorry.
Look, watermelon!
In thy dark eyes' splendor
Where the warm light
Loves to dwell
Weary looks
Yet tender
Speak their fond farewell
A day like this reminds me of...
...when I was a girl.
Things I haven't thought about
in a long...
...long time.
Now, Helen.
Flo...
...you'll never know what it's meant
to have you next door to me.
Watching your two girls grow up.
It's made it easier.
Now, Helen.
Where is everybody?
Don't you remember, Flo?
At a picnic...
...everybody disappears.
Look at that sunset, Howard.
A sunset's a beautiful thing,
all right.
It's like the daytime
didn't want to end, isn't it?
It's like the daytime was going to
put up a big scrap.
Set the world on fire...
...to keep the nighttime
from creeping on.
Hey, kid!
It's me!
I had a job as a model once.
Like this.
They had me posing in front of
a class, almost raw.
I sure do admire people
who are artistic.
I just like to draw.
People who draw...
...read books...
...listen to the...
...better music...
I used to go with a girl
who read books.
She joined the...
...Book-of-the-Month Club...
...and they had her reading books
all the time.
She'd no more finish one,
and they'd shoot her another.
Last summer I memorized
all of Shakespeare's sonnets.
No kidding?
You're thinking about your father,
aren't you?
I was thinking how impressed
he'll be when he reads you were...
...picked as
Queen of Neewollah tonight.
But they haven't picked me yet.
Besides...
...l'm sure he thinks
the whole thing is silly.
No, you don't know him.
He's always impressed by
people who win things...
...or make the most money...
...or score the most points
at a football game.
I write poetry myself.
I've written poems I've never
shown to a living soul.
Kid, I think you must be
some sort of a genius.
We're all going down to the dock
in a minute. Now remember!
Aren't you excited?
Millie won't be shocked
to see somebody take a drink.
- Are you, Millie?
- Gosh, no.
One more drink won't hurt you, honey.
I guess I know why you want me
to keep on drinking.
Now, honey, that's not so.
Ladies and gentlemen...
...the moment we have been
waiting for has arrived.
Is she the Queen?
I bet she is.
On October 31 st, next Halloween...
...we will crown our
Queen of Neewollah.
She has not yet
reached our shores, but...
Wait a minute!
Here she comes now!
It's Madge.
I'll bet you anything.
No kidding?
Neewollah
Ain't she sweet
See her coming down the street
Now I ask you very confidentially
Ain't she sweet
Ain't she nice
Look her over once or twice
Now I ask you very confidentially
Ain't she nice
Just cast an eye
In her direction
Oh, me
Oh, my
Ain't that perfection
Shoot!
When I was a girl I was
just as good-looking as she is.
You know...
...I look forward to seeing her
every time I go to the Owens' house.
But I tell myself,
"Howard, old boy...
...you look all you want...
...but you couldn't touch her
with a 10-foot pole."
Welcome to our shores...
...Your Majesty!
Ladies and gentlemen...
...the new Queen...
...Madge Owens!
Speech!
Thank you.
I'm very proud...
...and I'll try hard
to be a good Queen.
And I'll try hardest of all
not to get conceited.
No, Your Majesty!
The president's first.
Don't you worry, Mr. Benson.
We'll not leave you out.
Land! I love that music!
Dance with me.
Honey, I'm no good at dancing.
That's just what you men say
to get out of it.
We'll show you we can do without them.
Won't we, Millie? Come on.
All right, but...
Well, I got to lead.
Mr. President, could I see you
just a moment, please?
Excuse me.
Where's Mrs. Johnson?
I've got to return this cape.
- Excuse me a minute, Mom.
- All right, darling.
See how Millie is.
Stop it!
- I thought we were doing very nicely.
- You think you're so funny.
Hey, kid, dance with me.
I never dance with boys.
Sure you can. All you have to do
is follow the steps.
Here's the cape, Mrs. Johnson.
All safe and sound.
More!
I'll show you a step I learned in L.A.
Now watch this.
First you've got to set the rhythm.
I wish I could do it.
Aren't they graceful?
You used to dance like that, Flo.
Why can't you dance that way?
Honey, I'm a businessman.
One night I went dancing
at a big valentine party.
I danced so hard I swooned.
That's when they called me
the dancing fool.
Mighty pretty legs.
That's just like you men.
Can't talk about anything
but women's legs.
I just noticed their nice shape.
How'd you like it if we women...
...went around talking about
your legs all the time?
All right.
There's my legs.
I never saw anything so ugly.
Young man, let's see your legs.
New rule tonight.
Every man's got to show his legs.
Come on. The other one too.
Let him alone.
He's dancing with Madge.
It's his turn to dance with me.
I may be an old maid schoolteacher,
but I can keep up with you.
Come on, ride 'em, cowboy!
But, ma'am, I...
Used to have a boyfriend
was a cowboy.
Met him in Colorado.
He was in love with me
because I was...
...an older woman and had some sense.
Sorry.
He took me up in the mountains
one night...
...and wanted to marry me.
Right there on the mountaintop.
He said the stars would be our preacher
and the moon our best man.
Did you ever hear such talk?
You know what?
You remind me of one
of those old statues.
One of those Roman gladiators.
All they had on was a shield.
My, those ancient people
were depraved!
- I don't think I can dance.
- I can keep up with you.
Please, I want to dance.
Please, I gotta dance!
He was dancing with Madge.
Let them alone.
They're young people.
Young?
What do you mean?
I'm sick.
I just want to die!
Here, Millie.
Over here, darling.
I hate you!
Madge is the pretty one!
What did she have to do that for?
I guess that's something wonderful.
Young!
How much do you suppose
the little dickens...?
I want to know who fed
liquor to Millie!
He did, Mrs. Owens!
It's all his fault!
Wait a minute.
Millie was your date.
You should've been looking after her.
But you were too busy
making eyes at Madge.
The boy didn't do anything.
You've been stomping around in
those boots like you owned the place.
Thinking every woman you saw
was gonna fall madly in love.
Here's one woman
didn't pay you any mind!
Bragging about your father!
I bet he wasn't
any better than you are.
Strutting around here
like some crummy Apollo!
You think, because you act young...
...you can walk in here and
make off with whatever you like.
Let me tell you something.
You're a fake!
You're no jive kid.
You're just scared to act your age!
Buy yourself a mirror
and take a look in it.
It won't be long before
you're counting the gray hairs...
...if you've got any left!
And what'll become of you then?
You'll end your life in the gutter,
and it'll serve you right!
The gutter's where you came from,
and the gutter's where you belong!
Shut your mouth!
Turn that off!
This isn't a sideshow!
Go on now. Come on!
Go on about your business!
Get out of here!
Turn out that light, I said!
What happened, Hal?
Answer me.
What did you do?!
Same old Hal!
I'm sorry, Mrs. Owens.
I should have known better
than to trust him.
There's to be no more drinking!
It was my fault, Mrs. Owens.
I brought the whiskey.
Alan, come and help me with Millie.
What made me do it, Howard?
What made me act that way?
Maybe it's...
...the harvest moon, honey.
I wanted to have
a good time tonight, Howard.
This is my last night of vacation.
Maybe we should go for a ride, honey.
Yes!
Yes, let's.
I want to have a good time!
Beat it, baby!
I'm in a bad mood.
Please wait a minute.
Alan shouldn't have talked
that way to you.
I said, beat it!
Okay, baby, you asked for it!
Okay, go on home.
Tell them anything you want.
Thank Benson for his shirt.
- What are you going to do?
- There'll be a freight here soon.
Women like Miss Sydney make me mad
at the whole female sex.
What's the use, baby?
I'm a bum.
She saw through me
like an x-ray machine.
There's no place in the world
for a guy like me.
But there's got to be.
Don't pay any attention to her.
You are young.
Yes, you are.
But not so young you're not a man too.
And you're very entertaining.
I think you say
all sorts of witty things.
I just love listening to your talk.
And you're a wonderful dancer.
Thanks.
I can tell a lot about a man
by dancing with him.
You know, some boys...
...when they take a girl
in their arms to dance...
...they make her feel
sort of uncomfortable.
But with you...
...I had the feeling you knew
exactly what you were doing.
And I could follow you
every step of the way.
You've got lots of qualities.
Let me level with you, baby.
When I was 14,
I spent a year in jail.
Honest?
Called it a reform school.
Let me tell you, it was a jail!
For what?
I stole another guy's motorcycle.
I stole it because I wanted to get...
...so far away so fast,
nobody would ever catch me.
Everybody feels that way sometimes.
Then my old lady
went to the authorities.
"I've done everything I can
with the boy.
I can't do anything more."
So off I go to that
lousy, stinking place!
When I finally get out...
...the old lady's sorry
to see me back...
...because my dad's loaded
all the time.
And she's got a new boyfriend...
...and I'm in the way.
It's awful when parents
don't get along.
Well, there you are!
And I never told that
to another soul.
If you wanna faint
or get sick or go home...
...go on, because I won't...
Baby, what did you do?
I get so tired
of just being told I'm pretty.
The others!
We've got to get back to the picnic.
Do we?
Here we are,
back where we started from.
Everybody else must be home hours.
I'm glad we went off.
Good night, Rosemary.
I should say, "Good morning."
Where are you going, Howard?
Why, home, honey.
You can't go off without me.
Not after tonight.
Take me with you.
Honey, be reasonable.
What would people say?
People?
What do they say
if I thumb my nose at them...
...or if I showed my pink panties
on the street?
What do I care what people say?
Look, honey.
You'd better go inside
and get some sleep.
You got to start school
in the morning.
Can't we talk this over on Saturday?
Maybe you won't be back Saturday.
You know better than that.
Maybe you won't be back ever again.
You're not yourself tonight.
Yes, I am.
I'm more myself than I ever was.
I see what's in store for me.
After you...
...someone else...
...then...
...someone else.
Then...
Take me with you.
If you don't, I don't know
what I'll do. I mean it.
When we first started
to go together...
...you were the best sport
I ever saw.
Always good for a laugh.
I can't laugh anymore.
You said you'd marry me
after my vacation.
You said you'd be waiting
with the preacher.
- I've had a busy summer.
- Where's the preacher?
I'm not a boy anymore.
A person forms
certain ways of living.
And one day it's too late to change.
I'm no spring chicken either.
Maybe I'm a little older
than you think.
My ways are formed too.
But they can be changed.
They got to be changed.
It's no good living like this...
...in rented rooms...
...meeting a bunch of old maids
for supper every night...
...then coming back home...
...alone.
Each year I keep telling myself
it's the last.
Something will happen.
Nothing ever does.
Except I get a little crazier
all the time.
- Well...
- A well's a hole in the ground!
I wasn't trying to be funny.
Can't we talk this over
on Saturday?
I'm dead tired.
I got a busy week ahead of me.
You got to marry me.
I can't marry you now.
You can be over in the morning.
No.
I'm not going to marry
anyone who says:
"You've got to marry me, Howard."
I mean, the thing is...
If a woman wants me to marry her...
...she can at least say, "Please."
Please...
...marry me, Howard.
Please!
Come on inside.
Now go to bed and
get some sleep.
I'll drive over in the morning.
Maybe we can talk it over.
Don't come unless you're
taking me away.
Please marry me, Howard.
Please.
Go to bed.
Get some sleep.
Please?
How will you get in?
The kitchen door is always open.
Are you all right, baby?
Yes, I'm all right.
If I thought I'd done anything...
...to make you unhappy...
...l'd almost want to die.
Yes, Mama.
I'm coming.
You'd better go.
I'll take the car back
to Benson's house.
I didn't even think of him
until this second.
I ought to be shot at sunrise.
I guess neither of us
thought too much about anything.
Good night.
When will I see you?
I don't know.
What time are you through
at the dime store?
Six.
Maybe I could come by then.
I start a job tomorrow.
Maybe not with Benson.
Someplace.
You don't mind...
...seeing a guy who's...
...just a grain scooper, do you?
Of course not.
Baby, would you...
...kiss me good night?
No.
Just once for...
...for luck maybe, huh?
If I promise not to hold you?
Are you trying to punish me?
Yes.
I think I was trying to punish you.
Kiss me, Hal.
Being with you is wonderful, baby.
You make me feel...
...important.
No!
You make me feel...
...patient.
Do I?
Don't kiss me anymore.
Please don't kiss me anymore.
It's all right.
I put Mom to bed.
I was awful tonight, wasn't I?
Honest, I'm never gonna touch
another drink till the day I die.
So far, no go.
We've notified the highway patrol.
You've had hours!
Can't we all go to bed
and worry about this tomorrow?
- It's only a stolen car.
- It's not!
Maybe he kidnapped Madge.
Nobody kidnapped her.
She's home.
You got every right to be sore.
I didn't start out to...
You saw another pretty girl,
and you had to add her to your list.
It wasn't that way at all.
- No matter what you think.
- You're a liar!
You're the only friend I ever had.
I'm not your friend anymore!
Let me go, you bum!
You no-good hobo!
When I think...
...how glad I was
to see you this morning.
How glad I was!
I want him arrested.
He stole my car.
That's a lousy lie!
The car's outside.
It doesn't matter.
He stole it!
We'll book you for the night.
You've got no place to sleep anyway.
I'm not going to any jail!
No damn jail, see?
It wasn't the car.
Tell him.
Tell him it's not the car!
Tell him it's because of Madge!
Thanks, kid.
- Why don't you let him go?
- Nobody's going to push us.
Let's go to bed, son.
Don't pretend you're not
pleased about this.
- What are you talking about?
- Madge and me!
You wanted to break this up!
Well, I'm gonna marry Madge.
Start getting used to the idea!
I hope he gets away.
Over here!
He went over this way!
You check the freight cars.
I'll search the riverbank.
I have to have at least
one more easy chair.
What about the closets?
Barely enough room for my suits.
Slipcovers, I suppose.
That would have to go.
No!
What happened, son?
I remember you...
...saying you lived
next to the bank.
- The cops didn't see me hit the river.
- Cops?
I don't know.
Benson said I stole his car.
Please, sir. You got to help me.
I have to spend the night someplace,
then get out of town.
Get out of those and dry off.
What happened was this...
You don't have to tell me.
I understand.
What we need is a drink.
You've got your troubles,
and I've got mine.
You got a rag?
Sure.
You went for that Owens girl,
didn't you?
I'll admit they can get
under your skin.
That doesn't mean we got
to take them too seriously.
For instance...
...you wouldn't say a man had to
go as far as marrying them.
You wouldn't say a thing like that,
would you?
You're not being very helpful.
Were you awake when she got in?
No, Mom.
Didn't she say anything
to you this morning?
Nothing.
She's still got her door locked.
Have you been smoking?!
Hi, Mrs. Potts!
Is Madge all right?
Certainly.
She told me all about it.
She got out of the car
and left that hoodlum alone.
And she walked home.
- Has anyone seen Howard?
- Why, no.
He said he might be over this morning.
She's running around like a chicken
with its head off. Something's up.
Is Rosemary ready?
We promised the principal
we'd be there early...
...to help with registration.
All set for school again?
Lovely picnic, wasn't it?
Wasn't it?
How's Madge?
Just fine.
Come on, Christine.
Let's get that sleepy girl out of bed.
I gotta see Rosemary.
I think she's expecting me.
Holler at the bottom of the stairs.
The others are up there with her.
The others?
Miss Henderson and Schoenwalder.
I gotta see her alone.
I gotta explain something to her.
This is the beginning
of my busy season.
I don't think I'll be able
to make any plans...
It's Howard!
He's come for me!
You came back!
Girls! Girls!
Here's my man!
What are you screaming
and yelling about?
What's the matter with you?
Hear the news!
Most exciting thing you ever heard.
We're going to be married.
Now! Today!
Let me be the first!
Don't worry.
It won't take me long.
We'll help pack.
Packing's almost finished.
I was keeping it a secret.
Weren't we?
Don't forget to wear something old.
Nylons!
Something new.
My new handbag!
Something borrowed.
Thank you!
I don't see anything blue.
And you ain't going to.
We'll put something funny
in her bag.
Irma, you kill me!
Congratulations.
I know you'll be happy.
I want you to know...
I called and called.
Why didn't you answer?
Alan phoned.
He said to tell you he's not angry.
He knows it wasn't your fault.
And then he said...
Let me get this straight.
He said, "Tell Madge it's important.
I want to see her."
Did you hear what I said?
Yes.
You ought to thank
your lucky stars, young lady.
Come see this divine outfit!
We need your approval.
Come on!
Come help us with the bags.
He's outside.
He's hiding in my car.
The police are after him.
But he says he's got to see you.
Be careful.
I got the rice! Let's go get
some paint. Mrs. Potts has some!
Miss Sydney is getting married!
Who?
Let's decorate the car!
Let's get some paint!
Christine, get some rice.
Be ready. She'll be right out.
I'm gonna cry.
Imagine something like this
the first day of school!
All the happiness in the world!
Howard, look!
The sun has come out.
You would pick a wonderful day.
Let's go!
You've been a wonderful friend.
I wish you all kinds
of happiness, Rosemary.
I mean...
...Mrs. Bevans!
Wait till we tell
the principal about this.
Where's Madge?
Goodbye, Madge!
Goodbye.
And don't worry about
the room, Mrs. Owens.
I know Miss Breckenridge will take it.
And she's a darling girl.
Yes, she sure is. Look!
We've still got to
pick up the license.
I nearly forgot.
I left my hot-water bottle
and my curlers in the bathroom.
Would you store the rest
of my things in your attic?
We'd better hurry.
Where are we going?
I got a cousin who has
a tourist camp in the Ozarks, but...
- I love the Ozarks!
- Wonderful this time of year!
I was there three years ago
for my vacation.
Get ready.
Have a wonderful time!
So long. You know what
you can tell the principal for me.
Hey, kids!
It's Miss Sydney!
She's getting married.
It's Howard Bevans!
Hi, baby.
I'm in a jam.
Howard told me.
I just couldn't run out of town...
...and never see you again.
Where are you going?
Tulsa.
I always get a job...
...Hotel Mayo.
Bellhopping.
Did you see what I put
on the back of the car?
It's the young man!
Don't blow your top.
I'm leaving town.
Leaving?
I thought you were going
to stay here and settle down.
I thought so too, ma'am.
Aren't you gonna say goodbye?
Goodbye.
Are you mad at me?
I gotta know how you feel.
Last night I thought...
...you liked me.
I did like you.
I liked you from
the first time I saw you.
Are you out of your senses?
I've been thinking all night.
I've never said this before,
because it...
It'd make me seem like
such a freak, but...
What?
I love you, Madge.
Do you hear?
I want you in the house
this minute.
Do you love me?
Do you?
I'll have the police
put you where you belong.
If you please, ma'am.
I'm catching that freight.
Meet me, baby.
We'll get married.
They'll give me a room in the hotel
until we find something better.
Don't listen.
I got a chance with you.
It won't be bigtime,
but that isn't important, is it?
Come on.
Oh, Hal, I can't.
Why?
Don't you see why?
Don't you?
Listen, baby...
...you're the only real thing
I ever wanted.
Ever. You're mine.
I've got to claim what's mine, or
I'll be nothing as long as I live.
You love me.
You know it.
You love me!
You liked him, didn't you, Helen?
Yes, I did.
I got so used to things
as they were.
Everything so prim.
The geranium in the window...
...the smell of Mama's medicines.
And then he walked in.
And it was different.
He clomped through the place
like he was still outdoors.
There was a man in the house.
And it seemed good.
When I graduate from college,
I'm going to New York...
...and write novels that'll shock people
right out of their senses.
I'm never going to fall in love.
Not me.
I'm not going to live
in some jerkwater town...
...and marry some ornery guy
and raise a lot of grimy kids.
But just because I'm a dope
doesn't mean you have to be.
I was watching out the window
when he said goodbye.
Go with him, Madge.
For once in your life,
do something bright.
Hey, Madge,
do you want to go dancing?
Let me be next, Madge.
Get out of this yard!
Get out!
Neewollah!
I'm going to Tulsa, Mom.
You don't know what you're doing.
You can't.
I'm going, Mom.
Listen to me.
Put down that bag.
- Listen to what I've got to say.
- A bus is coming. I've got to hurry.
He's no good. He'll never
be able to support you.
And when he does have a job,
he'll spend it all on drink.
And after that,
there'll be other women.
I know.
You don't love someone
because he's perfect.
Just think about it a few days.
Goodbye, Mrs. Potts.
I'll miss you
almost as much as Mom.
Madge, look.
You've got to be here
for the festival.
It's your duty.
Alan's going to take you.
But I don't love Alan, Mom.
Don't worry about me.
My little girl.
My baby.
Don't go. Don't!
But there are so many things
I meant to tell her...
I never got around to it.
Let her learn them for herself.
Come on, Millie! You don't
want to be late the first day!