The beast that ascended
out of the bottomless pit
Shall make war against them
And shall overcome them
And kill them,
And their dead bodies
Shall lie in the street
of the great city.
Sister, we're all aware
of the book of revelations.
You can twist those words
to mean almost anything.
Right here
in Los Angeles,
15 people have been
brutally murdered.
All over the country,
Cult killings
are spreading.
They're signs
of his work.
Sister,
this is the 20th century.
So one mustn't mention Satan
in polite company.
His power is growing.
All of these bodies
have been marked...
Inverted pentagrams...
his sign.
We appreciate the intensity
of your beliefs.
But the last thing
the church needs
Is to stir up
more sensationalism
About devil worship.
Otherwise, we may all
end up on Geraldo.
No, I believe it's best
If you return
to your convent,
And in seclusion,
meditate less on the devil
And more on the virtues
of our lord Jesus Christ.
Especially the virtue
of humility.
Thank you.
Yeah.
I know where
he's going next.
Listen, lady...
The marks are always
exactly 6 inches in diameter.
The wound is always
at the center.
Keep going.
One condition...
No killing
And no death penalty
either.
Ok. Whatever you say.
Swear it.
You got it.
What's your name?
Near sunset boulevard.
The south entrance
to elysian park.
When?
Soon.
Don't forget
your promise, Logan.
Sleeper?
Nothing.
Even a psycho fucking killer
is smart enough
To stay out of the rain.
How are
my lovebirds doing?
Hey, Carmen,
How about a nightcap
later?
Dream on.
It's too bad, Carmen.
Watching your ass
Is the only thing
keeping me awake up here.
3-Lincoln-7.
Franklin.
All positions clear.
See? 3 nights
of this shit.
Everybody's
burned out.
The broad on the phone
is his girlfriend,
Setting us up, ok?
You know these serial
freaks love mind games.
Trust me.
She wasn't his girlfriend.
He'll show.
That's all you've been
saying for 3 days.
"He'll show." You ought
to put that to music.
You know what
your problem is, Ollie?
All this mumbo-Jumbo occult
bullshit's got you spooked.
Shh...
Guy's got you thinking
he's the bogeyman
Or the ku klux klan.
Fuck you.
That's
"fuck you, sir."
What the fuck?
Pull it over.
Is this a stakeout
or a fucking parade?
That what you call it?
I call it a jerkoff.
Russ, you asked
for 72 hours.
I gave 'em to you.
Nothing happened.
Look, I told you
I didn't know when
it was going down.
But this location fits
the pentagram pattern.
My informant says
This is where
he's gonna strike next.
I can't risk it anymore.
It's too thin.
I got 18 men sitting here,
But he's liable to hit
on the west side tonight.
Hey, Russ.
They lost Carmen.
Park side,
north of sunset.
Jesus.
Well, she's probably
just taking a piss.
Heaven in art,
which father our...
Shh.
It's all right.
I don't want you
to be afraid.
If you're afraid,
I won't be able
to help you.
Pulled her
into a car.
Nobody came down
toward sunset.
Up there's the entrance
to the park.
Park?
Yeah.
It's locked.
We're just...
Going to go through
a very small door...
Here.
We're going to go through
backwards.
That's why I say
the prayers in reverse.
Heaven,
in art which father our...
Our father,
which art in heaven.
Do you understand?
Take the road.
Shh.
It's all right.
Piggy, piggy.
Aah!
Aah.
Hyah!
You son of a bitch!
You motherfucker!
How does it feel, huh?
How does it feel?
Logan!
Come on. Logan.
Go easy.
You got him.
Holy shit!
Get an ambulance!
13-843,
no warrant on suspect.
352 clear.
Detective Russell Logan
Has been taken off
the critical list
After a dramatic
life-And-Death struggle
In the early
morning hours.
This is the third time
in less than 5 years
That Logan
has been responsible
For the death or capture
of a serial killer.
Coworkers described
Alleged
pentagram killer,
Patrick Channing,
A 9-Year employee
Of the department
of water and power,
As quiet, solitary,
good at his job.
Freak used to work
in this place?
It gives me the creeps
To think he had anything to do
with the water supply.
I’ll stick to bottled water
from now on, thank you.
Detective Logan,
Do you think you'll get
the death penalty?
You better believe it.
There he is!
How's it going,
Russ?
Stomach ok?
Not gonna let these pussies
wimp out on me, are you?
If a twisted scumbag like me
doesn't deserve the big one,
Who does?
Right on.
I'm with you, pal.
I knew I could
count on you, Russ.
I owe you one.
See you around, buddy boy.
I doubt it.
Come on, franklin,
take it easy.
It's not a twist-Off,
you know.
Whoa!
Woo!
Hey!
Yeah!
Harold, it'll help
your hemorrhoids.
Come on.
Give it to me!
Hey, come on!
Sister Agnes,
I’m sorry, you know.
Logan, it's for you.
Yeah. Coming.
Classic vintage.
What is this,
early Thursday?
Yes, sir.
Drink up.
Logan. Shoot.
I warned you.
I'm sorry. You're gonna
have to sp...
Jesus.
I'm sorry.
You'll have to speak up.
I warned you.
No death penalty.
Stop it before
it's too late.
What...hold...
Left one's a little loose.
Adios, creep.
It's just after-Shocks.
It's like a chicken
with his head cut off.
Get him!
Jack!
Getting a little jumpy,
huh, jack?
Aah!
Detective Logan,
are you in there?
Headquarters needs you.
There's an emergency.
They'll have to wait.
Send the evidence techs.
I got a fucking
blood bath in my...
Sir, they told us to
bring you immediately.
It's Carmen, man.
Freaks brought her back
to the same place.
Go to hell, lady!
Are you all right?
You could have
been killed.
Yeah. Thank you.
I'm sorry.
Good-Looking broad,
nice threads,
Doesn't look
like a nut,
Says she knows
who did it,
And she'll only talk
to you, man.
Let's give the lady
what she wants.
Detective Logan,
miss...
Seaton.
Tess Seaton.
I didn't want to
come here,
But I didn't know
what else to do.
Well, you did
the right thing.
Sit down, please.
Why don't you
tell me what you know
About
the officer's death.
You seem frightened,
miss Seaton.
You really don't know,
do you?
You really don't know
who killed her.
Why don't you tell me?
The pentagram killer.
Patrick Channing,
the pentagram killer.
I don't have time
to play games.
Games?
You talk
about games?
I saw you on TV
Celebrating
a man's execution
Like it was a party.
Bye-Bye, Patrick.
Adios.
Good riddance.
Except he's back.
You might have
executed his body,
But his spirit
has been released.
Oh, I see.
His spirit.
Yes, his spirit.
And I am frightened.
I am very frightened.
Thanks for coming in
to see me.
Don't patronize me.
I'm not some crackpot.
I am a professional
psychic.
I helped the St. Louis
police department
Find a missing child...
This isn't about
a missing child, is it?
No.
It's murder.
And it's not going
to stop.
You're not dealing
with a man anymore.
He's become a force.
I promise you
I’ll do the best I can.
You've already broken
one promise to me.
You promised
no death penalty.
You lied.
That was you?
It's certainly a pleasure
to meet you, miss Seaton.
I've been looking forward
to this.
Actually,
I wanted to thank you.
How well did you know
Channing?
I didn't.
Then how did you know
where he was going next?
I try to stay away
from police work,
But when I saw the picture
of the little girl he killed...
I opened myself up to him,
And I’ve never felt
such blackness and rage.
So you used
your psychic powers
To figure out where
he was going next?
I suppose that's also
How you got
my home phone number.
I have a friend who works
at the phone company.
Look, I helped you,
And you broke
your promise to me.
And now he's not just
after you.
He's after me, too.
How do I reach you?
You call me, Logan.
Soon.
So that's it?
After all this time,
She just walks in
like that?
Mazza, don't let her
out of your sight.
With pleasure.
We're on a roll.
They nailed
Carmen’s killer.
They just
brought him in.
You killed my friend,
asshole, didn't you?
Didn't you?!
He's been like that
since they found him
In an alley
across from the park.
Had the murder weapon
in his hands.
Looks like a slam dunk.
Who is he?
No I.D.
Just some junkie
With tracks
all over his legs.
I don't know what
this guy's vegged on,
But he's ready
for the salad bar.
See you around, buddy boy.
What did you say?
I didn't say anything.
You ok?
Hey, Russ.
Did that guy look
Like he could
kill anybody to you?
Well, that's...
Hey, maybe he did it
and went into shock, man.
Yeah.
And Perkins loves you
like a father.
And just by coincidence
Our little psychic
shows up today...
Bullshit.
It's a setup, man.
Let's go.
Man, it wouldn't hurt
if we had a warrant.
We'll just tell the judge
we had a psychic hunch.
Hey, kiss my black ass!
Looks like the psychic
business pays pretty well.
Forget it.
You wouldn't look good
in a turban.
Shit.
I don't know.
It's too bad the chick
doesn't have a view.
Hmm.
Ollie,
Look at this.
It's got my name on it.
It's your
horoscope, man.
Hey, you better
look out, man.
'Cause
she might have
A voodoo love doll
of you around, too.
You looking
for something?
What?
You've been following me
the last 2 blocks.
You're crazy, lady.
Don't bother lying.
It's all over your aura.
My what?
If you're lonely,
Try computer dating,
but leave me alone,
Or I’ll call the cops.
My name is Andrea Gregg.
Nancy Rosenberg says you're
the most accurate psychic
She's ever seen.
I'd like to set up
a private reading, please?
My number is 555-0511.
Uh, hi. It's Paul.
I'm not going to come over
Friday night.
You're just
too spooky for me,
Somebody who knows what
I’m thinking before I do.
I should have said this
to your face,
But I guess
I’m too chicken shit.
Bye, Tess.
Looks like the score
is pentagram 16, LAPD 1.
Nah. Not even 1, huh, Logan?
How about a romantic
rendezvous?
Church across
from lover street.
Buenos dias, buddy boy.
Church across
from lover street.
Buenos dias, buddy boy.
Buenos dias,buddy boy.
Come on in.
We're gonna have
a little chat.
I don't believe this!
You've been
going through my things?
Take a listen
to this, Ollie.
Those are private!
You can't do that!
I can do anything
I damn well want.
Somebody who knows what
I’m thinking before I do.
I should have said this
to your face,
But I guess
I’m too chicken shit.
Bye, Tess.
It's the next one.
What was it?
He was on there.
There were 3 messages
on that machine.
Machine says
2 messages.
Maybe
you erased one.
No, I heard him!
Who?
Channing!
I mean, somebody
imitating his voice.
Guess again, Logan.
What if it was Channing?
Listen to me.
No more horseshit.
No more goblins
or tooth fairies.
Tell me
about your friends.
What are you
talking about?
This yuppie psychic routine
just doesn't cut it.
I'm thinking you two
were part of the same cult.
I bet it was your
cute little idea
Leaving that zombie
in the alley,
Make it look like
he killed Carmen, right?
You found the killer?
You surprised?
No.
Probably some poor soul
that he possessed
And then abandoned.
Oh, yeah.
Don't fuck with me!
Let go!
A woman's dead,
and you're involved!
Let go of me!
Russ, cool out, man!
Russell.
You're in danger.
Lady, he's not in danger.
You are.
Where are you
taking me?
Lover street.
That's what
the machine said.
A romantic
little rendezvous?
Let's go.
He's here.
Channing.
Great.
Russ, excuse me.
What are we doing
down here, Russ?
"Church across
from lover street,"
That's what
the voice said.
What voice?
There was no voice
on that machine.
All right,
so maybe I did erase it.
I don't like
the feeling of this.
It's spooky.
And the chick is spooky,
you hear?
What if she's
on the level?
Come on, Ollie.
Give me a break.
I'm serious, man. You see
how she was looking at me?
She said
I was in danger.
We just need
to calm down.
Let's check out
the area.
Come on.
Aqui tenemos
carne asada.
Ayyyy!
Logan, it's him!
Aah!
Ollie!
Stay back!
I saw him, Russ.
It was him.
Ollie.
Ollie!
Get an ambulance.
Hey, watch it!
Me and your friend
will be right back.
You're doing exactly
what he wants you to do.
Logan!
Piggy.
Hold it!
You move,
and you're dead.
See you around,
buddy boy.
Where did he go?
Who?
The guy who just jumped
off the roof.
Jumped off the roof?
What you been smoking?
We could use some.
All right, Russ.
Let's try it again.
What for?
Because
I want to know
How a guy jumps off
a 10-Story building,
Waves at you,
And then
just walks away.
Where's my witness?
Oh, you mean the woman
Whose house you
illegally entered, hmm?
Who you then abducted
And recklessly
endangered the life of
During a high-Speed
auto pursuit?
Her lawyer came
and got her.
You want to hear
the size
Of the lawsuit
he was talking about?
It's too bad about
your suspect, Logan.
Maybe he flew away...
Like a little birdie.
Tweet tweet.
Look, Russ.
Yeah.
I know.
Sir?
Yeah.
They got Mazza.
How'd they get him
up there?
Get him out of here.
Lieutenant grimes,
I want you to take over
the investigation immediately.
Yes, sir.
God, I hope
I am going nuts, al.
'Cause if I’m not,
Grimes isn't gonna do
much good.
Forgive me, father,
for I have sinned.
How long since your
last confession, my son?
It's been a long time.
We had kind of a...
Parting of the ways.
Holy mother, the church,
accepts all
Who return penitent
to its fold.
I don't know
if I’m penitent, father.
I don't know much
of anything anymore.
I thought I knew where
things stood, but...
Please go on.
My dad was shot,
And after that,
I guess I just said
"forget it."
I mean,
if there was a god,
How could
he take my dad,
Who never did anything
wrong in his whole life?
My mother went crazy.
She never stopped praying.
She never stopped saying
that my dad's death was...
God's will.
Look, father, I’ve seen
a lot of dead bodies,
And when someone's dead,
they're dead, right?
Maybe I am going nuts,
but I need some answers.
What is your question,
my son?
Can the spirits
of the dead return
And take over the bodies
of people still living?
You mean possession?
Yes.
How can they be stopped?
Before I answer
your question,
It is necessary
That I ask you
one of my own, my son.
What is it, father?
How's the stomach,
buddy boy?
Logan!
Hey!
Are you ok?
Well, what about
the bottle?
Where's the priest
who just came in here?
Priest?
I didn't see
any priest.
There it is!
Pull over!
Logan!
Channing.
No, Logan!
Tess!
What the fuck?
This is an emergency.
Move!
Look, I’m not
an anti-Cop type.
You need help
with some creep...
Shut up!
Aah!
Oh! Aah!
Call this number
And ask for
inspector Perkins.
On second thought,
Talk to
lieutenant grimes.
He'll take care
of your damages
Personally.
Any time, officer.
Look, miss Seaton...
Tess.
Tess. Right.
I want to...
You don't have to
thank me.
Would you quit finishing
my sentences for me?
Sorry.
I forget sometimes.
God, I could use
a drink.
All right.
Tell me again
from the beginning.
What the hell
is going on here?
I don't really know
myself, Logan.
All I know is
that he's a spirit now,
And except
for mind games,
Like making you
see or hear things,
A spirit can't really
do anything
In the physical world
without a body.
So Channing
possesses bodies.
She just got out
of the hospital.
Might want to
put her back in there.
Ok, he possesses bodies,
But I saw him.
I saw him.
He wants you to see him.
That's his game.
He can reveal himself
to you,
Or he can hide.
And what am I
supposed to do?
Look, I spend
most of my time
Telling people
about their love life
Or if their TV show's
going to be renewed.
I have heard of a woman,
though.
Maybe she could
help us.
Yes?
Hi. We'd like to see
sister marguerite, please.
Sister marguerite
doesn't see visitors.
Could you tell her
That it's a matter
police business, sister?
I'm afraid that will mean
very little to her.
Tell her it's
a very important
Spiritual matter.
All right.
Wait here.
I'm surprised you didn't
pull your gun on her.
Thank you.
Sister marguerite,
We need your help.
An entity has returned
and is killing.
How did the entity die?
Execution.
Sister,
What can you tell us
about the first power?
The church doesn't
allow us to discuss that.
Sister, I don't mean
to be disrespectful,
But I really don't care
what the church feels.
People are
getting killed.
Forget the first power.
It's not
to be played with.
Sister marguerite?
Come on.
You heard the lady.
She just can't cut it.
So what's your next
hot lead?
You know, you're not doing
so great yourself, Logan.
Thing only thing
I’ve heard out of you so far
Is that you need
a drink.
Would have done me
more good
Than seeing
the flying nun.
Fine. Pull over.
What?
I said pull over.
I'm thirsty.
Hi.
2 scotches.
Doubles.
Look, I don't know what
you're trying to prove.
What's the matter,
Logan?
I never heard
of a cop
Turning down
a free drink.
Should have told me
These were the spirits
you were looking for.
Again.
Maybe this time I could
have it straight.
That was straight,
lady.
Well, then, McGuire,
You got a leak
in your roof
'Cause this stuff's
so watered down
It tastes like
a god damn Perrier.
I ain't McGuire.
I’ll do it.
You drink
like a vice cop.
That's seriously going
to fuck with your vibes.
You should slow down
on that stuff.
I'm trying to get
through to you, Logan.
I'm trying real hard,
But you've got
this shell around you.
It even started
in a place like this,
Didn't it?
Come on, Logan.
Talk to me.
It was 2 guys
in ski masks, right,
And your old man
by himself,
Closing up the bar?
I don't need this shit
from you.
He died for no reason.
That's when you stopped
believing in anything.
You've got to believe
in something,
And it can't
be vengeance.
Otherwise, you're
just like Channing.
You've gotta believe
in this.
You always talk
this much?
It's no wonder
your boyfriend split.
Wasn't my boyfriend.
We just went out
a few times.
Amazing it lasted
that long.
Hey.
Hey!
What?
I was an asshole.
I shouldn't have said that
about your boyfriend.
It's all right.
That's my problem.
I can tell
everybody else
What to do
with their life,
But my life
is a total wreck.
We have to go
to Channing's house.
I know he's returned
from the grave,
But do you really think
he's moved back in?
Mrs. Channing...
We're from the post.
We really hate
to bother you,
But these new
pentagram killings
Could prove that Patrick
wasn't guilty after all.
We'd like to talk to you
if we could.
All right.
Is it too dark
in here?
Light hurts my eyes.
Cataracts.
No, it's fine.
Well, sit down.
What made you decide
Patrick was innocent now?
Why didn't you
see the truth sooner?
That's why we want
to get the real story,
Mrs. Channing.
That's my husband Louis.
He was a good man.
The good always
die young.
Our daughter Sarah.
She was
Patrick’s mother.
She died when he was 7.
What about
Patrick’s father?
Patrick never knew
his father.
Oh, that's right.
He was illegitimate.
He was not
illegitimate.
He didn't mean anything.
We loved him
very much...
Especially Louis.
Oh, I’m just
talking on.
Where was
Patrick’s room?
Why?
We'd like to see
another side of Patrick.
I guess it would be
all right.
What could it hurt?
I don't care
what anybody says.
He was a happy child.
You tell them.
Tell the world...
What a good boy he was.
A murderer?
That's just nonsense.
He was always so quiet
and considerate.
Oh, he came in here
at night.
He was drunk.
Mommy!
No, grandpa, no!
Grammy!
Grammy, you have
to make him stop!
Help us!
Patrick.
What's he doing?
Not me.
It's not me.
It's my mommy.
Patrick,
is he hurting her?
Grandpa,
don't touch her!
I want you to leave now!
You were there,
weren't you?
You saw it happen.
You let it happen.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
You let him molest
his own daughter?
Patrick never
knew his father?
I think he did.
It was his grandfather,
wasn't it?
Wasn't it?
I know who you are.
You're not a reporter.
You're that cop!
You're a killer!
A killer!
You're
the real murderer!
Eternal punishment
will be yours!
Burn in hell!
Tess!
Tess?
What's down there?
What do you see?
Hey!
Hey, you!
What the hell do you
think you're doing?
Homicide investigation.
Get that out of my face.
I don't care
who the hell you are.
Can't stay down here.
It's unsafe.
Why? What is this place?
Part of the city's
old water system.
Got shut down
After major earthquake
damage in '71.
Hey. Don't touch that.
Those things still work.
It'll come flooding in.
Kid got drowned
down here
A couple of years ago.
That's why these things
were blocked off.
Channing used
to come down here,
Didn't he?
Hey, that was before me.
Come on, you guys.
We gotta leave.
He's mad
that we're here.
This is his place.
It's the only place
he ever felt safe.
He's...he's
laughing at us.
He's going to kill
again and again.
I never thought
you'd go this far,
Marguerite.
People came to me
for help.
I turned them away.
I can't do that
anymore.
But that doesn't excuse
The theft of a sacred
church icon.
Is it theft to use this
for its real purpose?
I believe Satan has granted
one of his disciples
The first power.
Resurrection?
Marguerite.
I’ll pray for you.
We have to hurry.
I don't know who,
But he's going to kill
someone else close to you.
Did you see where?
It's an area I recognize.
It's off
the Santa Monica freeway.
Attention, all units.
Officer needs assistance.
2130 Julian, near alameda.
Attention, all units.
Only a few blocks
from here.
3-Lincoln-43.
I'm on it.
Hold on.
Stay here.
Attention, all units.
Officer needs assistance.
2130 Julian.
You know
which officer needs help,
Don't you, sweet cakes?
It's Logan.
Aah!
I thought I told you
to stay in the car.
Logan, he's here.
Channing.
I heard him
on the radio.
You what?
Piggy, piggy.
Over here.
This way.
Come on. Check it out,
buddy boy.
Logan?
You're holding it
upside down.
You can't go on killing
forever, Patrick.
You want to bet?
Aah!
Hey, asshole.
Are you trying
to tell me
That grimes tried
to kill you?
What do you think, al,
I dragged him up there
And dropped him on
that spike for nothing?
All right.
Yeah, he was a drunk
and a total prick,
But he was also
a lieutenant in the LAPD,
And I do not believe...
And I do not believe
That he suddenly
went fucking insane
Or was secretly a member
of some fucking cult.
Sir,
chief is here.
Yeah, yeah!
I’ll be there.
You gotta give me
some more time, al.
Ok, but get that fucking girl
and get out of here,
And you don't talk to anybody.
You understand me?
Go out the back way.
Maid's day off.
What are we gonna do?
A buddy
on the bomb squad
Gave me this stuff
for a rainy day.
Channing can't do
anything to us
Without using
somebody's body.
So everyone he sends
at us,
We're gonna send
right back.
That's great.
What are we gonna do,
blow up the whole city?
What do you want me
to say?
Tess, every time
you kill the fucker,
He bounces
into somebody else!
I'm sorry.
What about grimes?
How'd he get into him?
You said grimes
was an alcoholic.
And people like that
and junkies,
They have less of a hold
on reality,
So they're vulnerable
to him.
Oh, terrific.
That narrows it down
to half of L.A.
Logan, I don't know
how to stop him.
He...he just keeps getting
stronger and stronger and...
Oh, Logan,
what are we doing?
This is crazy.
It's probably just
my old refrigerator.
Russell!
What?
What is it?
The bag lady,
She was outside
the window.
Tess, there's
nothing out...
Aah!
Don't you think
I look pretty, Logan?
Not nice to hit a lady.
Whee!
Hi, cutie.
Oh, good.
A game.
Hide-And-Seek.
I'm it.
I’ll count to 10.
1...
2...
3...
Where are we going,
Logan?
There's nowhere to go.
Hi, Logan.
Did ya miss me?
Give me a kiss.
Whee!
Come on. Pucker up.
Aah!
Whoo-Ee! This is fun!
Whee!
Whoo-Hoo!
Ooh, look!
There's a big truck.
Tess!
Tess.
Open up!
You want to hide out
from the rest of the world
In this little rat hole,
I don't give a damn.
But he's taken Tess,
and I’m not leaving here
Until you tell me
how to find her.
You don't have any idea
what you'll be facing.
I don't care.
If it's not too late,
He will have taken her
to the dark place
Where he performed
his rituals.
I know where that is.
Tess felt it.
How do I stop him?
It's not
just stopping him.
It's stopping a being
who has the first power.
There are 3 powers
That can be bestowed
by god or Satan.
The third power
is the ability
To take over
another person's body.
Your friend the psychic
has the second power,
The gift of knowing
the future.
The first power
is resurrection.
Immortality.
Look, sister,
I don't understand
these things.
All I know is that
I have to help her.
There's just one way...
Through the only soul
in history
Who had all 3 powers.
Aah!
Bitch!
Ha ha ha.
En nomini patri,
et matri
Et spiritus sancti.
Are you all right,
sister?
Yes.
Logan.
Hurry.
We have to get
out of here.
We have to hurry.
He's still here.
I feel it.
Sister marguerite!
Keep going.
Sister.
Take my hand.
Gee, thanks, Russ.
Let her go, Patrick.
So soon?
I just got here.
Come out and face me,
you son of a bitch.
Don't hide behind her.
Don't you know
that cursing is a sin?
You won't shoot a nun.
Not a good little
catholic boy like you.
Sister.
Oh, I’m afraid
she's not here.
Keep fighting him,
marguerite.
You can beat him.
Don't give up.
He isn't powerful.
He's just a scared
little boy
Who used to run
and hide in the dark.
You're pathetic, Logan.
Tell me something,
Patrick.
It's just
a wild guess...
But I bet the first
one you killed
Was your
grandfather.
Or should I say
your father?
Shut up!
You didn't know
I knew that,
Did you, Patrick?
You had to watch him,
didn't you?
That was it.
Shut up, Logan!
You can beat him,
marguerite.
It's just you and me,
buddy boy.
Aah!
Logan!
Time for your acid bath.
Aah!
Freeze!
Drop the knife!
No. Please.
Ohh!
Aah!
Russell.
Please come back to me.
Aah! Aah! Aah! Aah!
See you around, buddy boy.
Watch Movies, TV Series & Live Sports
www.admitme.app