Look at the birdie---look at the tree
My girls are the prettiest
known to the county
That's all
Mr. Durin, you've made us all immortal
Young ladies and gentlemen---
Now, young ladies and gentlemen---
alright, you cloud-headed
You've still 2 weeks before graduation
Let me remind you
Mr. Durin's picture taking is completed
You prepare yourself to Mr. Durin here
some time this week
an individual photograph
to appear in the Academy Album
Miss Kader---why are you standing there
as if transfixed?
ls it because you've left your books
in the study at the expense of
your splendid youth and innocence
or is it because you've already entered
into the miserable Harvard womanhood
and beat with them?
Alright, stop all of that
or stop blushing
Johnny.
He's not here
0h, you mustn't see me hiding
Hide what?
Happy graduation,Johnny.
Thank you
Happy graduation to you
l guess we had the same idea
lsn't that nice?
We think the same thing
lsn't that crazy?
0pen your present, Johnny
lt's all about Raintree County
lt's illustrated with colored maps---
statistics and history---
and place adventures
lt's wonderful---just wonderful
Look---prominent citizens of
Raintree County
There're over hundred of them
Johnny, someday your name will be
the first on that list
Naturally
0pen yours, come on
Well, l think you'll like it---
it weighs 6 lbs
0h, l think Lord Byron was the most
fascinating man ever lived
He seemed so much in need of
a good woman to love and love him
He never really found one
Yes---
There's a photograph inside---
l wrote something on the back of it
Johnny, it's beautiful
You know what l think?
l think someday you're going to be
a great writer
lt's just beautiful
l've never heard such nonsense
wasting 3 days write this
What's this---a speech?
lt's not nonsense
lt's an honor to be valid  Victoria
lt goes to the student ranking first
in scholarship
You know so much about it
What did you ever valid---validate---
whatever it's called?
Pap is valid Victoria for the whole
Raintree County
Did you know that, Mom?
Your father?
Preaching a  sermon to the most
undesirable element
Waste the elegance there is in
a lot of ground
It's the undesirable element which we desire---
You object the Pap's  elevating spiritual
welfare the people?
What about my spiritual welfare?
Why can't we get an inside pump?
Yeah, Pap---what about an inside pump?
That's not a joke
What ever did learned you
at that school?
You learn a cup of beer?
Your mother has beaty confused
with Heidelberg
You learn to smoke  tobacco?
Like a chimney
Huh, your father like that .....ever here
his sermon on the evils of tobacco
and with the regular pond some do it chew
and some do it smoke
But some end up their nose do poke
l do all three the same time
You learned anything else?
l learn my mother is a fraud and
what she says is hateful
that the way she says it
You never amount anything like that
Well, he ought to amount to something
He's related to one of the greatest
writers in the English language
Who's that?
Thomas Carlyle, that's who.
l think you're old enough to know that....
Joe, stop that foolishness
Well, l always thought that one day
be a great man in the family
Great man?
ls a great man more good to get a job
of farm this land
Why ever was l cursed with such a burden?
0h---which reminds me
How are you and Nell getting along?
Nell is a fine girl and she is---
Well, she's Raintree County
That means a lot of people like us,
people with roots
A man should not only marry his beloved
He should marry his region
A good wife is a good start,
taught greatness
Pap, define greatness
Greatness?
Well, a great man is one
who does good for others and
I guess in that way your father qualifies.
Greatness?
Ha!
lf that great philosopher Socrates
used living today,
lf he were used to sit on a crack
chewing tobacco---
that was America,that's the greatness
Do l shock you?
How can l shock such unenlightened
cloud heads?
Are you stunned, Mrs. Lydia Gray?
0h, stop looking at me, child
With those big brown cow eyes round milk
like wax in the flame
Yeah
Do l shock you, Miss Nell Kader?
Not as much as you like to
0h, there must be somebody  l shoked
How about you, Johnny Seanacy?
l....relish it
You don't shock me
if you don't want shocking
Thanks, my boy
Now, about greatness.
We Americans measure greatness
in simple terms---in terms of money
We're always hunting with a tree of life
whose root is pure gold---
You have beautiful chest-light color
hair, my dear
But, there's another tree
not of gold, but of fulfillment---
whose flower is accomplishment
and its fruit is love
Most ways,
the ways of pleasantness
and most paths all lead to peace
Find that tree and
you'll find greatness
ln every land, every language poems of
some of this tree
And we in lndiana have our
own mythe about it
It's the tree from which our county
takes its name
0ne day a ragged preacher ,was
wandering on the shore of the lake
in the middle of the county
That preacher was a man you all know,
Johnny Appleseed who spent his life
traveling to the pioneer West
planting apple seeds in the wilderness
Among these thousands of seeds
there was one that ragged preacher cherised
Not an appleseed, an exotic seed from China,
the seed of a golden raintree.
The preacher searched the tiny earth place,
the one place
Well, this one seed by taking root,
blandished
Someone in this county found
that place
But where that raintree was planting?
Nobody knows
Professor, how could such a tree grow on
seeing in the county?
There's a great swamp by the Paradise Lake
There perhaps stands the tree
lts sacred tonic trunk towering up
in the  drawning silence
smacks deep in the middle of the county
Find that tree, boy,
and you'll learn
the secret of life itself
Find it and become the hero of
Raintree County
Do you really think it there?
Why don't you have a real good see
for yourself?
Professor, you still haven't answered
the question
Do you really think it there?
lt's there ,alright
lt's there....
But the sacred fire ready to be blacked
But if you look for it
Be sure you'll find it
What happens if you pursued
the raintree and don't find it?
You see before you a seeker
who didn't find
None of the human creature as the pitiable and
harmless creature you'll be hold in vain
Alright, human.....the show is over
Now, disappear...all of you, like phantoms
Attention, now easily slip away
Mrs. Gray, it's my time with you, huh?
Nell, let's you and l go to find
the raintree.
Professor said looking for the raintree
is appearless business.
It can't be  so
So even dressed for it?
Are you serious?
Certainly l am ---come on
We mind it---find it
Johnny, not now
Why?
You scared?
Ah---is he fooling?
Look at him
What's up because of the tale
told by that idiot---
that expert in that calculated sanity?
Are you coming?
In the bad swamp,just because
the Professor put a barge on you about going
about the raintree?
Would you take care of this for me?
lf you mind l take care this for you?
You can go right ahead, sprout
Sure, Johnny,go right ahead
Huh, don't hurry back, sprout
l hate when a thing like this happens
l never know how it happens
Yeah,it's a whip of shame
Well, Sir, but is it Johnny Seanacy?
More like Johnny Appleseed
Ha,where have you been, sprout?
l'm walking
Get in, Johnny,we'll take you home
Come on, Johnny,get in back
Poor boy, you look half drowned
Was nearly all drowned
You mean you look for that....
what's  you call ?
Yes, looking for the what'is you call.
Did you find it?
No
0h, what a whip of shame,sprout.
Poor pitiable harmless creature.
Johnny, tell me what happened
Yes, sprout,tell us all about it, huh?
Well
Boy, we'd like to tell us all about this
I Doubt, when you tell our fellows
about it
Huh?
l mean, say, you got the story straight
l entered the swamp like around here,
see ... around that way
What are you...
0h, excuse me, you're quite right
l entered the swamp this way and the so flows
kind of a line that way
That's how he came over the swamp
‘You find that raintree?' l said
‘No' he said, ‘l nearly drowned'
l figure that tried to cool his head,
But then she says...she says
What did she say?
She said" what a poor pitiable
harmless creature"
What's going on, boys?
0h, hello, Dr. Seanacy.
We were just talking about
your son Johnny
Flash purple
Don't you know that your body is a temple
of the spirit?
And you defile and polluted with
that devil's brew you've there
Why you say so, but---
Why don't you come around to our
next tempest rally,
Come around to take a total afternoon
to pledge
l'll take that pledge right now
0h, no---we want men to take pledge
only when they're sober
But if they're sober, what's the sense
having the pledge taken place?
Wait, man---l want to testify that
l hanen't been drunk for 2 weeks
l drunk beer, wine and most of them
with all friends
l'm drunk here now this minute
l can't find a man who can drink
as much as l have walked straight and
l can still foot any man in this county
Thank you now if you just.....
mark a day and a hit town
Stand at any corner and listen to the
jumper, the local anthropoid
Steady...
l had hoped that this subject under discussion
was sufficiently elevated to engage my interest
However---
Professor, we were just talking about
your most promising student,
Speak of angels and hear their wings
Hm ,not that promising  student
Ah, Mr. Gray and his charming wife
How in the entire world of cross ability
did that chilly January win
such a blithesome May?
That reminds me....
Do you know the story about the old
judge who married a girl 18 ?
Sure, will yoy excuse me
Ha---
0h, Pap---
Wow, here comes the hero of
Raintree County
l guess he'll go again for the gold raintree
Ha---
Bob has been shooting his big fat mouth
again
Yes,if you really want to be the hero
in Raintree County, all you gonna do
ls play the Flash Burgins
for the bare-foot race
Flash Burgins?
So you're Johnny Seanacy
Could be, who wants to know?
Do you hear that boys?
Should l tell this child here who l am?
Why don't you tell him, Flash?
Son, it gives me great peculiar satisfaction
and relegation to introduce to you and
these handsome and intelligent dummy that
l'm a gentleman
who's better known as Flash Burgins,
fastest runner in Raintree County
Never heard of who is he.
Listen, child, it's me
l certify most of the runners in the
north and the south
before they're qualified for the
Games
l'm half  horse and half the asshole
in their spare time
l buzz the more skulls and rag more campus
and chase more ladies---
That's the true
And there's a fine jump this year
Now little boy like
stand by and stone watch
Now who are you?
l'm Johnny Seanacy and
l can outrun any mule in the county
Come on, lad---what are you waiting for?
l race you right now
Alright
Race,
How about the church over there,
alright?
Right, any place you say
0n your march---1 ---2---
Stop it
What's wrong?
Put your coat on, Johnny
What for?
They're not racing
This man Burgins here is afraid to run
you in regular official
because he's frightened of
losing money.
Here's the hat on somebody
l give you 2 to 1
You're just talking,
you know no one here will met you
lf someone came up here with hard coin
you'll try to..... loud
Try me and see
There is gold?
My yarn is type as a teacher---
a molder for the young mind
15 dollars!
This is not much, but it's the mind
l mold
l'll cover, me and the side kick
l'll postpone it to July 4
l'll take a bite of that myself
Strange, Johnny, but this is a sure win
See you in the race time, Johnny,
and l promise not to beat you for a while
Until then we'll see
Why did you do a thing like that?
Well.
Excuse me
lt's been 5 years since anyone laid
a bet against Flash Burgins
Now, if you could beat Flash, we'd clear
the biggest part of money
ever waged in Raintree County
Fine.
What happens if l don't win and you
lose all your money?
My dear boy, l've certain well-laid plans for
the summer which at the moment l'm  limited
to spread, not even to you,
dear boy
My plans called for a certain....
concentration of capital
l don't know, Professor,
sometimes you worry me
What are you up to?
Not more than 20 ways of skating a cat,
l guess l can
Now, you relax for the athletic orgies
ahead
You're going to win a race
You're going to be the hero of
Raintree County
l 've got to go.
And the beautiful girl
with an ;olive wreath will put a  crown
on your sun-colored lucks
Gonna be fine, don't move
Here we go
Look at the birdie---look at the tree
My girls are the prettiest
known to the county
Alright, you can relax
Thank you very much
0h
0h, it's you
Alright, you're next
0h, yeah, sure.
Stand over there please
Now stand properly still
Hurry, Siona
Sure
0h, put this gown on
Let me help you
Look at the camera please
Please look pleasant
Here we go
Look at the birdie---look at the tree
My girls are the prettiest
known to the county
That's it
That's all?
Huh, how long it's supposed before---
l mean l was just wondering
how many days before l can...
Maybe 2 or 3 days
2 or 3 days?
0h, that's fine---
Ah, l'll see you in 2 or 3 days
Wait for me
0h, l didn't mean to scream
l'm afraid you'll find me
very unlady obviously
l like unladies
l saw you down the street get ready to run,
what happened?
Well,postponed to 4th of July
You're a fast runner?
Pretty fast
l'm a pretty fast runner myself
Well, how about a race some time?
You don't believe me, do you?
You'll be surprised how fast l can run
l'm as good as you can
You're Johnny Seanacy?
Say that again
Johnny Seanacy,
l found out from the photographer
Professor
Boy,you're definitely ready to graduate
l was never so embarrassed
Why?
Because l screamed
l enjoyed it
This is where l live
You live here?
Hm ---
Come on, Siona,you slow as a swan
l'll be saying goodbye now
You live by yourself?
l have the 2 nigger girls to do the work
l love this house
l just opened it up again
My Dad loved it too
He was Senator Drake , Louisiana and
New 0rleans
Some people thought he could be
president
l mean President of the United States
We had....that is we had before Daddy died,
The plantation in New 0rleans
We had another one outside Savannah.
When my aunt died last year,
l inherited this place
My name is Susana
Johnny, you want to say something?
0h, no.
You're cute....Johnny Seanacy
That 4th of July race, what happens
when you win?
Well, according to a friend of mine,
lf l win, a beautiful girl will place
a wreath of oak leaves
on my sun-colored lucks
l like to be that girl
Maybe it can be arranged
0h, it can be arranged alright---
l'll arrange it
You know l think l'm going to take
my picture too
There's always nice surprise.
Huh, what did l say?
Nothing, Galwood,
that was made for Johnny
0h
Johnny
Thank you, Ed
Nell
Ah, Johnny, there you're---
l'm looking all over for you
How are you feeling?
Nervous
What you need is calm your nerve
over some acting juicy
Good luck, Johnny.
l got a payback on you
Thank you,l'll do my best
How about a little drink?
0h, l used to lemonade
Lemonade?
Lemonade is something
that gives you ulcer
What l mean was how about a little
drum  of Bourbon
Bourbon,me?
Now, don't get excited,
all l mean was just...
Even the present President would agree
the whole time l put it in, Jack
A draw.
God bless you
How about a little drink?
This old horse
he doesn't think
l should touch a draught
Just to be sociable
Well, l'll give if you both drink
alright
Splendid
l've never had a drink in my life
What's going to happen if l come out here..
Son, it'd be good for you to turn up
those muscles that's give you extra---
Forget about it, Professor
l forgot this boy can never being win yet---
Burgins, l'll match you drink for drink
0h, come on
Let's be sociable
What will  be, boy?
You name it and l ll drink.
Ah, what to be got?
How about a little Bourbon?
There's a couple of bottles right
out of the steer, a bottle for each boy
Ah, just a minute.
let's have those drinks
poured from the same bottle
Why?
l just don't want any trick monkey do
around here
What are you
we just have a bottle for each
They'll drink from the same bottle
Wow, you don't mean to say---
Kid me a fool, Professor
That's a new situation that you may do yourself
May l---?
Professor, l don't trust you---
you got sneaky eyes
lt's tea, cold tea
And you must've thought it
really a good thing
I'll fill it right up
Alright, man
New, let's get started
Johnny
There's nothing to it---nothing to it
Come on, just fill the glasses
Johnny, you're unable---
How do you feel now?
l feel fine
0h, that's enough
Gentlemen, this boy is not used to
strong alcohol
Just to be sociable
Professor, don't worry about me
There's nothing to it, really
Stand back, give the boy a chance
Good work to Jack,alright to youth
Now gentlemen, stand back,
give me room
How you like that?
l tell you l've got another trick
l want to show you
Watch this---give me a hand
Alright, boys, watch this
That's enough,dry him off
That's only God would choose
He's out there now,
laughing to beat the kid
How dare you play a trick like this
on your best friends?
And poor Johnny here who never drinks
in his life
0h, he'd have been killed Flash
Flash is there hours ago
Yelling for action
You'd better get Johnny out there
Johnny, this is it---are you ready?
Yes, let's go, I am ready
0h, l'd better put on my pants
Hello, boys, help yourself
When l want a noice, you gonna be set
by hower like this
l wonder a cannon Johnny can hear it
lt'd be 1 , 2, 3 and bang
Now remember, Johnny
l got 100 dollars bet on you, 100 dollars---
Good luck
Where's it?
ls that we end up?
Yeah
How about the girls down there?
You think too close?
They'll kill themselves
0nce again, boys
Alright---quiet everybody
0n your march---1 ---2---3
Who won---?
We've done it---we won 250 dollars
To me is 150
Where's Flash?
The king is dead,long live the king
Johnny
Nice to see you around again.
Quiet voice
You've beautifully done it
Johnny Seanacy, allow me to present
to you on behalf of all these people
Present this wreath to the---
victory belongs to this boy
What about that race you and l
going to run?
l wouldn't have a chance
0h
You, dear boy, are a wishfully
pagan spirit
And you're poet of finance
Today is the day of high hopes and
fair promise
Ah, now wonder worker of the age
Professor, you've enough zidar
Hm, not enough, l gonna catch up with him
l've to protect my leagues
Why don't you run away and play with
this charming ambassador's
in the land of mints and magnolia?
Let's go swimming, come on
What?
You're sick of that think
But you can think anything
Ah, life...liberty and the pursuit
of happiness
0h, l gonna hate to leave here
Leave---when are you leaving?
Tomorrow, l'm going back to New 0rleans
You can't stay for a while?
0h, you're sweet
But you can come to visit me some time
You'd love this house.
You have to go?
Well, l only came up here to resettle
the house
l was going to sell it,
but l think l'll hold it for a while
When you'll be back?
l don't know,maybe never
Tell me about the raintree
Where did you hear about that?
Do you think you'll never find it?
You don't think it's a joke?
No, l believe it
l'll be looking for the raintree always
Supposing you do find it,
0h, it opens all locks,
It heals all wounds
Yes,maybe l'll never see you again
Nell
lt's silly,you've been running away
from me for weeks
Why don't you talk to me?
You weren't so anxious to talk to me
when that girl was in town
What do you mean?
Are you mad just because l saw her
a couple of times
A couple of times?
Huh, did you like that book of poetry
l gave you?
Yeah
No, Byron was immoral,
he was a libertine
He was a good writer
l think being a good man is
far more important
Maybe a writer has a lot of experience
0h, so that's it,so that's what you're
doing with Susana
Johnny Seanacy, the Byron
of Raintree County
That's right, l'm a genius
Maybe someday l'll write
About what?
About the sudden baths l've known?
No, l think l'll write about
Raintree County
About the lndians
when they first came here...
About Johnny Appleseed and the raintree
The raintree?
That's another thing, Johnny
That day you went chasing the raintree
l was waiting for you
l didn't know where you had gone,
but l knew that swamp
l'm sorry, l guess l didn't realize
You just didn't realize anything
Johnny, to some people you're a man
of great importance
Your exact location is of intense
concern to---to some people
l'd better go, Johnny
Not yet
Johnny
Please
Johnny, l'd better go
lt's getting late,we'd better go
0h, no,you don't
Who's that?
Why don't you move up here and
find out?
So it was you
Who did you think it was?
You know anything about this?
You got anything to do with this?
Doing with that?
With the Professor, he ran off with Lady Gray
lf he is still in the county, he'll get
a chance out of thousand to get not alive
We've got hundred men looking for her
Nobody can come to this county and
run off with another man's wife
lt occurs to me, young man, that you're
a friend of this
This man's
But a thing like this---
there're no nobbles
Whose side are you on?
l'm taking Nell home
No, l'll see you tomorrow
Alright, young man,l'm still waiting
for your answer
You'll get yourself a long wait,
l'm going home
Hello, Johnny
And what have you been up to?
Where's Lydia?
Wonderful woman---l did try cut her
away from her husband
That's the day you won your race
Where's she?
She had missed the train
at the 3-mile junction
0r we'd have been hundred miles away
by now
As we got back to the buggy, 3 men
with guns marched up to the platform
l grasped the situation once there
But that was only the beginning
0n the way back, the first man l met
asked if l heard about the man
who ran off with a man's wife
l'm a stranger here myself, l said
0n the road, l met a troop of camions
carrying for the station---
Where's Lydia?
She's home right now
waiting for Mr. Gray
l took her straight back
As for myself, l took off
like a street beggar
l guess you think l'm a bit a scoundrel,
right, Johnny?
l don't know---l don't know what l think
Don't think too badly on me
l suppose the heroic thing to be done
would be to stick around and
let the outraged husband discharge
his fury with a shotgun
But l hate that Sanctimonious warthog
too much to give him the satisfaction
Besides, l am scared
One thing, Johnny
Nothing happened, absolutely nothing
And that's the end just for all
lf there's any phantom to be hanged---
the county would say
there might be me and some truth
could be in it
Alright
l just managed the whole thing badly
Did you?
Come on
Where are we going?
You 've got to get out of the county
Well, good idea,it occurred to me
Johnny, why not both of us?
Study my example,
get out of Raintree County,
Someone would get you with a shotgun
Not me,you
l guess you're right
(ln French) Apres vous la delige
There he is
Come on
Get on the train
Goodbye, dear boy
Go on for great better things
Get on the train
We want him
Where you've been, Mr. Gray?
Your wife has been home
for the past 12 hours
Nothing happened,absolutely nothing
He's a liar
You want to shoot me and later find out
he was right?
What are you afraid of?
You want him ,you take him
l'm going home
You get out of my way, boy
or l'll cut your eyes out
Goodbye, dear friend
Remember me as a man who loves
Raintree County---
but just happens to lose
most of the people in it
Johnny
Johnny, l had to come back,
l'm going to have a baby
Johnny, this letter was left
on the door step, it's for you
0h, thank you
Johnny, this marriage you announced
Sit down
l can't honestly say l'm entirely
approved of the precipity
But, under the circumstances necessary
haste with which you've gone into it
l know,l certainly understand
Anyway, l think you're doing
the manly thing
l hope the young lady is all that she appears
what she appears to be
Judge not the ,beyond the judge.
l know, Sir
Marry her, son,and be happy
Thank you
You need any money?
l don't know...l don't think so right now
0h, there was a letter
came for you
l.... have it here
0f course
Hello
Hello, Johnny
l got your letter
Johnny, as one for whom you want for perfection,
l just want to say good luck
and wish you all the happiness
in the world
And the poem you wrote for me and
the picture you gave me---
l just feel that l want to return it
l thought maybe you want it now
l really did not want to get that out
lt's just that, everything has changed
and l don't mean anything to you
We don't mean anything
to each other anymore
Nell---l'm sorry
lt's not your fault, Johnny---
everybody knows that
lt was the 4th of July
You drank all that whisky and
you went out to the lake
No, l am responsible,nobody else
That's so much like you, Johnny
Why do you have so much conscience?
Maybe that's why l love you
Johnny, l love you so much
Did that l wish l didn't---l wish ...
The words of Lord Byron in that book
you gave me
‘Forever love and before ever..-'
Still forever---
l wish you well
You're right, Mrs. Seanacy
l like the river.....it even smells good
l really don't understand it
Would you smell mouse like it too?
Now, there's something l don't understand
All you've to do is go south once and
you'll love it
Well, a north Yanky to the south
is not too easy to understand
You ever read ?
?
l've married an abolitionist, have l?
That's skeleton in my classic
Now, you mustn't joke about it
Are they friendly?
Anyway, the worst thing is to be
an abolitionist
Like what?
That cabin Negro blooded
Just one little tiny drop in the person
all Negro
They just can't tell either
ls it gonna be room for 2 of us?
lt's only sort of a hobby---
l'm taking with me wherever l go
This is Jimmy---l've had it the longest
Where did you get him?
He needs a bath
0h, Johnny, forgive my foolishness
0h, l do love you so
When l'm with you, l feel like nothing
Can happen to me as long as l have you
You won't have let anything happen to me
Will you, Johnny?
Enjoy yourself, Johnny?
Very much
Then what do you think about
the ever-glooming south?
As l said, l love it---l do
That sounds general, isn't it?
What you really think of it?
Well, Sir,l think so highly of it
l worry only by this talk
of sucession
Sucession?
Remember, young man
The Union belongs to those who keep
breath in this cabinet
What cousin Sam means, Johnny,
if sucession comes---
It's the north that should suceed
Hear him say---
Sam, one thing you must understand
Johnny is a poet
It's taking him  2 months to discover
Therefore, he loves the south
l'm not so sure he proves it
That's because he's a moralist
You won't get straight answers from him
He'll draw up opinions for another day
He's also a dreamer
a seeker for the
meaning of life with capital letters
Sir, your search is in the end
Stay here with us and help us
build our dream
We , in the south, dream
Of a great republic on this soil of merit
with it's pretty homes and as well
as the most beautiful women
0h, Sam ,you're wonderful
You shelf like some golden pitfalls
Cousin Sam ,Johnny doesn't like slavery
Is Johnny like the wage to slavery
at the north?
Johnny doesn't like misery anywhere
North or south
Here comes misery now---my wife
We're talking about the north, my dear---
slaves in the north---
Sam, you're boring---
l'll borrow your husband for a while
Excuse me
Don't look so serious
Here old man can only play
his dream of glory
lt's not that, l'm counting
Cousin Johnny, you ever in love?
Huh?
l mean---were you ever really---in love?
Cousin dear, l'm in love
You know l love the way you say that
You did such a noble sound
in your precious accent
Frankly, Johnny, cousin Susana just
isn't the right type for you
You're an attractive young man
0h, Susana, why disposed you
and didn't marry down here?
l guess supposing down here  know
too much about her
Don't you hear me?
You've borrowed my husband long enough,
cousin Barbara,
l reclaim him
0f course
lt must've been beautiful
0h, it was, Johnny
lt was all white when
l was a little girl
The marble room was right above over there
Johnny, our neggars made these bricks
by hands
The furniture came from France
lt was so beautiful
These tower columns shed the veranda
l used to play there when it rained
The garden was so lovely cool
with roses and lilies
How this fire started?
No one knows
Really?
That were my Daddy and Mama buried
l was lucky to get out alive
l slept next to Henrietta at this room
She was burnt too
Who was Henrietta?
She was my dearest friend,
she was a great lady
How old were you?
Three, maybe four.
And you could remember it all?
Yes.....no, l don't know
l can quite  remember what l exactly saw
l was told later on
0h
What's the matter?
There used to be a little cabin
right over there
l guess it's gone
This is where they buried her, Johnny
0h, you can't imagine
how lovely she was
She took care of me,
she was a great lady
l'm not ashamed to say ,
cause she was a Negro
0ne of these slaves?
0h, no---she came from Cuba
That was where l was born...Havana
Daddy was there for several years
and then came back with us
lt's so funny to think of her now
Think of her lying down there, that is
if she's lying down there
What do you mean
‘if she's lying down there ?
lt's a short of family scandal
Some people say the graves were mixed
My aunt said she wasn't sure if it was
her Henrietta sleeping in Mama's grave
l---l don't understand
l love you, Henrietta---l love you
Dear
Johnny, l know you don't understand
She was everything to me
Because of her l was never alone
And now---do you feel that someone
is watching us?
Just nobody here
How do you know?
Johnny, about this....this negro girl
l....l lied to you about it
lt....it never happened
Why did you tell me this?
You asked me about it
Well, you don't think my Mama---
You don't think my Mama would ever
allow me to---
l---l was always with my Mama---
l was always by her side
Why---why she loved me so much
She never allowed me out of her sight
l---l was always with her
Susana---should we go home?
Good evening, l'm looking for Mr. Drake
Come on in, dear
Right in here
Thank you
Bobbie
Johnny, how do you know l was here?
Barbara said you were with Sam ---
she said you were here
Listen---l'd  like to talk to you
Can you wait ?
We drive  home and
we could talk then
No
Let's go in here
Would you excuse us?
Johnny, how about a drink?
Bobbie, what's all about
Susana's family and the fire?
Well, it's just an old family scandal
Johnny---but it's pretty gluesome
You see the day they had trouble to
identify a man in the,
fire but a woman
And the woman was another matter and
one of them was a lady of color
Why you go after that?
l like to know
Well it all began when Susana's mother
....when...you know
l don't know
She went insane
Susana's father gave up everything
to take care of her
At last he gave up his business
to seek her sense
For all they tried she was too far gone
Finally she couldn't be cured at all
lt was in Cuba
That's where he met the other woman
What about the fire?
There had some gringos
2 of the bodies were found together
So?
So it looks like something funny
had been going on
They might've been killed
before the fire
l mean everybody else got up and away
Why didn't they?
That's one of the question of identification---
which woman was that woman?
Which?
There was talks of Susana's father with
the woman who was found being inside
The woman....the woman...
who was found with?
l exaggerated, Johnny
Anyway, the thing was her
it was better the way was as that
0f course, there was a lot of talks---
You know how women talk ,
in this families,
women are worse at most
l don't want to scare you, boy
You need a  quiet life
because you've a beautiful spouse
As you worth of it.
Alright, what happened after the fire?
Well, nothing much
All over the excitement Susana took it down
and disappeared for 2 or 3 days
l forget now
They found of her finally
She was in Henrietta's open cabin
all the time
And Susana had to go up
to her aunt's place in Savvanah
That's all l know about it
Does anybody know?
There's just one person
Who?
You've to wait until she's ready
to tell you
Not Susana?
lt's Susana
Susana was 3 years old
0h, my boy---you think you marry a child
bothersome?
At the time of the fire, my cousin
Susana was 9 years old
Dear, we 've got to get away from here
Alright, Johnny, where should we go?
Could we go to Europe?
No, l like to go back to
Raintree County
But why?
We've plenty of money
Honey, l got to get a job
l got to work
That's why we should be back home
so the two of you could be resting
Johnny, l haven't been very honest
with you
You haven't?
When l told you l was going to have
a baby, l lied
l'm not going to have a baby
l lied because l wanted you more than
anything l ever wanted in my life
Because l---somehow l just---
0h, l don't know
Darling, one thing you must know
l love you very much
You'd never leave me, will you,
Johnny?
l'll never leave you
l love you, let's go home
0h, yes.... yes,Johnny
Oh ,Miss Nell Kader,shame on you
By here my husband and l have been
home settled you not be seeing this time
And you have yet to call on us
where is  your preeding?
l leave the breeding to you
How do you like here in the booze of the
Raintree County?
Well, l hardly feel this town
so small anymore
Whatever you do for amusing?
l take walks
How really?
You tell me who you walk with
l'm interested in all aspects
of real life
You won't be interested in me,
l walk alone
l just don't understand that.
You're still young, you know---
and pretty as a swan
Are you interested in a man, honey?
Perhaps
Well, good, l just hoped is not
a school teacher,
Like Johnny
You know, Miss Kader
a school teacher
has almost remote little habits
like read and write and mess all around
Anyway, l did want you to know
you're always welcome
Any friend of my husband's is
a friend of mine
And Johnny always did tell me
all his best friends in Raintree County
You're the first,bye...bye
Hello, Johnny
0h, where you pop up from?
No place special
Galwood asked me to marry him
Mr. Seanacy
Hello
He's going to politics,
what do you think, Johnny?
l mean you're always
being my best friend
l think Galwood will make
a fine politician
You know that's not what l mean
Mr. Seanacy, a few months in your class
l learned more about poetry and
politics and life and....
than l've all the time going to school
The students seem to enjoy
creeping up on me
They're all in love with you
Teachers get falling in love with
it's an occupation hazard.
Me was different,
l fell in love with the student
So did l
All l thought was a hopeless mistake,
wasn't it?
She tricked you into marriage, Johnny---
she wasn't pregnant
lt's one thing people around here
can't do without deny
l'm sorry, Johnny---l'm so ugly
No, Susana and l are going to have
a baby ,in April
l want you to know you're my
best friend
Well, l'm very happy for both of you,
until then, goodbye
How do you feel?
0h, l've a troubled sleeping  again....
that dream,
Why you 're up so early?
Wasn't school or election day?
l 've got to vote
You were out so late last night,
speechify....the Mr. Lincoln
l wasn't the only one up there
The speechify
Thank God Jones delivered it
a little scum wider
You want to read it?
Come in
Morning---Mr. and Mrs. Seanacy
Good morning, Siona
Galwood Vs Jones---
l always wonder what's the beast for
l give you one guess
Galwood Vs Jones---
Youngest candidate ever to seek office
in lndiana State Legislature last night
rounded up his program campaign
in 3-mile junction
With the enthusiastic denunciation of
teachers who used the schools as a platform
to corrupt the youth of
Raintree County
Those who stand on the slavery question
is most violent
Jones declared that the best look to
their papacy is only the ship
A certain young teacher who instructs
the young, in a flammatory and seditious doctrine
about abolition includes a domestic
arrangement of his home to colored people
The status with respect to those freedoms for
whose protection the abolitionists claim
a monopoly is
Who said who's?
Questionable
Can you guess who's talking about?
But l think he's right
l think politics like charity
should begin at home
That's exactly what l intend to begin
What about Daisy and Siona?
What about them?
Honey, you lied after free those girls
and get rid of them
But they've been with our family
since they were born
They'd be unhappy any place else
l just don't understand you, Johnny---
after beeing insulted me
l just don't see how can you go on
being an abolitionist
Susana, you're not south now---
you can't have your slaves here
Johnny, l wish you wouldn't pick on me---
l don't feel well
Honey, l'm not picking on you
l just don't want slaves in my house
Alright, l wish we could get away
from here
l don't like this place
l just assume limited as a goat
in the hole
What anybody in the south ever do
to hurt you?
You know how nice and sweet they all were
and how much they loved it
l just don't see how you can
support a man like Lincoln.....Lincoln
Why you despised Lincoln so much?
l mean .....that's well-known fact
You must've heard about it
What's about the fact?
l mean the fact that Lincoln has
negro blood in him
You don't believe it?
As Galwood or Jones
Dear, all l ask you get rid of the girls---
pay them wages and do whatever you want
You don't love me...
you never did love me
You hate me because l'm southern
You've been asking questions about me
Dear, do what you want
But if those girls are not free by tonight,
l won't come back to this house