Our story takes you down
this shadowed path...
to a remote and guarded building
in the English Midlands:
Melbridge County Asylum.
Grimly proud of its new military wing...
which barely suffices...
in this autumn of 1918...
to house the shattered minds...
of the war that was to end war.
Now, Mr. And Mrs. Lloyd...
I should warn you
that even if he is your son...
he may not recognize you.
His memory is affected,
and he has trouble with his speech:
The result of shock.
He was picked up by the Germans...
in a shell hole near Arras in 1917...
close to death
and with no means of identification.
When he returned to consciousness
in a German hospital...
he could remember nothing at all
of his past life.
He had no name...
he had no family
with whom he could correspond.
Six months ago, he was exchanged
through Switzerland and sent here.
I sincerely hope he proves to be your son.
I believe that he could be cured...
with patience and care
in normal surroundings.
May we see him now?
Certainly.
Please, Mrs. Lloyd, don't hope too much.
I've seen many disappointments.
Good morning, boys.
This is just an informal visit.
Good morning, Clayton.
Sleeping better? You just keep it up.
Well, now, Trempitt, what's going on?
I thought you and I were friends.
Last time we shook hands.
Don't you remember?
Well, don't bother today
if you don't feel like it.
You can't discourage me.
There. You see, my boy? That's the spirit.
You and I will be going into town
very soon for a glass of beer...
to Melbridge Arms.
Would you like that?
Fine. Won't be long now.
Well, Smith...
you are looking better, really improved.
- Don't you think so, Doctor?
- Very much.
We have some news for you. Interested?
There are some people here
who are very anxious to see you.
Mr. And Mrs. Lloyd.
Lloyd?
The name mean anything to you?
Their son was reported missing in 1917.
At Arras.
Now don't pin your hopes on it.
You may be their son, you may not.
We'll soon know.
My parents.
There. You see, my boy?
You speak well enough when you want to.
It's just a matter of confidence.
You've just got to
get back your confidence.
My father.
Doctor, dress him up a bit
and take him to the reception room.
Very well. Come along, Smith.
Lloyd.
Sit down, old man.
If they are your parents...
They would take me out of here?
That's rather a big if, old man. Sit down.
Lloyd.
- He is not your son, then?
- No.
I'm sincerely sorry.
I told you, my boy, not to count on it.
Out in this weather, Major?
You are a one for a walk, ain't you?
Proper old pea soup this is.
I'm all right, thank you.
Coat's very warm.
I like to walk.
Proper old pea soup.
The war's over! Peace!
There's an armistice!
What is it you want?
Come on, I haven't got all night.
Cigarette.
What sort?
Why, you're from the asylum. You're...
It's all right, dear. You take your time.
Have a nice look around, see.
I'll be back in a jiffy.
You are from the asylum, aren't you?
Yes, but I'm all right, really.
If you have given them the slip,
I wouldn't stay here.
She's gone straight to the phone.
She's telling them to come for you.
Can I help you?
I thought you weren't feeling too fit,
so I followed you.
You don't mind, do you?
You look tired out.
Been walking about for hours?
Well, how about a brandy and soda...
just to pull you together?
I'm gonna have one.
Shall we go over to the home pub?
It's just across the road.
It's not the Ritz, but it's where we all stay
when our show's in town.
It's, you know, friendly.
Come on.
Excuse us, please.
That was Ella. She's our character woman,
and he's our manager.
- Hello, Sam.
- Hello, Paula.
He's a dear, really.
- Hello, Brett.
Have a drink, and the army, too.
- There, you see? You're amongst friends.
- Mind you, he was game, the gunner was.
Halfway through the 10th,
he run into my right hook...
and forgot his name and address.
You don't win fights
with your hands and feet.
You win them with your brains.
That's what brought me to the top.
What's it to be, my dear?
This is on the house.
Thank you, Biffer.
Mine's a Gin and French.
Can I have a brandy for my friend here?
With pleasure, my dear.
Looks as though he could do with it.
Feeling bad?
- No, I...
- He's just tired, that's all.
Not the flu, is it? Got them in the back.
Dying like flies at the hospital.
That's right, cheer him up.
Know any more funny stories?
I was only passing a remark.
It's a free country.
Pass him the free drink.
That'll do him more good.
Well, here it is,
and a drop of good stuff that is.
- Bring anybody back from the grave.
- The grave?
Aren't you a little ray of sunshine tonight?
- Paula. Don't be late.
- No, I won't, Sam.
I've got to get over to the theater.
Goodbye, and thanks for the drinks.
- Shall we go?
- Well, there goes a hero for you.
- He's one of the men what done it.
- Right.
I must get over to the theater.
I've cut it pretty close.
It doesn't seem very friendly, does it,
running away like this?
What are you going to do?
Will you be all right?
- What am I to do with you?
- I'll be all right.
I'm not so sure.
Listen, how'd you like to see the show?
You can sit in my dressing room,
see the stage. No one will bother you.
Then we'll have a chat, shall we?
Just you and I,
and settle what's to be done.
Good? Good, come on.
Sorry to keep you waiting all this time,
but I'm so excited about peace.
I've got one eyebrow halfway up my
forehead and the other behind my left ear.
Just a second. I'll be with you.
Well? How do you like me?
Or don't you?
Good.
Now, talk to me.
Tell me all about yourself.
Why'd you give them the slip up
at the hospital?
You don't like the place?
Surely you ought not to be there.
Come on. Answer me.
Cat got your tongue?
Make an effort.
I'm all right, really.
It's my speech. It's just nerves.
There, you see? You're doing splendidly.
Yes, I wasn't so bad then, was I?
I should say not.
You don't know what a job I have...
as a rule.
I can guess. I heard you up at that shop.
That old witch would scare anybody.
There's another thing.
I've lost my memory.
I don't even know who I am.
You mean...
I know who you are.
You're somebody awfully nice.
What did they call you at that place?
Smith.
It's not my real name.
- What's yours?
- Paula Ridgeway.
That's not my real name, either.
Look here, Smithy. You don't mind
if I call you Smithy, do you?
It can't be good for you up there
among all those poor souls.
You can't be happy.
And how are you ever going to get better
if you're unhappy?
Perhaps I shouldn't be very happy...
anywhere just now.
But, Smithy, the war's over.
Doesn't that mean anything to you?
I'm just silly. Don't take any notice.
It's the day.
It's so splendid for most of us
and so sad for some.
Why did it have to be foggy and wet?
It should have been all sunshine
and golden day.
Never mind, Smithy.
We've met, anyway, haven't we?
Have you no friends,
no parents that you can trace?
Have you tried?
Some people
came to see me at the hospital...
but I wasn't their son.
I'll bet they were disappointed,
weren't they?
Yes, I think so.
I was, too.
I'd have liked to belong to them.
Smithy, you're ruining my makeup.
But how you do chatter.
Yes, I seem to have talked rather a lot.
That's me. I always bring people out.
Much too far, sometimes.
- Ridgeway.
- All right, thank you.
I've got to go and perform now.
Smithy, look...
I'll put your chair outside. Come along.
You can see the front of the stage
from here.
Just sit there and nobody will bother you.
I'll be back in a couple of shakes.
- You'll be all right, will you?
- I'm fine.
Sure?
Your head seems awfully hot.
- Paula. You're on.
- Coming.
I spoke to her father and asked,
"Could I marry Daisy?"
"Certainly you can," he says.
"Certainly. On one condition. "
"Name it!" says I.
Says he, "Get married in the house
and after the ceremony...
"you leave by the back door. "
"Leave by the back door?
Why would we do that?"
He say, "I'm telling you,
you leave by the back door...
"so that the hens
can get the benefit of the rice. "
I love her for herself alone.
She's the bonniest wee lassie
in all Scotland.
As Harry would say...
I knew the minute I seen him,
he had the flu.
Biffer, there's something
I ought to tell you.
- He's from the county asylum.
- No.
But he's all right, really.
He would have been discharged
if he had a home to go to.
You don't think they'll come after him,
do you?
Any busybody comes snooping after him...
I'll give him what I give the gunner.
- Biffer, you're a darling.
- He's a gentlemen, he is.
Liked him the minute
I first clapped eyes on him.
I'm all right.
It's just my speech. I can't remember.
Rest now, Smithy. You mustn't talk.
I'm not like the others.
I'm not like them. I'm all right.
Yes, Smithy, you're all right.
But I can't go back.
If I go back, I'll never come out.
I'll be like the others.
You shan't go back, Smithy.
I won't let you go back.
Rest now.
Rest, Smithy.
Just go to sleep.
Hurry down. Supper's on the table.
The train leaves at 1:00.
I'm all packed. I'll be back in a jiffy.
How did the show go?
Splendidly. The last night.
Glad to get rid of us, I expect.
How did you get on?
I talked to the chambermaid today.
- Had quite a chat with her.
- You did?
Wonderful. What about?
The weather.
You are coming on.
I see you're all packed. That's a good boy.
So am I.
Our train leaves at 1:00.
- Paula.
- Yes, Smithy?
You're sure I can be useful?
Your manager isn't just taking me on...
because you asked him?
Good gracious, you don't know Sam.
He's as hard as nails.
No, you can take my word for it.
The whole thing was his idea.
I can't tell you what it means, Paula.
To be someone again, to be wanted.
It's all your doing.
How you do run on.
There's no stopping you
once you've started.
You just eat your supper.
I'll go down and I'll be up again
in time to fetch you for the train.
Goodbye.
- The usual?
- Please, Biffer.
Sam, he's as pleased as punch.
I wish you could have heard him.
You are an angel.
That's all right, old girl.
It's given him confidence
just knowing that he's wanted.
That's all he needs to get well.
- There you are.
- Thank you, Biffer.
Evening, Mr. W. What's it to be?
Half and half, and rush it, will you?
They've been watching me like hawks...
since I blotted me copybook
Armistice Day.
Why?
One of our loonies slipped off in the fog...
while I was supposed to be
watching the gate.
Got clean away, uniform and all.
No. Really?
But you got him back, didn't you?
Not yet, but we shall.
- What sort of a bloke?
- It's getting late.
Tallish, dark hair, shuffles a bit.
Can't get his words out.
Always thinking something different.
He's not dangerous, I suppose?
There's no saying with loonies.
Quiet as mice for weeks.
Then all of a sudden,
up and after you with an ax.
Sam, I'm going in to supper. You coming?
Just a moment, Paula.
- Ella, coming?
- Coming.
It's time, isn't it? Nearly 12:30.
- Smithy.
- I'm all ready.
Sit down a minute, will you?
There's nothing wrong, is there?
Smithy, I've got to talk to you.
I won't beat about the bush.
Sam won't take you.
Won't take me?
There was a man from the asylum
in the bar just now.
He told everybody about your escape.
Sam feels it's too risky taking you.
I think perhaps he's right.
I think perhaps you should go back
to the asylum...
until you're all well again, and then...
Go back?
It is best, Smithy.
You need care, and you need doctors
that understand your case.
I feel dreadful about it,
but it's for your sake.
Sam wants to help...
but he says I have no right to take you.
He says I'd be risking your sanity.
Your life, perhaps.
You do understand, don't you?
You're not angry with me? You don't think
that I've gone back on you?
It's not that I'm afraid.
It's because I think it's right.
They were all against me, all of them.
They couldn't have made me do it
if I didn't think it was right.
You do know that, Smithy, don't you?
Tell me you understand,
that you're not angry with me.
But tell me. Let me hear you say it.
Speak to me, Smithy.
You could always speak to me.
Wait for me, Smithy.
Come on, Smithy. Get your coat on.
I know I'm right. I know it.
I'm ashamed of myself,
letting them talk me out of it.
Here. Let me help you. We'll have to hurry.
Don't you worry, Smithy.
We can't go with the others...
but we'll find some quiet place
where you can rest and get fit.
Here's your hat. Take your parcels.
Come on.
We'll go by the back door.
I've got to see the Biffer.
Go that way. Don't let anyone see you.
There's a door leading to the alley.
Wait for me outside. I'll only be a minute.
Biffer, here's the money for my bill.
What? Off already?
They want to send Smithy
back to the asylum.
No.
I'm not gonna let him go.
I'm taking him into the country.
Giving up your job?
I'll let you know when we get settled.
- Will you send my trunk on to me?
- You bet, and good luck to you.
Thanks, Biffer.
You're one in a million. Goodbye.
Goodbye. Good luck.
Smithy, what have you done?
- He tried to stop you?
- Yes.
Sam?
I pushed him and he fell.
If they get you now, you're done for.
- I'm no good. Let me alone.
- No. I won't.
- We can't leave him.
- We must.
We'll think later. Come.
But I'm no good. I'd better go back.
That was bad luck, the stationmaster
recognizing me at Melbridge.
They may have wired ahead
to Canford to stop us.
Well, we won't go on to Canford.
We'll get out at Swinton Junction.
From Swinton, we can go into
the west country to Devon or Cornwall.
We'll choose some little country place,
quiet and lovely.
It's the end of the world.
Lonely and lovely.
We'll be safe here, even if...
We'll phone first, and then we'll see.
All right, Mrs. Deventer, he can come
for a couple of hours tomorrow...
and I'll look in on Friday.
- Thank you, Doctor.
- Goodbye.
Goodbye.
- Morning, ma'am.
- Good morning.
Sorry I wasn't down.
- Were you wanting rooms?
- Well, that depends.
- May I use your telephone?
- Certainly. It's in there.
Thank you.
Smithy, come and sit down.
You look worn out.
He does look poorly. The poor dear.
Is this the phone?
Yes. You just picks it up,
turns the handle...
Yes. Thank you.
I want to make a trunk call, please.
Melbridge 4294.
What?
Clevedon 2707.
Hello?
Hello, Paula.
No, he's all right. Come to in a jiffy.
Right as rain, barring a bump on his head.
Big as an apple, it was.
That fellow of yours must have given him
what I gave the gunner.
What? A bump.
Biffer, don't make me laugh.
I'll go into hysterics. What?
He is an angel. So are you.
Do you mind if I rush off now
and tell Smithy? He'll be so happy.
A thousand thanks, darling, and goodbye.
Smithy, it's all right.
Isn't it wonderful? Sam's all right.
Now you have nothing
to worry about, nothing.
Sam's being awfully decent about it.
He says it was just an accident.
An accident?
It's a friend of ours who had a bad fall.
We were terribly worried about him,
but it's all right.
And we would like to stay...
that is, if you can have us.
Well, I've got a nice double front.
Sun comes in all day.
Just the thing for your husband
after the flu.
He's not my husband.
Not yet, I mean.
We're just sort of engaged.
I've got two nice rooms adjoining...
with hot and cold and a view of the lake.
If you'd like to come up.
Smithy, isn't it wonderful?
I'm so thankful. I was terribly worried.
All you have to do is to get well,
and you will get well, won't you...
in this lovely place?
Say it. Let me hear you say it.
- I will.
- That's the spirit.
I had to tell her we were engaged.
You don't mind, do you?
I thought you was behind me.
Don't you want to see the rooms?
I'm sorry. Yes, of course.
We're just coming.
Come on, Smithy.
If I were you, I'd open it.
Smithy, you are a fraud.
I'm simply dying of curiosity.
It's from Liverpool, from that newspaper.
I say. So it is.
"Liverpool Mercury. Managing Editor,
Samuel C. Henson. "
Must be about that article you sent them.
- Yes, I suppose it could be.
- For pity's sake, Smithy, open it.
- It's a check.
- I don't believe it. Let me look.
It's a small check, but it's a check.
Smithy, how wonderful.
- Aren't you terribly happy?
- Yes, I am.
- Means an awful lot.
- Smithy, I'm proud of you.
You didn't know you had an author
on your hands, did you?
Yes, I did. I knew you were good.
I'm really not a bit surprised.
You think I can sell another?
Another and another and another.
Lots of them.
Smithy, I wonder if you were a writer
before you...
- Before the war.
- Yes, I've wondered that, too.
Aren't you terribly curious?
About the past, I mean?
Well, I'd like to know,
but the present's looking up.
Supposing it all
came back to you suddenly...
and it was awfully grand,
with all sorts of wonderful people?
I wouldn't mind a bit.
You might even be married, Smithy.
Who knows?
Nonsense.
- How can you be so sure?
- Well, because...
Paula, I wonder
if I could make a living at writing.
Of course you could.
Make a regular income, be independent.
Why not?
And I'm getting quite good at typewriting.
It's a lot of nerve, but...
I've fallen in love with you.
No, you haven't.
You're just being a gentleman.
No. I'm nothing of the sort.
I'm asking you to marry me...
on a check for two guineas.
Smithy, don't ask me, please.
I might take you up on it.
I'm just that shameless.
Paula.
I've run after you from the very beginning.
You know I have.
I've never let you out of my sight
since I first saw you in that little shop.
- Never do it, Paula.
- What?
Never leave me out of your sight.
Never again.
Smithy, you do mean it?
You do want it? Really?
More than anything else in the world.
My life began with you.
I can't imagine a future without you.
I better say yes quickly
before you change your mind.
It's yes, darling.
Now I can relax.
I'm hungry.
- Smithy.
- What is it?
But, darling, you proposed to me...
and I've accepted you...
What's wrong?
Smithy, do I always
have to take the initiative?
You're supposed to kiss me, darling.
Goodbye.
- I'm so happy for you.
- Goodbye. God bless you both.
Thanks, Vicar. Thanks, Doctor.
Thanks again for all your kindness.
- Here. Take this.
- Doctor, no.
That's all right. Keep it for the christening.
- Goodbye.
I must oil that hinge.
Wait.
- I must cut that back.
- No, darling. It's so pretty.
Home.
- Today, is it, sir?
- I think so.
- Have you got the nurse in?
- Three days ago.
- Pretty trying, this business.
- I know how you feel, sir.
Been through it myself.
- Did your wife suffer much?
- No, nothing to speak of.
But me, crikey.
Got neuralgia, have you?
- I don't think so.
- Lucky.
I had it something cruel with our second.
- What they call synthetic pain.
- Do they?
That's the scientific name for it.
I said I'd never face it again,
but you know how it is.
Here I am with four
and more bad news on the way.
Well, good luck to you, sir.
It's all right, Smith.
She's out of danger now.
It's been a hard fight, but she's made it...
and you have a son.
Come on. Pull yourself together.
She's all right.
Nothing in the world to worry you now.
It's a boy. That's what you wanted.
And eight pounds of him, too.
Don't you want to see her
after all her trouble?
Of course you do.
Good morning.
I've dropped in to register a new subject.
- Name of child?
- We're calling him John, after me.
My wife thinks he's the image of me,
but I don't see it.
Really? And the date?
He has her eyes, blue,
and when he smiles...
he's just like my wife, except for the teeth.
Yes, well, you can't expect everything
all at once.
- What did you say the date was?
- November 6.
- Don't you want his weight?
- No, thank you.
Eight pounds, three and a half ounces.
He's gained an ounce a day since.
- It's remarkable.
- Father's profession?
Writer. In a small way, of course.
Writer and parent. Parent in a big way.
That will be all. Yes. Thank you.
But you can form only
a very inadequate picture of him...
- from what I've given you.
- I'll have to struggle along.
- I'll bring him in one of these days.
- Do that.
Then you can see for yourself.
Do I get a receipt?
You do.
- Thank you very much. I'll bring him in.
- Do that.
Hi, nurse!
Here you are. I don't think I forgot a thing.
- Is he asleep?
- Lf he was, he isn't now.
Wait.
- Did I wake him?
- No.
I brought him a present.
Will he like it? Will he know it's a cat?
- Smithy.
- Yes.
- Come here.
- What?
No, here.
Look, I'm Mrs. Smith.
Do you remember me?
What's so wonderful about that fellow?
He just eats and sleeps.
Much of the time, he's not even friendly.
It would never occur to you
to buy me a present, would it?
Never.
- Smithy.
- They're not very much.
- I adore them, darling.
- They're just the color of your eyes.
You're an awfully nice
color scheme, darling...
and your hair is like a bright new penny.
- Mr. And Mrs. Smith here?
- Yes.
It must be the vicar.
- Hello, Vicar! Come in.
- Good morning.
Is it all right for the vicar to come in?
Good heavens!
How do you do, Mrs. Smith? How are you?
Very well, thank you, Vicar.
- And how is the heir?
- Take a look.
Hello, young fellow.
He's quite a size, isn't he?
Bigger and stronger
than babies twice his age.
I was at the post office just now.
I found Mrs. Goodbody
in a lather of excitement.
There had been an extraordinary event.
A telegram!
- No.
- How very thrilling. Who got it?
- You did.
- I?
Probably someone congratulating you
upon becoming a father.
Aren't you ever going to tell me
what's in it?
I can't believe it. It's fantastic.
Darling, please,
I can't stand it another second.
It's from Liverpool,
from the editor of The Mercury.
Read it out loud.
"Can you appear at Mercury office
10:00 tomorrow morning...
"November 14,
regarding permanent position on paper?
"Samuel C. Henson, Editor. "
Oh, darling.
Smithy, how marvelous.
Marvelous? It's incredible.
"Can you appear at Mercury office
tomorrow morning... "
Goodness, you're a terrible packer.
Let me see, shirts, socks, tie...
May I ask what you're going to sleep in?
Great Scott! Have I forgotten
the pajamas?
This cuff's a bit frayed,
but I don't suppose Keats was very dressy.
That's better.
All these labels.
He'll think I'm a commercial traveler.
- Are you excited?
- Wildly.
Think what it means.
A start in life, a career.
I'll be able to do things for you,
things I've always dreamed of.
I wish I could come, too.
Yes. I've been thinking of that,
but I daren't wait.
He might change his mind.
Darling, you're not worrying about me,
are you?
I'll be all right.
I feel absolutely sure of myself.
I know. I shan't worry.
It's just...
Our first parting.
- When will you be back?
- Tomorrow night.
I'll be in on the 8:00 train.
- Where will you stay?
- I hadn't thought.
The Great Northern isn't bad.
It's the best of the cheap hotels
and it's near the station.
- Got your key?
- Yes.
That must be the vicar. I must run.
Goodbye, darling.
Goodbye, young fellow.
- Take very good care of my little family.
- Indeed, I will, sir.
Goodbye, darling.
See you tomorrow night.
Tomorrow night. Good luck, Smithy.
Can you tell me,
where is the Mercury office?
The Liverpool Mercury.
Second on the left, sir, off George Street.
- Thanks.
- Taxi, sir? Looks like rain.
No, thanks. I'll take a chance.
Paper! Get your paper! Paper, sir?
Read The Liverpool Mercury!
Election results! Paper, ma'am? Paper, sir?
Election results! Paper, sir?
- Liverpool Mercury...
- Is this George Street?
- I'm looking for the Mercury office.
- Right across the street, on the corner.
Paper! Paper, sir?
Look out!
Call an ambulance.
He'll be all right. He's coming around now.
Feeling better?
You've got an unholy bump there.
Looks worse than it is, though.
You're lucky, I'd say.
- Do you feel any pain?
- My head aches a bit.
It would be funny if it didn't.
Quite a wallop.
My shoes.
A good blacking is all they need.
What on earth...
This is all wrong.
- I've no business to be in civvies.
- What should you be in?
In uniform, of course.
I'm on active service.
- Where the devil am I, anyway?
- You're in Liverpool.
Liverpool?
You've had a nasty shock.
You better go somewhere
and rest for a while.
Try not to think about anything.
- Is this the party who had the accident?
- Yes, Officer.
It's not my fault.
He slipped in the mud right in front of me.
- Is that the right of it?
- It's the truth, Captain.
- I think so.
- What cabby says is correct, Officer.
I saw the accident from my window there.
- Can I have your name, please, sir?
- Rainier, Charles Rainier.
- Rainier. Profession, sir?
- Captain of the Wessex Regiment.
Address, please.
The trenches, Arras.
I beg your pardon, sir?
- Random Hall, North Random, Surrey.
- Thank you, sir.
You don't wish to lodge a complaint, sir?
Thank you, no.
I'm sure whatever happened was my fault.
All right. Thanks, Mr. Rainier.
Thanks, guvnor.
Sure you feel strong enough to walk?
A little dizzy still, but I'll manage it.
Quite a bump.
Apart from that, what do I owe you?
- Never mind that.
- Thank you.
- Thanks.
- It's all right, sir.
- Here's your hat.
- Yes.
- Sure you don't want me to call a cab?
- No, thanks. The air will brace me up.
By the way, would you mind telling me...
what day is this?
This is Thursday.
Thursday, yes, but the date?
November 14, 1920.
Thanks.
1920. Three years gone.
Three years.
France, I remember distinctly.
An ensign was killed. Young Davis.
But after that?
What after that?
Liverpool? What am I doing here?
Where have I been?
Better go home. Yes. May clear things up.
Better go home.
Mr. Sheldon, I'm sorry to wake you...
but there's a gentleman here
asking for you.
He says he's Mr. Charles. Charles.
I'm sorry, Mr. Sheldon.
That's what he says.
The butler says
he'll come straight down, sir.
Step inside, sir.
Take a seat, sir.
You'll excuse me taking precautions, sir,
it being late and all.
It's quite all right.
Is Miss Bridget at home, do you know?
Yes, sir. The whole family's at home.
Really? Everything's all right
up at the house, I hope.
Haven't you heard, sir?
Old Mr. Rainier died Sunday.
The funeral was today, sir.
Was he a relative of yours, sir?
He was my father.
I'm sorry, sir.
I don't feel much like eating, but still.
I must say I think it most peculiar.
After three years of complete silence...
he suddenly comes back from the grave
with this cock-and-bull story...
and at the very moment
when the will is to be read.
Very convenient, if you ask me.
- You talk as if my brother were a fraud.
- Who's to say he isn't?
- You seem to forget Sheldon's seen him.
- Yes, in the dark...
and Sheldon was probably half-asleep.
Isn't this argument rather a waste of time?
We shall see him for ourselves
in a moment...
and with all respect to Lydia...
I think we shall be able
to recognize our own brother.
- Morning, everybody.
- Good morning.
- Morning, Mother.
- Morning, darling.
Where's Uncle Charles?
He's not down yet.
Besides, we're not all deaf, dear.
I'm sorry. I'm just dying to see him.
It's all so romantic...
like a thriller in the railway bookstore...
Back From The Dead
or The Disappearing Uncle.
Yes, or Three Years In Darkest Amnesia.
Three years! Think of it.
Where do you suppose he's been
all that time?
That's just what I've been asking.
In jail, for all we know.
Did Truslove say positively
that the will was written 10 years ago?
Yes, and I gather the estate
is divided equally between all of us...
with the exception
of the two business interests...
- which, naturally, fall to me.
- Naturally.
- And this house, which goes to Charles.
- To Charles?
But why on earth
should Charles get the house?
That gives him more than Chet,
the eldest son.
- Morning, Uncle George.
- Morning, Kitty. Morning, everybody.
- Morning.
- I say, have you heard the news?
Plenty for all and plenty more...
when up-to-date methods are used
in the handling of our various interests.
In fact, without being unduly optimistic,
I think I may say...
Sausages, by Jove!
But if the whole matter's
gonna be treated as a joke...
Sit down, Chet. It's no joke to me.
That is, supposing it really is Charles
who's suddenly turned up like a...
Like a bad penny?
Hello, my dear fellow. How are you?
- Hello, Chet. How are you?
- Delighted to see you, Charles.
- Welcome home, darling.
- Hello, darling.
- Charles, this is jolly.
- My dear.
Charles, dear, how nice to see you.
You haven't met Henry yet, have you?
A new brother-in-law?
How do you do? Congratulations.
- Thank you very much.
- You remember Lydia.
- How are you?
- Hello, old chap.
- I'm Kitty.
Jill had to take me when she took Daddy.
How do you do, Kitty?
Please sit down, all of you.
- I'm afraid I'm upsetting your breakfast.
- Here's a chair. Next to mine.
- What can I get you?
- You go on with your breakfast...
- and I'll forage for myself.
- Go ahead, my dear chap.
We're all absolutely delighted
to see you back.
Have to kill the fatted calf, what?
I'll settle for a couple
of George's sausages.
- Lf he's left any.
- Plenty. I'm on a diet.
- By Jove, he's kidding. Amazing.
- They sound absolutely deafening.
By the way, my dear fellow,
Truslove's reading the will this morning.
It's 10 years old,
so you won't be done out of your share...
- which includes the house, I understand.
- Really?
I'm sure you're all waiting
for some sort of explanation.
I really haven't got one.
That's what loss of memory does for you.
Sheldon's told you all I know.
I was in Liverpool yesterday morning.
Why or how, I've no idea.
I'd been knocked down by a taxi
and came to in a chemist's shop.
Before that, I can't remember a thing.
Since a shell hole in France,
and that was three years ago.
Those three years
are a complete blank to me.
I don't know what I've done,
where I've been.
I found a little money in my pocket
and this key.
The key to your house?
If I knew that, I'd know where I belong.
- You belong here, Uncle Charles.
- Yes?
Yes, of course. This house.
I hope you'll all still think of it as home
and come whenever you like...
and stay as long as you care to,
now or anytime.
- Charles...
- I shall come. Often.
- I'm terribly glad you're my uncle.
- Thank you, Kitty.
- Goodbye.
- Goodbye, sir.
- Sorry you're leaving.
- Well, Charles.
Take care, old chap, won't you?
Excuse my left hand.
Hello, Uncle Charles!
I've come to say goodbye!
- Hello, Kitty. You off, Julian?
- Yes.
I don't think I shall call you uncle.
You're not really my uncle.
Forward minx. Goodbye, Charles.
Let's meet again sometime, somewhere.
We must.
- Goodbye, young woman.
- Goodbye.
Let's sit down, shall we? Come on.
Mother will be hours yet.
She's always late.
Can I have a puff of that cigarette?
Do you think you should?
All the girls at Kerwood smoke
as soon as they're in sixth.
- You don't mind, do you?
- Why should I?
Charles, aren't you going to be...
terribly lonely all by yourself
in this big house?
Perhaps. Why?
Only when people are lonely...
they're rather apt to marry
the first woman who comes along.
It doesn't do, you know.
- It doesn't?
- Never.
Not once, in all your years of experience?
I shall be 18 in three years.
- I'll keep you in mind.
- Will you?
I know you're laughing at me...
but please don't do anything rash
in the meantime...
because I do like you awfully,
from the very first moment.
Is this a leap year, by any chance?
I don't know, and I don't care.
- I've said it and I mean it.
- I'll have to think it over.
Anyway, don't you think
that I might come here in the holidays...
and sort of take care of you?
- What would Mother say?
- Jill? She wouldn't mind.
- She loves to get rid of me.
- Kitty!
You'll write to me, won't you?
- Will you?
All right, if you want me to.
Here I am, waiting.
Goodbye, Charles. Goodbye, Sheldon.
- I've simply got to fly.
- Goodbye, my dear.
- Lovely to see you. Come along, Kitty!
- Goodbye.
- Goodbye, Kitty.
- Goodbye, Uncle Charles.
Thanks for asking me
to come and visit you in the holidays.
- Will you be dining at home, sir?
- Yes, I suppose so.
- Alone, sir?
- There's no one else, is there?
I thought perhaps you might like to ask
the vicar or Dr. Hampstead.
I don't think so, Sheldon. Thank you.
I'm afraid you'll be very lonely
in this great house.
May one ask, sir,
have you any plans for the future?
No. I might go back to Cambridge.
I never got my degree.
I might take a fling at writing.
I always wanted to, if you remember.
I wonder what he would have
liked me to do.
I think he always wanted you to carry on
at Rainier's where he left off, sir.
But Mr. Chetwynd
is head of Rainier's now.
Yes, now, sir, but... We shall see.
In any case, I'm not a businessman.
- Have you ever tried, sir?
- No.
I wonder what I was doing in Liverpool.
"Dear Uncle Charles... "
or "Dear Charles. "
What do you think?
He's not really my uncle, you know,
and I have intentions.
"Dear Charles, so you've left Cambridge
and gone into the business.
"What a shame.
I know you hated to leave your books...
"and that quiet corner of the river
where Rupert Brooke used to dream.
"Mother says you're simply a wizard at it.
We're all going to be rich again.
"Write to me soon.
"I keep all your letters.
"Sentimental little college girl.
"Dear Uncle Charles.
"Dear Charles, I've graduated with honors.
"I'm sending you my photograph
in cap and gown.
"Will you put me on the desk
in your study?
"And please, look at me sometimes.
"Dear Charles... My dear Charles...
"just to remind you that I'm growing up.
"I have lots of beaus.
"I do hope you're jealous.
"By the way, I saw your picture
in the paper.
"I was impressed.
"'Industrial Prince of England... "
"'Mr. Charles Rainier. "'
Hello, nuisance.
My word.
Do you like it?
My dear, you look adorable.
Adore me. I can bear it.
- Haven't I seen that hat before?
- It's not a bad hat, is it?
It's a lovely hat.
Now it will be a lovely lunch.
My dear, I cannot possibly afford the time.
Come on.
Yes, you can. Miss Hanson says so.
She says it will do you good
to get out of this office...
for an hour or two.
Or two?
- Miss Hanson.
- Yes, Mr. Rainier.
Owing to lamentable weakness
of character...
I'm having lunch at the Savoy
with your approval.
- I thoroughly approve.
- You do.
I do, Mr. Rainier.
Will you get me a copy...
of the Brown-Severing prospectus
while I'm out?
- Yes, I will.
- Have I any appointments for 2:00?
- Yes.
- Can you postpone them?
- Yes, I can.
- Thanks.
All right, young woman...
I can give you precisely
one hour and a half from door to door.
No. Miss Hanson said two hours.
Thank you.
- Cigarette?
- Please.
You're being very charming today.
You haven't looked at your watch once.
- That reminds me.
- No, please. Can't you relax for an hour?
An hour? It's just on 3:00.
- You used to say that you hated business.
- Did I?
You know you did.
You were going to whip things into shape
and get out quickly.
That was the original idea.
To save the family and then be off
before they needed more saving.
- In that slow and careful way of yours?
- I began to look into things, yes.
I found that Rainier's
kept other families going, too.
Little families in little homes.
Thousands of them, all over England.
I see. Uncle Atlas, eh?
Don't you ever want to get out
and have fun?
Kitty, the last time I...
It's that woman you sent me,
Lady Maxton.
One of the most interesting cases
I've had...
since I have been in private practice.
Well, goodbye.
Goodbye, Lola, and don't forget
that you're dining with me on Thursday.
Goodbye.
What is it?
Pardon me. It was nothing.
It was just for a moment, that voice...
- Was familiar?
- Not that, exactly...
but it seemed to remind me of something
that I didn't have time to get a grip on.
That happens to me sometimes.
A sort of wisp of memory
that can't be caught before it fades away.
- From those lost years?
- Perhaps.
Now, what were you saying?
That you should take a holiday.
You've got money enough, heaven knows.
- Money, yes, but not the time.
- That's nonsense.
You could make the time.
How old are you?
None of your business.
- You're awfully nice-looking, Charles.
- Thank you.
Clever, interesting.
It's not fair.
Why?
Because you've spoiled me for other men,
that's why.
Kitty.
It's no secret, is it?
I've always been mad about you...
even as a schoolgirl.
It might be fun if you loved me now.
We're a lot alike, you know.
We laugh at the same things.
We have marvelous times together.
I sometimes wonder why you don't.
In my slow and careful way...
I've wondered sometimes, too.
Why don't you? Just to be curious.
I haven't said that I don't.
Oh, no.
Would it be too incredible?
- It would be fantastic.
- Then it is fantastic.
But I don't believe it.
I don't believe that you mean it.
That you'll go on meaning it.
I shall wake up and find it isn't real at all.
- It's just a dream.
- No.
You do want me?
I'm not just a schoolgirl to you?
Darling, you're very sweet and dear to me.
I'm building a great hope on you.
I don't believe any of it.
At the office tomorrow,
you'll have forgotten all about it.
I'll have Miss Hanson remind me.
Charles, darling, it's too wonderful.
Take me out of here.
Take me somewhere and kiss me.
- Yes?
- Mr. Rainier, may I bring in...
Yes, Miss Hanson. I'm sorry.
Bring it in, please.
I've scribbled a note here.
Will you take care of it? And this.
Is the Ray-Novaille prospectus ready yet?
They promised it for 4:00.
I'll send it in as soon as it arrives.
You saw this offer
from Harwood and Williams?
Yes, Mr. Rainier.
You worked for Harwood and Williams
once, I believe.
They're driving a hard bargain.
- Do you think they're bluffing?
- I think not.
I used to know Mr. Williams pretty well.
- I was his secretary.
- Yes. I remember he was quite annoyed...
when you came to me.
He called me a pirate.
That was not fair.
It was really all my doing.
Indeed?
I'd heard Miss Lindy was leaving you,
and I applied for the position.
May I ask why?
A few weeks before, I'd come across
a picture of you in a magazine.
Underneath, it said,
"Industrial Prince of England. "
- Dear me.
- I was impressed.
I decided then I must leave
Harwood and Williams to better myself.
I'm sincerely glad you did.
You make things much easier for me.
What's all this?
That's the report on that firm
in the Midlands.
The Melbridge Cable Company.
Yes, my brother thinks this would be
a very valuable subsidiary.
I have a large file.
Photographs of the works.
- Would you care to see it?
- Please, yes.
Bring me
the Melbridge Cable Company report.
Yes, Miss Hanson.
Hello.
Yes, I did, Mr. Manders.
Can you make it 4:30 this afternoon?
That would be splendid. He's very busy.
Thank you.
Market reports?
In 10 minutes, and thanks
for the flowers. They're lovely.
I thought you'd like them.
Thank you, Sheila.
Their equipment's up-to-date.
And they seem to have plenty of space.
It does seem worth investigating.
I'll get my brother to run down.
I'm taking a long holiday.
- Are you? At once?
- In about a month or so.
Why, I think that's a very good idea.
I may be gone a year.
If things can be arranged.
A year?
If it's humanly possible.
I'm being married, Miss Hanson.
You're the first to hear my news.
I'm afraid it'll mean
a lot of extra work for you...
putting things in order so I can get away.
- It's Miss Chilcet, I suppose.
- Yes, it's Kitty.
- Was it so obvious?
- Not at all. She's a very charming girl.
Yes, I fully agree.
I hope you won't take it into your head
to follow my example, Miss Hanson.
I don't know what I should do without you.
I have been married, Mr. Rainier.
Remember, I told you
when I took the position.
Yes, to be sure. It slipped my memory.
You had a child, I believe.
Yes. A little boy. He died.
Yes. I remember. I'm sorry.
You'll see that Mr. Chetwynd gets this,
will you?
And I'll let him have the file later.
Hello?
Yes, he's here. Miss Chilcet.
Hello.
Definitely. You want me to confirm it
in writing?
You absurd young person.
What's that? No, Kitty. Of course not.
- Paula, don't.
- John, let me tell him.
- That you're his wife?
- Yes.
You can risk it, if you wish.
I hope you won't.
But what do I risk now?
What do you want of him, Paula?
His name? His protection?
I want him as he was.
I want his love.
Paula, two years ago,
you walked into his office.
If the sight of you
did nothing to restore his memory...
what can words do?
When you came to me at Melbridge
shortly after he disappeared...
I told you I was sure
he hadn't deserted you knowingly.
I told you a door in his mind had opened,
but another had closed.
I warned you even that if you found him...
the chances were
he wouldn't recognize you.
You gave me a hope.
There's always that hope,
but the impetus must come from within.
It can't be forced on him from outside.
You can tell him the truth
and claim your legal rights.
But what is going to be his attitude
when a strange woman appears...
and suddenly claims to be his wife?
He'd resent me.
He'd accept me.
He'd pity me...
and he'd resent me.
I can only offer you that frail hope
that someday the miracle will happen...
and he'll come back to you,
not as Charles Rainier, but as...
What was it you used to call him?
- Smithy.
- As Smithy...
with all his emotion for you
as warm and intact as it was...
on the day he left you.
That's not much help to me, John, is it?
I'm real, these tears are real,
and my jealousy is real...
and my need of him.
Paula, I wish I could help you.
What will you do?
I don't know. I'll have to think it out.
- You go to your dinner.
- I'll call it off if you'll dine with me.
No, don't do that.
Dear John. Always firm, but kind.
Thank you for the hope.
That is rather nice of me,
seeing that it robs me of mine.
Good night, John.
The law is quite clear on that point,
Mrs. Smith.
If it is proved that for a period of
not less than seven years...
no news of a person has been received...
by those who would naturally hear of him
if he were alive...
then he may be legally presumed dead.
You wish me to take the necessary steps?
Please.
Now, to complete the particulars.
Did you prosecute a search?
Yes, we investigated accidents
that had occurred on that day.
- Without result?
- Yes.
Then I became seriously ill.
I was ill for many months. My baby died.
As soon as I could get about,
I made some effort to return to the stage...
but without success.
I worked as a waitress, a saleswoman.
I studied stenography at night school.
Spent every penny I could spare
trying to trace my husband.
Thought he might have been taken
to a hospital...
or perhaps an asylum.
But years passed,
and I found no trace of him.
Are you employed at present?
For the last two years,
I've worked as a private secretary.
- To whom?
- To Mr. Charles Rainier.
I've studied your petition, Mrs. Smith...
and the affidavits attached.
In regard to the evidence presented,
I have entered the decree to the effect...
that the man known as John Smith
shall be presumed to be dead...
and your marriage to him
consequently dissolved.
Hello, you two!
I wish you'd remember
you're getting married on Wednesday.
That odd little Mr. Beddoes
has been waiting in the chapel for ages.
Oh, dear! How dreadful of me. I forgot.
He wants us to choose the hymns.
We'll go down. Back in a few minutes.
What's for tea?
Muffins, old boy! Terrific!
That's nice.
I forget the words.
Yes, I remember now.
Then there's another lovely one.
Nearly always used.
This, perhaps: O Perfect Love.
Yes, that's it.
I like that. Don't you, Charles?
What is it, Kitty?
I'm sorry, darling.
I must have been dreaming.
It's all right, Charles.
I'm glad it happened.
- It's better.
- Better?
What has happened?
I've been uncertain.
Almost from the beginning.
Now I'm sure.
It's no use, is it?
I've always known it. Really.
I was grasping selfishly
at my own happiness.
Because you could make me
perfectly happy.
If I were selfish enough not to care...
or stupid enough not to know.
To know what?
That I'm not the one.
Let's be honest about it.
I was letting things drift.
But I never really believed in my own luck.
Charles, you looked at me just now
as if I were a stranger.
An intrusive stranger.
Trying to take the place of someone else.
Someone else?
I know it sounds absurd, but let me say it.
Sometimes...
especially when we've been closest...
I've had a curious feeling
that I remind you of someone else.
Someone you once knew.
Don't leave me, Kitty. I need you.
I'm trying to make a life.
With someone you love
as you'll never love me.
I am nearly the one, Charles.
So nearly that I shall always be proud of it.
But nearly isn't enough for a lifetime.
It would be too hard to...
I've left it rather late, haven't I? I'm sorry.
I think I'll travel.
Mother's going to Luxor, I believe.
I'll go with her.
- Kitty...
- It's all right, Charles.
I asked for it, and I'll get over it.
One does, you know.
I shan't go in any tragic mood...
but looking to see what fun I can find,
and I usually can.
You'll probably hear
that I've married some nice man.
I don't know what to say.
You don't have to say anything.
But because I am so nearly the one...
and because I love you
more than anyone I shall ever marry...
will you kiss me goodbye?
Well, we can't keep this up indefinitely.
Where in the devil is he?
No normal man walks out of a big concern
without saying a word to a solitary soul.
Everything was arranged.
Could he have gone abroad?
He would have let us know.
Confound that girl!
What the deuce could have happened?
One minute they were picking hymns
for the wedding...
- Mr. Chetwynd?
- What now?
I'm sorry, sir. It seems to be important.
Stourton of the Lytham Liberal League.
All right, I'll see him. You talk to Sheldon.
Sheldon, when did you say
you last saw Mr. Rainier?
It was close to dinnertime, miss.
About an hour after Miss Kitty left.
Mr. Charles asked me
to put some things into a bag for him.
I don't know quite why, miss...
but I sort of think
that he may have gone to Liverpool.
- To Liverpool?
- Yes, miss.
It was from Liverpool he came that night...
that he came back from the dead,
as you might say.
Please try to tell me everything you
can remember about that night in 1920.
What did he tell you
about what had happened to him?
Well, miss, it was a wet night.
In November, it was.
He'd been knocked down by a taxi and
carried into a chemist's shop in Liverpool.
Come in.
Miss Hanson.
Please forgive me for coming.
We were all so anxious.
You're not well.
I should have let you know where I was.
I intended to. I'm sorry.
I hate to bother you,
but something very important came up.
How did you know I was in Liverpool?
- Something Sheldon said. I made inquiries.
- Sheldon, yes.
Won't you sit down, Miss Hanson?
You say some important business
induced you to follow me?
Sir Edward Lake, Member of Parliament
from West Lytham...
died on Monday morning.
There will be a by-election.
This morning, a committee
of the West Lytham Liberal Association...
unanimously decided
to support your candidacy...
should you consent to stand
in the Liberal interest.
Did Sheldon tell you of my experience here
about 12 years ago?
Yes, Mr. Rainier.
I came back here at that time...
hoping to stumble on the trail of my past...
but I failed then...
and I've failed now.
- Nothing helped you?
- Nothing.
Why should I feel
a sense of loss so acute that...
That it's spoiling your life?
No, I'm not being honest with myself.
My life's not complete,
and I've hurt others.
I don't know why I bore you
with my affairs.
You feel that perhaps
you lived in Liverpool?
- It seems possible.
- But not certain.
You mean I might have been
visiting the city?
Well, Liverpool's a big port.
I might have come in on some ship.
Strange. That hadn't occurred to me.
Or by train.
You might have come in
from a nearby town...
or from the country.
- Perhaps on business.
- Perhaps.
In that case,
maybe you stayed at some hotel.
I know Liverpool. I've been up here often.
You know the direction you were
walking in when the accident happened?
Yes, I checked that.
I was walking down Mason Street
toward the square. It was wet.
Well, there are two hotels
north of Mason Street.
There's the old Olympic
and the Great Northern.
It's quite a distance from the Olympic.
So, if it was wet, the chances are,
you were coming from the Great Northern.
Presuming I stayed at a hotel at all,
under what name was I registered?
There's just one chance to find out.
If you were at a hotel, you walked out
leaving unclaimed luggage.
Would they keep it so long?
- It's worth investigating.
- Yes.
I'm glad you came, Miss Hanson.
You've given me fresh hope.
You must come with me.
We'll start with the Great Northern.
Please be kind enough to tell the manager
this suitcase is of no interest to me...
and I'm sorry to have troubled him.
John Smith.
Highly unimaginative incognito.
What could be more anonymous
than these poor rags?
- Nothing seemed familiar to you?
- No.
There's a finality
about that most unrewarding find:
Like a door slammed and bolted.
Now I shall learn to accept myself
for what I am:
A psychological defective.
As Kitty saw me. As you must see me.
You must keep my secret, Miss Hanson.
Will you send a telegram
to the West Lytham Liberal Association...
telling them
I'll receive the Committee tomorrow?
Yes, Mr. Rainier.
- There's an express to London at 8:15.
- I'll make reservations.
Congratulations, Mr. Rainier.
Famous victory.
The Prime Minister's delighted.
Our new member from Lytham.
- Yes. Congratulations.
- Thank you.
- It's good to have you with us, sir.
- The party is honored, Mr. Rainier.
- Thank you, sir.
- Mr. Rainier, congratulations.
- Thank you very much.
Miss Hanson.
My compliments, Mr. Rainier.
A great triumph.
Thank you.
Have I kept you waiting? I was delayed.
Nice of you to come down for my debut.
- Was I satisfactory?
- Very.
Waiter, some tea, please.
What would you like? Cake? Sandwiches?
- Bring an assortment.
- Thank you.
By the way, I haven't really thanked you
for your help in the campaign.
I don't know what I should have done
without you.
I thoroughly enjoyed it.
Politics interest me.
Do they? I'm glad of that.
You're staring at me, you know.
I'm sorry. It struck me
your hair is bright red in the sunshine.
Was that all?
You were looking so intensely.
Everyone has these feelings of having
lived through certain moments before.
You mean, you have the feeling
that you've known me before?
I had, for a moment.
As a matter of fact, I felt it quite strongly
the first day you came into my office.
- You didn't show it.
- No?
- Is that why you engaged me?
- Perhaps.
It was also your air of quiet efficiency.
Forgive me...
but is there any possibility
that you might marry again?
Not the slightest.
I'm asking you
because I have a proposal to make.
I need your help in my parliamentary life.
- Social secretary?
- Not exactly.
You know...
it seemed quite a reasonable idea
when it came to me.
But now, I'm rather losing my nerve.
Why? Is it so startling?
It may sound outrageous to you,
but it's not a sudden impulse.
I've thought it over very carefully.
You and I are in the same boat,
Miss Hanson.
We're both ghost-ridden.
That sounds a bit romantic,
but I think it expresses it.
We are prisoners of our past.
Yes.
What if we were to pool our loneliness...
and give each other what little we have:
Support, friendship?
I'm proposing marriage, Miss Hanson.
Or should I call it a merger?
You know, I'm good at mergers.
A Member of Parliament
should have a wife, Margaret.
So I'm told on all sides.
"He needs a clever hostess. "
You have exceptional gifts.
Would it interest you
to have a wider field for them?
You need have no fear that I would make
any emotional demands upon you.
I have only sincere friendship to offer.
I won't ask any more from you.
Please. Don't answer at once.
Think it over.
It's completely a selfish proposal...
but I can't have you giving me notice,
you know.
I'd be lost without you.
Miss Hanson... Margaret...
- have I hurt you?
- I don't know.
This comes of boasting that I never cry.
You will think about it?
I'll call you tomorrow.
No, I can't wait so long.
Tonight, about 9:00?
I hope the answer will be yes.
Here's the tea.
It wasn't a very flattering proposal, really.
Rather, a suggestion for a merger.
He used that very expression.
- Pretty cold-blooded, isn't it?
- Well, it's honest.
I'm sorry. Sorry for myself.
- I want you to be happy, Paula.
- It may work out.
He might even fall in love with me.
Would that be so very extraordinary?
It would be very extraordinary if he didn't.
But the situation is very extraordinary.
It seems rather hard,
what I'm going to say...
but if you marry him, keep to his terms.
I suppose you're right.
And you love him?
Yes.
You're going to be hurt, Paula.
John, don't be against it.
Hello?
Yes, Mr. Rainier.
Charles. You're early.
It's yes, Charles.
Isn't that Mrs. Rainier,
who gives those political dinners?
Lady Rainier.
He was in the birthday honors.
They say he'll be in the Cabinet.
Pity there's no son to inherit the title.
Such a wonderful couple.
I hear he's devoted to her.
Well, it's really amazing.
She's got him to dance.
She's got him to smile, too.
That woman is a marvel.
Good night, Sheldon, and thank you.
You managed beautifully.
Thank you, milady.
- Thank you, Sheldon.
- Good night, Mr. Charles.
You certainly mellowed the old gentleman.
He was positively purring
when I put him into the car.
Yes, I think he really enjoyed himself.
- I know I did.
- Nonsense.
Good heavens! It's nearly 3:00.
You have two committees tomorrow.
- Today.
- Yes, that's true. It's nearly morning.
The morning of May 25.
Does that suggest something to you?
It's the anniversary of our wedding.
Our third anniversary.
Will you wait just a moment?
You don't look the least bit tired.
All my gratitude goes with this, Margaret.
I owe you more than I can put into words.
It's too beautiful, really. You spoil me.
The emerald is said to have belonged
to the Empress Marie Louise.
Really? That's thrilling.
Will you put it on for me?
There. How do you like it?
Do you know
you're a very beautiful woman?
Thank you. I rather hoped
you thought that.
Margaret...
are you happy?
- Why do you ask?
- A twinge of conscience.
- Lf I hadn't interfered in your life...
- I should have never been Lady Rainier...
entertained the Prime Minister,
worn a queen's emerald.
Is it enough?
Perhaps not.
Is there anyone else?
No.
- Charles, why are you asking me?
- Because if there were...
I've often wanted to say this,
I wouldn't hold you to our bargain.
I haven't the right.
- You're trying to get rid of me, Charles?
- You know I'd be utterly lost without you.
I'm glad to hear that,
because I like my job.
A woman told me tonight that she
envied me more than anyone she knew.
She envied me my husband, Charles.
Most women do.
Now I really am tired.
Good night, Charles,
and thank you for the wonderful present.
Good night, Margaret.
Smithy!
Margaret, I'm afraid
I said something to hurt you.
No, Charles.
If I expressed myself clumsily...
- It's nothing, really. It's just that...
- I wish you would be frank with me.
Do you?
Were those a gift?
Yes.
I came across them quite by chance.
They're just cheap little beads.
But they have a value for you
that this does not?
He said they were the color of my eyes.
They are, aren't they?
Oh, Margaret.
Isn't there something morbid
in burying one's heart with the dead?
- That's a strange thing for you to say.
- Is it?
You haven't even a memory.
No.
And the best of you...
Your capacity for loving...
your joy in living is buried
in a little space of time you've forgotten.
- It isn't quite the same thing.
- Why not?
Because in some vague way, I still have...
- Hope?
- Yes, I suppose that's it.
Have you, Charles?
Do you feel that there really is someone?
That someday you may find her?
I'd rather not talk of it, Margaret.
It's nothing I could put into words.
But doesn't it frighten you sometimes...
that the years are passing...
that you may sometime find that
you've lost your capacity for happiness?
You may have come so near her.
You may even have brushed by her
in the street.
Yes, I've thought of that.
You might even have met her, Charles.
Met her and not known her.
It might be someone you know.
Charles, it might even be me.
Oh, Margaret.
I know I'm talking wildly.
- It's after 3:00, and I'm tired.
- Yes.
I've sometimes thought I'd like to travel.
I feel I need a change and a rest.
- To travel?
- Yes. I've never been out of England.
I'd like to go to Buenos Aires or Rio
or somewhere colorful and distracting.
Perhaps when the House adjourns...
I don't want to drag you away.
I'll take a maid. Or a friend, perhaps.
Margaret, I believe
you want to get away from me.
No.
It's just that it's been a strain.
I'm just a little nobody, you know.
It's been harder than I thought...
being the wife of Charles Rainier.
If you wish, of course.
You are a little overtired, I think.
- Shall we talk about it in the morning?
- In the morning, yes.
- Good night, Margaret.
- Good night, Charles.
Smithy.
I think this is my compartment.
Yes, it is.
I hope Harrison
has made everything smooth for you.
Thanks. Yes, he's been very helpful.
He should be here any moment
with my letter of credit.
Will you have only two days
in the country?
Yes. My boat sails on Wednesday.
- It's on your way, this place.
- No. It's in Devon.
It's a quiet little country village...
with a delightful old inn.
I wanted to see it again.
I was once very happy there.
I'm glad I'm not late. Hello, sir.
I made you out an itinerary.
I thought you'd like to study it on the ship.
How kind of you.
- Here's your letter of credit.
- Thank you.
And some magazines.
I'll put these in the compartment.
I think you'll find everything in order.
- I hope you have a wonderful trip.
- Thank you.
Don't stay away too long.
If I do, blame your excellent arrangements.
- Goodbye.
I'll wait for you, sir.
I have a message from Mr. Chetwynd.
Well, goodbye, Charles.
Margaret, I wish you weren't going.
I don't feel quite happy about it.
- You'll let me hear from you?
- Of course.
Goodbye.
- You're going to the house?
- No, to the office. There's some trouble.
Seems strange not to talk it over
with you, Margaret.
This strike, sir, it's pretty serious.
Strike?
At the Melbridge Cable Works.
The men are out of hand.
Melbridge. Yes, of course.
It's all right, men. We've got our terms.
The strike is settled, and we've won!
Thanks to one man:
Sir Charles Rainier!
First back streets we came through.
Here. Let's pop in here
for a whiskey and soda.
Thank you kindly, sir. We appreciate it.
- What will you have, gents?
- Two double McWhirters and soda, please.
Two double Macs. Right-o, sir.
Here we are, sir.
Is that the proprietor?
Yes, sir. That's the Biffer.
Was, I should say.
He ain't much like that now.
That's him at the end.
He was a gentleman, the gunner was.
Not like these softies
what call theirselves heavyweights today.
Why, he'd take two of them for breakfast!
He didn't wear no fancy dressing gown...
Well, we mustn't lose our train.
We better go.
Thank you, sir.
- The fog's getting thicker.
- Yes. Beastly.
- Cigarette?
- Sorry. I don't smoke.
Of course not.
Never mind. There's a little tobacconist
just around the corner.
Well?
- Packet of Barclay Blue Ribbons, please.
- Yes, sir.
- Thank you, sir.
- Thank you.
- Good night, sir.
- Good night.
I thought you said
you'd never been in Melbridge.
I haven't.
But you said, "There's a little tobacconist
just around the corner. "
You said, "There's a little tobacconist
I said that?
That shop was off the main street.
You couldn't have seen it
on your way from the station.
No.
Then how did you know of it?
- I don't know.
- You went straight to it.
I did know, but I don't know how.
- Melbridge.
- What's the matter?
Melbridge.
Are you ill, sir? Let me get a cab.
No, let me think. There's something.
That shop...
That woman.
There's a taxi. I'll get it.
Here you are, sir.
Where is the hospital?
You mean the old one or the new one, sir?
The old one, I think.
It's on a hill.
Big gates...
a high wall all around it.
That don't sound much like either of them.
You wouldn't be meaning the asylum,
would you, sir?
Look here, sir.
You say you came out of these gates?
Yes. I'm sure of that.
There was some excitement
and a great deal of noise.
Then let's start from here.
Try and retrace your steps.
Now.
You must have gone into town.
Yes, I'd been to that shop.
Perhaps as we go,
you can piece the thing together.
Yes, that's right. That's a good idea.
I came along this path.
- You remember that?
- Yes, I think so.
There was a good deal of fog...
and people shouting, and the sound of...
Like I was trying to get away
from something...
trying to escape.
There was some danger, and I was afraid.
I was...
There was a girl.
Yes, there was a girl!
The mist is lifting.
Yes. It looks as if it will be
a nice day after all.
Could you take the luggage
to the station and wait for me?
I've lots of time. I think I'd like to walk.
Right you are, ma'am.
I'll wait for you by the newsstand.
You're leaving us now?
I do hope you'll come and see us again.
Not very soon, I'm afraid.
- I'm sailing for South America at 2:00.
- You are? My, I envy you.
Are you sure
you'd prefer to walk to the station?
Yes. Such a pretty walk.
I used to live here, you know, years ago.
Mrs. Deventer's time. Did you know her?
No, not very well.
She died three years ago.
So Albert was telling me.
She was quite a character, Mrs. Deventer.
Lots of people ask after her.
There was a gentleman in here
a few minutes ago...
asking after Mrs. Deventer
and the old vicar.
Really? I should be going.
I don't want to have to hurry.
Goodbye, Miss Barnes. Thank you.
- I'm sure you'll have a wonderful trip.
- Thank you.
Did you say a gentleman
was asking for Mrs. Deventer?
Yes, miss, and the old vicar.
That's Mr. Durham, you know.
He lives at Seven Oaks.
Mr. Pauly's our vicar now.
- Is the gentleman staying here?
- No.
He was looking for a cottage.
Said he used to rent one here years ago.
He remembered it was near the church.
Was he a friend of yours, miss?
Excuse me.
Smithy?
Oh, Smithy!
Darling!
Paula!
Watch Movies, TV Series & Live Sports
www.admitme.app