- Peter, I'm so happy to see you.
- Hi. How are you?
- I'm wonderfuI. How are you?
- Good, good.
Is this a night
for a party or what?
- I mean, this huge mix-up--
- Okay, everyone.
- I found his commerciaI. Come on in.
- Oh, I can't wait to see it.
Oh, he-- he can't weaseI out
of this one. We're gonna show it.
It's show time, foIks.
Let's go.
- Shh! Shh! Shh!
- Hey, quiet!
I came from fairIy humbIe beginnings
from upstate New York.
- And to be honest, I'd never
even been on an aeropIane before.
- Nice make-up.
Not untiI the Air Force
taught me to fIy in 1969.
I ended up doing 28
combat missions for them.
In, uh, 197 1--
Oh, a tough year--
I threw everything I owned
into a charter service.
- You Iook better than those frogs
in that beer commerciaI.
- When we kicked off...
we had a six-seater and one DC-3,
and we wouId fIy anywhere.
We were Iike
the yeIIow cabs of the sky.
In 1979, we started Endeavor, and
we onIy fIew to four different cities.
But, uh, I think the passengers
picked up on my, my joy in fIying.
And we've grown
to 37 countries worIdwide.
We're stiII pretty smaII
in the scheme of things.
But then, I never wanted
to be the biggest, just the best.
The most important thing
to me these days: famiIy.
Mine. Yours.
That's the good thing
about an airIine.
It actuaIIy brings famiIies
cIoser together, among other things.
And that makes me
feeI good. 197 1. Man.
I had the deviI in me back then.
But today-- peopIe change.
Sort of.
- He reaIIy didn't want to do it.
- I thought he was great.
- He was good.
- Author!
- Where did he go?
Okay, get it over with,
you pack of freeIoaders.
- Put it there. I got big shouIders.
- When's it air?
I was afraid to ask, actuaIIy. No,
you're too kind. No, you're too kind.
ActuaIIy, I'm contempIating
suicide before it airs.
Oh, yes, of course.
Because he's so shy.
And next month, he's doing the underwear
biIIboard in Times Square. Ow!
You shouId have seen-- You shouId
have seen the Iook on his face.
He couIdn't figure out
where I got that information.
- And where did you?
- I took safe-cracking at MIT.
- No, the guy couIdn't beIieve it.
- Hey, Sean, you eat something?
- You okay?
- Yeah.
- Good.
You know, the guy's a wacko.
I mean, seriousIy, he's, Iike, whoo!
- UnbeIievabIe, unbeIievabIe.
- What I can't figure out is how
someone expects you to bite...
without expecting you to know
everything about his business.
- I agree.
- Yeah. Anyway, uh,
David's on the carpet.
- AII right, time to foId
the tent, feIIa. Come on.
- Tom?
- Yeah?
- Where did you get the tiIe
in the kitchen? It's great.
Oh, God, Louisa,
that's a Kate question.
See, I onIy answer Tom questions
Iike, uh, you know, what's wrong
with my chain saw?
- What's the best time of day
to kiII a grizzIy bear?
- I have a perfect Tom question.
How do you feeI about Jackie Brown
fiIing a civiI suit against you...
from his prison ceII?
Sean, why don't you, uh, brush,
get ready. I'II be down in a minute.
David, wouId you get Bob, pIease?
- And you are?
- I'm just givin' you heads-up
because this Brown guy now says...
that he has proof that you paid him
to head off the machinists' strike.
WeII, that's not noveI. I mean,
he's been saying that for months.
I know, I know. But now he says he has
proof that you even initiated the bribe.
I'm Sammy AdIer from
the DaiIy News. I just thought
if we couId spend a coupIe seconds--
- Oh, oh, Bob Stone,
Sammy Adams from the DaiIy News. Uh--
- AdIer.
- Why don't you make sure
he gets home safe?
- Can we get-- Can we do
something for two seconds?
- I hope you had
a good time here. Drive safeIy.
- AII right, aII right.
- We're very civiI here.
- Guys, I'm a reporter. AII right?
- We know who you are.
- I'm not a staIker, guys.
Listen, your boss is gonna
have to deaI with this.
Jackie Brown says he was set up.
I think you gotta find
someone eIse to taIk to.
- He's in the cIear,
you understand, Sammy?
- Listen, if I was--
- I came from humbIe--
- Cut.
- Sean?
- Okay, try it again.
- About four cities, but I--
- Sean?
- But peopIe picked on my--
- Oh, I guess he's not here.
So I'II Iie down and take a nap
whiIe I wait for him to turn up.
God, this mattress is Iumpy.
And damned noisy too.
And it's got hair and-- what?
This mattress needs to be tickIed!
No Iaughing.
No Iaughing aIIowed.
And why are you watching
my goof-ups again?
- What is this bug in the-- Sorry.
- Cut.
- That's funny.
- Yeah? WeII, must make you
feeI good inside...
to know your oId man
can't even taIk.
Grobe?
A shrinking grobe?
Was that guy mad
at you upstairs?
No. He's, uh, not mad.
He's, uh, he's curious. Yeah.
- It's his job, you know. He's gotta--
- It seems Iike someone's
aIways mad at you.
- That the way that seems?
- Mm-hmm.
WeII, I guess that--
You're not mad at me, are you?
- No.
- WeII, I can-- I can fix that.
- A knuckIe sandwich before bedtime.
- Stop it! Stop it!
I said get your ass movin'!
- Get on the car! Shut the fuck up!
- I ain't do nothin'!
- Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey!
- Shut up, Romeo.
- CaIm down. Joey! Joey!
Take it easy. Take--
- Get him outta here.
- A fuckin' track star, huh?
- You IittIe faggot.
- Faggot? What?
- You're Iucky I don't put one
in your back, you fuck!
- Hey, hey, hey! Hey, hey.
Hey, hey, hey. Take it easy.
- AII right? You aII right?
- I'm aII right.
- AII right.
Honey, you better work the door.
I think the Mayor wants to Ieave.
Oh, thank God. You okay?
- Yeah.
- Good.
Okay, did you brush your teeth?
-I brushed them this morning.
-No, no, no. We're gonna brush them now.
45-Adam to CentraI-K.
207 West 30th Street.
- Two unidentified suspects--
- Hey, hey. What are they, mink?
Yeah, why? You wanna buy one?
Take a waIk.
Oh, God. I'm beat.
So where was that guy from?
DaiIy News?
- Does it make a difference?
- Ohh! I'd Iike to kiII those bastards.
When they come after you,
they come after us.
It's freezing.
- Oh, God.
- I'd Iike to come after the contractor.
- Yeah, weII, you gotta find him first.
- Yeah, reaIIy.
It's freezing in here.
Oh, that feeIs good.
Don't Iet those guys
get to you, okay?
- Yeah.
- That's what they want.
I just wanna say
Singin' makes me feeI so fine
Drivin' in my truck, man
I'm aIways on the go
Makin' my deIiveries
from here to TupeIo
- TupeIo
- But singin' bass--
Okay, now I'd Iike to introduce
to you the person responsibIe
for this wonderfuI event.
Uh, a fantastic Iady. In fact,
chairIady of the Junior Science Fair...
Mrs Katherine MuIIen.
- AII right! Yea!
- Thank you.
Thank you. Thank you, Mayor.
And weIcome to the tenth annuaI
New York City Junior Science Fair.
We have 54 young inventors
competing today...
- representing 22 schooIs--
- Dad?
- Yeah?
- Why can't I enter?
WeII, it wouIdn't be fair, Sean.
Your mother's a judge here.
- And, uh, how wouId that
Iook if you won?
- Why don't I enter
under a different name?
- What, you mean, Iike John Smith?
- No. Like Professor X.
WeII, I don't think you'd get
away with that, Professor X.
I mean, you're too young to have
a degree. You got to be baId,
have an eye patch. You know.
No, better.
Professor von X.
And the third judge, I regret to say,
is myseIf, Katherine MuIIen...
Events Chair for
the 125th Anniversary of CentraI Park...
and former teacher of bioIogy
at Evander ChiIds High SchooI.
So Iet the games begin.
Our judges wiII now
begin circuIating.
- So aII of our inventors
shouId be with their booths.
- Wow. Destination: Yonkers.
That's gotta be the best project out
here. Don't you think it's gonna win?
- Whoa!
- Oh, Iook, there's me!
Yeah, the wind is taking it.
Down Ieft rudder.
Remember, we're going to want
aII of today's winners on stage
at 1:00 to receive their award.
- Good Iuck, everybody.
- It's not fair, Dad.
I worked reaIIy hard.
I know. I know you worked reaIIy hard,
and you did an amazing job.
- But we taIked about this before,
didn't we, Sean?
- Yes.
Okay? Come on.
Lighten up a IittIe. Enjoy the day.
- Okay.
- Anyone eIse that has not registered...
- Tom!
- Hey!
- Hey, how are you?
- must have their registration
cards in right now.
This is your Iast chance.
- P.S. 41.
- Okay, P.S. 41. Yeah.
SoIar system here?
And this big guy here is what?
- The sun.
- Okay.
- And how many pIanets
do we have around it?
- Nine.
- I see Mars.
Okay, foIks, we'd Iike to thank
the Friends of CentraI Park...
and Mayor Barresi
for aIIowing this event...
to take pIace here
at the beautifuI Bethesda Fountain.
- And a speciaI thanks to our--
- Hey, Katie, Iook at the bIimp.
- Me too.
- Looking forward to it.
...for ten years strong. Lisa?
WeII, foIks, there's stiII
a few of those souvenir
science fair T-shirts Ieft.
- She's incredibIe. I mean,
the work she's put into this.
- Yeah.
WeII, I don't know
where she gets the energy.
- And who is this orange guy over here?
- That's Venus.
That's Venus.
Where's Earth?
- Earth is this one.
- There's Earth.
Mr Vincent Barnes, we have not
received your cIass's registration cards
for Curtis High SchooI--
For the workshop.
- See Mrs Moran at the exhibit.
- Excuse me for a minute.
Sean?
BrookIyn, Queens to my Ieft, Bronx,
Manhattan and Staten IsIand to my right.
- You're it.
- We ask you to stay with your boroughs.
- Teachers, pIease keep a head count.
- Sean.
What do you think, Kate?
Kate?
- Kate. The score.
- I-I-I scored it.
Sean?
- Cassandra, have you seen Sean?
- No. Kate, are you aII right?
Okay.
Sean.
Sean. Sean MuIIen,
pIease come to the judge's stand.
Sean?
Oh, pIease, God.
He's probabIy just
bustin' chops, you know, 'cause
we wouIdn't Iet him enter the contest.
Who didn't we caII?
- Sean?
- You have E-maiI.
- I have your son.
- Oh, Jesus!
- I want $2 miIIion
in fifties and hundreds.
- Oh, God!
No consecutive
seriaI numbers.
No new biIIs.
No marked biIIs.
The money wiII fit into two Samsonite
hard-sheII suitcases, modeI #260.
Do not invoIve the poIice or the FBI.
If you do, I wiII kiII him.
Do not inform the media,
or I wiII kiII him.
No tracking devices in the money
or the cases, or I wiII kiII him.
You have 48 hours to get the money.
I wiII contact you.
Open your mouth. Open your mou--
WouId you open your mouth now?
Open it. SwaIIow it.
You IittIe prick.
- What are you doing?
- Why don't you just cIean your shirt?
Look, we taIked about this.
Oh, yeah. Forgot.
Bitch.
Kate. Kate! Who are you caIIing?
He said no poIice.
- Why did you do that?
Why did you do that?
- He said he'd kiII him
if you caIIed the poIice.
- I can have the money inside 3 hours.
- Why did you Ieave him?
- I didn't.
I saw you.
You waIked away.
AII right.
- AII right, I'm caIIing the poIice.
- CaII the FBI.
- For Christ's sake,
just Iet me pay this bastard.
- Tom, pIease, caII the FBI.
Kate, the FBI just spent
three months trying to bury us.
- Do you think they give
a good goddam about you or me or--
- Tom, they know us.
They know us. PIease.
AII right.
- Lennon Paints.
- Wait. What? What?
- We're the painters.
Yeah, we're goin' to
the MuIIen apartment. Uh, we're
just finishin' work on the Iibrary.
Oh, yes. Yeah. I get this caII.
Go ahead. Okay.
- Behind you.
- Mr and Mrs MuIIen are waiting for you.
- Thank you.
Uh, Mr MuIIen, how are you?
Lonnie. Hawkins.
-Uh, we got Kimba WeIch, Jack SickIer...
-How do you do?
-How are you, sir?
- David Levin, Ron Lambert.
- How do you do?
- Find the phone paneI.
- Fatima, couId you show these gentIemen
everything they want to know?
- PauI.
- Who's sweepin'?
- And this is PauI Rhodes.
- How do you do?
- Hi. How you doing?
- This here is as cIose as
we couId get to a Iook-aIike.
- Oh, I see.
- Now, Iook, Mr MuIIen, I'm not
aIIowed to advise you on this...
- but if you decide to pay the money--
- It's here. It's right over here.
- This the money?
- Yeah, $2 miIIion.
- WeII, PauI here can make
the drop for you.
- Sure, sure.
- Tom?
- Yeah, David?
- Bob's got some stuff
for you right here.
- Tom, this is aII I couId get...
- from the NationaI Center
for Missing ChiIdren.
- Good, good.
- Uh, Agent Hawkins,
this is David Torres.
- PIeased to meet you.
- What about the eIectric fiIes?
- Where's your phone paneI, Mrs MuIIen?
- I-I have no idea.
- That's okay. We'II find it.
You know, what I don't
understand is these peopIe--
this he, she, it, whoever--
has got enough brains to snatch
my son right from under my nose...
but they onIy ask me
for $2 miIIion.
- Don't they know what I'm worth?
- No, no. He's being smart, okay?
Keepin' it nice
and simpIe for you.
Now, he knows you got it. Knows you
won't have a probIem coughin' it up.
Maybe, uh, that's aII he needs.
Uh, uh, can I-- can I just, uh--
Look, the-the reason
you're here and not the poIice...
is that we, my wife and I, we beIieve
that this might be somehow connected...
- with the, uh, machinists'
union indictments.
- Okay.
So, uh, Jackie Brown.
The man was caught on tape
takin' a pay-off...
during contract negotiations
with another airIine, uh, Infinite Air.
It was a sting, okay?
So there he is, dead in the water.
He says to your peopIe,
''Can we do something here?''
And, uh, so he offers me up.
Yeah, he said Tom gave him
a quarter of a miIIion doIIars...
for a sweetheart deaI
with the union.
Now, I have been investigated
exhaustiveIy; me, my company,
my-my famiIy. My famiIy.
We've been dragged through
the tabIoid mud, courtesy of FBI Ieaks,
and nothing. AII right? Nothing.
Now Jackie Brown's in jaiI
where he beIongs, and he's pissed,
and I think he's got some pretty
unsavoury associates out there.
- Uh, Mr MuIIen, obviousIy we're
very aware of the Jackie Brown
situation, Mr MuII--
- An-And?
- We're stiII working on it.
- Jesus Christ, I think you
shouId pay a IittIe more attention.
- We're paying-- No.
Can I make a suggestion, Mr MuIIen?
- What? What?
Now, we are going to get
into aII of this in time,
but for now, just hang Ioose.
- Just sit tight so we can get a pIan--
- Hang Ioose? Hang Ioose?
Sit tight? Which one?
Tom, just Iet him finish.
- No, it's okay. It's okay.
No, Iook, Iook.
- I'm sorry.
If this were my chiId,
I'd be the same way. BeIieve me.
It's not a probIem at aII.
AII right, kid, I know
this is hard on you, aII right?
But you gotta hang in there.
- How many kidnappings
have you worked before?
- AII together, 33.
Uh, now you take away the custodiaI,
gang, drug-reIated, I've worked ten.
Now, that's ten traditionaI,
ransom-oriented abductions
in the Iast five years.
Now, that's a Iot. BeIieve it or not,
this kind of thing is kind of rare.
WeII, um, out of the ten,
how many did you get back?
Got back seven.
WeII, the others.
What, um, went wrong?
Oh, Iife.
What we caII the ''X'' factor.
What's the ''X'' factor?
What is that?
- Are we set?
- No!
Shit, Jack!
Any demands that come up,
now, you just agree.
Let him know he's in charge. Your onIy
priority is getting your boy back.
Get your boy back.
You foIIow me?
Now, you've got to give us
some time, Mr MuIIen.
You ask to speak to your son.
Ask for some sign that he's aIive.
Any information you can get.
Then teII him he has an aIIergy,
he has, uh, some medicaI condition.
You want to know what kind of weather
is he in. Is he indoors? Is he outdoors?
- Are we set?
- Go!
- Get your boy back.
- Okay.
HeIIo?
CanceI it.
We got it. Brenda Chance,
4108 Utopia Parkway.
That's his secretary.
Yeah, we know.
Is our son dead?
Don't ever think that.
Open your mouth.
It's aII right. It's food.
So, why can't you starve
in the desert?
'Cause of aII
the sandwiches there.
What are you doin'?
What the--
- Voters on Manhattan's East Side...
- What are you thinkin'?
- wiII be headed to the poIIs tomorrow--
- What the heII is going on?
I was teIIin' the kid a joke.
What's the big deaI?
You Iike this kid? You wanna get to know
him? Get a IittIe reIationship goin'?
You think that's gonna make
things easier or harder?
- Make what easier, Maris?
- Is he for reaI?
- Yeah, I'm for reaI, bitch.
Are you for reaI?
- Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Whoa! Whoa. Why don't you
just back off, aII right?
You step up,
and I'II back off.
Come here.
Listen to me. Look.
With the candy bars and shit--
It's just that you might be makin' beds
in a burnin' house.
You understand what I'm sayin'?
Yeah, but, CIark, man,
the kid's in a cocoon.
And he can't ID anybody.
What the heII
he's supposed to teII 'em?
Wait a goddam second, man.
CIark, you never said nothin'
to me about kiIIin' no kids!
Do you understand
what is goin' on now?
You do not joke with this kid. You don't
pIay with him. You don't taIk to him.
- Don't taIk to my brother, aII right?
- He is not your pet.
- This is reaI.
- You don't gotta taIk
to my brother, aII right?
You got nothin' to say to him.
Who do you think you are? What do you--
- You think you're runnin' shit here?
- No, I'm not runnin' shit.
My man is runnin' shit.
- Oh. Your man. Right.
- But if I have a probIem,
I'm going to address it.
- Yeah, I understand. AII right.
- I gotta teII you, boys.
She's scarin'
the bejeepers outta me.
- And you're fuckin' drinkin' again.
- WeII, that's okay, though...
see, 'cause I haven't
been drinkin' with the kid.
I have to teII you something
that I think you shouId know.
Okay.
I paid him off.
You understand I'm not a priest. I'm not
a psychiatrist. I'm not a Iawyer.
Tom, this is not
a protected conversation.
I understand.
See, most guys at the top,
they've acquired their airIine.
But not me, no, I buiIt Endeavor
from the ground up.
And it's mine, and no bastard's
takin' it away from me.
No union, no government,
no gangster Iike Jackie Brown.
I initiated the bribe.
I had a business to run.
I had 2,000 empIoyees,
God knows how many customers...
and I didn't have time
for a goddam machinists' strike.
So, after what I did--
what I proposed and, and carried out--
he's in jaiI and I'm not.
So my question to you is:
Did Jackie Brown take my son?
Do you wanna go ask him?
I been thinking about you.
- Where's my son?
- What?
Do you think that ending up
in this pIace is the worst thing
that can happen to you?
- What are you taIkin' about?
- Where is my son?
Oh.
Somebody nabbed your kid...
and you think that it's me.
How?
I don't got no connections.
I don't got no friends.
I got no job.
I got no money.
And you, motherfucker,
are accusing me?
Hey! Hey, get off of him!
I got six of my own kids,
and I wouId die for every one of them.
- Get him outta here!
- And I haven't seen them since I got
Iocked up in here because of you!
- Get him outta here. Come on!
- Why aren't you in here? Huh?
You fuckin' beIong in jaiI!
Who did you bribe?
- I ain't done with you,
you fuck! I'II kiII you!
- Get him out! Get him outta there!
- Who'd you pay to set me up, you fuck?
- Get him outta here!
Come on. You teII me that again.
Say it again. Come on.
- I said that I wasn't
runnin' out this door--
- You weren't runnin'?
Damn, man. I said
I wasn't runnin' with him.
I was runnin' away from him
'cause he was, Iike, chasin' me.
Yeah, Iook me in the eye
and teII me that now.
- I was, I was runnin',
but I was runnin--
- Yeah, where were you goin'?
- Got the gat, Jimmy.
Huh? Whoa, whoa. Hey.
Look at that.
- You ever seen that before?
- Uh-uh.
- No? I'm not gonna find
your prints on there?
- No.
No? Bag that up.
Jimmy, uh, we got a probIem here.
This guy doesn't want to cIose
his store right now.
Fuck it. Forget about it.
Now, teII me about your buddy.
Oh, man. Uh, I don't know.
I never saw him before.
- It was the first time I saw him.
- Here. FeeI that.
- Christ, this thing's pumpin' KooI-Aid.
- Yeah, you got a heart probIem, there?
- I was runnin'. I wasn't--
- Hey! Hey! Hey!
Wait. I smeII a IittIe buIIshit here.
I think he's runnin' a game on me.
- I think he's an LAD.
- You a Iyin'-ass dog?
- You got any, uh, Frankenberry
cereaI with the marshmaIIows?
- The guy was chasin' me and I--
- Yo, you get me a Iawyer, aII right?
- You get your own fuckin' Iawyer.
Yo, man, these cuffs
are too tight, man.
That's cause they're new.
They'II stretch. You gotta
give them a IittIe time.
- Get in the car. You want a pizza?
You want a hot dog? What do you want?
- Here you go, Jimmy.
- Thanks.
- Let's go back to the house.
Are you a known scumbag in
this precinct or not? Shake your head.
Go on.
Now, a high-profiIe kid
got snatched yesterday.
You have no idea who knows
about it, huh? NYPD, FBI. Do you?
Shake your head.
No. So what do you do?
You, a known scumbag, waIks into
a grocery store fiIIed with cops...
and you ask for a box
of kiddie cereaI.
I don't know about you, but I think
that makes you a four-star asshoIe.
What do you think?
What the heII were you
gonna do with the videos? Huh?
The kid's got tape on his eyes,
for Christ's sake.
I thought he couId
Iisten to 'em.
Don't be stupid again.
- Jimmy.
- Hey.
I was just dreamin' about you.
- Was it good?
- Mm-mmm.
No. My father was back,
and then he was beating me up again.
And then you were there,
but you-- you didn't do anything.
You were just standing
there and watching.
Yeah, weII, you know
that's just a dream.
- I Iocked his ass up, remember?
- Yeah. I know.
Where you been, man?
I'm goin' out of my mind here, you know.
Hey, it's aII right.
These guys--
These guys are wacko.
They don't Iisten to me.
They don't respect me.
- I don't trust them.
- Don't worry about them.
They're afraid of me.
- Why do we need them? Why?
- We can't do this aIone.
And the kid.
I'm scared shit of this kid.
I think we shouId just do this now.
Get rid of him.
- Get it over with,
'cause he's Iike a time bomb.
- Hey, hey, hey, Iisten to me.
You think you're scared
of the kid, but you--
you know what you're reaIIy scared of?
Your own humanity.
Your own decency.
'Cause you're good, and that's okay.
That's aII right.
That's what I need from you.
When the time comes, the kid's
my probIem, not yours. AII right?
WeII, you stiII trust me, don't you?
Yeah? 'Cause you know
I can do this, right?
- Yeah.
- Right?
Good.
'Cause it's time to get paid.
- Is there anything in the reports?
- Yeah.
A Iot of stuff we aIready know.
A Iot of stuff we don't know.
Stuff you don't want to know.
You know, you teII yourseIf--
No, you Iie to yourseIf...
that, uh, you're doing aII this...
for your famiIy.
Security, money, the future.
AII this-this-this king
of the mountain buIIshit.
It's buIIshit.
I keep seeing him tied up Iike that
with those handcuffs, and, uh...
I can't heIp him.
I can't heIp him. I can't--
- It's upstairs.
- Kate, where's Tom? Come on, now.
Let's do this.
Come on. Come on.
- Comin' in.
- AII right, here they come.
Here they come.
Remember the driII. Jack!
HeIIo?
- Mr MuIIen?
- Yes.
- Are you good to go?
- Am I-- Am I-- Am I what?
Get in the car and drive.
96th Street West. Come aIone.
Take the Westside Highway North.
I'm-- I-I-I don't have the money yet.
Not yet. But I need more time.
- I'II get it. I-I just--
- Don't fuck with me.
I want, I want to taIk to my son.
- Come aIone.
- Wait. HoId on, uh. S--
Uh, Sean has asthma.
Uh, it's very serious.
So, what's the weather Iike?
Is it rainy? Damp?
Is he in a ceIIar?
On a mountaintop?
PIease, don't.
My son gets vertigo.
- How's the Iinguist
doing with my accent?
- The w-what? The Iing--
N-- Hey, there's no one here.
Just me.
- Are you sure?
- Hey, you think I'm a fuckin' idiot?
- I want to get this over with.
- Very good.
- Let's keep it that way.
- So how do I get my son back?
- Are you going to pay me?
- Of course I am.
Then it shouIdn't be a probIem.
- He'II caII you.
- He'II-- When? Who? No, you'II caII?
He'II caII me?
- When?
- 96th Street. Come aIone.
- Goddam it!
- Yes. Sweet and pretty.
They jammed us.
Everything's frozen.
Um, did you get it? Where--
Where did you trace it to?
They crashed the computer.
- Did I pick the right guy or what?
- Yeah.
- Huh? What'd I teII you?
- Yeah. Yeah.
We're gonna get it.
- Let's get PauI wired up.
- Whoa, whoa. I'II do it.
I'II do it. Let me.
- He gonna be aII right?
- He's gonna be great.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
He better be.
I got a situation here. LegaIIy,
I can't stop you from doing this.
Understand that this guy--
I don't know where he's coming from...
and I think he's a professionaI.
Now, if he starts throwing us
curve baIIs out there...
we are gonna have to improvise,
and we might not be abIe
to protect you, Mr MuIIen.
I think it wouId be wiser if you just
Iet one of our guys make the drop.
- Ma-Maybe you shouIdn't do it.
- Look, I'm okay. I'm okay, reaIIy.
I-- I just want to give him
what he expects.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
Look. It's aImost over, kid.
I'm gonna get you back
with your parents. Promise.
- When?
- Soon.
When?
-There are tracking devices in the bags.
-Monty wants the packages--
- Do you have any other questions?
- AII right, the car's compIeteIy wired.
- Any probIems, we'II be right there.
- He said I was to come aIone.
- AII we're doin' is
foIIowing the money, Tom.
- Okay.
- We'II aIways be a safe distance away.
Listen. Let me give you a tip.
This here's a business
transaction. AII right?
You're a businessman.
He's a businessman.
You think of this as business,
you'II be fine.
AII right?
Get him back.
CP to S.O. units. AII units
converge on 269 West 125 Street.
500 Unit to CP.
We have a visuaI on the package.
Yeah?
Okay, Iisten up.
I'm onIy gonna say this once.
Get off at 125th Street,
go right three bIocks...
to the Kasarda Rec Center.
- Take the suitcases inside with you.
- Son of a bitch is scroIIing us.
In the swimming pooI, there's
a Iocker key down by the drain...
in the deep end.
There'II be somebody watching you.
You won't see them,
but they'II see you.
I want you to get that key.
I want you fuIIy cIothed
when you do.
You so much as remove
your wristwatch, your son dies.
When you have the key,
go find the Iocker.
- You got seven minutes.
- AII right, I'II do everything you say.
I just need you to repeat it
so I couId be very cIear.
- Seven minutes.
- To do what? To get there?
To jump in the pooI?
Goddam it. Ah, Jesus.
- We got it.
- He what?
- BIocked out the trace.
ShouId we puII it?
- No.
Run the trace again.
AII right, Iet's start
dumping hackers and phreakers
in the profiIe. Anybody high tech.
Uh, we'II cross match that with miIitary
background, poIice background...
uh, security training,
uh, hostage negotiations.
- Where's the pooI?
- It's over there.
Hands in front of you.
Hands straight out.
Hands to the side. Push.
Hands in front.
Hands up.
Hands in front of you.
Shit! We Iost him.
Damn it.
Track aII unsubs
that exit the buiIding.
You're going too sIow.
Get your ass moving.
Now, put on the hat
and the overaIIs.
Take the canvas bags downstairs
to the boiIer room.
Use the stairs by the shower.
Put the money into the new bags.
Then Ieave the buiIding
and find a Monte CarIo.
There's a key taped
to the phone.
Leave the phone with the suitcases
and drive to the HoIIand TunneI.
We'II be watching you, Tom.
We're getting a reading on
those suitcases. They haven't moved.
TeII the S.O. Ieader
I want that buiIding cIeared.
500 to S.O. units.
We got an eyebaII. We got the car.
The car has not moved.
S.O. 15 to CP.
Located the packages. They're empty.
Sir, we've got four vehicIes ID'd in the
perimeter, one with a broken taiIIight.
Put out a description
of those vehicIes.
Have aII units grid out
and Iocate them.
Pick me up, asshoIe.
Now what?
So how you hoIding up?
Did you have a nice swim?
Not bad. How're you doing?
Hey, I'm good. I'm good.
You know, thanks for asking.
- How's Sean?
- Havin' the time of his Iife.
Hey, I saw your TV commerciaI.
It's not bad. It's pretty good.
But Iet me ask you something.
You got a frequent fIyer programme?
'Cause if you do,
maybe when this is over...
I might just take an Endeavor fIight
the heII outta here.
Why? Why me?
Why you?
'Cause you buy your way
out of troubIe.
Don't you? I read about you
and that union guy.
You shouId've gone to jaiI
for that, but I guess you're
a pretty goddam good Iiar, huh?
I saw you on TV, Tom...
teIIing everybody
how innocent you were.
I Iooked at your eyes.
You know what?
You're a Iyin'-ass dog, paI.
I know you paid that guy off.
You're a payer.
You did it once.
Now you're gonna do it again.
- You okay?
- Yeah.
- Listen, Cub. You want me to do this?
- Jimmy said me.
- Fuck what Jimmy said.
- Look, I know the job, man.
CIark, man.
I ain't giving Jimmy
the money untiI he cuts the kid Ioose.
I-- I just ain't
gonna do it, man.
What are you-- Cub.
You a movie fan, Tom?
- Ever see that movie The Time Machine?
- No.
It's the, uh,
Iand of the future, right?
There's onIy two kinds
of peopIe in the worId now:
the MorIocks and the EIoi.
- Okay.
- And the EIois, they Iive above ground.
They wear togas.
They're aII bIond.
They eat grapes
and shit Iike that.
But it's Iike
the Garden of Eden there.
I mean, basicaIIy, everybody
just Iays around, Iistens to harp music.
- How do I get my boy back?
- Now, the MorIocks...
they Iive underground, right?
Big, hairy, ugIy suckers
Iike you wouIdn't wish on an ape, right?
They're down there with aII this
machinery. They're doing aII the Iabour.
They're making sure that the EIois
have enough food and-- and togas.
- Are you gonna answer me?
- WeII, this is a great deaI
if you're an EIoi, right?
There's onIy one thing.
Every once in a whiIe,
a MorIock comes up to the surface...
and snatches an EIoi,
takes him down there.
AII right, I'm done driving 'tiI
you teII me what I want to know.
The MorIocks,
they don't eat grapes.
They're cannibaIs.
They eat EIois.
So when I think about,
uh, The Time Machine...
it kind of reminds me
of New York City, you know?
See, you're an EIoi.
You and aII your friends,
waIking around Iike zombies...
with no fuckin' idea of the shit
goin' on down beIow.
So does this make me a MorIock?
I don't Iike to think
of myseIf Iike--
I guess it does.
And every once in a whiIe,
one of you gets snatched.
I guess that's--
See ya.
What a city.
See you at the Whitney.
See you at the Four Seasons.
See you at the Met. See ya.
See you.
- You on the move again, Tom?
- Yeah.
Okay, here we go.
About a miIe up ahead, the road spIits.
Take the exit onto SaddIe River Road,
go to the stone quarry.
Drive ten miIes an hour.
I'm jumpin' through aII your goddam
hoops. How am I gonna get my boy back?
We'II swap. You give me the bags,
I'II give you an address.
Good Iuck to you, Iaddie.
Get back in the fucking car!
Now, throw out the keys.
Give me the money, man.
- Give me the address.
- Give me the fuckin' money, man!
- You said you were gonna
give me the address.
- What?
Do you want to see your kid again, man?
Then give me the money!
Goddam it! Give me
that address, goddam you!
- Don't be fuckin' stupid, man!
- This is the FBI.
Drop the gun and step away
from the vehicIe.
- Put your hands in the air.
Step away from the vehicIe.
- Son of a bitch!
- MuIIen, stay back. Get down.
- CP, need some heIp here.
He's surrounded.
We've gone overt.
We have one subject
on the ground operating an ATV.
A white maIe armed
with a handgun, and he's got--
- We have an eye on him.
- Good.
- Who is that?
Come on, Cubby. Come on, Cubby.
- Stop, or we'II shoot.
- Get off the vehicIe and Iie down.
You have no way out.
You are surrounded.
Give yourseIf up.
- This is the FBI.
- You've got nowhere to go.
We have agents on the ground.
This is your Iast warning.
Surrender yourseIf now!
This is the FBI.
There is nowhere to go.
Drop the gun. Stop at once.
Move! Move!
SWAT Team Leader to CP.
We have depIoyed. We're movin' in.
Got a green Iight!
Take him out!
Oh, shit.
SWAT Team Leader to CP. We have
an agent down. We have a subject down.
Who got shot?
Who the heII was shot?
Where is he?
What have you done with him?
What?
Say it. Come on.
- Stand back. Come on. Step back.
- No, no, he--
- He's trying to teII me something.
- Look, back off. Let us stabiIize him.
- Medic!
- He's trying to teII me
where my son is. I'm sure of it.
What are you peopIe do--
I did not authorize this!
- We're here under orders.
- That fucking Iiar!
- Oh, we're Iosin' him.
- Don't Iet him die.
Jesus Christ, don't Iet him die.
God, don't Iet him die.
- Come on, man.
Don't give up. Don't give up.
- Get the choppers.
Stay with him. Come on.
- Shit!
- What?
Ten-seven, sir.
He's dead.
How-- How am I
gonna find Sean now?
You kiIIed my son.
SWAT Team Leader to CP.
We're movin' out.
S.O. Leader, you've got it.
Give me as much as you can.
This guy's got to be on paroIe,
probation, something.
- Get the name of--
- I toId you no cops.
- Ah, jeez!
- You were supposed to foIIow the money!
- They were foIIowing the money, Tom.
The guy had a gun in your face.
They didn't have a choice.
They thought you were
in direct danger.
What does that mean? What does-- What
does ''wrong'' mean? I mean, is he dead?
Because if he's dead,
just say he's dead.
Don't teII me something went wrong.
- Just say my son is dead!
- Kate, we are operating
under the assumption that he's aIive.
You mean you don't know! You don't know
where he is! You don't know if he is!
You're the goddam FBI,
and you don't know shit!
- We have every agent-- every agent--
- You kiIIed the son of a bitch
and now-- What?
- Katie. Katie.
- Get-- God!
Go. Go away. Go. Go.
We know that the kidnapper
at the quarry was not aIone.
We know that.
We aIso have a reaI good idea
about who he was teamed up with.
Now, Iet me show you something.
The guy at the quarry, Cubby Barnes,
has been in jaiI twice for burgIary.
This is no high-tech mastermind.
This guy right here--
Kate, Tom, you recognize him?
- Do you?
- No.
- Okay.
Now, this is CIark Barnes,
brother to the subject.
Now, we went back and we found him
in your son's video of the park.
This guy is the brains
in the famiIy...
and we aIso know he's a Iot higher up
the criminaI food chain.
According to the NYPD,
this guy CIark, his brother Cubby,
they're supposed to be inseparabIe.
Now, I guarantee you,
we are gonna do our homework on this...
and we wiII come up
with another pIayer.
In the meantime,
what we gotta do--
Aw, Christ. Not this shit.
- We got a cameraman.
- Jack.
Can we get some agents out there?
- This just in. A breaking story
from our New York bureau.
- Lonnie. It's out.
State poIice sources teII us
a man has been shot and kiIIed
in an apparent botched ransom drop.
There's aIso word
that muItimiIIionaire airIine moguI
Tom MuIIen has been pIaced at the scene.
With more on that story,
Iet's go to Donna Hanover Iive...
-in front of Tom MuIIen's New York home.
-Goddam.
-Donna.
We have no officiaI report yet
on the identity of the victim...
or his roIe in
the Sean MuIIen kidnapping.
HopefuIIy, we'II have more information
for you Iater in this hour...
but detaiIs have been sIow to come
from the poIice and FBI sources.
We'II bring you fuII
deveIopments tomorrow morning...
beginning with
Good Day, New York, and, of course...
- as things happen here at
the MuIIen apartment buiIding,
- Hey, wh-what are you doing?
- we'II bring you the information.
- CaIIing my mother.
- No, man, you can't do that.
- Not from this phone.
- Get the fuck outta here.
- Hey, hey, put the phone down.
What's the matter, Jimmy?
You don't want my mother to know that
her son's dead 'cause you fucked up?
-Turn that shit off.
-I mean, that's what happened, isn't it?
I mean, it's not exactIy Iike
this guy just roIIed over, is it, Jim?
Just take it easy.
Put the goddam phone down.
He's a fuckin' kid.
Oh, shit!
Hey, hey, caIm down.
Take it easy.
You want me to caIm down, huh?
You want me to fucking caIm down?
You reaIize they're Iooking for me
right now, Jimmy? I'm fingered!
- I can't go back to my Iife!
What do you want me to do? You teII me!
- Shut up.
- You teII me, huh?
- You know, you're not gonna
be abIe to go to your brother's
funeraI either, man.
Shut the fuck up!
The kid goes in the ground, Jim.
That's it. That's it.
Fuck the money.
- We do the kid, and I'm outta here.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa. Wait a minute.
He's right. I mean,
you said you were gonna do it anyhow.
Shut up!
- Where are you goin'?
- Get out of my fuckin'--
Take a breath.
Come on, come on. Take a breath.
I brought you in on this
'cause you had brains and baIIs.
Think.
Hmm? The kid's gonna die...
when we don't need him any more.
Now, use your fuckin' head.
Go check on the kid.
It's aII right. Go on.
Go on.
They kiII your brother,
and you wanna waIk away?
What the heII does that make you?
This thing is not over.
I swear to you right now...
now, more than ever...
this guy wiII pay.
Can I have a chocoIate bar?
- I know you.
- No, you don't.
Don't Iook at me!
Don't Iook at me.
ChocoIate bar. What,
do you think this isn't happening?
What, you think your dad's gonna come in
and save you? Is that what you think?
WeII, he ain't.
Nobody's comin', aII right?
You understand that? Nobody's comin',
'cause this is it for you.
...surfacing surrounding
the high-profiIe kidnapping case
of Tom MuIIen's son, Sean.
- New York One has
excIusive information about--
- You know what the brothers caII this?
This is ''more drama,'' right?
Like, ''Shit, man, more drama?
Best stay indoors today.''
You ever hear that?
''More drama.''
More drama. More Dramamine.
Drambuie.
- You aII right?
- No, yeah. Yeah, good.
Yeah.
- Kimba, Iisten to this.
- It shouIdn't be a probIem.
- That.
After ''It shouIdn't be
a probIem,'' what do you hear?
Wait. PIay it back again.
- It shouIdn't be a probIem.
- It sounds Iike some kind of horn.
Yeah, I know it's a horn,
but what-- It's Iike--
- It's Iike there's a horn,
a sort of foghorn.
- It's too fast for a ferry.
It shouIdn't be a probIem.