Sir, what's that there?
What's that?
Well, that's not the cuttlefish
that I told you to look for.
That's for a start.
That is an insulator.
Aye, an insulator, that is.
Probably off a German battleship.
I'm sure there's no German
battleships coming here, sir.
- You don't know, there might be.
- No, Timmy's right.
Now, tell me this.
Why is there so much
stuff around Killins Bay?
It's a tide... Tidal
eddy around the head.
Tidal eddy. Very good, Tim. Good.
All right, come on,
now. Go on looking.
The tide's going
down. Go on, hurry up.
Go on, Kathleen. Off with the others.
You never know, you might
find a diamond tiara.
Sir, sir.
Aye, that's a cuttlefish.
- Good lad.
- I'll try and find a bigger one.
You do that, Tim.
Come on.
What is it, sir?
No, it's nothing. Nothing.
'Tis all right, Kathy.
Come on.
Time we had lunch.
We're eating at Barrow.
It's a long way to Barrow, sir.
Step off, then. That's
where we're eating.
Tide's coming in, sir.
So it is.
Hey, would you look at Michael?
Michael.
It's the Major.
Hey, Tom, will you
have a look at this?
He's getting worse, you know.
Michael, let's have
a look at your V.C.
- How many Germans did you kill, Michael?
- All right.
All right, very entertaining.
Michael, you're a perfect fool.
You ask for trouble. Come on,
now, take the foolish things off.
Michael, take them off, now. Come on.
Michael!
What's eating him?
- What've you been doing?
- Don't know, Father.
We've not done anything.
Come on now, Michael.
What're you up to?
Let go!
Michael, let go, or I'll hit you.
Michael, darling, let go.
Major, darling, let me touch your V.C.
You see, my husband hasn't got one.
Well?
Well.
What was the meaning
of that pantomime?
I don't know.
- Where have you been?
- Riding...
- with Major Doryan.
- You're bold as brass.
You think that's a suitable
connection for a decent Irish wife?
I think that is for my
husband to say, Father Hugh.
- You've told him, have you?
- Yes.
Yes, you would.
Your husband would say anything
you wanted, pretty well...
because he loves you
sorely, doesn't he?
- Yes, he does.
- Have you nothing to say to me?
- What should I have to say to you?
- You could say:
"Father Hugh, there's nothing
between me and Major Doryan. "
- There isn't.
- Say it, then.
There is nothing between
me and Major Doryan.
Look at me, Rosy.
Oh, child, what a face.
- Rose, tell me now.
- What?
You'll have to tell it in
confessional, you little fool.
I don't have to come...
- to the confessional.
- Child!
Child?
- Father.
- Hello, then.
Rosy...
was there something?
No, I just...
- Will you take the prayers, then?
- Aye.
"Our Father...
"who art in Heaven,
hallowed be thy name.
"Thy kingdom come, Thy will be done...
"on Earth as it is in heaven.
"Give us this day our daily bread.
And forgive us our trespasses...
"as we forgive those
who trespass against us.
"And lead us not into temptation,
but deliver us from evil. "
In the name of the Father and
of the Son and of the Holy Ghost.
All right, children, off with you.
Thank you, Father. Good day.
Glad to help, Charles.
Is there anything else
I can help you with?
No, I don't think so.
Well, I'll be off home, too, then.
- You're late.
- I took them for a nature walk.
Up Brandon?
Along the shore.
- For cuttlefish?
- Aye.
For cuttlefish.
If you'd come up Brandon,
we might have seen you.
Why?
- Did you go to Brandon?
- Aye.
I got some heather.
So you did.
You haven't been to the beach, then?
No.
Oh, well.
- It's nice up Brandon.
- Aye, it's grand.
Is something the matter?
I don't know, Rose. Is there?
There's nothing the matter with me.
Nothing's the matter, then.
And the jam, and the...
The jam...
and the soap.
Maggie.
That'll be 18 pence.
Could it wait to the
end of the week, missus?
Aye, to the end of the week.
Not to the crack of doom.
Thank you.
- What was it, then?
- I want a dishcloth, please.
- I've none.
- Oh.
Then I'll just take some
potatoes. Five pound.
I've no potatoes, either.
What's them, then?
Aye, them.
They're gone. I've no potatoes.
Oh, I... I see.
The way I see it, Mrs. Kenyon, there's
loose women and there's whores...
and then there's
British soldiers' whores.
- Coming up fast, Father.
- Aye.
Will you look at those things?
You'd think they was
announcing the coming of Christ.
- Off you go!
- Right.
Put her down!
Slowly does it.
All right, now! That's it. Come
on, Joe, there's a good lad.
Come on, it's late.
All right. Come on, Sean.
Come on, Tom. You've
got to go to sleep.
Go on. Good night!
Hello, Tom.
- You? What are you doing here?
- Come on, now, Tom.
Phoenix Park, 1913.
Tim O'Leary.
Come on.
Right, lads.
Now, what do you usually
do at this time, Tom?
- I go to bed.
- Right.
This is Bernard. Go on up, lads.
- Paddy.
Sean.
Joseph, Peter...
Mr. O'Keefe.
- And you know Pat.
- Which room?
At the back.
But, Commandant,
sir, what's happening?
Guns, is it?
- That's right, Tom. German guns.
- German?
Dynamite, grenades. All the
stuff the movement needs.
We tried to launch the boat...
- You must get to them somehow, then.
- We can't.
But Sean here says there's a good chance
some of it will break away and come to us.
- Float in?
- You're on to it.
But, if it does, we won't know where.
You can't see the nose on
your face out there now.
So we'll wait till daylight.
- Absolute madness.
- Will you shut up?
Tom...
if it's to be done in
daylight, it's to be done quick.
So we must have some
fellows, say a dozen...
good, strong fellows, and
that's where you come in.
- What if it don't break away?
- Exactly.
Then we'll wait one
hour and go without it.
One hour, Tom...
and 12 strong men.
That's all I'm asking.
Can you do it?
I could rout out a dozen, yes.
- Do you want them now?
- Not at all.
The later they know
we're here, the better.
You let them lie till nearer morning.
Can you find us something to
eat? It's gonna be a long night.
Paddy, Tom.
Take the Constable his breakfast.
Jesus and Mary, what a night.
Now, do not make one sound, Constable.
Right. You.
Fat guts, get the handcuffs.
- Where are they?
- In the cupboard.
Turn around.
- I'm acting under duress.
- Shut up.
Put them on him.
Open your mouth, Constable.
Is that a telephone line?
Cut it.
Oh, God.
Why have you done this to me?
Hello?
This is Ryan.
- Did you cut the wire?
- I did.
You're doing well, Tom.
- Where's the Constable?
- In the cellar.
We can put a bullet
in him if you like.
Constable... No!
- Then get your men.
- Aye, Commandant.
Right.
They've gone!
Busted loose!
It's no good, Commandant!
Why don't you get up
out of it while you can?
Tim!
- Hey, are you Tim O'Leary?
- Yes, son, yes.
Father, what the hell
have you done this for?
I didn't, they did!
Well, do you know what you're doing?
- Do you know what we've come for?
- Aye.
- Have you got it?
- Well, look.
- T'will be on the slabs.
- Where?
The slabs!
Tim!
Come on.
Yes, Kathy?
- Aren't you coming to the beach, sir?
- The beach?
Everyone's at the beach.
- And why is everyone at the beach?
- I don't know, sir. I think it's a wreck.
A wreck?
Now, that's enough, Tom. You're
not as young as you used to be.
Aye, come on!
Oh, God.
Pull!
Right, up you get. You, too,
Father. Up. Keep it going.
That's right, darling.
That's right.
Hey!
Dynamite.
What are you doing here?
- Why shouldn't I be?
- Why?
Thank you, ma'am.
You know, we made speeches
about these people...
but, by God...
Thanks. You're a man!
Come on, then!
One!
Two!
Three!
Sean?
- I must take a chance.
- Aye.
Good luck.
Thank you. Get down, please.
- Sergeant?
- Sir.
You, here. You.
No. No trouble now,
for your own sakes.
O'Leary.
That thing could kill
a lot of people, Major.
Sir?
No.
Go on. Run, Tim!
Run, Tim.
Make it, Tim. Come on!
- Run.
- O'Leary!
Sir.
- No!
- Murderer!
- Don't shoot.
What's wrong with the bastard?
Boo!
Shoot that slut, Shaughnessy.
Careful, man.
My God, they're a well-matched pair.
All right, sir?
- Got a cigarette?
- Yes, sir.
Is there anything you want?
Cigarette.
- Anything else?
- Yes.
Get out of my country.
God bless you, Tim O'Leary!
What are they going to
do with them boys, Father?
They'll hang them, dear.
They'll hang them.
Bastard!
Get out!
You're very kind to me today.
Am I?
Yes. Why?
Am I not usually kind to you?
Yes, you are. Always.
Charles, do you know or not?
I know.
- Since when?
- The beginning.
Don't lower your head, Rose.
Why didn't you speak?
I should have, shouldn't I?
I don't know.
It was easier not to, I suppose.
I didn't want to know, you know.
And then I thought, if I let you
burn it out, the pair of you...
you'd perhaps come back to me.
Charles?
Mr. Shaughnessy has been called
away, so I'm taking class.
What's the first lesson today, Danny?
- Danny?
- My father says not to speak to you, miss.
- It's right then, he's not here?
- No.
I don't know where he is.
- You mean he's gone off?
- Yes.
When?
Last night.
You had a row?
I wasn't here.
Where were you?
Oh, I see.
There's nothing I can do tonight,
I'll find him in the morning.
- If he turns up, you'll tell me.
- Father?
You'd better take his clothes.
His clothes?
He was in bed?
Yes.
You left his bed and went to...
Rose.
Oh, Rose.
Come on, this isn't a picnic.
All right, Corp, but
there's nothing here.
He's got something there, sir.
Padre.
Good morning, padre.
I'm sorry, but what is
it you have there, please?
A man's clothes.
I see.
- And where are you taking them, Father?
- To the man.
Come on, padre. I don't
suppose you mean any harm...
but after the other day, we've
got to be careful. What man?
A man whose wife went off two
nights back with her fancy fellow.
And a man I've been looking
for since dawn today.
- A man- -
Excuse me, sir.
A man who must be half out of his mind
to have gone off as he did, barefoot.
That's right. Charles Shaughnessy.
I think we're finished here, sir.
Very well.
- Hello, Charles.
- Hello, Father.
I've brought your clothes.
Thanks, Father. I was
wondering how I should get home.
- And something to drink.
- Thanks.
- Yourself?
- Aye, I will.
- You seem all right, man.
- Aye, more or less.
Well, I'll get dressed now.
Michael.
He'll be after catching
a few flounders.
So, what have you been
doing down here, Charles?
Oh, thinking.
About Rosy?
About myself, mostly.
Thanks for the clothes. You're
a man in a million, Father Hugh.
The children haven't come today, then?
No.
Rose, I have something
to say to you. Come in.
Sit down, will you?
Rose, I thought I could stand by and
let you two burn it out, like I said.
But I find I can't.
I'm not sure I ought to have
tried, but anyway, I can't.
So I'm going to leave you.
- Very well.
- Sit still a minute, Rose.
What about you? You and him?
- Nothing.
- What do you mean, nothing?
It's over.
Was that because I
went and stayed away?
No.
It's over.
- Have you told him?
- No.
He doesn't know, then?
Yes, he knows.
How?
He must.
You're as close as that, are you?
We were, yes.
Rose, you must tell me the truth.
Do you think you're
ever gonna forget him?
Of course not.
He'd be like a ghost about the place.
Rose, am I right?
Yes, you're right.
It's busted, Charles.
I busted it.
Now, have you thought what to do?
- No.
- Well, I have.
I don't think either of us can
stay in this village any longer.
No.
It's time I moved on anyway. And
you were never worse suited here.
I've reckoned up, I've
got about 200 pounds.
Take all this, without the
gramophone, fetch another 50.
We'll split it down the middle.
I can't do it.
We're not enemies, Rose.
Stop that! There's to be none of that.
But why must it be Rosy?
Because she was
fornicating with the fellow.
So, you're back, are you?
What is this? What do you want?
- Not you.
- Well, then get out.
- Go on, get out.
- Shut up, Shaughnessy.
We're waiting for her.
You.
You've been tried and found
guilty. You're the informer.
- What?
- Busting at the seams with innocence.
Joe, for God's sake, don't
hurt her, Joe. Don't hurt her.
If she was a man, Mr.
Ryan, she'd be shot.
- What is this?
- Listen, numbskull.
Someone that morning
went up to the camp...
and betrayed Tim O'Leary.
Now, who lives near
enough? Who had time enough?
Who would? Who did?
That bitch you call your wife.
String her up!
But anyone could have, if anyone
did. The whole village was abroad.
No. The village was down on the beach.
- Except you.
- You came late.
- We came together. We spoke to no one.
- You'd say that, of course.
Young Kathy was with us.
Young Kathy would say black
was white if you told her.
Then anyone, anyone at all could've
gone into the police station...
- and used the telephone.
- That's where you're wrong.
They couldn't. Could they, Tom?
- No.
- Why not?
Because Tom went in there
himself and cut the wire.
Didn't you, Tom?
Well, you went in there
yourself, didn't you?
- Yes.
- And you cut the wire, didn't you?
Yes.
Well, what do you say now?
Nothing.
Take her out.
No, you're taking her nowhere.
Stop it!
- Informer.
- There she is!
Hold him.
Take him by the hands.
Quiet! Get back!
Get back!
Do it.
Princess...
What is it?
There she is.
Look here, Father Hugh, the
stripping of her was an accident.
Steady, Joe.
You're taking advantage
of your cloth, Father Hugh.
- That's what it's for.
- Come on, Joe.
It's not right. A
priest is only a man.
Go on.
Go on, Michael, get off.
Get off out of it!
Hello.
Keep it.
What?
They really thought...
I was the one who betrayed that man.
Rose...
I don't for one moment suppose
that anyone betrayed him.
Why should they? They just...
They just wanted it so, that's all.
And they wanted it to be you, too.
For other reasons.
Truth was told, they envy
you. They always have.
They've always had a rare,
old contempt for me, too.
I tell you, I'm not for letting any
of that lot know we've busted up.
We'll just keep up a front
until I'm well and out of it.
What?
I don't know.
It just seemed funny, that's all.
Michael, give that to me.
All right, keep it.
I thought we were friends.
That one, too. Give it to me.
No! Look.
For Christ's sake, man,
I'm not going to hurt you.
- It'll be the soldiers.
- Soldiers?
Aye.
The beach was fairly littered with
stuff. They'll be destroying it.
Oh, yes.
Come on, lads, pick them up.
What about my blisters, Corporal?
- Well, they're not mourning long.
- No.
Does she think he killed
himself deliberate?
She says...
I think he was a man who
suffered, Father Hugh.
You love her sorely,
don't you, Charles?
Yes.
- Ready, then?
- Yes.
It's not all your doing, Rosy.
I should not have married you.
No.
You can tell Father Hugh that
we're parting if you like.
No.
- Rosy.
- Father.
It'll be a fair day for
the journey, yet, I think.
I hope so, yes.
Well, now, how shall we manage?
Margaret.
Come here, Margaret. Come here.
Kathy, come in.
Kathy, will I take the belt to you?
Take my arm.
A rousing sendoff.
We'll be out of it in five minutes.
Dad.
Goodbye, Dad.
Bye, princess.
I'm all right.
- Are you, darling?
- Aye.
I'm looking forward
to Dublin and that.
Really.
That's your mother speaking.
- Do you remember your mother, Rose?
- A bit.
Do you, like...
- remember the rows?
- Aye.
- I never raised a fist to her, Rose.
- I know that, Dad.
You wouldn't hurt a fly
if you could help it.
- I'll write to you.
- And I'll write to you.
- Well, maybe.
- No. I swear to God, Rose.
- I will write every...
Every- - All right, Dad.
We'll both write regular.
Bye-bye.
Well, wait a minute, I must
say goodbye to your husband.
You know, Rose...
when you married him, I thought
you could have done a lot better.
Now I'm not so sure
they come much better.
Would you tell him that?
It's not a thing one fellow
can easily say to another.
Shaughnessy.
Mike.
Goodbye, Shaughnessy.
Goodbye, Mr. Ryan.
Are you all right for money,
you two? I have a bit by me.
We're fine for money,
Dad. Thanks. Goodbye.
Good luck.
- Get out and don't come back!
- Get out!
Informer.
Bus will be here in a minute.
It's brightened for you, like I said.
Aye.
Grand day for a journey.
Sign of good luck.
Thanks.
Bus is coming.
You won't have an address
in Dublin yet, I suppose.
No, Father, we...
I've wrote down here the name
and address of a decent woman...
who'll ask six shillings a week
for a dry room and a clean bed.
Six shillings, the pair of you.
You'll not do better
than that, not in Dublin.
No, I don't suppose so.
Thanks, Father.
Bye, Michael.
I have a parting gift
for you here, Rose.
It's supposed to be a fragment
of St. Patrick's staff.
I don't suppose it is, though.
God bless you, child.
Come on, now. Come on, get on up.
I'll help you load up.
Thanks, Father. Thanks
for a great many things.
Charles?
I think you have it in your mind
that you and Rosy ought to part.
Yes, I thought as much.
Well, maybe you're right,
maybe you ought, but I doubt it.
And that's my parting
gift to you. That doubt.
God bless.
I don't know.
I don't know at all. Come on, Michael.