Salomé was written by
Oscar Wilde in 1893
and it was unlike any
of his other works.
He wrote the play deliberately
in a lush and ornate style.
It takes place in the ancient city
of Judaea, in King Herod's palace
and all references in the play relate
to that specific biblical era.
The company of actors are
interpreting the play in modern dress,
but all references in the
play relate to that period,
just before the
death of Christ.
How beautiful is the
Princess Salomé tonight!
Look at the moon! How
strange the moon seems.
She is like a woman
rising from a tomb.
She is like
a dead woman.
You would fancy she was
looking for dead things.
She has a strange look. She's like a
little princess who wears a yellow veil,
and whose feet
are of silver.
She is like a princess who has
little white doves for feet.
She is like a
woman who is dead.
She moves
very slowly.
Who are those wild
beasts howling?
The Jews. They are
always like that.
They are disputing
about their religion.
Why do they dispute
about their religion?
I cannot tell. They
are always doing it.
I think it is ridiculous to
dispute about such things.
How beautiful is the
Princess Salomé tonight!
You are always
looking at her.
You look at
her too much.
It is dangerous to look
at people in such fashion.
Something terrible
may happen.
She is very
beautiful tonight.
The Tetrarch has
a sombre look.
Yes, he has a
sombre look.
He is looking
at something.
at someone.
At whom is
he looking?
I cannot tell.
Herodias has filled the
cup of the Tetrarch.
ls that the Queen Herodias? -Yes,
that is Herodias, the Tetrarch's wife.
After me shall come
another mightier than I.
I am not worthy so much as to
unloose the latchet of His shoes.
When He cometh, the solitary
places shall be glad.
They shall blossom
like the lily.
The eyes of the blind
shall see the day,
and the ears of the
deaf shall be opened.
The new-born child
shall put his hand...
Make him be silent. He is
always saying ridiculous things.
No, no. He is
a holy man.
He is very gentle, too. Every day,
when I give him to eat, he thanks me.
Who is he?
-A prophet.
What is his
name? -Jokanaan.
He came from the desert, where
he fed on locusts and wild honey.
A great multitude used to follow
him. He even had disciples.
What is he talking of? -We can never
tell. Sometimes he says terrible things,
but it is impossible to
understand what he says.
May one see him? -No. The
Tetrarch has forbidden it.
The Princess has hidden
her face behind her fan!
Her little white hands are fluttering
like doves that fly to their dove-cots.
They are like white butterflies.
They are just like white butterflies.
What is that to you?
Why do you look at her?
You must not look at her.
Something terrible may happen.
What a strange prison.
-It is an old cistern.
An old cistern. It
must be very unhealthy.
Oh, no! For instance, the Tetrarch's
brother, his elder brother,
the first husband of Herodias the Queen,
was imprisoned there for 12 years.
It did not kill him. At the end of
the 12 years he had to be strangled.
Strangled? Who
dared to do that?
That man yonder,
Naaman, the executioner.
He was not afraid? -Oh, no!
The Tetrarch sent him the ring.
What ring? -The death-ring.
So he was not afraid.
Yet it is a terrible
thing to strangle a king.
Why? Kings have but one
neck, like other folk.
I think it
terrible.
The Princess rises! She
is leaving the table!
She looks very troubled. How pale she
is! Never have I seen her so pale.
Do not look at her. I pray
you not to look at her.
She is like a dove
that has strayed.
She is like a narcissus
trembling in the wind.
She is like a
silver flower.
I will not stay.
I cannot stay.
Why does the Tetrarch
look at me all the while
with his mole's eyes
under his shaking eyelids?
It is strange that the husband of
my mother looks at me that way.
I know not what it means.
In truth, yes, I know it.
You have just left
the feast, Princess?
How sweet the air is
here! I can breathe here!
Inside there are
Jews from Jerusalem
who are tearing each other to pieces
over their foolish ceremonies,
and barbarians who drink and drink,
and spill their wine on the pavement,
and Greeks from Smyrna with
painted eyes and painted cheeks
and frizzed hair curled
in twisted coils,
and silent, subtle Egyptians, with
long nails of jade and russet cloaks,
and Romans brutal and coarse,
with their unoouth jargon.
Ah! How l loathe
the Romans!
They are rough and common, and they
give themselves the airs of noble lords.
Will you be
seated, Princess?
Why do you speak to her? Why do you look
at her? Something terrible may happen.
How good to see the moon! She
is like a little piece of money,
you would think she was
a little silver flower.
The moon is
cold and chaste.
I am sure she is a virgin,
she has a Virgin's beauty.
Yes, she is a virgin.
She has never defiled herself.
She has never abandoned herself
to men, like the other goddesses.
The Lord hath come. The son of
man, the son of man hath come.
He hath come!
The son of
man hath come.
Who was that who cried out?
-The prophet, Princess.
Ah, the prophet! He of whom
the Tetrarch is afraid?
We know nothing
of that, Princess.
It was the prophet
Jokanaan who cried out.
ls it your pleasure that I bid
them bring your litter, Princess?
The night is fair
in the garden.
He says terrible things
about my mother, does he not?
We never understand
what he says, Princess.
Yes, he says terrible
things about her.
Princess, the Tetrarch prays you return
to the feast. -I will not go back.
Pardon me, Princess, but if you do
not return some misfortune may happen.
ls he an old man,
this prophet?
Princess, it were better to
return. Suffer me to lead you in.
This prophet...
...is he an old man? -No,
Princess, he is quite a young man.
You cannot be sure. There are those
who say he is Elias. -Who is Elias?
A very ancient prophet of
this country, Princess.
What answer may I give the
Tetrarch from the Princess?
Rejoice not thou,
land of Palestine,
because the rod of him
who smote thee is broken.
For from the seed of the serpent
shall come forth a basilisk,
and that which is born of
it shall devour the birds.
What a strange voice!
I would speak with him.
I fear it is
impossible, Princess.
The Tetrarch does not wish
anyone to speak with him.
He has even forbidden the
high priest to speak with him.
I desire to speak with him.
-It is impossible, Princess.
I will speak with him. -Would it not
be better to return to the banquet?
Bring forth
this prophet!
We dare not,
Princess.
How black it is, down there! It must
be terrible to be in so black a pit!
It is like a tomb.
Did you not
hear me?
I said bring forth this
prophet. I wish to see him.
Princess, our lives belong to you, but
we cannot do what you have asked of us.
And indeed, it is not of us
that you should ask this thing.
Ah!
Oh! What is
going to happen?
I am sure that some
misfortune will happen.
You will do this thing for
me, Narabeth, will you not?
You will do this thing for me.
I have always been kind to you.
You will do
it for me.
I would but look at this strange
prophet. Men have talked so much of him.
Often have I heard the
Tetrarch talk of him.
I think the Tetrarch
is afraid of him.
Are you, even you, also
afraid of him, Narabeth?
I fear him not, Princess.
There is no man I fear.
But the Tetrarch has
formally forbidden
that any man should raise
the cover of this well.
You will do this thing
for me, Narabeth.
You know that you will
do this thing for me.
And tomorrow when I pass in my litter
beneath the gateway of the idol-buyers,
I will look at you
through the muslin veils,
I will look at you,
Narabeth, it may be...
...I will
smile at you.
Look at me,
Narabeth.
Look at me.
You know you will do
what I ask of you.
You know it well.
I know you will
do this thing.
Let the prophet
come forth.
The Princess Salomé
desires to see him.
Oh! How strange
the moon looks.
You would think it was
the hand of a dead woman
who is seeking to cover
herself with a shroud.
She has a
strange look!
She is like a little princess,
whose eyes are eyes of amber.
Through the clouds of muslin she
is smiling like a little princess.
Where is he whose cup of
abominations is now full?
Where is he, who in a robe
of silver shall one day die
in the face of
all the people?
Bid him come forth, that he
may hear the voice of him
who hath cried in the waste
places and in the houses of kings.
Of whom is he speaking? -You never
can tell, Princess. -Where is she...
...who gave herself unto
the Captains of Assyria,
who have baldricks on their loins and
tiaras of divers colours on their heads?
It is of my mother that he
speaks. -Oh, no, Princess.
Yes, it is of my
mother that he speaks.
Where is she who hath given
herself to the young men of Egypt,
who are clothed in fine linen and
purple, whose shields are of gold,
whose helmets are of silver,
whose bodies are mighty?
Bid her rise up from the
bed of her abominations,
from the bed of
her incestuousness,
that she may hear the words of him
who prepareth the way of the Lord,
that she may repent
her of her iniquities.
Though she will never repent, but
will stick fast in her abominations;
bid her come, for the fan
of the Lord is in His hand.
But he is terrible,
he is terrible.
Do not stay here,
Princess, I beseech you.
It is his eyes above
all that are terrible.
They are like black holes burned
by torches in a Tyrian tapestry.
They are like black caverns
where dragons dwell.
Like black caverns in Egypt in
which dragons make their lairs.
They are like black lakes
troubled by fantastic... moons.
Do you think he
will speak again?
Do not stay here, Princess,
I pray you, do not stay here.
How wasted he is! He is
like a thin ivory statue.
He is like an image of silver. I am
sure he is as chaste as the moon is.
He is like a moonbeam,
like a shaft of silver.
His flesh must be
cool like ivory.
I would look closer at
him. -No, no, Princess.
I must look at him closer.
-Princess! Princess!
Who is this woman
who is looking at me?
I will not have
her look at me.
I know not who she is. I do
not wish to know who she is.
Bid her begone. It is not
to her that I would speak.
I am Salomé, daughter of
Herodias, Princess of Judaea.
Back! Daughter
of Babylon!
Come not near the
chosen of the Lord.
Thy mother hath filled the earth
with the wine of her iniquities,
and the cry of her sins hath
come up to the ears of God.
Speak again, Jokanaan.
Thy voice is wine to me.
Princess!
Princess! Princess!
Speak again, Jokanaan,
tell me what I must do.
Daughter of Sodom,
come not near me.
But cover thy
face with a veil,
and get thee to the desert
and seek out the Son of Man.
Who is he, the Son of Man? ls he
as beautiful as thou are, Jokanaan?
Get thee
behind me!
I hear in the palace the beating
of the wings of the angel of death.
Princess, I beseech
thee to go within.
Angel of the Lord God, what
dost thou here with thy sword?
The day of him who shall die in a
robe of silver has not yet come.
Jokanaan! Jokanaan, I
am amorous of thy body!
Thy body is white like the lilies of a
field that the mower hath never mowed.
Thy body is white like the
snows in the mountains of Judea,
that come down
into the valleys.
The roses in the garden of the Queen
of Arabia are not so white as thy body.
There is nothing in the
world so white as thy body.
Let me touch thy body.
-Back. Daughter of Babylon.
By woman came evil into
the world. Speak not to me.
I will not
listen to thee.
I listen but to the voice,
the voice of the Lord God.
Thy body is hideous. It is
like the body of a leper.
It is like a plastered wall
where vipers have crawled.
It is like a plastered wall where
the scorpions have made their nest.
It is like a whitened sepulchre
full of loathsome things.
It is horrible, thy
body is horrible.
It is thy mouth that
I desire, Jokanaan.
Thy mouth is like a band of
scarlet on a tower of ivory.
It is like a pomegranate
cut with a knife of ivory.
The pomegranate flowers that
blossom in the garden of Tyre,
and are redder than
roses, are not so red.
The red blasts of trumpets that
herald the approach of kings,
and make afraid the
enemy, are not so red.
Thy mouth is redder
than the feet of those
who tread the wine
in the wine press.
Thy mouth is redder
than the feet of doves
who haunt the temples and
are fed by the priests.
It is redder than the feet of
him who oometh from a forest
where he hath slain a lion
and seen gilded tigers.
Thy mouth is like a branch of
coral that fishers have found
in the twilight
of the sea,
the coral that they
keep for the kings!
It is the vermilion that the
Moabites find in the mines of Moab,
the vermilion that the
kings take from them.
It is the bow of the
King of the Persians...
...that is painted
with vermilion
and is tipped
with... coral.
There is nothing
in the world
so red... as
thy mouth.
Let me kiss
Never! Daughter of Babylon.
Daughter of Sodom. Never!
I will kiss thy mouth,
Jokanaan. I will kiss thy mouth.
Princess, Princess, thou who
art like a garden of myrrh,
thou who are the dove of all doves,
look not at this man, look not at him!
Do not speak such words to
him. I cannot suffer them!
Princess, Princess, do
not speak these things.
I will kiss thy mouth,
Jokanaan. -No, no!
The young Syrian
has slain himself!
The young captain
He has slain himself
who was my friend!
Princess, the young captain
has just killed himself.
Let me kiss
thy mouth.
Daughter of adultery, there
is but one who can save thee,
it is He of whom I
spake. Go seek Him.
He is on a boat on the sea of Galilee,
and He talketh with His disciples.
Kneel down on the shore of the
sea, and call unto Him by His name.
When He cometh to thee, and to
all who call on Him, He cometh,
bow thyself at His feet and ask
of Him the remission of thy sins.
Let me kiss
thy mouth!
I will kiss thy mouth,
Jokanaan. I will kiss thy mouth.
Thou art accursed,
Salomé, thou art accursed.
We must bear away the
body to another place.
The Tetrarch does not
care to see dead bodies,
save the bodies of those
whom he himself has slain.
You are right, we must hide the
body. The Tetrarch must not see it.
The Tetrarch will not come to this
place. He never comes on the terrace.
He is too much afraid
of the prophet.
Salomé. Where
is Salomé?
Where is the
Princess?
Why did she not return to the
banquet as I commanded her?
Ah! There she is!
You must not look at her! You
are always looking at her!
The moon has a strange look
tonight. Has she not a strange look?
She is like a mad woman, a mad woman
who is seeking everywhere for lovers.
She is naked, too.
She is,
quite naked.
The clouds are seeking to clothe her
nakedness, but she will not let them.
She shows herself
naked in the sky.
I am sure she is
looking for lovers.
Does she not reel
like a drunken woman?
She is like a mad
woman, is she not?
No, the moon is like
the moon, that is all.
Let us go within. You
have nothing to do here.
I will stay here!
Manasseh, lay
carpets there.
Light torches, bring forth the ivory
tables, and the tables of jasper.
The air here is delicious. I will
drink more wine with my guests.
We must show all honours to
the ambassadors of Caesar.
It is not because of them that you
remain. -Oh yes, the air is delicious.
Come, Herodias, our
guests await us.
I have slipped.
I have slipped in blood!
That is an ill omen.
That is a very evil omen.
Wherefore is there blood here?
And this body, what
does this body here?
Think you that I am like the King of
Egypt, who gives no feast to his guests
but that he shows
them a corpse?
Whose is it? I will not look on
it. -It is our captain, sire.
He is the young Syrian whom you
made captain only three days ago.
I gave no order that
he should be slain.
He killed himself, sire.
-He killed himself?
For what reason? I
made him my captain.
We do not know, sire.
But he killed himself.
That seems
strange to me.
I thought it was only the Roman
philosophers who killed themselves.
ls that not true, Tigellinus, that
the philosophers kill themselves?
They are
the Stoics.
It is strange that the young
Syrian has killed himself.
I am sorry he has
killed himself.
I am very sorry, for he
was fair to look upon.
He was, even
very fair.
He had very
languorous eyes.
I remember I saw that he
looked languorously at Salomé.
Truly, I thought he
looked too much at her.
There are others who
look at her too much.
His father was a king. I
drove him from his kingdom.
And you made a slave of his
mother, who was a queen, Herodias.
So he was here as my
guest, as it were,
and for that reason,
I made him my captain.
I am sorry
he is dead.
Ho! Why have you left the body here?
Away with it. I will not look on it.
Ah! It is
cold here.
There is a wind blowing.
ls there not wind blowing?
No, there is no wind. -I say
there is a wind that blows.
And I hear in the air something
like the beating of wings,
like the beating
of vast wings.
Do you not hear it?
-I hear nothing.
I hear it no longer.
But I heard it.
It was the blowing of the wind,
no doubt. It has passed away.
I hear it again. Do you not hear
it? Just like the beating of wings.
I tell you there is nothing.
You are ill. Let us go within.
I am not ill. It is your
daughter who is sick.
She has the mien of a sick person.
Never have I seen her so pale.
I have told you
not to look at her.
Pour me
forth wine.
Salomé, drink a
little wine with me.
I have here a wine that is
exquisite. Caesar himself sent it me.
Dip into it thy little red
lips, that I may drain the cup.
I am not thirsty,
Tetrarch.
You see how she answers
me, this daughter of yours?
She does right. Why are
you always gazing at her?
Bring me
ripe fruits.
Salomé, come, eat
fruit with me.
I love to see in a fruit the
mark of thy little teeth.
Bite but a little of this fruit
and then I will eat what is left.
I am not hungry,
Tetrarch.
You see how you have brought
up this daughter of yours?
My daughter and I
come of a royal race.
As for thee, thy father was a
camel driver! He was also a robber!
Thou liest! -Thou
knowest well it is true.
Salomé, come sit next to me. I will
give thee the throne of thy mother.
I am not tired,
Tetrarch.
You see what she
thinks of you.
Bring me... what?
What is it I
desire? I forgot.
Ah! Yes, I
remember.
Lo!
The time is come! That which
I foretold has come to pass...
...saith the
Lord God.
The day of
which I spoke.
The Lord has come. The
Son of Man has some.
Command him to be silent. I
will not listen to his voice.
This man is forever
vomiting insults against me.
He has said nothing against you.
Besides, he is a very great prophet.
I do not believe
in prophets.
Can a man tell what will come
to pass? No man knows it.
Moreover, he is for
ever insulting me.
But I think you are afraid of him.
I know well you are afraid of him.
I am not afraid of him.
I am afraid of no man.
I tell you, you
are afraid of him.
If you are not afraid of him, why
do you not deliver him to the Jews,
who for these six months past
who have been clamouring for him?
Truly, my lord, it were better
to deliver him into our hands.
Yes, my lord. -Enough on this subject.
I've already given you my answer.
I will not deliver
him into your hands.
He is a holy man. He is
a man who has seen God.
That cannot be. There is no man who
hath seen God since the prophet Elias.
God is at no
time hidden.
He showeth himself at all
times and in everything.
God is in what is evil, even
as he is in what is good.
That is a very
dangerous doctrine.
No one can tell how God worketh.
His ways are very mysterious.
It may be that things which
we call evil are good,
and the things which
we call good are evil.
We must needs submit to
everything, for God is very strong.
Very strong. -He breaketh in pieces
the strong together with the weak,
for he regardeth
not any man.
Truly God is terrible, he
breaketh the strong and the weak
as a man brays corn in a mortar.
But this man hath never seen God.
No man hath seen God
since the prophet Elias.
So the day is come,
the day of the Lord.
And I hear... I hear
upon the mountains
the feet of Him
who shall be...
...the saviour
of the world.
What does
that mean?
Saviour of the world.
What does that mean?
It is a title
that Caesar takes.
But Caesar is not
coming into Judaea.
Only yesterday I received
letters from Rome.
They contained nothing
concerning this matter.
And you, Tigellinus, who were
at Rome during the winter,
you heard nothing concerning
this matter, did you?
Sire, I heard nothing concerning the
matter. I was explaining the title.
It is one of
Caesar's titles.
But Caesar
cannot come.
He is too gouty.
They say that his feet are
like the feet of an elephant.
Also, there are
reasons of State.
He who leaves Rome loses
Rome. He will not come.
Albeit, Caesar is lord,
he will come if he wishes.
Nevertheless, I do not
think that he will come.
It was not concerning Caesar that
the prophet spake these words, sire.
Not of Caesar?
-No, sire.
Concerning whom
then did he speak?
Concerning Messias
who has come.
This man worketh
true miracles.
Thus, at a marriage which took
place in a little town of Galilee,
a town of some importance,
he changed water into wine.
And he was seen on a
mountain talking with angels.
Angels do
not exist!
Angels exist, but I do not believe
this man has talked with them.
He was seen by a great multitude
of people talking with angels.
Not with angels. -How these men
weary me! They are ridiculous!
There is also the miracle
of the daughter of Jairus.
Yes, that is sure. No
man can gainsay it.
These men are mad. They have
looked too long on the moon.
Command them
to be silent.
What is the miracle of
the daughter of Jairus?
The daughter of Jairus was dead.
He raised her from the dead.
He raises the dead? -Yes,
sire, he raiseth the dead.
I do not wish
him to do that.
I forbid him
to do that.
I allow no man to
raise the dead.
This man must be found and told
I forbid him to raise the dead.
Where is this man at present? -It
is said that he is now in Samaria.
It is easy to see that this is
not Messias, if he is in Samaria.
It is not to the
Samaritans... -No matter!
Let them find him,
and tell him from me,
I will not allow him
to raise the dead!
To change water
into wine...
...to heal the
lepers and the blind.
He may do these things if he will.
I say nothing against these things.
In truth I hold it a good
deed to heal a leper.
But I allow no man
to raise the dead.
It would be terrible
if the dead came back.
Wanton!
You harlot!
Daughter of Babylon with her golden
eyes under her gilded eyelids!
Let there come against
her a multitude of men.
Let the people
take stones
and stone her! -Command
him to be silent.
Let the war captains pierce
her with their swords.
Nay, but it
is infamous.
It is thus that I will wipe out
all wickedness from the earth,
and that all
women shall learn
not to imitate
her abominations.
You hear what he says against me?
You allow him to revile your wife?
He did not
speak your name.
What does that matter? You know well
that it is I whom he seeks to revile.
And I am your
wife, am I not?
Of a truth, dear and noble
Herodias, you are my wife,
and before that you were
the wife of my brother.
It was you who tore
me from his arms.
Of a truth, I
was stronger.
But let us not speak of that matter.
I do not desire to speak of it.
It is the cause of the terrible
words that the prophet has spoken.
Peradventure on account of
it a misfortune will come.
Let us not speak
of that matter.
Come, Herodias, we are
not mindful of our guests.
Fill thou my cup,
my well-beloved.
Fill with wine the great goblets of
silver, and the great goblets of glass.
I will drink to Caesar. There are
Romans here, we must drink to Caesar.
Caesar!
Do you see your daughter,
how pale she is?
What is it to you whether
she be pale or not?
Never have I
seen her so pale.
You must not
look at her.
In that day the sun shall become
black like the sackcloth of hair,
and the moon shall
become like blood,
and the stars of the heavens shall
fall upon the earth like ripe figs
that fall from
the fig tree.
And the kings of the
earth shall be afraid.
I should like to see that
day of which he speaks,
when the moon shall
become like blood,
and the stars shall fall upon
the earth like ripe figs.
This prophet talks
like a drunken man.
But I cannot suffer
the sound of his voice.
I hate his voice.
Command him to be silent.
I will not.
I cannot understand what it is that
he saith, but it may be an omen.
Oh! I do not believe in omens.
He speaks like a drunken man.
It may be that he is drunk
with the wine of God.
What wine is that,
the wine of God?
From what vineyards is it gathered?
In what wine-press may one find it?
Tigellinus, when you
were at Rome of late,
did the Emperor speak
with you on the subject?
On what
subject, sire?
On what subject?
Ah! I asked you a
question, did I not?
I have forgotten what
I would have asked you.
You are looking
again at my daughter.
You must not look at her.
I have already said so.
You say nothing else.
-I say it again.
And the restoration of the Temple
about which they have talked so much,
will anything
be done?
They say that the veil of the
Sanctuary has disappeared, do they not?
It was thyself
didst steal it.
Thou speakest at random. I will
not stay here. Let us go within.
Dance for
me, Salomé.
I will not
have her dance.
I have no desire
to dance, Tetrarch.
Salomé, daughter of
Herodias, dance for me.
Let her alone.
Salomé, I command
thee to dance.
I will not
dance, Tetrarch.
You see how
she obeys you.
What is it to me whether she
dance or not? It is naught to me.
Tonight I am happy,
I am passing happy.
Never have I
been so happy.
The Tetrarch has a sombre
look. Has he not a sombre look?
Yes, he has a
sombre look.
He shall be seated
on his throne.
He shall be clothed
in scarlet and purple.
In his hand he shall bear a golden
cup full of his blasphemies.
And the angel of the
Lord shall smite him.
He shall be
eaten of worms.
You hear what he says about you.
He says you will be eaten of worms.
It is not of me that he speaks. It is of
the King of Cappadocia that he speaks;
the King of Cappadocia,
who is my enemy.
It is he who shall be eaten
of worms. It is not I.
Never has he spoken word
against me, this prophet,
save that I sinned in taking
to wife the wife of my brother.
It may be that he is right. For,
of a truth, you are sterile.
I am sterile, I?
You say that, you that are
ever looking at my daughter,
you that would have her
dance for your pleasure?
It is absurd to say that.
I have borne a child.
You have gotten no child, no,
not even from one of your slaves.
It is you who are
sterile, not I.
Peace, woman! I say
you are sterile.
You have borne
me no child,
and the prophet says that our
marriage is not a true marriage.
He says it is an
incestuous marriage,
a marriage that
will bring evils.
I fear he is right, I am
sure that he is right.
But this is not the moment
to speak of such things.
I would be happy
at this moment.
Indeed, I
am happy.
Never have I
been so happy.
There is
nothing I lack.
I am glad you are of so fair a humour
tonight. It is not your custom.
But it is late. Let us go within. Do
not forget that we hunt at sunrise.
All honours must be paid to
Caesar's ambassadors, must they not?
Salomé, Salomé, dance for
me. I pray you, dance for me.
I am sad tonight. I am
passing sad tonight.
When I came hither I slipped in
blood, which is an evil omen,
also I heard, I am sure I heard
in the air a beating of wings,
the beating of
giant wings.
I cannot tell
what they mean.
Therefore dance for me. I pray you,
Salomé, I beseech you, dance for me.
Salomé, if you
dance for me,
you may ask of
me what you will,
and I will give it to you, even
unto the half of my kingdom.
Will you indeed give me
whatsoever I shall ask, Tetrarch?
Do not dance,
my daughter.
Everything, even the
half of my kingdom.
You swear
it, Tetrarch?
I swear
it, Salomé.
By what will you swear, Tetrarch?
-By my life, by my crown, by my gods.
Whatsoever you desire I will give it to
you, even unto the half of my kingdom,
if you will but
dance for me.
O, Salomé, Salomé,
dance for me!
You have sworn,
Tetrarch.
I have sworn,
Salomé.
My daughter,
do not dance.
Thou wilt be passing
fair as queen,...
...Salomé, if it please thee to
ask for the half of my kingdom.
Will she not be
fair as queen?
It is cold here!
There is an icy wind.
And I hear in the air, wherefore do I
hear in the air this beating of wings?
One might
fancy a bird,
a huge black bird that
hovers over the terrace.
Why can I not see it, this bird?
The beat of its wings is terrible.
The breath of the wind
of its wings is terrible.
It is a chill wind. Nay, but
it is not cold, it is hot.
I am choking.
Pour water on my hands.
Give me snow to eat.
Loosen my mantle. Quick!
Quick! Loosen my mantle.
Nay, leave it! It is my garland
that hurts me, my garland of roses.
The flowers are like fire.
They burn my forehead.
I can breathe now. How
red those rose petals are.
They are like stains
of blood on the cloth.
That does not matter. You must not
find symbols in everything you see.
It makes life
impossible.
It were better to say that stains of
blood are as lovely as rose petals.
It were better
far to say that.
But we will not speak
of this. Now I am happy.
I am...
passing happy!
Have I not a right to be happy? Your
daughter is going to dance for me.
Will you not dance for me, Salomé?
You have promised to dance for me.
I will not
have her dance.
I will dance for
you, Tetrarch.
You hear what your daughter says?
She is going to dance for me.
You do well to dance
for me, Salomé.
And once you have danced for me, forget
not to ask of me whatsoever you will.
Whatsoever you will I will give it
you, even unto the half of my kingdom.
I have sworn it, have I not?
-You have sworn it, Tetrarch.
And I have never broken my word. I am
not of those who break their oaths.
I know not how to lie.
I am a slave to my word,
and my word is the
word of a king.
The King of Cappadocia
always lies...
...but he is no true
king. He is a coward.
Also, he owes me money
he will not repay.
He has insulted my ambassadors. He
has spoken words that were wounding.
But Caesar will crucify
him when he comes to Rome.
I am sure Caesar
will crucify him.
Yet will he die, if not,
being eaten of worms.
The prophet prophesied it. Well,
Salome, wherefore dost thou tarry?
I am waiting until my
slaves bring perfumes to me
and the seven veils,
and take off my sandals.
Ah, you are going to
dance with naked feet.
'Tis well! Oh, 'tis
well. Your little feet.
Your little feet will
be like white doves.
They will be like little white
flowers that dance upon the trees.
No, no, she's going to dance on blood.
There is blood spilt on the ground.
She must not dance on
blood. It were an evil omen.
What is it to you whether
she dance on blood or not?
Thou has waded deep
enough therein.
What is it to me?
Ah! Look at the moon!
She has
become red.
She has become red as blood.
The prophet prophesied truly.
He prophesied that the moon would
become red as blood. Do ye not see it?
Oh, yes, I
see it well,
and the stars are falling
like ripe figs, are they not?
And the sun has become black
like a sackcloth of hair,
and the kings of the
earth are afraid.
That at least one can see. The prophet,
for once in his life, was right,
the kings of the
earth are afraid.
Let us go within. You are sick. They
will say at Rome that you are mad.
Let us go within,
I tell you.
Who is this who cometh from Edom,
who is this who oometh from Bozra,
whose raiment is
dyed with purple,
who shineth in the beauty of his
garments, who walketh mighty?
It is the Lord!
Let us go within! The voice
of that man maddens me!
I will not have my daughter dance
while he is continually crying out.
I will not have her dance while
you look at her in such a fashion.
In a word, I will
not have her dance.
Do not rise, my wife, my queen,
it will avail thee nothing.
I will not go within
till she hath danced.
Dance, Salomé,
dance for me.
My daughter,
do not dance.
I am ready,
Tetrarch.
Wonderful!
You see, she has danced
for me, your daughter.
Come near,
Salomé,
come near, that I may
give you your reward.
I pay the dancers well.
I shall pay thee royally.
I shall give thee whatsoever
thy soul desireth.
What wouldst
thou have?
Speak.
I would that they presently
bring me in a silver charger...
In a silver
charger?
Surely yes, in a
silver charger.
She is charming,
is she not?
But what would you have them bring you
in a silver charger? Tell me the thing.
Whatsoever it may be, I will give
it you. My treasures belong to thee.
What is
it, Salomé?
The head of
Jokanaan.
That is well
said, my daughter.
No, no, Salomé. You
do not ask me that.
Do not listen to
your mother's voice.
She is ever giving you evil
counsel. Do not heed her.
I do not heed my mother. It is
for my own pleasure that I ask
for the head of Jokanaan
on a silver charger.
You have sworn, Tetrarch. Forget
not that you have sworn an oath.
I know. I have sworn by
my gods. I know it well.
But I pray you, Salomé,
ask of me something else.
Ask of me the half of my
kingdom, and I will give it you.
But ask not of me what you have asked.
-I ask of you the head of Jokanaan.
No, no, I do not wish it.
-You have sworn, Herod.
Yes, you have sworn. Everybody
heard you. You swore it...
Be silent! It is
not to you I speak.
Oh, my daughter does well
to ask the head of Jokanaan.
He has covered me with insults. He
has said monstrous things against me.
One can see she loves
her mother well.
Do not yield, my daughter.
He has sworn, he has sworn.
Be silent,
speak not to me!
Come, Salomé, be reasonable.
I have never been hard to you.
I have ever loved you. It may be
that I have loved you too much.
Therefore ask not
this thing of me.
This is a terrible thing. This
is an awful thing to ask of me.
Surely, I think that
you are jesting.
The head of a man that
is cut from his body...
...is ill to look
upon, is it not?
It is not meet that the eyes of a
virgin should look upon such a thing.
What pleasure can you
have in it? None. No, no.
Harken to me. I
have an emerald,
a great round emerald, which
Caesar's minion sent me.
When you look
through this emerald,
you can see things which
happen at great distance.
Caesar himself carries such an
emerald when he goes to the circus.
Only my emerald is larger.
I know well it is larger.
It is the largest emerald
in the whole world.
You would like
that, would you not?
Ask it of me, I
will give it you.
I demand the
head of Jokanaan.
You are not listening.
Salomé, you are not listening.
Suffer me to speak.
The head of Jokanaan.
No, no, you would
not have that.
You say that to trouble me, because I
have looked at you all this evening.
It is true, I have looked at
you. Your beauty troubled me.
Your beauty has grievously troubled
me, and I have looked at you too much.
But I will look
at you no more.
Neither at things, nor at
people should one look.
Only in mirrors should one look,
for mirrors do but show us masks.
Ah! Bring
wine! I thirst.
Salomé, come let
us be friends.
What would I say? What was
it? I've forgotten. Ah, yes!
Nay but come nearer, Salomé,
I fear you will not hear me.
You know my white peacocks,
my beautiful white peacocks,
that walk in the garden between the
myrtles and the tall cypress trees.
Their beaks are gilded with gold,
and the grains that they eat
are gilded with gold also and
their feet are stained with purple.
When they cry out
the rain comes,
and the moon shows herself in the
heavens when they spread their tails.
Two by two they
walk in the garden
between the black myrtles
and the cypress trees,
and each has a
slave to tend it.
I will give them all to
you. I have but a hundred.
Only you must loose
me from my oath.
You must not ask of me that
which you have asked of me.
I demand the
head of Jokanaan.
Well said, my daughter! As for you,
you are ridiculous with your peacocks.
Be silent!
You cry out always, you cry
out like a beast of prey.
You must not!
Your voice...
...wearies me.
Be silent, I say.
Salomé, think of
what you are doing.
This man comes
perchance from God.
He is a holy man. The finger
of God has touched him.
God has put into his
mouth terrible words.
In the palace, as in the
desert, God is always with him.
At least it is possible.
One does not know.
It is possible that God
is for him and with him.
Furthermore, if he died, a
misfortune might happen to me.
In any case, he said
that the day he dies,
a misfortune will happen to
someone. That could only be me.
Remember, I slipped in
blood when I entered.
Also, I heard in the air
the beating of wings,
the beating of
giant wings.
These are very evil omens,
and there were others.
I am sure there were others,
though I did not see them.
Salomé, you do not wish a
misfortune to happen to me?
You do not wish that.
Then listen to me.
Give me the head
of Jokanaan!
Ah! You are not
listening. Be calm.
Be calm.
I am calm.
I am quite
calm. Listen.
I have jewels hidden
in this place,
jewels that
are marvellous.
I have a collar of
pearls, set in four rows
that are like unto moons
chained with rays of silver.
They are like 50 moons
caught in a golden net.
On the ivory of her breast,
a queen has worn it.
Thou shalt be as fair as a queen
when thou wearest it, Salomé.
I have topazes, yellow as
are the eyes of tigers.
I have opals that burn
always, with an icelike flame,
opals that make sad men's minds,
and are fearful of the shadows.
I have sapphires
big like eggs
and blue as blue flowers.
The sea wanders within them
and the moon comes never to
trouble the blue of their waves.
I have chrysolites and beryls
and chrysoprases and rubies.
I have sardonyx and hyacinth
stone, stone of chalcedony,
and I will give them all to you,
and other things will I add to them.
The King of the Indies
has but even now
sent me four fans fashioned
from the feathers of parrots,
and the King of Numidia, a
garment of ostrich feathers.
I have a crystal into which it is
not lawful for a woman to look,
nor may young men behold it till
they have been beaten with rods.
In a coffer of nacre, I have
three wondrous turquoises.
He who wears them on his forehead
can imagine things which are not,
and he who carries them in his
hand can make women sterile.
These are great treasures, Salome,
these are treasures above all price.
These are treasures
without price.
But this
is not all.
In an ebony
coffer,
I have two cups of amber,
that are like apples of gold.
If an enemy pour poison into these cups,
they become like an apple of silver.
In a coffer
encrusted with amber,
I have sandals
encrusted with glass.
I have mantles brought here
from the land of the Seres,
bracelets decked about with
carbuncles and with jade
that comes from the
city of Euphrates.
What desirest thou
more than this, Salomé?
Tell me the thing that thou
desirest, and I will give it thee.
All that thou askest I will
give thee, save one thing.
I will give thee
all that is mine...
...save one life.
I will give thee the
mantle of the high priest.
veil of the sanctuary.
Give me the head
of Jokanaan.
Let her be given
what she asks.
For of a truth she is
her mother's child.
Who has taken
my ring?
There was a ring
on my right hand.
Who has drunk
my wine?
There was wine in my
cup. It was full of wine.
Someone has
drunk it.
Surely some evil
will befall someone.
Wherefore did
I give my oath?
Kings ought never to
pledge their word.
For if they keep it
not, it is terrible...
...and if they keep it,
it is terrible also.
My daughter
has done well.
I am sure that a
misfortune will happen.
Why does he not
cry out, this man?
If any man sought to
kill me, I would cry out,
I would struggle,
I would not suffer.
Strike, Naaman,
strike, I tell you...
He has let his sword fall. He is
afraid, this slave! He did not kill him!
He is a coward this slave.
Let soldiers be sent.
Come hither, thou welt the friend
of him who is dead, is it not so?
Well, I tell thee, there are not dead
men enough. Get ye to the soldiers
and bid them go down and
bring me the thing that I ask,
the thing the Tetrarch has promised
me, the thing that is mine.
Hither, ye soldiers. Get ye into this
cistern and bring me the head of this man.
Tetrarch,
Tetrarch!
Command your soldiers that they
bring me the head of Jokanaan.
Thou wouldst not suffer me
to kiss thy mouth, Jokanaan.
Well, I will
kiss it now.
I will bite it with my teeth
as one bites a ripe fruit.
Yes, I will kiss
thy mouth, Jokanaan.
I said it. Did I not
say it? I said it.
I will kiss
it now.
But wherefore dost thou
not look at me, Jokanaan?
Thine eyes that were so terrible, so
full of rage and scorn, are shut now.
Wherefore are
they shut?
Open thine eyelids! Lift
up thine eyes, Jokanaan.
Art thou afraid of me, that
thou wilt not look at me?
And thy tongue, that was like a red
snake darting poison, it moves no more,
it says nothing
now, Jokanaan,
that scarlet viper that
spat its venom against me.
It is strange, is it not? How is it
that the red viper stirs no longer?
Thou wouldst have none of me,
Jokanaan. Thou didst reject me.
Thou didst speak evil
words against me.
Thou didst treat me as
a harlot, as a wanton.
Me,...
...Salomé
daughter of Herodias,
Princess of Judaea!
Well, Jokanaan, I still live,
but thou, thou art dead...
...and thy head belongs to me.
I can do with it what I will.
I can throw it to the dogs
and to the birds of the air.
That which the dogs leave behind,
the birds of the air shall devour.
Oh, Jokanaan!
Jokanaan, thou welt the
only man that I have loved.
All other men were hateful to me.
But thou, thou wert beautiful!
Thy body was a column of
ivory set on a silver socket.
It was a garden filled with
doves and silver lilies.
It was a tower of silver
decked with shields of ivory.
There was nothing in the
world so white as thy body.
world so black as thy hair.
In the whole world, there was
nothing so red as thy mouth.
Thy voice was a censer that
scattered strange perfumes,
and when I looked on thee,
I heard a strange music.
Wherefore didst thou not
look at me, Jokanaan?
Behind thine hands and thy
curses thou didst hide thy face.
Thou didst put upon thine eyes the
coverings of him who would see his God.
Well, thou hast seen
thy God, Jokanaan,
but me... me, thou
didst never see.
If thou hadst seen me thou
wouldst have loved me.
I saw thee, Jokanaan,
and I loved thee.
Oh, how I
loved thee!
I love thee
yet, Jokanaan.
I love
thee only.
I am athirst for thy beauty,
I am hungry for thy body,
neither wine nor fruits
can appease my desire.
What shall I do
now, Jokanaan?
Neither the great waters nor the
floods can quench my passion.
I was a princess,
thou didst scorn me.
I was a virgin, thou didst
take my virginity from me.
I was chaste, and thou didst
fill my veins with fire.
Wherefore didst thou not
look at me, Jokanaan?
If thou hadst looked at
me thou hadst loved me.
Well I know that thou
wouldst have loved me,
and the mystery of love is
greater than the mystery of death.
Love only should
one consider.
She is monstrous,
thy daughter,
she is altogether
monstrous.
In truth, what she has
done was a great crime.
I am sure that
it was a crime
against an
unknown God.
I approve of what my daughter has
done. And I will stay here now.
Ah! There speaks
the incestuous wife!
Come.
I will not
stay here.
Come, I tell thee.
Surely some evil
will befall.
Manasseh, lssachar, Ozias,
put out the torches.
I will not
look at things,
I will not suffer
things to look at me.
Put out the
torches!
Hide the moon.
Hide the stars.
Come, Herodias,
let us hide ourselves
in our palace.
I begin to
be afraid.
I have kissed thy
mouth, Jokanaan.
I have kissed
thy mouth.
There was a bitter
taste on thy lips.
Was it the
taste of blood?
But perchance it is
the taste of love.
For they say that love
hath a bitter taste.
But what of that?
What of that?
I have kissed thy
mouth, Jokanaan.
Kill that woman!