That's the boy. Miracle Lad.
Go on!
Break his blasted neck.
You keep quiet or I'll
take a sock at you.
Yeah?
Go ahead and I'll take a
sock at you right back.
There he goes. The last
stallion I've got on the place.
Hey.
How do you think I'm going to run
a breeding farm without a stud?
Huh? How am I?
That's your tough luck.
You can figure it out for yourself.
Hey, Limpy. Wait a minute.
Take that stallion back to the stable.
I've got an order from
the bank, Mr Bradley.
That half-witted son of mine
give him over to Ed Kenyon.
I'll come into the bank
and fix it with Mr Kenyon.
Alright, Mr Bradley. If you'll fix it.
Your darn tooting he'll fix it.
Go on. Take the horse back to the stable
the way I told you in the first place.
The idea. Trying to take
other people's horses.
That confounded son of mine.
I wonder how he thinks I can run
a breeding farm without a stud.
Well, now that you bring it up it would
be quite a stunt wouldn't it, grandpa.
Selling off all the stock on the place.
Moonray will be the next
on the list, I suppose.
I'm surprised he
hasn't tried to sell me.
Has he had any offers?
Ah, but Duke. Think of it.
Brookvale.
When I was a young man, Brookvale
was the show place of all Saratoga.
When I first brought my bride
home from Niagara Falls.
It was all I could do to
get her into the house.
She was so crazy about the
champions in the stables.
You're kind of proud of
Brookvale, aren't you grandpa.
I was then.
Not now.
Say.
We got more dead horses
on this place than live ones.
Come here.
Look at that.
Every one of them champions.
There wasn't a line bred in
Kentucky could touch this stock.
We left those blue grass also-rans
on every stretch in America.
Why, they toasted Brookvale champions ..
And drank champagne
out of gold slippers.
At the old Haymarket way back
in my daddy's day in 1881.
There is Ebony Star, the greatest
two-year old of the nineties.
Pranced home at The Hopeful Stakes.
And her record has never been touched.
And then there is Blue Bold,
and the Flying Demon.
By Mad Power .. this one's grandpa.
And there is his daddy.
Dawn Boy.
The greatest stud in the
history of American racing.
I bred him, trained him
and buried him myself.
Grandpa, I forgot. Why is it Dawn Boy's
grave is out in front of the others?
Because Dawn Boy was always
out in front of the others.
And that is where he is going
to finish. Dead or alive.
Grandpa, I love you.
Mr Clayton.
A telephone call over long
distance from London, England.
It's Miss Carol.
Ah, she don't want me.
She wants her daddy.
Tell her he's at the doctor.
I can't talk so far, Mr Clayton.
I gets too scared.
Oh go on, Duke. You talk to her.
- Alright.
I'm only her grandpa.
I can't talk to her.
She's got so high and mighty
since she's been in Europe ..
That she won't talk to nobody but Kings.
She's got her daddy worried.
She moves around all the time
and don't leave no address.
Yeah, I know. That brat
needs a good spanking.
She don't mean nothing, Mr Duke.
That's just her way.
Rosetta. I love you.
Hello?
Hello? Hello, daddy.
Daddy, this is Carol.
Get ready for a big surprise.
I'm going to be married.
That's alright with me but don't bring
anything home to frighten your dad.
Who is this?
My name is Duke Bradley.
A friend of your father's.
Why don't you try it sometime?
Put my father on the phone.
- Who is it?
It's some fool.
I would like to speak with my father.
He isn't here.
Where can he get you?
I'm at Northborough House.
What's the address?
Northborough House is the county
seat of the Duke of Northborough.
Say, you'd better take that crown
off your head and come home.
What's that?
Who do you think you're talking to?
Who is it, darling?
Will you please tell me where my
father is that I may call him there?
Well, if you must know.
He's down at the doctor's. He's
having a little trouble with his heart.
Heart?
Is .. is it serious?
Well, he'd be better off without it.
Tell father I'll take
the next boat home.
Now you're talking, honey. Even if you
must bring that foreign monkey with you.
What did he say?
- Nothing. I ..
And please tell my father that I'm
marrying a perfectly good American.
Hartley Madison of New York.
Who did you say?
Hartley Madison.
Well, nice going, honey.
You certainly hooked a big one.
Bring him home.
I want to give him a kiss.
Hey, wait a minute.
Here comes your father now.
Hello?
Hello!
She hung up on me.
That's Miss Carol alright. Chock full
of temper ever since she was born.
Hello, Frank. I've just
talked to your daughter.
Carol? How is she, Duke?
- Get yourself set for some great news.
That little lady has hooked
herself a very wealthy chump.
Hooked?
- Getting married.
No.
- To Hartley Madison.
You don't say.
Not that rich New York fellah?
- Nobody else.
A sucker in the family.
Now we'll go places.
We'll have a real breeding farm again.
Hundreds of brood mares
and bloodied stallions.
We'll put Brookvale back
on the map, where it belongs.
My, my.
You said it, Rosetta.
Just a minute.
Do you fellows call him a sucker?
Sure.
Well, who was it I heard took you
for $50,000 once at Belmont?
Hartley Madison.
I thought so. And he's the sucker, eh?
Madison just happened to
quit when he was ahead.
His old man died I think and he
had to take over the business.
But if I can only get him back again.
Hot dog. I'll help you, Duke.
I'll make Carol bring him round.
Grandpa, you're a pal.
Duke, are you crazy?
- Why?
Why, a big player like Hartley
Madison could wind you up.
You or any other bookmaker.
He has a bankroll like the US Treasury.
Frank, ever since the depression I've
been making book for piker bettors.
Fifty dollars, a hundred dollars.
A thousand dollars, tops.
But happy days are here again.
Your little girl is bringing home
the biggest bettor of all.
Well, all I can say is you've
got plenty of nerve.
Frank, I love you.
What did the croaker say, Frank?
Did Kenyon send over
yet for Miracle Lad?
Heck yes, and the Duke here
wouldn't let him have him.
Wouldn't let him?
He's going to fix it up with Ed Kenyon.
- No, he's not.
Now Frank, this is a matter
between grandpa and me.
Now, there will be no argument.
I won't have it.
Now dad, you take that
horse over to Kenyon.
Say, what kind of a son are you, anyhow?
I wish you could figure out how to
run a breeding farm without a stud.
I can't.
I'm going out behind
the barn to get drunk.
Frank.
I wish you'd let grandpa keep his stud.
No. Thanks a lot, but I owe
you too much already.
Say, that reminds me.
Come in the other room now, will you.
You know, Duke.
Carol must really like Madison.
It can't be his money because
nobody knows I'm broke but you.
What about the croaker, Frank?
Well, he scared me a little and
says I really got a bum heart.
There is nothing wrong with me
that a winning bet won't cure.
There wouldn't be a thing wrong with you
at all if you cut out this fool betting.
Get wise to yourself, Frank.
You can't beat us bookmakers.
The old law of averages will flatten
out the biggest bankroll in the country.
Well, anyway. My bankroll can't
take it. This is my last season.
Now that Carol is going to be taken
care of, I want you to have this.
What is it?
- Deeds of the farm.
Security for the sixty
grand I've lost to you.
Are you nuts?
- Please to take it.
Your friendship means a lot to me.
You've only known me a bit over a year.
- I don't care if it's only for a week.
We're pals and you want to give
me a mark. Put that thing away.
Thanks, Duke. But that's
the way it has to be.
Please shut up and behave.
- I mean it, Duke.
I won't take that and you know it.
- Now, I'm not going to argue.
Now listen here.
The croaker told me not to start
hollering at anybody. Here, take it.
Alright.
- Thanks.
If that's the way you want it.
A funny thing. After all the
big heart specialists I've seen.
Nothing seems to regulate the old ticker
as well as plain bicarbonate of soda.
That's right.
Golly Duke, I'm glad the kid is
getting away from racetracks.
You know, I've always wanted her to be
something more than a dressed-up gypsy.
Here's to you, kid.
50 dollars across on Jay Bloom.
550 to win, 250 to place and
a 150 to show on number 748.
Hi, Duke. She finally got here.
Hello, grandpa. Who got here?
- Carol.
10-1 on Rester.
Yes sir. 60-10 to win on
Rester, number 738.
Where is Madison? Is he with her?
- Sure he is.
Take a gander.
Oh .. so that's Frank's kid, huh?
Well, the sucker is certainly
getting his money's worth.
Yeah, but she's got so
all-fired high and mighty ..
You can't understand a word she says.
Rusty Gate, 20 to place.
Yes, sir. Rusty Gate.
40-20 to place. Number 410.
Here Tip, take charge.
Come on, grandpa. Front for me.
10 across on Light Fantasy.
Light Fantasy. 60-10. 25-10. 12-10.
Number 526.
- Right.
Hello Frank.
- Duke.
Hello, Mr Madison.
Good to see you again.
How are you?
You remember him: Duke Bradley.
I haven't forgotten what you
did to me at Belmont once.
Oh, of course. Now, I remember.
Well, I won some money
from you, didn't I?
Some money is right.
Duke, this is Carol.
- How do you do.
Charmed, I'm sure.
- What did I tell you.
I doubt you remember me, Miss Clayton.
- I'm afraid I don't.
I talked to you on the phone
that day. Duke Bradley?
I think you were in some Count's place.
Oh. Oh, quite.
Congratulations on your engagement.
You certainly picked a winner.
You know, it's good to see a big
bettor back on the track, Mr Madison.
Thanks. But I'm only
a spectator nowadays.
The horses are at the gate.
Well, the track isn't much
fun if you don't bet.
If you're looking for a future customer,
you're wasting your time, Mr Bradley.
We have no intention of
being around the track.
Not really?
We're only here today because of father.
Just slumming, huh?
Rather comfortable slumming, Mr Clayton.
Hello, Duke.
Hello, Fritzi.
Why honey, you look as sharp as a razor.
Why not? I'm married.
- No.
Who's the sucker?
- Harriet Hale.
Who?
Harriet Hale.
The big coldcream and skin man.
His real name is Kiffmeyer.
- Oh.
Plenty of dough, huh?
All the government allows.
- Honey, I love you.
Fritzi, please meet Miss Clayton.
- Oh. I'm pleased to know you.
How do you do.
And how are you, Mr Clayton?
- Well ..
My ticker has been missing for
forty years and I'm alright.
I think he's got a horse doctor.
What have you bet on, daddy?
- I have a big bet on Jay Blue.
Come on, Jay Blue.
Daddy? What is it, daddy?
Hartley, Hartley.
- Take it easy.
Look honey, will you
fetch my bicarbonate.
Of course, dad.
Fix me a bicarbonate of soda, please.
Sure. How are you, Miss Clayton?
- Fine, thanks.
Don't worry, dear. He'll be alright.
He's gotten so grey and feeble, Hartley.
- When did you get back, Miss Clayton?
Just the other day.
You look mighty pretty.
- Thanks.
Is it for your dad?
- Yes.
Thought so. Getting to be quite a habit.
- Thank you.
Keep it.
What is it?
Well, what is it?
Oh, Hartley.
Hello?
Who?
Mr Bradley?
Who wants him?
Just a minute.
Hey, it's Frank Clayton's girl.
What?
Back in Saratoga?
That means the sucker must be with her.
Good morning, Carol.
How are you?
I'm downstairs in the bank, Mr Bradley.
Would you be kind enough to come down?
"At the bank?"
Look Carol, couldn't I meet
you somewhere else?
"Banks do something to me."
I'll only detain you a few minutes.
I'm in Mr Kenyon's office.
"Kenyon?"
That's the granite-faced old buzzard
who took grandpa's Miracle Lad.
"He never smiles. When he was born, they
had to open his mouth with a chisel."
"I couldn't talk to Kenyon.
He'd dry me up like a dust storm."
Well, you come down here please.
I'm in a hurry.
Well, look Carol.
I haven't had any breakfast yet.
Couldn't you bring Mr Madison up here?
Hello .. hello.
It's getting to be a habit
of hers, hanging up on me.
I never knew a banker to
lay a decent bet in my life.
You know, it must be something about the
market that Frank made me take the farm.
Hey, I must dig that
up and give it to her.
Give it to her?
- Would you have me keep it?
She don't need the farm. She'll own half
of New York when she marries that chump.
Yeah. But grandpa won't.
I guess you've blown your topper.
Tippy, I love you.
Good morning, Mr Bradley.
- Good morning, Ernest.
No-one can ever tell me Hartley
Madison is through with racing.
Why, I can see him now putting
down 10, 20, even 50 Gs at a clip.
Sure sounds sweet.
Come in.
Good morning, Carol.
Good morning.
- Well, come in honey.
Thank you.
Isn't Mr Madison with you?
- No, he isn't.
Where is he?
- Newport.
Newport?
- Yes.
Not to stay?
- We're marrying there next month.
Oh.
Then he won't be coming back here?
- No.
And as I told you before ..
If you are planning on Mr Madison as a
victim you might as well give it all up.
Well, you can't blame
me for being ambitious.
Will you have some breakfast?
- I will not.
No? Well, would you mind
sitting down while I have mine?
I came up here to learn what you
intend to do with my father's farm.
Do with it?
- I ..
I hope you won't dispose of it without
at least giving me a chance to buy it.
Oh .. I see.
I assure you I dislike
asking favors of you.
But my grandfather doesn't know
you hold a deed to his property.
I know that.
Well, it would be a kindness if
you don't let him know the truth ..
Until I can have Mr Madison pay you off.
Is that all, before I
reach for a hairbrush?
I don't know how to parry
wisecracks with you.
I fear I have been away
from America too long.
I'll say you've been away too long.
Sit down.
I see coming here was a mistake. I'll
leave things in the hands of the bank.
Just a moment.
Come in.
Hello Duke. Oh, hello Carol.
How do you do.
Hello baby.
Honey, are we off to look at horses?
Fritzi, I must have a talk with Carol.
Do you mind if we postpone our trip?
Why, of course not.
I'll see you at the track, Dukey.
Fritzi, I love you.
Goodbye, Carol.
- Goodbye.
So you think I'm going to
foreclose the mortgage, eh?
Now I'm going to tell
you what I think of you.
I'm not interested in
what you think of me.
I'll not have the frost put on me by
a fellah you roped out of Saratoga ..
With clover on her heels and finished
up with a bad case of swellhead.
It's taken mean old men
working in banks all their lives ..
To figure out notions you
just fastened on me.
Me, Duke Bradley. One of
the boys. Father's friend.
Just a moment. My father could
have lost to other bookmakers.
It seems to me his friendship
paid you mighty well.
I'll answer that crack by assuring you
no matter what other bookmakers do ..
I'm not going to oust grandpa
because I love the old pest.
You can stop worrying about the
farm and start springing the trap ..
When the sucker is bankrolled.
For your information, I'm marrying
Hartley Madison because I love him.
This is Duke. You can level with me.
- I don't know what you talk about.
Don't pretend that Frank's daughter
has fallen for a Wall Street chump.
A Wall Street chump?
Where would you people be if it
weren't for the word 'chump'?
To you it wins any argument.
If you call someone a chump,
then it proves you're his superior.
You, a fly-by-night bookmaker ..
Calling a member of one of the most
important families in American a chump.
A man who could buy and sell 20 petty
gamblers like you with his small change.
I suppose you'd marry him
if he didn't have a quarter?
I'd prefer him that way.
Now open that door.
Alright.
I guess you'd better go ahead and marry
the sucker and let him pay me off.
That's exactly what I intend to do.
You'd better quit kidding yourself
about being in love, babe.
You know from where I sit a gal
that puts the bite on a bridegroom ..
For sixty thousand smackers before
she even gets him to the altar.
Is awfully full of larceny.
- What ..?
Will you open that door?
Sure.
Honey, you're strutting like a pacer.
This bay filly before you
is lot 45 'Dubonnet'.
Thoroughbred and registered.
Her sire is Giva.
One hundred and fifteen
thousand dollars.
Duke.
I'm the most unhappy
person in the world.
What's the matter?
- Dubonnet.
The yearling I wanted to buy ever since
he was born and my husband isn't here.
I got him clear up to the gate
but he wouldn't come in.
What's the matter? No time?
No. He doesn't like horses.
They make him sneeze.
Did you say 'sneeze'?
- Yes, sneeze. Hay fever.
Oh there he is, the sweetheart.
Who, your husband?
- No, that colt.
Twenty-five hundred.
25 hundred.
The gentleman starts right up.
25 hundred. Do I hear 35? Do I hear 35?
Oh, there they go.
Now don't you worry, honey.
Just lead me to Mr Kiffmeyer.
And I'll explain to him that
Dubonnet is sneeze-less.
No, no. Not the two of us together.
- Why not?
He's jealous. He thinks I'm Cleopatra
and every man is in love with me.
Well, who says he's wrong?
Oh, darling. I'd like you to
meet an old friend of mine.
Mr Bradley.
- How do you do.
How .. how old?
- Oh, darling.
There is the horse I was talking about.
There is Dubonnet. Look.
Don't try to change the
subject. I said how old?
Since I was in the chorus.
Oh, there he goes.
Well, let him .. go.
Look Mr Kiffmeyer.
A horse would keep Fritzi from being
lonely while you're away on business.
What?
Yes. And besides, he'd be good
publicity for your cold cream.
Well, my horses don't
need any cold cream.
I mean cold cream doesn't need any ..
- We know what you mean, dear.
Well, you know I can't be around horses.
And how do I know what you
will be doing around horses?
While I can't be around .. horses.
Why, Mr K. Do you mean that?
Well, I .. I .. why?
Fifty-five. Fifty-five hundred is bid.
Now then, do I hear six? Do I hear six?
Six thousand is bid. Thank you, sir.
Whose bid was that, please?
Thank you, sir. Six thousand is bid.
Now then, do I hear six-five?
Gesundheit.
Well, you needn't bother.
Sold for six thousand.
What is the name please?
Mr Jessie Kiffmeyer of New York.
Here, what are you doing?
Sold to Mr Jessie Kiffmeyer of New York.
Good work, Mr K.
You can't .. we can't ..
Boys, how long will to take
a picture of Mr Kiffmeyer?
Why?
Never mind.
But I'm all out of plates.
- That's alright.
There he is, boys.
The new owner of Dubonnet.
You can't bamboozle me into this.
- Fix his tie, Fritzi.
Let me make you pretty, honey.
- I won't buy that horse.
Kiffmeyer is his name but he's enthroned
by 50 million women as 'Harriet Hale'.
Is that who she is?
- The greatest cosmetician in the world.
Well, 'beautician' is
the more modern term.
Hold up your head, Mr Hale.
- Miss Hale.
Well, 'Kiffmeyer' will do.
I beg your pardon, Mr Kiffmeyer.
- Yes?
Please make arrangements
with the cashier.
I'm not ..
Stay here Kiffy at a good sneezing
distance while I go settle for Dubonnet.
I'll go help you.
- No, wait a minute.
I'll take care of your wife.
I mean you take care of ..
Hi, Duke.
Hello, grandpa.
I wish you'd talk to that girl.
I can't do a thing with her.
What girl?
- Carol.
Carol? She's in Newport.
- Newport, nothing.
She's right over there getting
ready to sell Moonray.
The last yearling I've got on the place.
Don't worry now. I'll go
and see what I can do.
Good evening, Carol.
- Well, good evening.
So you didn't go to Newport, huh?
No, I'm at Coney Island.
Why Carol, that almost
sounded like a crack.
You think you ought
to sell grandpa's colt?
I've found I must have some money.
Money?
I'll pay you off before my marriage.
- Pay me off?
Not because of that crack I made
about you clipping Madison?
That had nothing to do with it.
I thought things over. That's all.
Well, I think you're an awful sucker.
If I had a come-on I'd marry him myself.
Besides, this yearling won't bring you
more than a few thousand dollars.
I can run it up to what I owe you.
Run it up? On your stocking?
- Bet it.
You can't beat the law
of averages, Carol.
No?
- No.
Even though you know the track and
know all about handicapping horses.
That's your opinion.
What does Mr Madison think about
you postponing his wedding?
Mr Madison recognises that
there is such a thing as integrity.
Oh, I see.
Say Carol, if you're ready to sell
that horse, they're waiting for you.
Evening, Miss Clayton.
- Good evening.
Good evening.
Alright, Miss Clayton.
Ladies and gentlemen,
this yearling colt is Moonray.
He was bred at the Brookvale farm
and is by our famous sire Dawn Boy.
His dam is that great race
mare .. Planet Girl.
He has been handled and
broken since the first of the year.
He has a grand disposition
and with his royal breeding ..
In a capable trainer's hands should
develop into a great racehorse.
Thank you.
You heard what Miss Clayton
has said about this colt.
Now what is your pleasure,
ladies and gentlemen?
One thousand dollars.
A thousand dollars.
Do I hear two? Do I hear two?
Ha. A thousand dollars?
His tail is worth more than that.
Be still, grandpa.
What did I ever do to have such
a grandchild? A thousand dollars.
Cripes.
Five thousand dollars.
Five thousand is bid.
Thank you. Five. Five.
Well, as I live and breathe
it is Hartley Madison.
And he went for five
grand the first clip.
What a beautiful sucker.
Here's where you get your stake, honey.
- But I don't want ..
Look out, Mr Madison.
I'm coming into this.
Go ahead old boy.
- Fifty-five hundred.
Six thousand.
Sixty-five.
What are you doing?
Bookmakers can't own horses.
I'm going to run the
stake in for you, honey.
Seventy-five.
- Good for you.
Eight.
Say, you're going rather
high on the colt aren't you?
Think so?
Eighty-five.
- Stop it, will you.
Oh, let him alone.
Nine.
Nine thousand is bid.
Ninety-five.
Ten thousand dollars.
I don't want him to be stung
for more than fifteen thousand.
Oh you're crazy. He'll go for twenty.
Ten-five.
Don't go over fifteen Duke, please.
Eleven.
Eleven-five.
I must just say hello to Hartley.
Eleven-five the gentleman bids.
Do you make it twelve?
That colt isn't worth that much.
Twelve thousand.
Hello, sweet.
- Hello, darling.
Twelve-five.
Let him have him at fourteen-five.
But why dear? Thirteen.
I see larceny in your
granddaughter's kisser.
You do?
Please do as I say.
Darling, I'd like to own Moonray.
- Won't you do this for me?
Of course I'll do this for you.
Fourteen thousand.
- Now let him have him.
Fourteen-five.
Mr Madison, you've bought a horse.
Swell.
- But ..
But what, dear?
- Don't you see that he was trying ..
Don't you want me to have Moonray?
Well, of course I do, but ..
Well, Mr Madison. That was a lot of fun.
- Hey, wasn't it.
Why did you quit? You know,
Carol wanted you to have Moonray.
She did?
- Yeah.
Now, wasn't that sweet of her.
Mr Madison, what are you going to
do with that yearling of mine?
I know you didn't buy him for yourself.
How are you, Mr Clayton?
- Alright.
What are you going to do with him?
I got a birthday coming up this month.
Grandpa.
- Oh shut up.
If you want him well trained,
nobody can do it better than grandpa.
That's an idea. Would you keep Moonray
on at Brookvale and train him for me?
Of course he won't.
- Why not?
Darling, he would be doing
me a favor. Will you?
Oh here I am ending up as nursemaid
to a yearling I don't own.
And I ain't even got a stud.
I sure could use one.
Mr Madison. Think you'll do any
betting while you're down this time?
I don't know. Perhaps.
Mr Madison, will you make arrangements
with the cashier, please.
Oh yes, of course.
Duke, look after Carol for me, will you.
- With pleasure.
You leave him alone.
Carol, if a man wants to make
a few little bets, why can't I ..
I told you Mr Madison wasn't betting.
Now leave him alone.
You know, you're kind of cute.
Do you want to take my
bets by any chance?
Carol, if you only bring a man
around the track once in a while ..
Do you want to take my bet?
- Oh sure.
Alright.
Weight a hundred and ten pounds.
[ Laughter ]
I guess that's Miss Fritzi. I guess
Mr Duke told her something funny.
Will you be still.
Look here, honey. You is going to have
a nervous breakup working so hard.
Belmont, Aqueduct and Maryland.
You ain't had a day's rest
since we left Saratoga.
He's carrying a hundred
and fifteen pounds.
That means he's picking up five.
[ Laughter ]
Will you tell Mr Bradley
I'd like to see him.
I sure will.
You got a pencil smudge
on your chin, honey.
What of it?
Don't you want to look
pretty for Mr Bradley?
Why should I?
I would fix up for him anytime.
If he was only the right
color, I'd marry him.
[ Buzzer ]
Come in.
Good evening, Carol. I didn't
know you were on this train.
How long will those friends
of yours keep up that racket?
Surely honey, you haven't forgot
how the mob acts on a racing special.
We're likely to whoop it up all night.
Why not join us and have a little fun?
I'm afraid I've gotten away
from that idea of 'fun'.
Oh .. oh, I see.
How are they coming?
- I can't complain.
No, I should think not.
Do you realize you've nicked my books
for thirty-seven hundred dollars?
Thirty-seven fifty.
- No.
Why, if this luck of yours
keeps up, I'll cut my throat.
Oh, it's luck, is it?
- What do you call it?
I'm afraid I call it hard work.
Say honey. If it's noisy here you can
change with me and take my compartment.
No. No thank you.
No trouble. I'll move the stuff.
- I prefer not.
Rosetta. Tell the porter
to switch our bags.
I sure will.
If there's a crap game there,
tell the boys to get out.
I will.
- And don't get in the game.
You go on, Mr Duke.
Is this everything?
- Yes.
Excuse me.
Hello, Miss Clayton.
- Hello, Clipper.
Look folks, we've got an
Frank's daughter. Good for you.
Thanks.
Hello, honey.
Good evening, Mrs Kiffmeyer.
Hello Fritzi.
- Hello, Duke.
Hello Miss Clayton.
- Hello.
You remember 'handwriting Hurley'?
- Oh. How are you?
Gee, Miss Clayton. It's good to see you.
- Thanks.
I've been thinking about you a
lot since .. since your dad went.
He thought a lot of you, too.
Hurley. I bet she doesn't
remember this one.
Hello Miss Clayton.
Why that's the baby. Little Katy.
It's little Katy, but it's not the baby.
Come here .. oh, Pearl.
Hello, Miss Clayton.
Here is the final edition.
Pearl, how you do things.
Oh you angel. May I take one.
- Of course.
Oh Miss Clayton, you've
come back home again.
Teddy, look out. Duke, take the baby.
- Yeah, yeah.
Katy, you're going to smother me, honey.
Katy, will you be careful and
come here and sit down.
Hey, take this guy will you.
No, Duke. Okay. You're out in front.
- Well, here ..
Here, take this sucker
before I break him.
No. You can keep him.
I've got another one here.
But I didn't want him.
Say, I'm doing alright with this guy.
Say, Duke. I must hit you
for five bucks. You too.
What for?
- Duggan lost his job.
Kick in the green, fellahs.
I'd like to get in on that too, sweet.
- That's swell. Thanks.
Add it for me please.
- Okay.
Come on fellahs, let's see the green.
Hey, Pearl.
I think you'd better take this guy.
- Oh, of course.
Pearl, you'd better take this one too.
Will you join in with me?
- Too right.
[ Singing: ]
"Lend me your ear
and I'll tell you a tale."
"It's the tale of a horse and a frail."
"Who went boom ti-di ad-da-da
da-da-da boom ti-di eh."
"With a boom ti-di ad-da-da
"It's the story of trouble and woe."
"And the loss of a big pile of dough."
"On the nose of a nag
I have learned to despise."
"The horse with the dreamy eyes."
"He went boom ti-di ad-da-da
da-da-da boom ti-di eh."
"The horse with the dreamy eyes."
We want Fritzi.
- Come on, Fritzi.
"He was left all alone at the post."
"But the dope wouldn't
give up the ghost."
"He went boom ti-di ad-da-da
da-da-da boom ti-di eh."
"Boom ti-di ad-da-da
"Oh he ran like the devil to pay."
"But they tell me he ran the wrong way."
"I don't know because I
fainted and Elmer likewise."
"Oh, the horse with the dreamy eyes."
"He went boom ti-di ad-da-da
da-da-da boom ti-di eh."
"Oh .. the horse with the dreamy eyes."
We want Bradley.
Get away.
Alright, alright. You asked for it.
"When he came trotting
out on to the track."
"He had a limp and a crick in his back."
"He went boom ti-di ad-da-da
da-da-da ti-di eh."
"Boom ti-di ad-da-da da-da-da ti-di eh."
"His whinny was more like a cough."
"And when somebody
shouted: they're off!"
"To his face came a
horrible look of surprise."
"The horse with the dreamy eyes."
"He went boom ti-di ad-da-da
da-da-da ti-di eh."
"Oh .. the horse with the dreamy eyes."
We want Mr Oglethorpe.
Look. There is Rosy.
We want ..
Miss Carol, your compartment is ready.
- Thank you, Rosetta.
Hey Rosetta, come on.
Give us a little song.
Mr Duke, I can't do that.
Go on.
- Oh, alright.
"So you know why I'm feeling forlorn."
"I've been broke since
the day I was born."
"I went boom ti-di ad-da-da
boom da-da-da ti-di eh."
"Boom ti-di ad-da-da da-da-da ti-di eh."
"And the reason I'm in such a fix."
"Is that men and horses don't mix."
"Take a tip and beware girls,
if you recognise."
"The horse with the dreamy eyes."
"He went boom ti-di ad-da-da
da-da-da ti-di oh."
"The horse with the dreamy eyes."
We want Preston.
"If they ever discover .."
I guess I'd better be going. Goodnight.
Wait a minute. I'll go with you.
Now you can work to
your heart's content.
The gang won't disturb you in here.
You think I'm an awful snob, don't you.
No, I wouldn't say that.
- I know you do.
There are really other things in
the world beside racetracks.
Well, yes. I suppose there are.
- You've never been to Europe, have you?
Nope.
You should see England sometime.
You mean Ascot, Epsom Downs, Newmarket?
They must be swell.
No. I wasn't thinking about racetracks.
Oh no. That's right.
You ought to see one of those
big English country houses ..
Where one family has
carried on for centuries.
You know, traditions of sportsmanship ..
Honor handed down from father to son.
Oh yeah, like a line of
thoroughbreds, huh?
Well, yes.
Did you ever look at an old painting
and know just what the artist ..
Wanted you to feel when he
painted it 400 years ago?
No, I never did.
- Well, I learned all of those things.
You know what you'd like?
Punting on the Thames.
With the oaks making a green
roof and the sky coming through.
Hey, I did punt once when I was a kid.
In a mud scow on the Ohio.
There are so many things to do
in the world. So many things to see.
And so many wonderful people to meet.
Now, Carol. I never got you before.
I begin to see what you're driving at.
You are?
- Yeah.
I believe I'd go for those things myself
in a big way if I wasn't such a mug.
You're not a mug. You've got
brains, looks, personality ..
Will you quit your kidding.
- I'm not kidding.
Gee honey, it kinda gives me
a lift to know you feel that way.
I'm all for you getting
the things you want.
Thanks. I'm glad you understand.
I do. But you never put it to
me straight like that before.
I know. I'm sorry.
Say look.
I've got an idea that will put us both
closer to punting on the Thames.
You have? What is it?
When you get to Florida,
where will you stay?
The Park Central. Well go on, Duke.
Well, when we get there .. you phone
Madison and have him come down.
Now all you have to do is to say the
word and he'll come running. Then.
Let him do a little betting with me.
I'll cut you in for 20% of my winnings.
And gee honey, you'll have that
market paid off in no time at all.
Get out of here.
What?
- I said get out of here.
Why, what's the matter?
Nothing, except that I thought
you had a grain of decency.
Don't be like that.
You brought me here just
for this. Now get out.
You'll get wise to ..
- Get out of here.
Alright, alright.
Carol, you don't belong to this ..
- I said, get out!
Why, Miss Carol.
Tell me child, what is the matter?
I never want to see that
cheap, swell-headed ..
Smart-aleck bookmaker
again as long as I live.
Oh Miss Carol. Why, honey.
Baby.
Just a minute, please.
- Hello, Mr Madison.
Hello Bradley.
Why are you in New York?
- I came to see you.
Really?
- Yes.
This place is tougher to
crash than the pearly gates.
Duke, will you excuse me just a minute?
- Yeah, sure. Go ahead.
Where was I?
'If they could be procured
on a satisfactory basis ..'
I am willing to pay 101 net to me for a
commitment up to a million and a half.
Kindly advise me regarding
this immediately.
Yours, etc. That's all.
Shall we do any of that new
government issue, Mr Madison?
I'll see about that later on.
- Yes, sir.
Now what can I do for you, Duke?
Well.
It's about Carol.
Carol? What's wrong?
Carol needs you, Mr Madison.
She's not well.
No? Why, I spoke to her last night in
Baltimore before she left for Florida.
Did she seem alright?
She didn't say anything about not being.
- She didn't seem nervous, irritable?
Well, now you mention it. Yes she did.
Yes, yes. You know,
Carol is not her old self at all.
She's seen a doctor?
- No.
No she hasn't and she's
just a bundle of nerves.
Why, do you know that last night on the
train I tried to make her send for you.
And believe it or not she ordered
me out of the compartment.
She did?
- Yes. Flew into a rage.
That's bad, Duke. That's very bad.
She takes this job of hers so seriously.
- Yes. I'm afraid she does.
I think you should go to
Florida and talk with her.
Well, maybe you are right.
Yes. With you there to bounce around the
track and help her pick those winners ..
I'll go, Duke. I'll go right away and ..
And say, I'll take Dr Bierd with me.
That's what I'll do.
He'll find out what's the matter.
Hello, get me Dr Bierd on the phone.
Dr Harmsworth Bierd.
- Now look, Mr Madison.
You needn't do that. There's
plenty of good doctors down there.
Nobody like Bierd. The best nerve
specialist this side of Vienna.
Yes, I know. But a big doctor like
that, he might upset her terribly.
But at least he'll find
out what's the matter.
Hello? Hello Dr Bierd, can you fly
to Florida with me right away?
Now look, Mr Madison, I don't think ..
We are going today.
It is for my fiance.
It's a bad case of nerves and
I want you to look her over.
Well, we're leaving from Roosevelt
Field in a couple of hours.
Uhuh. Alright, I'll pick you up.
Goodbye.
May I assist you, Miss Washington?
- Thank you, Mr Meyers.
Why, Miss Carol, there is Mr Madison.
Don't be silly, Rosetta.
Mr Madison is in New York.
Carol.
Darling.
- Hello, honey.
Why sweetheart, what's the matter?
- What are you doing down here?
Darling, Duke said you weren't
feeling up to scratch.
Oh, he did?
See, I had to go back to
New York on business.
So, naturally I dropped
in to see Hartley and ..
Well, here we are.
Thought I'd help you pick some winners.
- I don't need any help.
Why Carol, of course you don't.
And darling, it's ..
Oh, Dr Bierd.
Oh yes. Dr Bierd just happened
to be coming down too.
This is Miss Clayton, Dr Bierd.
Oh yes, yes.
How do you do, my dear?
- How do you do.
I thought Dr Bierd could look you over.
What for? What is the meaning of this?
You see, Hartley was very worried ..
- What are you talking about?
Now don't get excited.
- Who's excited?
Nobody. I'm sorry if I upset you.
I'm not upset, but
let's get out of here.
Carol. Carol.
Haven't you forgotten something?
What?
Oh well, go ahead dear. Don't mind us.
Of course not.
Of course not, what?
You haven't kissed Hartley hello.
Aren't you glad to see him?
- What do you think?
This is absolutely ridiculous, doctor.
I said there's nothing wrong with me.
Quiet now. Just relax.
Miss Clayton, when was your
wedding originally planned?
Last August.
- That's five months ago.
Dear, dear, dear, dear.
There's nothing organically
wrong with that little heart.
But it's beating much, much too fast.
I told you I was alright.
Of course. But you are a
highly emotional type.
What are you drivelling about?
You are a woman who's entire system
is regulated by her emotions.
You should be married now.
And cooing contentedly in
your own dear little nest.
What?
And now I want you to take a soothing
lukewarm effervescent bath.
I will send you a masseuse who'll
give you a light gentle massage.
And then in this quiet, darkened room
you can have a restful, peaceful nap.
I've let you spoil my day at the track.
But I won't take a warm, dark
effervescent nap for you or anyone else.
Dear, dear, dear. Mr Madison
should never have come down.
Neither should you.
- Now, now. My dear child.
There is nothing wrong with me.
I am perfectly normal.
That's just it. Entirely too normal.
I suggest you see as little as possible
of your fiance until you are married.
And I hope I may soon have the pleasure
of an invitation to that wedding.
Goodbye.
Bless your heart.
Hey ho.
What is it?
- Oh, it's nothing, really.
Are you alright, darling?
What's happened?
It's just nerves.
You see, she's ..
Would you excuse us?
- Yes.
What did you find? Is it serious?
But it's no case for a doctor.
Well, what is it?
'Amor solum a medicina
sanari non posse'.
What does that mean?
It means that love
cannot be cured by pills.
Love? Why ..
You mean ..?
- Uhuh.
Why, the poor little darling.
- Yes.
She ought not to see too much of you.
- Alright.
We make it as easy for her as possible.
- Oh yes. Yes, of course.
I'll see you before I leave.
- Alright. Thanks.
You are a very lucky man.
- Hmm.
Goodbye, Mr Bradley.
- Goodbye, doctor.
[ Radio: ]
"Nineteen horses are lined up."
This is the race that Carol is on.
- Really?
Uhuh.
Rosetta. Want a hot tip?
Yes sir, Mr Duke. Give me
something I can hope for.
Ski Ball. 3-1. I got it right
from the horse himself.
Won't them other horses be surprised?
I'm going to bet two bucks on him.
Oh, make it five.
- Alright, Mr Duke. I'll make it ten.
Ski Ball? That's Carol's one isn't it?
- Uhuh.
Want a bet?
No, I don't think so.
Oh, why not do it for Carol?
She's got that wedding date.
They've started.
Invite me to the
wedding and I'll take it.
"At the turn it's Ski Ball by a length."
- Look at that Ski Ball go.
Man, look at her go.
Odds on Ski Ball now?
3-1.
- 3-1?
That's what I offer.
How about a thousand dollars?
- Make it two.
Alright. You're on.
- My, oh my.
Come in.
Will you want me again, Mr Madison?
No, that's all today.
Come on, Ski Ball. Come on.
"At the three quarters,
it's Ski Ball by four lengths."
"Mink Coat is second by a head."
Where is Gloria Kay?
Not mentioned.
- Where's Rocket?
Left at the post.
Were you on Rocket?
- Yes.
Too bad. I could have given
you Ski Ball. Come on.
Come on, Ski Ball. Come on.
Come on.
- Come on Ski Ball.
"It's Ski Ball by five lengths."
Yo!
Ain't that Ski Ball a
sweetheart? My, oh my ..
Did you lose much, Boswell?
- Two dollars, sir.
That's too bad.
Here you are, Rosie.
Thank you, Mr Duke. It's just
like you made us a present.
I'll give you a check, Hartley.
- That's alright, Duke.
Oh, hello honey. When did you come in?
I came in with Ski Ball.
One touch of horse flesh
makes the whole world, kid.
Darling, I won six
thousand dollars on Ski Ball.
Well, isn't that fine.
- Yes, the man is a wizard.
For your fund. We are six thousand
dollars nearer our wedding day.
I can't do that, Hartley.
- Why, darling ..
Now honey, you're spoiling
half of Hartley's fun.
Please.
I've got to do this myself.
You know that.
Alright, darling. Just as you say.
Duke .. it's been a long time since
Hartley and I have seen each other.
Do you mind?
Oh no. No, of course not.
Thanks, Duke.
Hartley, when you going
to pick a new winner?
Oh, I'll make some
selections in the morning.
Why don't we all have luncheon together
on the patio and go to the track later?
That's fine.
You know, I think Florida is
going to do us all some good.
Be careful you don't get sunstruck.
Isn't she cute?
Hartley. I don't want you
betting with that fellow.
Why not?
- Because ..
Because, can you see
what he's trying to do?
He's trying to get you
to start betting again.
But sweetheart, Duke always lost to me.
Look what I did to him today.
- That doesn't matter.
You don't belong to the track. What do
you know about handicapping horses?
It's all simply a ..
- Carol, wait.
What you are trying to tell me is ..
Well.
Is that .. that you want
me to go, isn't it?
Yes.
Well, I understand, sweetheart.
It's alright.
Understand what?
Why you want me to go.
You see, Dr Bierd explained it to me.
Dr Bierd?
- Uhuh.
Dr Bierd ..?
But darling, there is
nothing to be ashamed of.
'The chump with the dreamy eyes'.
'He'll go boom ti-di ad-da-da
da-da-da boom ti-di eh'.
What do you think you're doing?
- Getting the odds ready for Hartley.
Yeah, that was a great idea of yours.
Giving him 3-1 on Ski Ball today.
I think so.
Do you know that Ski Ball
was a 10-7 shot?
Why you're the meanest man I ever saw.
Denying a poor little sucker his bait.
Did you say 'sucker'?
The trouble with you is you don't know
how to deal with the bigtime operators.
Why, in ten days we'll
be rolling in dough.
Yes, and in thirty minutes he'll
be rolling off the flying field.
His bags are down on the sidewalk now.
What?
He's leaving for New York.
And he took you for six G's.
If he's a sucker, I'm a goldfish.
Where you going, chump?
[ Buzzer ]
Is that you, Rosetta?
- Yes, ma'am. It's me.
Well, come in.
Well.
It's Bradley. Fancy seeing you here.
So you sent him away, huh?
- Of course I did.
You didn't think I'd let him stay?
- Why you double-crosser.
Hello.
Hello. Get me room 218.
Nice weather for Hartley's flight.
Hello, Tip? Pack me a bag right away.
I'm catching a plane with Madison.
Yeah. Okay.
That will do you a lot of good.
- All we need is a radio.
You've been to Hartley's
office, haven't you?
Yep.
And of course, he'll
just drop everything.
What do his financial
transactions amount to?
He'll disregard the stock market and ..
Simply devote his time to
listening to the radio with you.
Look, Carol. Won't you let me
have him for just ten days?
I think you'd better go now. Hartley
phoned and he's coming to say goodbye.
Well, what of it?
He won't like you if he finds you here.
No.
That wouldn't look so good
for you either, would it?
I'll explain: you forced your way in.
[ Door knocks ]
Wait a minute.
What are you doing?
If you're so good at
explaining, explain this.
Will you come out of there, Duke.
- If I were you, I'd ask him to stay.
Hartley might not like it if I
happen to make some noise.
[ Door knocks ]
Duke. Please.
Please.
Will you come out of there.
[ Door knocks ]
Carol, I haven't much time, sweet.
Is that you dear?
Come in.
Hello, sweet.
I am sorry. I was too sore.
No, no. Don't get up. I've only
time to kiss you goodbye.
Darling, it's been wonderful being with
you. And I do hope that you will feel ..
Is there ..?
Sweetheart.
Well, what is it, Hartley?
When did you ..?
When did I what?
When did you start smoking cigars?
Oh, I just picked it up.
I am trying to obey
doctor's orders. He said ..
No more cigarettes.
But dear, you'll make yourself ill.
Yes.
Well, I've got to do
something for my nerves.
I know darling, but cigars?
And that's a strong one.
I know. I ..
I won't smoke it anymore if
you don't want me to, Hartley.
You poor darling.
I'm so worried about you.
But you mustn't worry about me.
What is it, sweet?
Hartley.
I wish you'd stay in Florida.
You do, dear?
- Yes.
Well, darling, I'd only
be too happy to stay.
That is .. well ..
If you are sure my being
here wouldn't upset you.
Why, of course it wouldn't upset me.
I want you to stay.
But you said this afternoon ..
- Yes. I know.
But I'm nervous. Sometimes ..
I want you to go and
sometimes I want you to stay.
Right now I want you to stay.
- I know.
What difference if I am nervous?
What difference if I am a little upset?
I want you stay.
Don't you see, darling?
I couldn't do that.
You are too considerate, Hartley.
You always think of
everybody but yourself.
Why shouldn't you have a holiday?
Darling, I'm going to go.
Please.
- No.
Please, Hartley.
- No more.
You mustn't go. You can't go.
I won't let you.
Darling, we settled
all that this afternoon.
Now please calm yourself.
And believe me darling,
I know what's best.
Alright .. whatever you say.
Goodbye, sweet.
Bless your little heart.
You will go straight to bed
now won't you, darling.
And please don't smoke
any more of those things.
I won't.
I'll phone when I get to New York.
Goodbye.
- Goodbye, darling.
Why, the man is an iceberg.
Now I've got to steam
him up all over again.
I hope you weren't too uncomfortable.
Well, it was pretty warm
until you smoked that cigar.
I'll send you a box sometime.
Oh but baby, how you
went to town for Dukey.
You idiot. I did the one thing
that would send him away.
You did? What was that?
- I kissed him.
And that sent him away?
Oh Carol, you underestimate yourself.
You don't understand.
Hartley happens to be a gentleman.
Oh. Then I'm glad I'm a mug.
Kiss me like that and see if I go home.
Well ..
You don't think that I tried to make
him stay here for you, do you?
Oh no, no. Of course not.
Why, I never dreamed of it.
I sent him away.
- Yeah.
You don't believe me, do you?
- Sure, sure. I believe you.
Didn't I hear it?
He went because the
doctor told him I was ..
The doctor told him that you were what?
- That I was ..
Nothing.
Will you please leave?
Honey.
I love you.
You and your sucker, huh?
We trail him to New York. I bet you all
I got against a quarter we get him back.
Yeah. Just like your girlfriend
got him to stay here for you.
Carol tried to get him to stay. She went
to town for me like a little champion.
She did, huh? She double-crossed
you like a 6th Avenue girl.
And you thought you were
shoving her around. Ha.
What a ladies' man. What a ladies' man.
Hello Duke.
Will you say that again?
- Say what?
Well, is it really you?
- Surprised, are you?
Well, no. Not exactly. Sit down.
- Thanks.
Carol fairly insisted on my staying.
She stopped me at the airport.
She did?
- Yeah.
Well, bless her little heart.
Meet Carol's fiance.
This is my sheet writer.
How do you do.
- I'm certainly pleased to meet you.
Thanks .. say Duke, there is
horse Carol likes today: Rester.
Rester?
- Yes.
Did you say 'Rester'?
- And Carol likes him?
Yeah.
Well, he's in this next race.
They are at the post now.
Oh is he? What price can you give me?
7-1.
- 7-1?
How about five thousand?
- Hartley, you got a bet.
Where's the lady?
She's a headache.
She's staying in her room.
Oh, that's too bad. I'm sorry.
Come on, Rester. Come on, Rester!
Say .. where is Rester now?
I'm afraid he's running a bad third.
Yes. I am afraid.
Come on.
Rester seems to be falling behind.
Slightly.
Yes, he's now running a deep last.
- Carol must have had a headache.
Yes, she must have.
Well, he'll be home in time for dinner.
Anyway, it took eight
horses to beat him.
That's right. Well, I've got to get
back to the hotel and see Carol.
Give her my love.
- Thanks.
I'll give you a check tonight, Duke.
- Alright. Put it on tomorrow's bet.
Thanks. See you later, boys.
- So long.
Well, I've certainly
got to hand it to you.
Is he worthwhile waiting for.
But .. why did she ever pick Rester?
Why do you think?
- Huh?
[ Whistle ]
Dukey, I love you.
Mr Bradley.
- Morning.
One?
Hello, Duke. How's things
at Huntingdon Downs?
Okay.
No, never mind.
Well, this is luck.
Good morning, honey. How are you?
Duke.
Oh madam, you look broadminded.
I've loved this woman for years.
You're lucky. Mine only lasted two days.
Duke, you remember my husband?
Oh yes. Brother Kiffmeyer.
How do you do?
How do you do.
- I didn't know you were on the train.
No, that's quite obvious.
Would you mind dropping my wife's hand?
Where would I drop it? Out the window?
- Don't try to laugh your way out of it.
Madam, I ask you. Is there
anything wrong with this?
I wish she'd change places with me.
- There. You see?
There you see.
You were so afraid my wife would be
lonely if I didn't buy her horses.
Well, I bought her horses.
And now I wonder whether she's around
the country with horses or whether ..
She's around the horses with you.
You heard what she said.
Madam, would you rather be around
horses or would .. or would ..?
Mister, I'm afraid you
don't understand us women.
I? I don't understand women?
Madam. Do you know who I am?
I haven't the slightest idea.
- Yes. Well, I'm Harriet Hale.
Not the beauty queen?
Exactly, and now Mr Bradley.
If you would ..
Can you say why your foundation cream
always cakes when you put on powder?
Cakes? My cream cakes?
Madam, you don't know how to apply it.
And madam, here for you ..
- I'd say you don't know how to make it.
Madam. Harriet Hale's foundation cream.
Has been the basis for women's
beauty for twenty years.
Now Mr Bradley, I just want ..
- Kiffy please.
Well, just a moment.
- So how do you apply it?
With a circular motion.
Don't you read the directions?
I tried that.
Yes. Well, from now on madam,
your face is in your own hands.
That's a fine way to
talk to your public.
Well I ..
Yes. Well, I'm sorry.
I was distraught.
Yes. I distraught him.
You keep out of this.
If you come to my compartment, madam,
I will show you how to apply it.
May I watch?
If you so much as speak to your wife ..
I mean .. his wife.
We know whose wife you mean, darling.
Well just ..
Mr Hale, you'll never know how my face
looked before I used your preparation.
Yes. Well, I can imagine.
All I want to say to
you, Mr Bradley is ..
I don't fool you for a minute.
I mean you don't fool ..
You're a pernicious influence.
Oh Kiffy, why don't you show
the lady how to use the cream?
Oh, so you want to get
rid of me. That's it, is it?
Alright.
I'll see you in the compartment.
And alone.
Do you think he can do my face any good?
Well, look at me madam.
And I'm forty-five years old.
Why, you don't look twenty-five.
Well, that's what Harriet
Hale has done for me.
What's the number of
Mr Hale's compartment?
6B. Car 51.
Thank you. I'll leave the door open.
Thanks.
Poor Kiffy. Isn't he an old darling.
The salt of the earth.
If he just wasn't so jealous.
Not only that. You know. He's a pretty
smart guy when he's away from the track.
A lot smarter than I'd be.
- Good morning.
Good morning.
- Good morning, Rosetta.
How is Miss Carol?
- That cold she caught is worse.
It is?
- Yes, Mr Duke.
I came to get her some more juice
so she can take some castor oil ..
But I know she won't take it.
- Yes she will.
You hustle up the orange juice.
Bring me some too.
Yes, sir.
I'd say it's tough on a kid ..
Knocking around the country all
alone trying to beat the ponies.
Yes.
You're in love with
her Duke, aren't you?
Who?
- Carol.
What makes you think so?
- Oh, I've been around the block.
I knew it before you did.
No you didn't. I knew it the
first time I took a hinge at her.
Why don't you tell her so?
Well Fritzi, Carol's father
was my best friend.
The last thing he ever said to me was he
wanted her to get away from this racket.
To be something better
than a dressed-up gypsy.
I can't ask her to leave
what Madison gives her ..
Just to knock around
a racetrack with me.
If she loved you, she'd be
happy staying in a barn.
No, Fritzi.
I haven't the dough to fix up Brookvale
the way it was for her and grandpa.
And to sure that it would always be
kept that way. You know, security.
And I expect to get it from Mr Madison.
Madison is going to make
you and Carol comfortable?
And grandpa.
Why, you magnificent so and so.
Fritzi, I love you.
I'll go and give her that medicine.
Who is it?
- It's Duke.
Just a minute.
What's the matter, honey?
- I'm not dressed.
Well, put on something.
I don't look good in 'something'.
Well then, put on 'anything'.
You could be dressed
for the Arctic by now.
Come in.
Good morning, honey.
How are you feeling?
- I'm fine.
Say, you look great in that Kimono.
Thanks, but it's a negligee.
Well, what did you want, Duke?
- What?
Oh, I came to doctor that cold of yours.
Hey, you've got a fever.
- No, it's warm in here. That's all.
Oh yeah? Well, I think you'd
better get into this bed.
Were you in this horse blanket
when I knocked just now?
Yes. Rosetta brought it for me.
Alright. You get right back in it.
I know you're pretty.
Well. But I ..
- Come, now. Get in this bed.
This is more work that I've done
for a woman since my mother.
You got any goose-grease around here?
- There is something in that case there.
But I don't need anything, Duke.
Hey, that's a pretty swell layout.
Everything but a pipe.
A present from Hartley?
- Yes.
Isn't that just like him.
Thoughtful until the last detail.
I don't want that. It smells.
- Alright then. Hold your nose.
Did Kiffy and Fritzi make the train?
- Sure. I just left them.
Oh you did?
Are you in love with her, Duke?
With Fritzi? How you talk.
Well, Kiffy thinks you are.
Did he tell you that, too?
Isn't he cute, the old sweetheart.
Only me and fifty others.
Roll over.
- No. I don't want to.
Come on, roll over.
- Oh Duke.
What's the matter?
Oh, I was thinking about
that night in Miami.
When you tried to smoke my cigar?
- If I live to be a thousand ..
I'll never forget the way you looked
coming out from underneath that couch.
Lie still, will you.
Lie still.
Okay, will you lie still.
What's the matter?
Here.
You alright?
Yes.
I'm alright now.
You had me scared there for a minute.
Hey, Duke.
Yeah. What is it honey?
I love you, Duke.
Say, what are you trying to do?
Steal my gag line?
Isn't it about time we
quit kidding ourselves.
Kidding ourselves?
- Yes.
I've just been riding Hartley.
Breaking our engagement.
You what?
It's all over. I never
want to see him again.
You never want to see him again?
- No, I'm breaking it all off.
Great guns, honey. He'll be
coming down to Kentucky.
You can't do that to me.
What?
I can't do what to you?
- Take my chump out of circulation.
I can't ..?
I can't do it to you?
Well, how do you like that.
- What's the matter?
I see what I've been to you.
Just a come on, a steer girl.
Will you talk sense. Stop dramatizing.
- A steer girl, just a steer girl.
There you see. Now get
back under those covers.
You get out of my room.
You get back under those covers. What
are you trying to do? Catch pneumonia.
Here, take this.
- It's the wrong one.
I will not.
- Take it.
Alright.
Now, that's a fine thing to do.
And to think I nearly let
him go. A man. A real man.
That's just what I was telling you.
The most beautiful man in the world.
He is, eh? Right, I'll get him for you.
- You will?
I'll get him for you in Kentucky.
- Honey, now you're talking.
I'll handicap for him ..
And he'll wind you up on a street
corner with a tin cup in your hand.
Thank you, honey. And here's luck.
My, my.
Dixie Gordon has grabbed
the lead and he's riding pretty.
Looks like you made a bad bet, Hartley.
- Hurley's passed him though.
When Gordon gets out
in front he's hard to catch.
Hurley is riding the best horse though.
That's why Carol picked him.
Hurley is moving up. Come on.
Hurley is giving him his head.
He will pass Gordon at the turn.
Want to double your bet?
I'll give you four to one now.
Huh?
- 4-1.
Take it.
Okay.
- You're on.
Gordon is sure giving your horse a ride.
- He certainly is.
Try it on the outside, Hurley.
- I've got the right of way.
Stay back or I'll put
you into the fence.
Who went down?
- Hurley.
Hurley?
That's done it.
The little fellow is alright, honey.
Just shaken up a bit, that's all.
Can you beat that Dixie coming home on a
nag that couldn't pull a laundry wagon.
Duke .. Duke.
Fritzi.
Did you see Dixie ride? And I have him.
I got him on contract for The Hopeful.
What?
- Yeah.
So The Hopeful is in
your pocket, Fritzi.
Honey, I love you.
Wait a minute. I want you all to witness
that I've ordered this man to keep ..
It's alright. Don't apologise.
- I'm not apologising to you.
You keep away from my wife.
That's all I'm telling you now or ..
Kiffy, look out.
You've got the horses doing it.
Don't you try to laugh
your way out of this.
I can't stay around horses. Come on.
You'd better watch out, Duke.
Do you mind, dear? Let's go.
- Right, darling. See you at the hotel.
Fine. Too bad you lost today.
Better luck next time.
Thank you, honey.
- What for?
For getting Hartley to double his bet.
What do you want to make her mad for?
The madder she gets, the more she makes
him bet and the worse she handicaps him.
Hey, son.
- Yes? A Coke?
No, no. I just want one of these cups.
Take her this and tell her
I'm sorry it isn't tin.
Thank you.
Oh, Carol.
Duke asked me to give you this and
tell you he's sorry it isn't tin.
My, my.
Oh Miss Carol, here is some
more tin cups from Mr Duke.
Throw them out.
- All of them?
- Yes, ma'am.
Does you want to hear the note?
- No.
Well, it says: 'Remember Dukey'.
Ain't he the tease?
He teases me about my complexion.
And he teases you about
Mr Madison losing all that money.
And he teases Mr Kiffmeyer
about his wife.
He's always teasing somebody.
But nobody gets mad except
you and Mr Kiffmeyer.
Get me the United States Hotel.
These cups is just what I need
to put my knick-knacks in.
Throw them things in the ashcan.
Get Mr Kiffmeyer. Mr Jesse Kiffmeyer.
Can't I have just one
to remember him by?
Throw those things in the ashcan.
Hello? Hello?
Hello?
Yes, this is .. oh, Miss Clayton.
Yes, of course Dixie Gordon's
contract is in my name.
You see, my financial responsibility ..
Oh. My wife and that Bradley?
Yes. Well, I'd do anything. I mean ..
Almost anything.
You do?
Oh, you don't.
Oh you do?
Oh. You don't.
Well, I mean ..
You do.
Yes, you can have the contract.
You can have the horse if you want to.
Well, just hold the phone.
I'll see if it's here.
Just .. one moment please.
[ Singing: ]
"It has a lucky new swing."
"Saratoga."
"But it's a dangerous thing."
"Dames from Who's Who."
"With the lads."
"Do this rambling, gambling hullabaloo."
"Whenever you're on the go."
"Saratoga."
"Whenever you're in the dough."
"Straight played for show."
"Celebrate."
"Find the hottest spot of hide and ho."
"For if tonight is the night,
tomorrow is the day."
"Your luck may change."
"Romance while you play."
"It's the height of delight."
Here is to the greatest
two-year old in the world.
Hartley, what's his name?
- Moonray.
What a charming name.
Gentlemen, I give you Moonray.
I say Hartley, a racing
chap up at the hotel ..
Has given me Dubonnet to
win on account of his jockey.
Dixie Gordon is the best money
riding jockey on the turf.
But Moonray is a great horse.
And horses have a little bit
to do with racing you know.
Hartley, I'm afraid you prejudiced.
Maybe, but I think my horse is
going to win. And I'm backing ..
Ah, of course ..
Carol doesn't agree with me but
I'm backing him nevertheless.
Excuse me, gentlemen.
Shall we dance, darling?
Why do you aggravate me like this?
Wait a minute, Carol. I've lost a lot
of money on your handicapping.
If I want to bet on
my horse it's my risk.
But why must you bet tonight?
By race time tomorrow,
Duke's odds might change.
Hello there, you two lovebirds.
- Hello, Steve.
Keep right on. We don't want
to interfere with romance.
Thank you.
I tell you Moonray can't win tomorrow
with Dixie Gordon on Dubonnet.
That's your opinion, but my
new trainer thinks he can.
Your new trainer is
trying to keep his job.
He can't do any more for
Moonray than grandpa did.
You're darn tooting.
Putting a new-fangled
trainer on Moonray.
Why, I raised him on the bottle
from the time he was four.
And nursed him through that
bad sickness in September.
We know that, grandpa.
His sire had distemper twice in '31.
And his granddaddy had a quarter
crack a month before The Preakness.
And I cured them both.
Did you know that?
- Yes. You told me that Mr Clayton.
Yeah. Well, they was both champions.
Moonray will be a champion, too.
Go and take him away from me just before
The Hopeful when he needs me the most.
I've been just like a father to him.
- Oh, please, grandpa.
Moonray ain't going to fold up tomorrow.
I got him ready. He's a fit horse.
And he'll win.
He ain't going to forget
nothing I told him.
Grandpa, why are you
taking your shoes off?
I'm taking them off so I won't
kick that new trainer of yours.
That isn't funny, grandpa.
- You ain't funny either.
And he's blowed his topper.
Shall we go inside?
- Yes, Hartley.
Goodnight.
Confound this halter.
Household full of Newport chumps.
Nothing in the stable but dry rot.
A new trainer.
My dogs hurt.
Hey .. who are you?
Shush. Please, I'm a ..
Are you the caretaker here?
- Caretaker?
Why you infernal jackass.
My grandfather built this dump.
Oh, well. I'm very sorry.
I want to see Miss Clayton.
What about?
Well, it's .. it's something personal.
Very Private?
Private? Why you old fool.
You're old enough to be her father.
What do you mean? Are you insinuating?
Why, I am a married man.
I wonder.
- Here you is, Mr Clayton.
Would you tell Miss Clayton I would like
to see her at once? It's very important.
Yes, sir. Come right in.
- No, ask her to come out here please.
Yes, sir.
You know, I don't know what it is ..
But there is something
about you I don't like.
Oh.
Well, if you feel that way, I must say
I don't like you very much either.
Hello, Mr Kiffmeyer.
Miss Clayton, I wanted ..
Grandpa, do you mind?
Do I mind what?
It?
I'm going down to the
barn where it don't smell.
Do you think that we'd better ..?
Well, how about it?
Well, it's a great idea, but do you ..
Think that I am doing the right thing?
Is Duke Bradley doing
the right thing to you?
No. But are you sure that your horse
will win if that Dixie Gordon rides him?
I'll be my farm on it.
And will Mr Madison make a
large bet with that Bradley?
Big enough to break him.
Yes. Well, that's all I want to know.
Here it is.
She tells me she doesn't care for him ..
But I can't believe a word she says now
she's been running around with horses.
You have to sign this over
to me, Mr Kiffmeyer.
Oh, yes.
But suppose that Bradley finds
out and won't take the bet?
He can't find out unless you tell him.
Don't tell the jockey until tomorrow.
Now, sign right here.
Yes, well.
Alright.
I've been trying to place this guy.
Do you know who he is?
His wife owns Dubonnet.
Go along, grandpa.
- He's up to something.
Look at him. He's as
guilty as a horse thief.
Now look here, Mr Clayton, you can't ..
Will you desist.
First of all he calls me a caretaker
and then tells me to 'desist'.
Get off this place.
- Now look here, grandpa.
Don't you call me grandpa.
- Will you leave us alone one minute.
Alright. But I don't trust that guy.
A house full of monkeys and no stud.
I don't ..
Hurry. Before we're
interfered with again.
Yes.
I hope this ..
Puts that Bradley where he belongs.
- So do I.
Yes, and I hope that nobody
will know I've been here.
Goodbye.
- Goodbye.
Hello?
Saratoga 1-5-5-8.
Darling, do you think
this is quite right?
Quite right?
Carol, have you and Duke had a quarrel?
A quarrel? With that bookmaker?
I don't know. You get so violent about
the man I can't help thinking that ..
Hello?
Let me speak with Mr Bradley.
Mr Duke Bradley.
Please.
Has there been anything between you two?
You're out of your mind.
Hello? Hello, Duke?
I'd like to place a bet on Moonray
in tomorrow's Hopeful.
Did you say Moonray?
Well, how about me coming out to talk
it over with you? I've nothing to do.
Sure, I'll be right over. Goodbye.
Well, cross your fingers.
Brother Madison?
- Yeah. I thought I'd lost him.
But he's gone sentimental.
- He's going to back his own nag?
You know how a sucker goes when
he falls in love with his own horse.
Fritzi, if luck is with me,
this closes my book for good.
You wouldn't quit the track?
Why not?
That leaves me a lone gypsy.
Honey, I love you.
So long.
- Good luck, Duke.
How are you, Dixie?
- Hello, Duke.
Hey listen you little mug. You'd better
give that Dubonnet a ride tomorrow.
Duke my boy, cracks like that annoy me.
I wish I had your humility.
Hello, Mr Bradley.
How are you this evening?
Fine, fine. What's the matter with you?
Oh, nothing is the matter with me.
I'm quite alright.
Give me a brandy, please.
Better make it a double brandy.
Oh, Kiffy. Hello, darling.
Well. It's good to see
you alone for a change.
Are you going to start that again?
Yes, but you haven't been alone long.
I just saw your boyfriend leaving.
May I sit down?
Oh look, darling, are you going
to stop that silly nonsense.
Well, maybe.
Kiffy, darling.
- Yes?
Duke has given me
something to think about.
He has?
- Yes.
He may leave the track after tomorrow.
Yes, that's right. He may.
What do you mean by that?
Well I mean, that's what you just said.
Oh, yes.
He's been in love with
Carol Clayton for a year.
But he wouldn't ask her
to marry him because ..
Well, he didn't feel that he could
do as much for her as Madison can.
But if Duke wins enough money
tomorrow, he's going to tell her.
He's ..? You mean he's ..?
Duke?
Oh.
Oh, barman.
Get me another .. double brandy.
Kiffy, isn't that an awful lot?
Well, I'm, I'm ..
I am very distressed.
Oh, darling.
You know.
Duke has made me realize
how selfish I've been.
Dubonnet is in the pink and I'm going
to win The Hopeful tomorrow ..
And have my hour of triumph, but ..
Win, lose or draw, darling.
I'm going to quit the track for you.
Muggins, darling.
I ..
Yes, dear?
Well, there is something you ought ..
Well, what is it?
Darling?
Hello.
Oh, I told you.
You shouldn't drink all that.
Oh, Muggins darling, I've ..
Done something terrible.
What is it?
- Oh ..
Get me another double.
Bring me the bottle.
Kiffy.
Please don't be angry with me.
Well Kiffy, what is it?
Well .. I've given Miss Clayton.
Dixie Gordon's contract.
What?
- Yes.
Isn't that awful?
He is going to ride Moonray tomorrow.
Will you get me the Brookvale
Farm, and hurry please.
Say look, this is ..
Hello? Hello, Brookvale?
Has Mr Bradley arrived there?
No ma'am. He ain't come yet.
Yes ma'am, I'll tell him
just as soon as he comes.
Good evening, sir.
- Good evening, Sam.
Good evening, Mr Duke.
Hello Rosetta.
Mrs Kiffmeyer just phoned and
wants you to phone her right away.
I'll call her later. Will you
tell Mr Madison I'm here.
Yes, sir. Go right in the
lobby and I'll tell him.
Evening, Duke.
- Evening, Hartley.
Nice of you to come out.
- A pleasure. Where's Carol?
She is busy with our guests.
She asked to be excused.
Do you mind if we get down to cases?
- No, of course not.
Duke, what price can you give
me on Moonray tomorrow?
Well .. let's see.
Well, twelve horses in the race .. uh ..
I think I can give you 2-1, Hartley.
That's good with me.
- How much do you want?
You're quite a cigar
smoker, aren't you Duke.
Yeah, why?
- Oh, nothing.
How much do you want on Moonray?
- Fifty thousand dollars.
Okay.
Sure you don't want any more?
What's the most you could cover, Duke?
Well, let's see. I just figured ..
You know, this is a
beautiful spot here, Hartley.
A few thousand dollars would make
it the prettiest place in the world.
A new barn stocked with thoroughbreds.
I asked you what's the most
you could cover, Duke.
Would you like to make
it a hundred thousand?
Is that all you can pay off on?
- It's all I want, pal.
Okay.
Mr Duke.
Mrs Fritzi Kiffmeyer is on the phone
again and says she's got to talk to you.
Thanks, Rosetta.
Will you excuse me, Hartley?
Yeah.
Rosetta.
You've been around Mr Bradley
a good deal, haven't you.
Oh my yes. All I could.
He certainly smokes strong
cigars, doesn't he.
Yes sir, Mr Madison. And he leaves
them around all over the place.
Yeah. All over the country.
Did I make a bet?
The sucker just went for a hundred G's.
You heard me. A hundred thousand bucks.
What?
Say that again.
Dixie Gordon is riding Moonray?
What do you mean? I thought
you had him under contract.
Oh.
Oh, Carol arranged the switch, huh?
Well, it looks like I'll be
leaving Saratoga on a boxcar.
Call it off?
No Fritzi, I said yes to the chump.
Yeah. Okay, babe.
I love you.
Well Hartley, I'll be running along.
- Won't you have a drink before you go?
No thanks.
I've got to help Fritzi dig up another
jockey to ride Dubonnet tomorrow.
Goodnight.
Tell Carol I took this.
I may be sitting on a street corner
after The Hopeful tomorrow.
How is he, Medbury?
- Fine. Raised him a half this morning.
He's a lot of horse today.
They'll have to beat him to win.
Good.
Dixie. I've got a big bet on this race.
There will be five thousand
extra if you win.
Well, you can make out
your check right now.
I hope you lose.
You double-crossing Newport termite.
I'll see you after the race, boys.
Get away from that horse.
What?
You heard me. You'll make him nervous.
I raised him from the
time he was foaled.
And I should make him nervous?
Get the old buzzard out of here.
I told you to keep away from that horse.
You and who else?
Why don't you go home and go to bed?
Hey, I'll sprinkle flit on you.
- Alright. That's enough.
What's the matter, grandpa?
Are you alright?
What happened?
I guess he fell down.
Yeah. I fell down alright.
Moonray.
I'm going to bet ten dollars agin you.
I'll see you again, young fellah.
Hey Duke. Come here.
Hello, grandpa. What's the
matter, pulled a tendon?
No, I bumped into a rat
and pulled up lame.
Say, did you lay off that big
bet you took on Moonray?
No, no. All the other books are loaded.
I've been following the
track for sixty years.
This is the first time I ever pulled
for my own horse to lose.
Thanks grandpa. If I'm
lucky you'll get your stud.
You mean my old stud Miracle Lad?
- You bet.
I'll see you after the race.
- Yeah, alright.
Hey Duke .. Duke.
I can't lay off enough to talk about it.
- Okay. Forget it.
Your Dubonnet looks fit.
I'll string along with him.
You've only one horse to be afraid of
and that's Moonray with Dixie Gordon.
Dixie is plenty rough and
he'll win any way he can.
I found that out in Kentucky.
- Here we go, Hurley.
Keep your horse clear until
you come to the stretch.
Then pop her a few times.
She'll get you home.
Thank you Mrs Kiffmeyer for giving
me my chance to come back.
Hello Duke.
- Hello, Fritzi.
She looks ready.
- I hope so.
Hello, Fritzi.
Ha.
Will you say hello?
Why sure. Why not? Hello.
Well, I want to take over your losses.
Who's lost?
Well, you might lose and
I want to protect you.
Kiffy, I love you.
Yes. But she doesn't.
Hey, now wait a minute.
Fritzi.
You give him a kiss or I will.
Muggins, will ..?
- No.
You are the most impossible
man in the world.
I know I am ..
- But Dubonnet had better win.
Oh, heavens.
I've been holding the thought.
Hello, Hartley.
Aren't you excited, darling?
- Yes, rather.
How much have we got on this?
- Enough to give you heart failure.
Why don't you get back in your
wheelchair Hurley, where you belong.
Go, get that horse out of here, Gordon.
- Ah, shut up.
Rocket by a length.
Moonray, second by a half.
Dubonnet third.
Ah, I can't stand to watch this.
- Then close your eyes.
How is it?
Gordon is whipping Moonray.
He's going to pass Rocket.
Where is Dubonnet?
- Third.
Come on, Hurley.
Gordon is giving Moonray a ride alright.
Where's Dubonnet?
- Third.
Oh, my goodness.
Dubonnet is moving up.
He'll not touch Moonray.
Not with Dixie Gordon riding.
Dubonnet is second now.
- That's still not good enough.
Come on, Gordon.
- Gordon?
I mean Hurley.
Lay up, Gordon.
- You can't get through, Hurley.
Do you want it again?
Come on.
- Dubonnet.
Maybe he cut that way because
he was on the outside.
Boy, that was close.
Who do you think won it, Tip?
Don't ask me.
- Alright. I won't.
What is it, Hartley? A dead heat?
I don't know.
How about it, judge. Who won?
I think it's Moonray but we can't
tell until we see the picture.
Slow motion or still camera?
Slow motion. It's more accurate.
Judge, it looked like
Moonray from where I sat.
You were sitting down
when you trained him.
Will you leave before I blow you away?
You know, I got a good mind to slug you.
How long is it take to
develop the pictures?
17 minutes.
You'd have saved yourself a lot of
time judge if you'd kept your eyes open.
Hey. Grandpa. What happened?
I think he must have fainted.
- Oh.
Give me a bicarbonate of soda.
- Yes, Ma'am.
What's the matter, Fritzi? Nervous?
- Yes.
I know. A stomach full of butterflies?
- Oh, Duke. They feel like pigeons.
When you start on that
stuff it's time to quit.
I'm not getting it for myself.
It's for Carol.
Carol? Where is she?
Outside in my box. She knew you
were here. She wouldn't come in.
Why not?
I think she's the most
miserable girl in the world.
Oh. Tell her to get wise to herself.
I'd have done the same thing she did.
Oh no you wouldn't. And she
knows it. That's what hurts.
We women can do things to a guy we love
that a man wouldn't do to a rattlesnake.
Yeah, I know. That's what
makes me feel so good.
What are you going
to do if Moonray wins?
Well, I'll be in a pretty tight spot. I
won't be able to buy grandpa that stud.
Or fix up Brookvale or
restock it with thoroughbreds.
Yeah, that's right.
Oh Duke, don't feel like that.
Here, you take it to her.
- Oh no, not me.
Oh, Duke.
- Will you turn off that tremolo.
Oh you fool.
Oh, here you are. Hello Dukey.
Hello pal. Have a snort?
- Oh, no thanks.
I'll see you boys in the judge's room.
- Alright.
Do that again.
- Yes, sir.
I don't know what I'm going to
do if that Dubonnet doesn't win.
And you won't be able to fix
up the farm for that lovely lady.
Brandy, sir.
- Yeah, thanks.
Here. You need this worse than I do.
- Yes. Well, perhaps I do.
Why hello, Hartley. Looking for someone?
- No.
You'll find her in the Kiffmeyer box.
Oh, thank you.
I don't know. I don't like that man.
Hey, it's about time.
Let's see the pictures.
Yes. Well come on.
What's going to happen if
Dubonnet doesn't win?
You can give me a job in
one of your beauty parlors.
Yes, I'll give you one
of the beauty parlors.
Hurry up, Kiffy. They're ready to start.
Where shall I sit?
- Right here. Come on.
Thanks, darling.
Well, are we ready?
- All set, Mr Boswell. Close the shades.
Oh Duke, I never wanted to win a
race so much in my life. For all of us.
Let's have the picture.
Now which one is that on the rail?
That's Dubonnet.
Muggins, I can't stand this much longer.
Can't they run a little faster?
I'm dying.
Well, how do you think I feel?
Hurley certainly is
giving Dubonnet a ride.
This is the first time Gordon has
been on the outside in a long time.
Come on, Dubonnet.
Dubonnet wins.
- Oh Duke.
Kiffy, darling.
How about that stud you promised me?
Go get him, grandpa.
- Hot dog.
Did I hear you say 'Dubonnet'?
That was Duke's cigar you
smoked in Miami, wasn't it?
Yes Hartley, it was.
You can leave the track now, Duke.
Fritzi.
I love you.
[ Singing: ]
"And when somebody
shouted: They're off!"
"To his face came a
horrible look of surprise."
"The horse with the dreamy eyes."
"He went boom ti-di ad-da-da
da-da-da boom ti-di oh .."
"The horse with the dreamy eyes."
..t-g..
Watch Movies, TV Series & Live Sports
www.admitme.app