Neighbors, may I have your attention?
All you folks that have come
from far and wide...
Henry here wants me to thank you
for coming to help him raise his barn.
Thanks, folks.
And he thanks the ladies
for all the fancy victuals.
Since the barn's got four sides,
there's going to be four teams.
The team that gets their side up first
wins the little heifer.
Henry, show them Annabel.
Now, get your teams set up, neighbors,
and lets see who wins the little lady.
Adam, we could use her on the farm.
How about it, boys?
Mr. Perkins, put the seven of us brothers
down for one team.
Milly says she's taken a fancy to Annabel.
You hear, boys? That was Adam Pontipee.
Last time he came to town, he bragged
how he always got what he set out for.
And danged if he didn't.
He's a hard one to beat, I'm warning you.
- Don't worry.
- We'll handle them.
That's the spirit.
We got a team all set up here, Pete.
And here's your fourth, Pete.
- That's fine. Got your hammers and all?
- Yeah!
Then take your positions.
The sooner you raise the barn,
the sooner you get the victuals.
- Are you ready?
- Yeah!
Let's go!
Come on, Adam.
Come on, Frank.
My fault. Sorry,
I shouldn't have had my hand there.
What happened?
Nothing.
Caleb, get that board up there.
Now what happened?
I stubbed my big toe.
Come on, let's get going.
Hey, Frank, get those sideboards up here.
Hurt yourself, Frankincense?
Well, come on, let's go!
What's wrong with you boys today?
Just a little dizzy spell.
Hold it! Take it easy!
He didn't drop that hammer. He threw it!
- We don't want no fight!
- We promised Milly.
We're gonna keep it calm,
so don't start anything.
Come on, we're way behind now.
She's made you
into a bunch of momma's boys.
They're out to murder you,
and what do you do?
Apologize for living! You're a disgrace
to the Pontipee name!
You're a bunch of lily-livered,
chicken-hearted, lick-spittles.
Serves you right!
I hope they break your necks!
All right, Gideon, let's go!
Why're you doing that?
He ain't done nothing!
Boys! Stop the fight!
Witch hazel.
Split lip.
Don't smile for a few days.
Next.
Two beefsteaks. Frank?
A kick in the pants.
Next?
A loose tooth and swolled-up knuckles.
A wonder you have any teeth left at all.
Witch hazel, please.
I'm sorry, Milly, honest.
But when that fella took after Adam,
an innocent bylooker...
I understand, Gideon.
You all did your best, I guess.
Good night, boys.
Good night, Milly.
- Good night, Milly.
I feel awful strange-like, Milly. Here.
If it's what I think ails you, Gideon,
witch hazel's not going to help.
Alice is sweet, isn't she?
Good night.
What's the matter with you?
Somebody butt you in the breadbasket?
No.
I felt this way even afore the fight.
Ever since I seen Alice.
Adam?
Yeah?
Do you reckon I could be in love?
Well, Pa used to say, love's kind of like
the measles. You only get it once.
The older you are, the tougher it goes.
Young fella like you
ought to get it kind of light.
No, I guess not.
I don't know as I can answer
your question, Gideon.
But according to Milly, and she's had
a heap of book-learning:
When you're in love
There is no way on earth to hide it
Really in love
You simply let your heart decide it
How can you tell
What's in its spell
How can you tell until you've tried it
Wait for that kiss you're certain of
And let your heart decide
When you're in love!
I guess I got the beginnings.
But them townspeople will never
let us court them gals now.
Not after today.
Don't let it fret you.
If you don't get this one,
there'll be another to come along.
One woman's pretty much like the next.
Come on, let's go feed the stock.
I'm a lonesome polecat
Lonesome, sad, and blue
'Cause I ain't got no
Feminine polecat
Vowing to be true
Can't make no vows
To a herd of cows
I'm a mean old hound dog
Baying at the moon
'Cause I ain't got no
Lady friend hound dog
Here to hear my tune
A man can't sleep
When he sleeps with sheep
I'm a little old hoot owl
Hooting in the trees
'Cause I ain't got no
Little gal owl fowl
Here to shoot the breeze
Can't shoot no breeze
With a bunch of trees
It is beautiful, isn't it?
Not to me.
I've seen too much of it.
I'm getting out.
Why, Benjamin!
I'm not gonna spend another winter here,
snowed in for three, four months.
What would we do without you?
We'd miss you so.
There's plenty here
to take care of the farm without me.
- Adam.
- Yeah?
- Benjamin says he's leaving.
- What?
He says it's the winter,
but I know it's not that.
He's grieving for his girl.
They're all grieving for their girls.
Why grieve for them?
They hardly saw them more than once.
Once is all it takes if it's the right one.
I had such dreams
about all of them living around...
dozens of babies and children...
visiting back and forth
at Christmas time and birthdays.
If Benjamin goes, then another will go...
and another.
I'll talk to him.
If you could just get a look at yourselves.
You look like a bunch of lovesick
bull calves.
If you're so sweet on those girls,
do something about it.
Why don't you go marry them?
Sure, just go marry them, as easy as that.
They'd never let us marry them,
not in a thousand years.
Then do like the Romans did
with the "sobbing women"...
or, "Sabine women"
or whatever they called them.
Those Romans were in the same fix
you're in.
They was opening up new territory,
women were scarce, just like here.
And there were these "sobbing women"
in town, so what did the Romans do?
They went down there
and they carried them off.
Now, if you can't do as good as a bunch
of old Romans, you're no brothers of mine.
'Course, this being Oregon
and God-fearing territory...
you'd have to capture
a parson along with them.
Hey, them Romans...
they the ones settled up north of here?
No, this was in olden days.
I read about it here in Milly's book.
Oh, a book.
Why, this is history! This really happened.
Tell you about them sobbing women
Who lived in the Roman days
It seems that they all went swimming
While their men was off to graze
Well, a Roman troop was riding by
And saw them in their me-oh-my
So they took them all back home to dry
Least, that's what Plutarch says
Oh, yes, them a-women was sobbing
Sobbing, sobbing fit to be tied
Every muscle was throbbing, throbbing
From that riotous ride
Seems they cried and kissed
And kissed and cried
All over that Roman countryside
So don't forget that
When you're taking a bride
Sobbing fit to be tied
From that riotous ride
- So, then what happened?
- Gather around, I'll tell you.
They never did return their plunder
The victor gets all the loot
They carried them home, by thunder
To rotundas, small, but cute
And you've never seen, so they tell me
Such downright domesticity
With a Roman baby on each knee
Named Claudius and Brute
Oh, yes, them a-women was sobbing
Sobbing, sobbing, passing them nights
While the Romans was going out
Hobnobbing, starting up fights
Is that so?
They kept occupied by sewing lots
Of little old togas for them tots
And saying, "Some day, womenfolks
Will have rights "
- Passing all of their nights
- Just sewing
While the Romans had fights
Hey, listen to this.
When the men folk went to fetch them
The women would not be fetched
It seems when the Romans catch them
Their lady friends stay catched
Right!
Now, let this be because it's true
A lesson to the likes of you
Rough them up like them there Romans do
Or else they'll think you're tetched
Oh, yes, them women were sobbing
Sobbing, sobbing buckets of tears
Mighty sad!
On account of old dobbin, dobbin
Really rattled their ears
And that ain't all
Oh, they acted angry and annoyed
But secretly they was overjoyed
You might recall that
When corralling your steers
Oh, oh, oh, them poor little dears
What are you sitting there for?
Let's go get them.
Oh, yes, them a-women was sobbing
Sobbing, sobbing, weeping a ton
Just remember what Robin, Robin
Robin Hood would have done
We'll be just like them there merry men
And make them all merry once again
And though they'll be a-sobbing
for a while
Oh, yes, we're gonna make them
Sobbing women smile!
Whoa, there!
Go get them. Be quiet about it.
I'll wait for you here.
Dan! Eph!
Your two's in here.
They're coming out.
- Good night, Liza.
- Good night.
Hey, you got mine.
- How about my good night kiss, Sarah?
- Oh, Carl! You're so persistent.
Be a sport. Just one kiss.
Maybe just a little one. Close your eyes.
Why, Carl!
Frank! What are you doing? Put me down.
That a boy, get them in.
Come on, Frank.
Where's Gideon?
I hear the cat outside.
I'll go, Mrs. Elcott.
Poor Pansy, out on a night like this.
Hurry it up, will you?
Sounds like Pansy has the croup.
I'll look out in back.
It's all right, Alice, she's here.
Dorcas!
Pa! Pa, come quick!
That a boy, Gideon.
- What's keeping Benjamin?
- I don't know.
Keep them quiet.
Let's go!
Come on!
Hey, there, come on!
- Sarah Kines! She's gone!
- So is Alice.
- Ruth Jebson, too!
- Where's Dorcas?
It was them Pontipees.
The whole seven of them jumped me!
Come on, we'll get them.
Make them stop that yelling.
We're coming to the Pass.
Keep them quiet or we'll have
an avalanche down on us.
All right. Here we go. Hold your breath.
Keep her quiet!
Hurry up, Adam. I can hear them coming.
All right, let them go!
There she goes!
On account of old dobbin, dobbin
Really rattled their ears
All right, boys, line them up.
Milly! Milly!
What have you done?
- Milly, help us, please!
- Milly, we've been kidnapped.
Make them take us back!
You take these girls back at once,
do you hear?
- Can't.
- There was an avalanche.
I guess they'll just have to wait till spring.
It was your idea, wasn't it?
I'd say it was more yours.
It all came out of that book
about them "sobbing women."
What kind of men are you, anyway?
Are you animals that you'd do
a thing like this?
Swooping down like hawks,
carrying off poor innocents.
They're just young boys in love, that's all.
Didn't you tell me today you wanted them
all married with wives of their own?
I want my mother!
Please don't cry, Alice. I'm sorry, honest...
but it was the only way
I could get to marry you.
- Adam!
- What?
We forgot to get the parson!
Now, don't worry. Go on in the kitchen.
Nothing's going to happen.
Cheer up. You've got them, haven't you?
Everything's going to turn out all right.
This house is for the girls...
and you're not gonna set foot in it
as long as they're here.
You're gonna eat and sleep in the barn
with the rest of the livestock.
Now, get out of here. I'm ashamed of you.
Go ahead, boys, go on.
- Now, Milly...
- You, too!
You're taking this too hard.
It'll work out fine. Me and the boys'll
get a parson here some way.
Do you think those girls
would marry them now?
You think because you got a wife
so easily...
'cause I didn't make you court me
and coax me, that that's all there is to it.
I said yes to you
'cause I fell in love with you...
the first time I saw you standing there.
- I thought it was the same with you.
- Milly...
You think a wife is just to cook and clean.
You got no understanding,
you got no feelings.
How could you do a thing like this?
When I think of these poor girls,
sick with fright...
and their families crazed with worry...
I can't abide to look at you!
This isn't exactly the way we'd planned
on spending the night, in a barn!
- What do you think you're doing?
- Getting out of here.
Going up to the trapping cabin
to wait out the winter.
You can't do it, Adam.
You can't stay up there alone.
The cabin's got enough supplies
for six months.
Don't go, Adam. It's us she's mad at.
It's more than that.
It's something goes a lot deeper.
Suppose you get sick...
or break a leg or something,
up there all alone?
And the wolves are mighty bad this year.
The wolves will seem like good company
after what I've just been through.
Nothing like a nice, hot cup of tea
when you're all tuckered out.
Milly, it's me, Gideon.
I gotta speak to you.
Oh, Milly! Please, Milly,
don't open the door!
What is it?
It's about Adam.
He's going away up into the mountains,
up to the trapping cabin.
Milly, can you hear me?
I hear.
If you'd just speak to him,
ask him not to go.
Please, Milly.
He's gotta learn
he can't treat people this way.
Now, Eph, let's start here.
You afraid of a little snowball?
Snowballs with rocks in them!
"Them poor little dears,
sobbing buckets of tears."
"When the sign was given,
drawing their swords...
"and falling with a great shout...
"they ravished away
the daughters of the Sabine."
Who is it?
It's me, Caleb.
What do you want?
It's a mighty cold night, Milly.
I need an extra blanket.
Go and get one.
"It continues the custom to this day...
"for the bride, not of herself,
to pass her husband's threshold...
"but to be lifted over...
"in memory that the Sabine women
were carried in by violence."
Who is it?
Benjamin.
What do you want?
My leg is feeling poorly.
I need some liniment.
Go ahead, but be quick about it.
Yes, Milly.
"Some say, too, the custom
of parting the bride's hair...
"with the head of a spear
was in token of..."
I got me a stiff neck.
That's enough of this nonsense.
- We just wanted to...
- Look, Milly...
Go on out to the barn, all of you.
Go to sleep, or I'll bolt the door on you.
"...was in token of their marriages.
"It began at first by wars
and acts of hostility...
"and then..."
Doesn't it do anything but snow up here?
We've had a blizzard every day
for the past two months.
I'm going crazy, shut up in this house!
- Alice, why don't you read out loud to us?
- No.
We've heard that book
three times already.
Yes, go on. Read us
about the "sobbing women."
- Please, Alice.
- I can't stand it again.
Then go get the dress Milly promised,
and I'll fit you.
What's the use
when there's no one to see it?
No one?
Well, I like that! We're no one.
Where's Milly?
Out in the barn, hunting eggs.
I wish I could hunt eggs.
I love to hunt eggs.
Which boy slept in this bed,
do you suppose?
Dorcas Galen!
What's the matter?
Didn't you ever think of that...
that you're sleeping in one of their beds?
Well, I certainly never thought
any such thing.
Liza, Alice. Come away
from that window this minute.
I think it's disgusting standing there
where they can see you.
I notice that you peek out often enough
when you think no one's looking.
- I never!
- I saw you!
So did I!
You take that back!
You hear?
How could you dare say a thing like that
about Martha?
And what were you doing last night,
out at the woodpile?
Oh, you!
Girls! Girls!
Girls!
Stop it this minute!
Dorcas! Alice!
Alice, get up!
Girls, please don't squabble.
Not now, not when I need you so much.
You see, I'm counting on all of you
to help me.
'Cause I'm gonna have a baby.
Milly! Come sit down!
Are you comfortable?
You're not going to lift a finger
from now on.
We'll take over everything.
We'll do your chores,
cleaning, cooking, everything.
No, really. That'd be silly.
Where are you going?
I have a few things to do.
When's the baby coming?
You have to be patient.
But when?
In the spring.
- I wish it was me.
- Dorcas!
I've always wanted to be a June bride...
and have a baby right off.
In the spring, maybe.
Oh, they say when you marry in June
You're a bride all your life
And the bridegroom who marries in June
Gets a sweetheart for a wife
Winter weddings can be gay
Like a Christmas holiday
But the June bride hears the song
Of a spring that lasts all summer long
By the light of the silvery moon
Home you ride
Side by side
With the echo of Mendelssohn's tune
In your hearts
As you ride
For they say when you marry in June
You will always be a bride
The day a maiden marries
Is the day she carries through the years
The church is full of flowers
Bridal showers are passé
The groom 's waiting at the altar
Here comes the bride
They're each promising to love and obey
Best man is celebrating
Every bridesmaid's waiting just to see
Which one of them will catch
The wedding bouquet
For they say when you marry in June
You will always
Always be a bride
In November the snow starts to fly
Piling up, ankle-high
Come December it's up to your knees
Still a bride's a bride-to-be
January, higher still
Through the parlor windowsill
February finds a drift
And a storm that seems never to lift
March comes in like a lion, what else
Still the snow never melts
April showers will come, so they say
But they don't and it's May
You're about to forget the whole thing
All at once, one day it's spring!
Oh, the barnyard is busy
In a regular tizzy
And the obvious reason
Is because of the season
Ma Nature's lyrical
With her yearly miracle
Spring, spring, spring
All the hen-folk are hatching
While their menfolk are scratching
To ensure the survival
Of each brand-new arrival
Each nest is twittering
They're all baby-sittering
Spring, spring, spring
It's a beehive of budding son
And daughter life
Every family has plans in view
Even down in the brook
The underwater life
Is forever blowing bubbles, too
Every field wears a bonnet
With some spring daisies on it
Even birds of a feather
Show their clothes off together
Sun's getting shinery
To spotlight the finery
Spring, spring, spring
From his aerie the eagle
With his eagle eye
Gazes down across his eagle beak
And affixing his lady with a legal eye
Screams, "Suppose we set
The date this week?"
Yessiree, spring discloses
That it's all one supposes
It's a real bed of roses
Wagging tails, rubbing noses
Each day is Mother's Day
The next is some other's day
When love is king
Frank, Dan, Ben, Caleb!
Everybody!
Milly's having her baby!
Liza, Martha, Ruth, hurry!
Hurry!
I'm an uncle.
Adam!
Hey, Gideon!
Couldn't stand the barn any longer?
I've come to get you, Adam,
take you back with me.
Yeah?
Well, Milly has a baby.
It come day before yesterday.
I don't believe it.
- It's as true as I'm standing here.
- I don't believe it!
Just one of her tricks to get me back.
Tricks?
You lived with Milly as man and wife,
and you don't know nothing about her.
She's got pride and she's spunky.
She'd never bring herself to ask you back.
She'd be wasting her breath.
I don't figure to go.
Not even to see the baby?
Your own kin? Your own little girl?
A girl?
I might've known she'd have a girl.
I'll be back when the Pass is open.
And I'll stay away till the shooting's over.
Adam...
you're my eldest brother.
I've always looked up to you,
tried to ape you...
but today I'm ashamed for you.
Now, I know you can lick me,
lick the tar out of me...
but I wouldn't hold myself no kind
of man unless I showed you how I felt.
Now, get!
The Pass is open! The Pass is open!
All able-bodied men gather
at the Meeting House.
Bring your rifles, your knives,
your guns, axes, any kind of weapon!
The Pass is open! The Pass is open!
Are you ready, men?
Yeah! Let's go!
Well, what are you staring at?
I told you I'd be back
when the Pass was open.
The Pass?
Milly! What are we going to do?
Go upstairs, girls. Go on. Quickly.
Let's get the guns.
Tell them to hitch up the wagon.
The wagon?
Put plenty of blankets and straw in it.
Go ahead.
What do you call her?
I was thinking of some name like...
Hannah or Hagar or Hephzibah.
Picking up where your mother left off.
Hannah.
I got to thinking up there
in the mountains...
thinking about the baby.
About how I'd feel if somebody
came sneaking in and carried her off.
I'd string him up the nearest tree...
shoot him down
like I would a thieving fox.
I thought about you, too,
while I was up there.
It seemed like I couldn't get you
off of my mind.
Milly, when you're in love...
when you're really in love...
The wagon's ready, Adam.
All right.
Now, get the girls. I want to take them
back to their families.
Oh, Adam!
Adam, you will be careful?
We're not letting you
take them back, Adam.
We've talked it over amongst us,
and we're all agreed. They ain't going.
They're our girls now.
I say I'm taking them back.
I'm still head of this family.
Then I reckon you'll have to show me.
Likewise.
What do I have to do,
beat some sense in your dumb heads?
Taking them back is the only way
you'll ever get them.
The whole town's coming up here.
Let them come! We'll fight them all.
Sure.
Sure you will. And who'll you be fighting?
The girls' kinfolk.
Someone's bound to get hurt,
a father, a brother, maybe.
Think they'll marry you after that?
Adam's right.
I stand with Adam.
Well, don't stand too close.
Adam, the girls have gone.
They've run away!
Go get them, get them back! Go on!
- Ruth!
- Dorcas! Come back here!
- Sarah, where are you?
- Ruth!
Dorcas! Come back! You'll get hurt!
Now, let's keep it quiet.
They can hear us from here.
We'll creep up on them.
Alice!
Please, Alice!
Martha, where are you?
Come back, Martha. Don't run away.
I'm not going back!
I want to stay with you!
You've got to. It's the only way.
I won't! No!
It's Alice!
Come on, Ruth!
Hey, there they are!
Let me go!
No!
Don't! You'll hit Dorcas!
Oh, no!
Not that!
Grab her dress, Ben!
In the barn!
Ruth!
Why, Pa!
Get up!
Alice!
Get off of her!
What are you going to do to him?
We're going to hang him with
the rest of them from the nearest tree.
Just a minute!
Before we go, there's one thing
we've got to know from our girls.
Girls! Girls!
Now, Reverend,
what is it you want to know?
We're all fathers here, and we love you,
so don't be afraid to answer.
A while back I heard a wee babe
crying in the house.
Whose is it?
Whose is it? Don't be afraid to tell.
Mine!
Do you, Alice, Ruth, Martha,
Liza, Sarah, Dorcas...
take these men to be
your lawfully wedded husbands?
We do.
Do you, Benjamin, Caleb, Daniel,
Ephraim, Frankincense, Gideon...
take these girls to be
your lawfully wedded wives?
We do.
I now pronounce you men and wives.