Shao Lin, Shao Lin.
How many heroes adore you.
How many wonderful stories
mentioned you.
Your martial art is the only one
in the world.
The Shao Lin Temple is famous
everywhere.
Its history last forever.
The Shao Lin Temple is splendid.
The thousand years' old temple,
the mystic place,
the valley of Song Shan,
every people dreams of,
the original place of martial art,
the charming place,
is well-known in everywhere,
and will be praised forever.
Shao Lin, Shao Lin, Shao Lin...
You good boys.
Ya Chu Lai has suffered for you,
and you have been purified.
Now I tell you the facts of ten laws,
to advise you respecting yourself,
and others.
Chueh-Yuan.
Firstly, thou shall not kill.
Can't you do that?
Thou shall not kill,
can't you do that?
Who is lazy, who shall be killed.
Wars happened during the end
of Sui Dynasty.
Heroes fought for empire
and divided the land.
The traitor Wang Shi Chuang
settled at Tung Tu.
Named himself King Cheng,
and ruled cruelly.
Li Shi Min and his army
are already near Hwangho.
How can be defend
with these weak men?
General,
we really can't get strong men.
We even have to use
the dying prisoners.
Take all prisoners
and Mighty Leg Chang to me.
Yes.
Hurry! Hurry!
Get out.
You are called Mighty Leg Chang.
I'll make your legs broken.
Father.
Be careful.
Hsiao Hu, run away.
Dad...
Ready,
Who is it?
Amida Buddha.
Abbot, more and more people
are starving, soon,
our property,
Can't afford to feed the people.
To help them
is our Buddhist's business.
Amida Buddha!
From now on,
tell those people to leave.
No one can stay here.
Abbot. This boy is seriously hurt
and fainted.
Will you keep him stay?
No.
That will bring us great trouble.
Jen Jih,
save one's life is important,
Talk no more.
Abbot.
His identity is unknown,
I'm afraid he may bring us trouble...
Since Wang Jen-Tse settled,
he killed innocent,
that made people angered.
Abbot, Buddhist should be kind,
you let him stay.
Abbot...
Saved him first.
Buddha bless him.
You are bringing yourself
into trouble.
Master,
we can't put water into him mouth.
He is too weak.
We don't have rich food,
may be we can't saved him.
How can we be like this,
what shall we do?
"Go as wind, stand ad pine,
sit as bell, rest as bow"
Then what are you doing?
We... we are practicing Toad Kung-fu.
Right.
Don't do that.
You offend the law,
face the wall for three days.
What?
Why do you follow me?
What are you laughing for?
What so funny?
As a monk,
you should neither cheer nor anger.
You beast.
Master, kill it.
It's a sin, Set it free.
Yeah.
Amida Buddha.
Master.
Master, I'm guilty.
What is it?
I committed murder.
"Save one's life
and you can go to heaven."
The frog will be grateful
if it knows.
Sure?
Monks won't cheat.
I do understand.
Painful?
No.
Thank you...
Let's talk again
when you have recovered.
Master, congee with frog.
Wu Sha sent him two eggs.
She cares him so much.
Master, how is the taste?
You should know,
He think he is smart.
The sun rises from Song Shan.
Morning bell wakes the birds.
Streams runs along the wood.
Grasses are green on the hillside.
Fruit smell sweet,
flower look pretty.
The dogs hop, the rams run.
Hold up the whip and flicks softly.
Song drifts along the mountain.
Watch out!
Ya Wong, chase him.
Wo, Wo. Come on.
It's really coming.
Ya Wong, chase him.
I go to take again.
Get away.
It's useless
if one only knows to eat and sleep.
Hey, wake up.
Oh, it's dead.
Who is it?
It's me...
What are you doing?
I want to take the short cut
to get water.
T'a Lin is the land
for burying monks of Shao Lin.
Nobody is allowed
without the abbot's permission. Get!
Yes!
I didn't mean to kill you.
I think it's good of me, to bury you
in this scenic place.
It's buried, that's pitiful.
Fairy would come
if he smells the taste of dog's meat.
It's a pity that you are monk.
Hsiao Hu.
Big Monk.
You are weak,
this food is good to your health.
I...
You are not buddhist,
and you are outside the temple.
You need not obey our law,
you may eat.
You have eaten before, aren't you?
This is usually cook with ginger,
wolfberry's fruit...
But it is my first time
see this way of cooking.
You are tired enough for caring me,
and you should take some rich food.
Amida Buddha.
As a buddhist,
it's guilty even to think of it.
It's hard to enjoy such good food.
No one will come here, you may eat.
Master...
Master, during these years
in Shao Lin Temple,
we work more than we eat.
It's tired.
It's hard to have this rich food.
You have one.
Master, let's eat together.
These buddhists came here
when they were in danger,
in such case,
so they aren't so devoted.
Let's eat, it taste good...
Master, then,
aren't we breaking the law?
"With Buddha in your heart,
wine and meat are nothing."
We must have Buddha in heart,
and help people.
No need to worry about too much.
I understand.
"With Buddha in your heart,
wine and meat are nothing."
Brother Shih K'ung realized this
already.
Big Monk, he?
Love can't be forgotten.
Shih K'ung,
wine increase sadness,
don't get drunk.
We've eaten Hsiao Hu's dog.
And we haven't requite.
Master, monks have nothing,
nothing to requite.
Shih K'ung, aren't you hurt?
He's drunken.
The fool.
Shih K'ung.
Big Monk, he?
He looks drunk but he isn't drunk.
Looks drunk but not drunk?
Drunken stick?
Yes, years ago,
when his wife was giving birth,
he was so happy
that he bought a large pot of wine.
But, his wife had been killed
by the robber Wang Jen-Tse.
So he became very fond of wine.
Every day he is sad and drunk.
And that made him
to create the "Drunken Stick".
He has such smart kung-fu,
why don't he revenge?
Can't defeat so many enemies alone.
Somebody.
Hide.
Get away.
Amida Buddha. It's a sin.
Ya Wong. Ya Wong.
Madam.
Did you see my dog?
Oh, you killed my dog.
No. Madam, please listen to me...
No, give me back my dog,
give me back.
Is that enough? Otherwise,
I'll hurt you.
You dare hit me?
As you are a girl,
I let you hit few times,
If you continue on,
I'll hurt you.
Father.
Father?
What's so serious? You are so cruel
to make him hurt like this.
It's him who's so cruel.
Madam, I didn't mean to...
However you explain,
I won't forgive the one ate my dog.
That means,
you won't even forgive me?
You?
I also ate the dog.
Father, why do you shelter him?
So are you. He recovered so fast,
all because of your eggs
and goats' milk.
I...
Thank you.
I hate you, revenge instead of thank.
Look at this girl!
Is she really your daughter?
This girl had no mother
since she was a baby.
At that time,
I was being attacked by Wang Jen-Tse,
and was force to hide myself
in Shao Lin Temple.
So I made her stay at a farmer's home.
The old man spoiled her
because he had no kids.
I must kill Wang Jen-Tse for revenge.
Please teach me Shao Lin Kung-fu.
The temple has rule,
kung-fu is use for protection,
it cannot be learnt by other people.
You aren't Shao Lin monks, I...
I'm willing to become a monk.
No killing.
It bite me.
The Temple's door is widely opened,
good man my enter.
He seems enjoying to kill.
The Temple cannot allow him.
Buddhist should be merciful.
Chueh Yuan wills to cut his hair,
he has been good.
Willing to do evils,
willing to achieve goodness,
must task to save all people.
Chueh Yuan, what's the matter?
Master, I have been a monk
for nearly three months,
besides gett water and cut wood
bricks, I stand here all day long,
when will you teach me
Shao Lin Kung-fu?
It's only three months,
look at your senior brothers,
smoke coming out from head,
holes made by foot,
this Vajra breaking power,
needs three to five years
of practicing.
What? Just stand like this
need three to five years.
Remember, practice kung-fu,
don't fear bitterness.
I'll remember.
Chueh Yuan, good!
Stop it!
Shao Lin kung-fu is for defense
and not attack.
You look like enjoying to kill.
You're punished to face the wall
for three days!
Oh brother!
Brother
Aren't you afraid of being punished
again?
I...
Go back to your work!
Should we regard killing mosquito
as a sin?
If that is so,
how can I revenge my father's death?
Why should I be a monk
without learning kung-fu?
It is not that easy to be a monk.
I don't want to be a monk any more.
Master, please forgive me
for leaving you.
Miss Pak, I own you a life.
I'll repay your kindness in future.
She is pretty, let's bring her back.
She's such a wild girl.
Let's kill her!
Stop it!
Thank you.
General, please taste these velvet
and ram's penis.
No.
They are good for nothing
without the girl.
It's a sin.
General,
I have got some gaming food for you.
Gaming food?
Oh, it's good!
Good.
General, watch out for her wildness.
Her wildness? Her wildness?
General!
What?
There's a kid outside the door.
He has wounded several of us.
How come you are not dead yet, kid?
That is tough for her.
It won't be funny
without the wildness.
Chueh Yuan!
It's you.
Oh, be careful!
He's drunk.
Drunken sword?
Chueh Yuan!
You better run quickly.
How about you?
I have to take revenge.
Aren't you woken yet?
You are looking for death, Kid.
Run quickly!
Li Shih-Min? Let's chase!
Oh! You are bleeding!
Thank you.
I also thank you for saving my life.
Miss Pak, aren't you angry with me?
Angry for what?
I owe you a life.
A dog's life or human life?
I have already got an advantage.
It's a pity I am unable
to kill Wang Jen-Tse.
He's got too many lackeys.
Dad is good at kung-fu,
yet has to hide in Shao Lin.
You better return to Shao Lin.
But I have sneaked our from it!
Oh! You are back!
I know you will come back.
You don't want to leave us,
don't you?
It is better to be a monk, isn't it?
Well, it took us years to achieve it.
You can achieve it
in only one day's time.
Well done, little brother!
Master!
Master, please punish me.
You have not grown up yet.
Nothing is that easy.
You are lucky to come back alive.
Are you hungry?
Drink it!
Thank you, master.
Learn it hard
from your senior brother in future.
He's got no way to go. Catch him!
My gracious Saviour!
Is you.
They've got too many men.
Don't fight with them.
Here is a cliff. Come with me.
Kill him.
Let's search!
Don't you dare to stop us
from catching the prisoner.
This is T'a Lin holy land.
No admission without permission
from our abbot.
Bald-head,
you are looking for death!
Stop it!
No fighting!
Abbot.
Amida Buddha.
General. This is a land
for burying Shao Lin monks.
Even King Cheng will respect
this land.
Why do you want to fight,
General?
A prisoner of King Cheng
is hiding here.
I want to have a search.
A little bald-head has helped
the prisoner to escape.
If you don't let me search,
the king will blame us.
Will you dare
to take the responsibility?
T'a Lin is our holy land.
Please dismount from horse
and go inside for search.
Alright!
Come with me.
Guard the road and go
for the search separately.
Master!
Chase
Yes...
Keep guard here!
That way
Run up to the back of the hill
and don't turn back.
Don't stop or I will shoot!
Run for it!
Who told you to come in?
We are helping the General
to catch the prisoner.
Damn it!
The prisoner has run away
to the back of the hill.
Mount the horses and chase!
Yes...
Run!
I've heard King Li Shih-Min
went to visit
enemy's place by himself.
Is that you?
Thank you, Madam.
You've not taken food for two days.
Eat the food!
As you are a monk,
can you take meat?
With Buddha in your heart,
wine and meat are nothing.
Monks always have Buddha
in their hearts.
Take it!
Your life as a monk is too simple
and poor.
Right.
Wang Jen-Tse's soldiers
have searched everywhere.
You better stay here for a few
more days.
I will send you food.
Okay.
Thank you, Madam. I've a job to do
must cross the river at once.
Do you know if there is a shortcut?
Well, we can escort you
to cross the river.
There are many check points.
How can you pass them?
Put down your hand at once!
You're born to be a couple.
It's a pity you're monk.
Dont' be shy.
What now?
Let's go!
You've got a lot of romance, Kid!
It's a pity you are a monk.
Sir, it's late now.
The bridegroom and
bride must return to their room.
Will you please let them go.
Damn it! Stop pretending.
How can we fool you?
Don't play that!
I'll buy you a drink.
Will you give me a favor?
Alright, you may go!
Thank you, Sir.
Don't be too cautious, brother!
Let's go and have a drink!
Is it hurt?
No.
Tear if off quickly.
Oh! It's bleeding!
What are you laughing for?
You really look
like a sweet little wife.
Thanks for saving my life.
I'll repay your kindness.
Li Shih-Min, you can't get away.
Shoot.
Stop it! The general wants him alive.
We'll get promotion
and fortune this time.
Capture him alive!
Will you take him cross the river?
How about yourself?
Hurry.
They are running!
Shoot!
Master!
Bald-heads,
don't you want to betray us?
I guess they don't have guts
to do that.
Buddhists do not kill. Let's move!
Master, what shall we do now?
We need to defend ourselves.
Buddha will not give mercy to devils.
I understand.
Chueh Yuan, kill him!
Don't you dare to kill?
Buddhist and thief
won't live together. I'll kill you!
Chueh Yuan, kill.
Chueh Yuan, kill him!
Amida Buddha! My holy Buddha,
please forgive us.
Chueh Yuan is only taking them
to the heaven.
Buddha will forgive us.
Yes!
Chueh Yuan is doing it
you goodness sake.
Master.
I know I have committed sin again.
But, they would have killed me
if I didn't do it.
Yes, he is right.
Your mind can never he purified
and stay with Buddha.
You are leaving Buddha from now on.
Master!
Go far away from us!
Master! Wang Jen-Tse is still
waiting in Temple for him.
You can't be responsible
for letting him go.
Let's go back.
Why don't you mount the horses?
Master,
the buddhists are always merciful.
I know I'm wrong.
Please give me another chance.
Go away!
Don't come back to Shao Lin Temple!
Master!
Master...
Stop him!
Don't let him come into the Temple!
Master!
Hurry and go.
Wang Jen-Tse is waiting to catch you,
run quickly!
I don't want master and brothers
to be blamed.
Please let me in!
Master!
Tie him up and take him down hill!
Master, you have saved my life.
And abbot has helped me
in reincarnation.
I can't cause disaster
to Shao Lin because of me.
Let me have the suffering. Master!
Sorry for not seeing you off.
The monk has gone
but the temple still remains.
If you don't hand over the monk
and Li in three days,
I'll destroy Shao Lin Temple.
It's really a big trouble.
I've said he would get Shao Lin
into trouble.
We should have not let him stay.
Amida Buddha.
Buddhists are all merciful,
As Chueh Yuan is my disciple,
we must help him.
Being a Buddhist for years,
how can you say this?
You are wrong!
I'm sorry.
General!
Have you found Li Shih-Min
and the monk?
I've found them.
Where are they?
The Shao Lin monks have helped Li
to escape.
Chueh Yuan has killed
all our soldiers.
Traitors!
Let's march into Shao Lin Temple!
There'll be a disaster
in Shao Lin Temple.
Master, let's fight with them!
Yeah, fight with them...
We are trained in kung-fu.
We must protect Shao Lin.
Master, please let me go out.
I'll be responsible for everything.
To take the responsibility alone
be yourself?
How can you fight against
Wang's army by yourself?
I...
You are too eager to take revenge.
You better unfrock
and join Li Shih-Min.
Master,
I have not repaid your kindness.
I'm a buddhist monk
and have nothing to worry.
Only my daughter worries me.
Fahter!
If you can
take care of her in future.
I'll have no more to worry.
Father!
Master!
You go with him.
No matter what happens to us,
protect him and don't come back.
You may go!
Master...
Father!
Abbot! It's no good!
Wang Jen-Tse's army has passed
the Shao Shih Shan.
They'll reach our main entrance
very soon.
If we don't worry anything,
nothing will worry us.
Then we'll have a sound mind.
Why are you still so afraid?
Buddha bless us!
Tell the monks not to start any move.
Yes!
Let's lay siege to Shao Lin.
Bowmen to a ambush in hide-out!
Don't let any monk to escape.
Kill...
Amida Buddha!
Abbot...
Why do you want to
attack our temple, General?
Because Shao Lin monks conspire
with Li Shih-Min.
There is evidence
to prove the treason.
I'm ordered to punish the monks
and burn the temple.
Burn it down!
Hold it, General! I have a request.
Say it!
This is a historical land.
If there's a crime,
it should not involve the temple.
And the punishment shouldn't extend
to the monks.
As a temple abbot,
I'll take all responsibilities.
Alright, I'll kill you first.
Light up the fire!
Abbot!
If anyone tells me the whereabouts
of the traitors,
I'll keep your temple in peace
and abbot alive.
Abbot!
Abbot! Amida Buddha.
Kill him!
Oh, you!
If none of you speaks,
I'll kill you all.
Abbot!
No killing!
Abbot,
kindness results nothing to evil.
Kill the devils and enter Buddha.
Let's release their souls
and bring them to death.
Abbot!
Brother
Pan K'ung!
Master, you start killing now!
Let's kill them. They deserve it.
Shoot the arrows!
General...
Master!
Father!
Shoot the arrows!
Let's charge into the temple
and burn it down!
Master!
Father!
Li Shih-Min has crossed the river
with his army.
They are heading for Tung Tu.
You must defend Shao Lin
and uphold the justice.
Master!
Father!
Let's kill them!
General!
It's a bad news. Li Shih-Min
and his army have crossed
the river heading for Tung Tu.
What?
Kill them!
Kill!
Chueh Yuan, watch out for the sword!
Thou shall not kill. Can you do that?
I'll stop killing but not stop
to uphold justice.
Secondly, thou shall not steal.
Can you do that?
I've determined to enter Buddha,
Thirdly, thou shall not covet,
can you do that?
I've determined to enter Buddha,
to defend Shao Lin
and uphold the justice.
Thou shall not covet,
Can you do that?
Yes.
Fifthly, thou shall not drink.
Can you do that?
I suggest this vow should be exempted.
Your majesty!
Since your majesty has given an order,
this vow of drink
shall be exempted forever.
To show appreciation,
King Li of T'ang Dynasty awarded
the Shao Lin monks
many fortunes.
The monks only accepted
a gown for each,
a tea set, and forty acres of land.
The King permitted Shao Lin
to form a defence force.
Such legend was recorded
on a temple stone
with the royal signature
of King Li Shih-Min.
The martial art of Shao Lin began
to prevail.
The fame of Shao Lin kung-fu was
everlasting.