We have arrived at the Hong Kong International Airport.
Please take all your baggage with you.
We have arrived...
You're back!
Daddy.
Miss me?
One…
Two…
Three…
Yeah!
Leave at once!
Due to an emergency at the airport,
passengers please leave the airport immediately.
Be careful! Go!
This way!
Due to an emergency situation,
passengers please leave the airport immediately.
Hong Kong International Airport,
sitting on 1,255 hectares and cost $70 billion to build,
was blown to bits in an instant,
killing thousands.
Why did that happen?
Anger.
Anger can destroy everything.
Luckily when all hope was lost,
one man
overcame his anger
and stopped this tragedy from happening.
Help!
It'll blow.
One hour ago,
a man armed with a grenade robbed a watch shop.
This is a stickup!
This is a grenade!
Put the watches in the bag.
Hurry!
Put out your hand!
Hold this!
Tightly!
Don't let go!
Or it'll blow.
It'll blow up! Help!
Help!
- Help me! - Stay where you are.
Stand still.
Don't be afraid.
The hole of the grenade is displaced.
Can't put the pin back in.
The only solution
is to detonate it on the spot.
Extend the lockdown area to 40m.
Yes, Sir! Calling command post!
Find an open area and start piling up sandbags.
Yes, Sir! Get the sandbags.
It'll be over soon.
Fung!
The sandbags are ready.
Let's begin!
No!
It'll blow.
No! No!
No!
It'll blow up!
OK! OK!
Calm down! You'll be fine.
Fung! What are you doing?
You took off the suit?
Don't worry!
Here we go.
OK!
Give it to me…
Easy… No rush!
OK!
Very good!
Why did you take off the suit?
The girl was so scared. I couldn't do anything.
Here…
Covering her with the bomb suit can ensure safety?
If the grenade went off,
what will happen to you?
You'll both fry!
Hey!
You don't save lives by risking your own.
You're right. Saving lives doesn't mean risking my own.
But as an EODB (Explosive Ordnance Disposal Bureau) officer,
when do we not risk our lives?
You're right.
There's no need to spell it out.
Tung Sir has a point.
Because he's Tung Sir!
You're taking his side?
Over here! Hurry!
Over here! Over here!
- Police! - What's is it?
What's going on?
Somebody threw corrosive liquid off the building.
We wish to come in for a look.
Police!
Open up!
Get down!
"Dad : Mom has terminal cancer."
What's going on?
We got a call,
someone threw corrosive liquid off the building.
We went door to door, someone on 7/F refused to open up.
We broke the door down,
and found the owner hold his ex-girlfriend and her husband hostage
and tied them to two bombs.
Stay calm, Miss! Sit tight and don't move.
We'll get you out ASAP.
The bombs are identical.
Should be the same design.
Detonated by pressure.
When she stands up,
the bomb will go off.
Luckily we caught this in time.
We're finished if she gets tired.
Are these wires
connected to the bomb on your end?
Bingo!
They're synchronized.
If one goes off,
the other one will too.
If we defuse one bomb,
the other will also go off.
The wiring is of a basic design.
If we cut the power,
the bomb won't go off.
It's black powder.
100 grams in each pipe…
that's 300 grams total.
Based on Sadovsky's formula,
the brisance is that of 3 grenades, the bomb suit will hold.
Man,
let's get them out first.
OK!
Miss, please stay calm.
I'll now cut the chain for you.
After that, go out this door,
someone will help you.
We're ready to cut the chain.
Copy!
Ready?
Ready!
Don't be afraid. Go out now.
Come.
Cut the green wire.
In sync.
The timing…
no more than 1/4 second apart.
Copy.
Give me a beat.
Fine!
On 420.
Ready.
To! We're ready to roll.
Copy!
4-0-3-4-2
4-3-4-2-4-3
4-3-4-2-0
OK!
All clear!
You can go. I'll wrap up.
Thanks!
Watch out!
Officer down! Send in the paramedic!
Tung Sir!
Go check on Fung!
Yes, Sir!
What?
I lost a leg, but I still have two hands.
I can defuse a bomb with my left hand
and hold your hand
with my right.
I may be the only coolest
handicapped EODB officer.
Tell the boys, I'll be back soon.
Fung said he'll be back soon!
Hey! Talk to me!
I'll be back soon.
"Gabapentin Capsules for epilepsy/neuropathic pain"
Madam, something for you.
What?
I love you!
800 m
in 2 minutes and 21 seconds.
Take a break.
I'm not tired.
You beat the Police standard,
you should take a break.
A toast to me, I can walk again.
And to you, for your promotion.
So you have heard?
The boys said we should celebrate with you.
Sure thing!
I knew you can do it.
I was afraid you'd get ahead of me and now you did it.
Cut the crap!
I wonder when I can go back to work.
If I don't start working soon,
I think I'll go crazy. Seriously…
The brass said as soon as you're ready,
they'll have a desk job for you.
A desk job?
A desk job.
Are you kidding me?
But…
I'd think the same if I were in their shoes.
They don't know how fit I am.
Arrange for the fitness test ASAP.
Once they see the results,
they'll be begging me to come back to work.
Come back!
Please come back!
Like that?
Yes!
8!
Here we go.
29!
29 minus 8…
Very good!
Even higher than Police standard!
Sir, can I help you?
The bombing at the Education Bureau is an isolated incident.
There's no specific intel suggesting Hong Kong
is a likely target of terrorist attack.
The city's threat of terrorist attack
is currently assessed to be moderate.
The suicide bomber at the Education Bureau was a terrorist,
called Cheung Chi Man.
He was a grad student working on his PhD.
6 months ago,
his girlfriend, who was also a grad student jumped off a building.
Inside the computer in his flat,
we found a downloaded file from the dark web
about a new extremist group called Vendetta
and its "The Guide to Lone-wolf Terrorism".
In the past,
Vendetta used the social networking platform of the dark web
to provide assistance to those who detest society
and engineer lone-wolf terrorist attacks overseas.
Our intel shows
two people are the masterminds behind the group.
One uses the codename Maverick,
Ma Sai Kwan,
a rich 2G from Hong Kong.
When he was at University College London studying Economics and Political Science,
he was already an anarchist.
In 1997, he was in Seattle for the anti-WTO protests.
In 2000, he took over the family business.
A year later, along with several foreigners,
he trashed up an international fast food chain.
Get out of the place!
Mr. Ma, about what you're doing, will your family be disappointed?
They have no right to be disappointed.
My family
made their fortune
from the Brits
selling opium.
Their money was dirty.
When he was out on bail, he jumped bail
and illegally transferred
USD$300M from his family's account to an offshore bank.
He once said
his family fortune was sinful.
He wanted to use justice to clean it up.
5 years ago,
he used a fake passport and returned to Hong Kong.
After that, he vanished without a trace.
Our intel shows
in his external communications,
he often mentioned someone called Davy.
INTERPOL believes
Davy is another mastermind behind Vendetta.
But we have yet to confirm his real identity.
Over the past 4 months,
they have arranged for at least 30 armed personnel to sneak into Hong Kong.
It appears they're using Hong Kong to launch a terrorist attack.
I'm now putting you in charge
of tracking them down.
Find Ma Sai Kwan and Davy ASAP.
To prevent any leaks,
this operation is classified.
Understand?
"Gabapentin Capsules for epilepsy/neuropathic pain"
Sir,
meds
should be taken with water.
Look at that!
Sorry, I'll pay you $5,000.
Where did you learn how to drive?
How about $10K?
Money isn't everything.
Of course not.
I just want to pay you. Sorry! Is this OK?
Do you have a license?
Of course!
- Officer! Sorry! - Well?
- Can you settle this? - We're trying.
- You wanna pursue this? - Of course!
I'll pay for it.
I'll jot down the damages of both vehicles.
I need you to stand...
Are you new here?
Yes!
I want a staff...
Lock down elevator No. 4.
Copy!
Fighting in elevator No. 4.
It's now locked on 5/F,
send someone over right away.
We reached the elevator.
He jumped onto elevator No. 5
and got off on 10/F.
Go check it out!
Stay where you are!
Hey!
So noisy!
What's going on?
Open the door!
The lighting ceremony of Glimmering Hong Kong is about to commence.
Let's have the Chairman of the Real Estate Developers Association,
Mr. Leung Chi Choi
to come up here for the lighting ceremony.
Key! Key!
Open the door!
Don't move!
Check the hotel carefully.
Look for any suspicious looking or potential explosives.
Yes, Sir!
Tung Sir, what kind was it?
We think it was C-4.
C-4?
Madam,
a victim was in hotel uniform,
but the hotel has nothing on him.
He's probably a suspect.
Over there!
Fung!
One…
Two…
Three…
Up!
More casualties are on the way. Everyone, standby!
Yes!
In the Island Hotel explosion,
the death toll has increased to 18.
According to a reliable source,
the Police investigation is skewed towards a terrorist attack.
For security reasons, several major events have been canceled.
Three…
Two…
One…
Again!
Three…
Two…
One…
The bomb had a primer for military use
with an instantaneous detonator.
Probably the on/off switch of the lighting ceremony.
Unlike the Education Bureau explosion 4 months ago,
RDX, cyclonite was used.
This time, C-4.
They're both high performance explosives.
The suspect in the custodial ward, any updates?
He's still in a coma.
We cross-matched his fingerprints
and confirmed he's ex-EODB officer,
Poon Shing Fung.
The CCTV showed him coming out with the on/off switch.
He also got in a fight with a security guard.
Don't get ahead of ourselves
in drawing conclusions.
"Poon Shing Fung is awake"
Chan Sir,
Poon Shing Fung is awake.
Tung Sir,
Poon Shing Fung was your ex-partner.
Madam Pong,
he was your old friend.
You should both stay away.
That's why Lee Sir will follow up with Poon Shing Fung.
Yes, Sir!
Before we have any leads to go on,
not a word to anyone
about Poon Shing Fung.
Yes, Sir!
"Ming Sum Hospital"
Long time no see.
Do I know you?
Fine!
I'm CIP (Chief Inspector of Police) of the Crime Unit Lee Yiu Sing.
You are not obliged to say anything
unless you wish to do so,
but whatever you say
will be taken down in writing
and may be given as evidence in Court.
I want some water.
Hey!
Poon Shing Fung,
you're a suspect in an explosion.
In 2019, on October 3,
what were you doing
at Island Hotel?
I want some water.
I'm asking you about Island Hotel...
I don't remember.
With other suspects, I'm never this patient.
Poon Shing Fung,
what were you doing there?
Do you have accomplices?
Poon Shing Fung?
I don't even remember my name.
Can you tell me what I am doing here?
Sure!
Let me jog your memory.
You blew 18 people to bits and dozens more are injured.
If you refuse to work with the Police,
prison is where you'll spend the rest of your life.
No way!
I had nothing to do with it.
It wasn't me.
Also, Wong Lai Ling, the cleaning lady.
It was her last day, she was retiring.
You blew her up.
Look again!
Get away from me!
Start talking!
What are you doing?
- Speak up! - Lee Sir!
The patient had a major concussion
that resulted in PTA (Post-Traumatic Amnesia).
He had no idea how he ended up here.
Can't even remember his own name.
Can he fake it?
He may be able to fool you,
but not this machine.
The temporal lobe consists of hippocampus
responsible for short term and long term memory.
The fMRI (Functional Magnetic Resonance Imaging) shows the inner temporal lobe is inactive,
which means he lacks memory activities.
Obviously, he suffered an injury.
Will he recover?
It's hard to say.
Some have a speedy recovery.
For others, external factors may lead to a gradual recovery.
But for some, they may never recover.
Damage to the hippocampus only affects declarative memory.
For example, he won't remember where he has been,
what he has done
or won't recall people he knows.
But for things he's accustomed to, his motor skills,
such as brushing his teeth,
driving a car or using a computer;
what we consider procedural memory,
won't be affected.
Because this type of memory is deeply embedded
in our subconscious as implicit memory,
and won't need our consciousness to recall.
Someone who suffers from declarative memory loss,
may form a new consciousness,
exhibit a new temperament, develop new concepts
or even form a new outlook on right and wrong.
In other words, become a different person.
Sir,
I have an idea.
Salute!
Place your men in deadly peril and they will survive.
Leave them in dire straits and they're reborn.
Boss!
My troops.
They're willing to die for you.
Boys,
are you ready?
Yes, sir!
Good!
Let's wait for Davy,
and Resurrection Day may proceed as planned.
How is Blizzard?
Still in the hospital.
Resurrection day
cannot happen without Blizzard.
Yes! Boss!
"Ming Sum Hospital"
We're taking you to do a MRI scan.
Please remove all metals on him.
Don't move!
Be quiet! Don't move!
Lee Sir, Poon Shing Fung is doing a MRI scan.
Out to all, the prisoner escaped from the MRI room.
You in the wheelchair, don't move!
Sit tight! We'll break you out!
Police!
Freeze!
Come back!
Due to an emergency at the hospital…
Follow me!
…please follow instructions from hospital personnel and evacuate at once.
Hurry! It's not safe here.
Follow me.
Get down.
Out to all, suspect is in Prosthetic and Orthotic Unit on 2/F.
Stay back!
What is it?
Don't move!
Stay where you are!
Get back! Get back!
Poon Shing Fung,
let the driver go.
You framed me for killing 18 people.
I don't mind adding one more.
Drop your weapon!
Don't push me!
Take it easy!
Stay where you are!
Drive!
Poon Shing Fung,
come back!
Stop the car!
Now!
Relax!
Just drive!
I will catch you.
Definitely!
Madam, the vehicle is over there.
He's the owner. We confirmed it's his car.
How much longer will it take?
I need to work.
That's my wallet.
Thank you!
Madam!
RoadCams spotted Poon Shing Fung in Mongkok.
He went inside a cybercafe.
"Siu Ming"
Poon Shing Fung?
"Poon Shing Fung"
"EODB officer lost one leg in IED (Improvised Explosive Device) explosion"
"EODB officer defuses 2,000-pound wartime bomb after 20 hours"
"Cell phone radio wave or interference may increase risk of explosion"
Hang in there!
Seal off the back and guard all the intersections.
Yes, Sir!
Poon Shing Fung!
We located the suspect.
He escaped through the back door.
He's in a navy jacket and grey jeans.
Copy!
Poon Shing Fung!
Stop!
Stay where you are!
Come back!
Guard the back door!
Let's go up!
Poon Shing Fung!
What is it? What are you doing?
Move! Police!
Poon Shing Fung!
Up there!
Suspect on Fa Yuen Street!
Fa Yuen Street!
Stop!
Stop.
Suspect entered the back alley in between no. 46 and no. 48 on Fa Yuen Street!
He turned onto Tung Choi Street.
After him! Step aside!
Lock down all exits on Tung Choi Street.
Move! Step aside…
Police!
Please step aside!
Step aside!
Move it!
Police!
Step aside!
- Step aside! - Police!
Move!
This way!
Step aside!
Sorry! Police!
Move aside!
Hey!
Freeze!
Step aside!
Suspect in Kam Wong Plaza.
Poon Shing Fung!
Don't move!
Get out!
Go!
Everybody out!
This way!
Move in!
Go!
Stop!
Don't move!
You called me.
It's me.
I'm calling you.
"Dialing…5696 0142"
You still remember my number.
Tell me…
Can you carry on your mission?
Why didn't you pick up?
I don't take unknown calls.
Seal off Sai Yeung Choi Street and the nearby area. Keep looking.
Copy.
They'll be here soon.
Go south on Nathan Road.
I'll contact you.
Suspect is northbound on Nathan Road.
Copy.
You're Pong Ling.
Drive!
What are you doing?
You're a suspect in an explosion.
Turn yourself in!
I don't remember anything.
I have nothing to say.
Turn yourself in or I'll have you arrested.
Go ahead!
Don't push me!
I'll kill you if I had no choice.
Drive!
Traffic 34, over!
Please check a stolen car.
I know we used to be friends.
Tell me…who am I?
I know different versions of you.
We used to go through Hell and back together.
You were an EODB officer who saved lives.
After that, you became so full of yourself,
you drove yourself into a dead end.
The current you suffer from amnesia.
Which one do you want to know?
I lost my left leg in the line of duty?
Yes!
In that explosion,
we both burnt our hands
and you lost your leg.
That's why EOD fired me?
They did not.
We all know you don't want a desk job at EODB.
So we had a discussion
and decided to transfer you to PPRB (Police Public Relations Branch).
Sorry, Sir!
I believe there's a misunderstanding.
I'm an EODB officer,
I should be in the field.
All officers in the field must pass a strict physical.
I have more than passed it.
Tung Sir of EOD is waiting outside.
He can attest to that.
That won't be necessary.
I hope you'll understand,
if any future incident
is caused by the Police employing disabled personnel,
we'll have a lot of explaining to do.
You still doubt my ability.
I'm willing to undertake any fitness test.
If I don't pass,
so be it.
That really won't be necessary.
Don't waste anyone's time.
I hope you'll understand.
What do you want me to understand?
You want me to understand
you don't want to be accountable?
Poon Shing Fung, mind your words.
I lost a leg. Why?
For work.
You won't even give me a chance.
You think I'm a waste of your time?
UI63660,
we're aware of your valor
and have been more than considerate.
You had a fallout?
Didn't you tell them
in order to get back to EOD, how hard I have worked?
I did.
You did not.
You don't want me back.
Why would I do that?
Fine!
If I wrote a petition to the CP (Commissioner of Police),
will you co-sign it?
What petition?
You won't!
I will! I definitely will.
But Tung Cheuk Man is too small a potato
to make them change the system.
You're right!
Absolutely right!
On January 15, 2015,
colleagues of EODB, Tung Cheuk Man and Poon Shing Fung
risked their lives
to defuse a bomb and saved two civilians.
The Hong Kong Police hereby awards them the MBG (Medal for Bravery - Gold)
to commend them for their noble act of risking their lives to save others.
Let's have
CIP Tung Cheuk Man of EODB.
Now, let's have CIP Poon Shing Fung.
"The Police is ungrateful. I'm now dispensable."
No, Poon Sir!
Don't do this, Poon Sir!
No pictures!
Watch out, Tung Sir!
Assault!
Every newspaper mentioned the assault.
None reported what I protested against.
They don't care about me. Fine!
Don't they care about justice?
What about the truth?
Never mind what they wrote.
I'd be just as angry.
But what you did was wrong.
What did I do wrong?
You can go back after your injury, but I can't.
I'm only fighting for what I deserved.
What's wrong with that?
That's what I'm doing.
But after what you did, there's no turning back.
How long will it take?
One year?
Two?
Three?
You're my buddy. You should be on my side.
Come with me to protest.
- Our job is to serve the people, - We go together.
- not serve our own purpose. - Protest.
Protest…complain…
Hey, get a grip!
What kind of a fool do you take me for?
Everyone thinks I'm sick.
And you are!
The world is sick!
Back then,
you turned a deaf ear to everything I said.
You treated the world like your enemy.
But when my Mom died,
you came to show your last respects.
Remember that?
Family and friends, all rise!
Everyone, please bow your heads.
Family, press the button.
The ceremony is over.
Please step out of the hall.
Alone?
If I can manage, I'll do it alone.
How's business?
Tough.
People nowadays
toss whatever is broken.
They don't want to fix things.
Congrats!
You defused another wartime bomb.
Next week, I'm taking the team out to dinner.
How nice!
If...
I were still with EOD,
who do you think will be treating dinner?
Look,
Pong's house-warming.
King To's new baby.
Look.
Congratulate them for me.
The team wants to see you.
But I don't.
Actually…
Can't think of anything to say?
You should leave.
Thanks for paying my Mom your last respects.
I also want to know
who is Pong Ling.
She is your ex.
She asked me
if I can carry on my mission.
You saw her?
What mission do I have?
I don't know.
Pick this up at the foot of the mountain.
Pong Ling,
it's Tung Cheuk Man.
Fung just came to see me.
He said you told him he had a mission.
What mission?
Sorry!
It's highly classified. I can't tell you.
Why did you let me go?
You're an UC (undercover) for the CTRU (Counter Terrorism Response Unit).
I'm your handler.
I don't remember anything.
But I remember your face
and your name.
If you were to tell me we're dating each other, I'll believe you.
We used to.
I treated you horribly?
No, you were great.
But after you lost your leg, you became a different person.
"The Police is ungrateful. I'm now dispensable"
Poon Sir! Don't do this!
What do you mean dispensable?
They transferred you to a desk job with the PPRB.
You didn't want it.
You're my girlfriend.
You should know how I feel.
I do.
But the disciplinary services require physical fitness.
There's nothing wrong with me.
With your leg like this, how can you defuse a bomb? How can...
I don't defuse bomb with my leg.
I use my hands.
Other than me,
no one can tell me no.
You're disabled.
How can you protect civilians?
Then why can Tung Cheuk Man go back and I can't?
His injury is different from yours.
How different?
You mean he's not handicapped,
but I am?
That's not what I mean...
Do I have to make a bomb,
then defuse it to prove myself?
Listen to yourself!
You're a ticking bomb.
Fung, let's go see a doctor, OK?
I did.
I'm on meds.
I'm talking about a psychiatrist.
Let's go see a psychiatrist.
I'm not crazy.
I'm hurting.
Do you understand?
I do.
I don't think we can stay together.
Get out!
No!
Fung, calm down.
Will you calm down?
Yours and Man's injuries…that was an accident.
No one knew it would end like this.
Fung! You can't blame anyone.
Calm down!
Fung!
Even though we broke up,
I have never given up on you.
I knew you always wanted to be a cop.
Go away!
What's your hurry?
I found a way to help you.
Try me.
I know your anger got the better of you.
It finally clicked?
Then why didn't you tell them?
What makes you think so?
I know you want to be a cop again.
But they don't want me.
That's not true.
They need someone exactly like you.
We received word from the FBI
about an extremist group called Vendetta
planning a terrorist attack in Hong Kong.
They're actively recruiting people who think alike.
After your accident,
you began to hold extreme views and became anti-social.
These qualities fit their profile.
I suggested to Chan Sir to send you to Vendetta as an UC
to catch the men behind the group, Ma Sai Kwan and Davy
and stop the terrorist attack.
Here's the file on Vendetta.
Because there are terrorists,
you don't think I'm crazy anymore.
The Poon Shing Fung I know would never stand by and watch people die.
Accept the offer and make an arrest,
Chan Sir will agree to reinstate you.
Think it over.
Hello?
I'm in.
Before the explosion,
you gave me the intel.
But we don't want to go public
and cause public panic.
So we let you in to defuse the bomb.
In this operation,
everyone thought you planted the bomb.
Only I know you went in to defuse it.
After the explosion,
we found some of your personal belongings.
Your phone got wet.
Luckily colleagues of Team D recovered the data inside.
Judging from the GPS records,
you stayed in one place every night.
Want to check it out?
"Gabapentin Capsules for epilepsy/neuropathic pain"
You said this one is most comfortable.
I hope you can carry on your mission.
When you escaped from the hospital,
Vendetta sent someone to your rescue,
that proves you have become a crucial member of the group.
How did we meet?
7 years ago,
we met at a Police cocktail party.
You accidentally
spilled red wine on my uniform.
You apologized
and I said it was OK.
Then you said you did it on purpose.
You meant to
get my attention.
Let's not go into that.
This watch
has GPS and recording functions.
Wear it
and it can ensure your safety.
Can I hug you?
I don't remember much.
I can't tell what's real
and what's not.
If you trust me,
you're a cop.
If you don't,
you're a terrorist.
Ask yourself
what kind of person is Poon Shing Fung.
Your top priority
is to contact Vendetta,
help us catch Ma Sai Kwan
and find out Davy's real identity
in order to foil their terrorist attack.
Blizzard.
After you lost your leg, you became so full of yourself,
you drove yourself into a dead end.
If I were still with EOD,
who do you think will be treating dinner?
After you lost your leg,
you became a different person.
Pong Ling,
tell me honestly,
what mission can Fung possibly have?
Man,
I told you it's classified. I can't tell you.
He's a suspect in a bombing incident that killed 18 people.
He's an armed fugitive.
Every cop in town is looking for him.
He doesn't remember any mission.
You know the kind of danger he's in?
You asked him to find terrorists.
If you really want to know, talk to Chan Sir.
Someone who suffers from declarative memory loss,
may form a new consciousness,
exhibit a new temperament, develop new concepts
or even form a new outlook on right and wrong.
He can become a different person.
Sir,
I have an idea.
Madam Pong, I'd like you to meet
Professor Wong Ching Yi and Dr. Lam Chi Ming.
Hello!
"Dr. Lam Chi Ming Specialist in Neurology"
"Wong Ching Yi Professor in Clinical Psychology"
You're Pong Ling.
He still remembers my name.
We can implant memories,
but not feelings.
You're still inside his subconscious
that means he still misses you,
though he may not remember what happened in the past.
I only want to know if this will affect our plan.
According to past research,
even though implanted memories need
to be substantiated by actual events
and not something fabricated,
it's also best that someone trustworthy to the subject
can verify everything.
Madam Pong,
I do not doubt you.
On the contrary, I need to tell you
your relationship with Poon Shing Fung
is in our favor when we implant fake memory.
You're an UC for the CTRU,
and I'm your handler.
Do you know why
Fung became what he is today?
He wanted to be reinstated back then,
you rejected him because you didn't want to take the rap.
Now that he has amnesia,
you had the nerve to tell him he's working undercover?
He can't even remember if he's a cop!
What's wrong with you people?
If we had other options,
I wouldn't have accepted Madam Pong's suggestion.
In order to close file, you're capable of anything!
What if he got himself killed?
Will that be in the line of duty, Madam?
He has no record with the Hong Kong Police!
Fung already lost the job he loved.
He lost a leg.
He had nothing left.
I understand.
Sorry, Sir! I don't think you do.
We should be helping him.
Not lying to him.
He was your boyfriend.
I wanted to help him.
By pushing him off the cliff?
To atone for his crime.
The explosion at the hotel,
based on prima facie evidence,
he's likely to get a life sentence.
But if he helped the Police
take out Vendetta
and stop the terrorist attack,
we'll have a reason
to make a plea to the judge.
Or else,
he'll always be...
...a wanted man.
Atone for his crime?
Use his life
to save 100 other lives?
That's what you call atoning for his crime?
You're his buddy.
You tell me.
How can he ever go back
to be the Poon Shing Fung we know?
Tell me!
The Poon Shing Fung we know,
will risk his life
to save others.
Madam,
Poon Shing Fung went inside a coffee shop.
In that area, flyovers blocked the roadcams.
The black vehicle across the street
will pick you up.
Madam, we lost the GPS signal.
Probably from interference. But we still have audio.
Where are we going?
"The Water Margin"
Blizzard,
we meet at last!
I'm Money.
I'm Slave.
Sniper.
Blizzard,
welcome back!
Thanks.
The Boss is worried about you.
After you left the hospital,
why didn't you contact us right away?
When I woke up,
I don't remember much.
After I broke out of the hospital,
I had the cops on my tail.
I didn't want to get anyone in trouble.
That's why I didn't make contact.
You're always very careful.
We have so much to learn from you.
I'm sorry!
I made a mistake and you had to fill in for me.
I almost got you in trouble.
You did a great job
with the lighting ceremony.
They're talking about the hotel explosion.
The Boss is tied up.
He can't meet with you.
He told us to contact him after we picked you up.
Blizzard,
I'm glad you're back.
Our plan
will proceed as scheduled.
Nothing will stop Resurrection Day.
It's probably Ma Sai Kwan.
Do a voice analysis and track the signal.
Yes, Madam!
I already told you
Our minds are in sync
and we're comrades with the same belief.
Vendetta
has not let me down.
Not now,
not ever.
Now...
Madam, we have voice confirmation.
It's definitely Ma Sai Kwan.
We have waited long enough for Davy.
I have more good news.
I just picked up Davy.
Davy is here!
Do we have the location?
Still tracking.
See?
Yes!
After Davy settles down,
I'll come to you.
Whatever you need,
just tell Rhino.
OK?
We lost the signal.
Do we have the location?
No!
The Boss has a present for you.
It's the latest model.
You're now a wanted man.
You must be careful.
Don't go home.
The Police locked down the place and it will be heavily guarded.
You should know by now,
I'd rather die than betray a comrade.
No wonder the Boss trusts you
and never once doubted you'd be a rat.
Let's roll!
Out to the open sea!
We just lost the voice signal.
Here…
A toast to Doctor.
Cheers!
Doctor was a hero.
But so what?
Only we'd remember him.
No one else would.
Blizzard,
you taught me
I should place the index finger tip on the trigger
of a sniper rifle for a better aim.
I'll remember that.
But
when I pick up a rifle to do something meaningful,
I want to go out with a bang.
Whether anyone will remember me,
I don't care.
Maverick told us that
being brave is the key to facing life.
We all have to die.
Yes!
Be brave!
A true genius
will not be KO'd by this sick society.
We must fight back!
Cheers!
When I was in the hospital, what have you been doing?
We followed your instructions
and made bombs.
Bombs?
Yes!
You and Maverick had it mapped out.
The prelude to Resurrection Day.
Good!
Do you have the suspect who placed the bomb?
CCTV captured a man wearing a mask
who placed it around noon.
Should be a lone wolf.
5 kg of C-4
could be deadly.
The design of the bomb isn't complicated.
But this device
has an unusual direction.
It's pointing down.
We have cables and gas pipes underground.
When it blows,
the chain reaction will cause a regional airblast
that can be disastrous.
"Good guys stay away"
It's the media.
Get rid of the drone.
Yes, Madam!
The best is yet to come.
"Private number"
The phone is ringing.
I'm picking up.
"Handsfree mode"
Hello?
Calling EOD,
what is Tung Sir doing?
There's a phone on the bomb.
Someone just called.
Who?
We don't know. I'll put it through.
You must be
Tung Cheuk Man, the EODB officer.
Who are you?
Just an ordinary citizen.
Unlike you, Tung Sir, I'm not in the news.
It's just a job.
Cops are very different from civilians.
I really want to know,
if a cop and a civilian
are both shot,
who will you save first?
I'm working.
I don't have time to think.
To! Scissors!
Yes, Sir!
Man.
Find cover!
Such precision!
Stay back!
Tung Sir! Your position is too dangerous.
Pull out!
My suit is bulletproof.
Try to save To.
Search sniper's location.
Don't go out there!
I heard you said your bomb suit can protect you.
Let's see.
Did you find him?
No, Madam!
Keep looking.
Hurry!
Sniper's location
should be at my 5 or 6 o’clock.
Madam, out of range.
Go!
What is it?
Police!
Stay here.
Bomb clear!
To!
Ambulance!
To! Stay awake! To!
Police!
Drop your weapon!
Hey!
Sniper down!
Place your men in deadly peril and they will survive.
Leave them in dire straits and they're reborn.
Salute!
Ambulance!
Hurry!
To, look at me!
To!
Hang in there!
Ambulance!
To!
Look at me!
Sir, let us take over.
I missed you…
It breaks my heart.
I want you to come home.
Even though I don't remember who they were.
I still feel bad.
Where you took me was not my home.
I'm a terrorist.
Whose idea was it, lying to me about being an UC?
Mine.
Yours?
If I said you were involved in 2 terrorist attacks
with a total casualty of 29 dead and 91 seriously injured,
how would you feel?
How would you feel?
But when I look at these dead colleagues, I begin to wonder...
...if my plan was a mistake.
Don't blame yourself.
You did nothing wrong.
If I were in your shoes,
I would have done the same.
I went back
and confirmed I'm a core member of Vendetta.
Davy
is not a person.
It's a U.S.
nuclear bomb developed during the Cold War.
Davy Crockett, as one of the smallest nuclear weapons ever built,
its destructive power is
between 10 and 20 tons of TNT equivalent.
Resurrection Day
is the code name for an operation.
The details of which
are still unknown.
I must carry on with the mission
and I'll find out soon.
We chose this path together.
Even though I have only one leg,
you must stick with me
and see this through.
You must be careful.
I will.
What was it like for us?
You were never in love with me,
but I can't tell if it's real or not.
The Boss wants to see you.
Calling Madam,
the barge blew up.
They took Poon Shing Fung away.
Madam,
we still have Poon Shing Fung's signal.
He's probably meeting with Ma Sai Kwan.
CTRU, let's roll.
Hang back! Keep a 1 km distance.
Madam,
we lost the signal.
Probably by a radio interference device.
OK! Go!
Boys, come on!
Hurry up!
"The Water Margin", never get bored from reading it.
Vendetta is like the Liangshan Marsh.
I'm Chao Gai and you're Song Jiang.
I foot the bill, you come up with ideas
upholding justice for Heaven.
I just didn't expect our ending
would be the same as "The Water Margin".
Song Jiang accepted the Court's amnesty
and betrayed his brothers.
Is the prosthetic any good?
The lady you were with works for CTRU.
She was my ex-girlfriend.
I'm a man on the run,
she wanted me to turn myself in.
We were childhood friends,
comrades with the same beliefs.
How can I possibly doubt you?
By the way,
how long have we known each other?
I don't remember.
I have amnesia.
Amnesia?
I'll have another go!
That's enough! Stop bullying Ma Sai Kwan!
We're playing with him.
I will always remember
how nice you were to me.
Why did they punish you for helping someone?
They didn't punish me for helping you,
but for getting into a fight.
But they hit you first.
You were protecting yourself...
...and me.
I want to give you something.
Mastermind?
It has 6 colors to choose from to be placed into 4 slots.
You must guess the correct color and order.
You lost.
Let me see.
I can't believe it.
Wouldn't that be easier to guess?
You never said you can use the same color.
I like uniformity.
I hate people who change.
After high school, I went to the U.K.
I sent you a Christmas card every year.
But after a few years, you stopped writing back.
Until one year, the Christmas card I sent was returned.
"Unable to Contact" was written on the envelope.
Then years later,
I saw you in the newspaper,
standing in front of a bomb with a big hole.
You became an EODB officer.
Right there and then,
I was heartbroken.
Until one day,
I found out this system finally abandoned you.
The world is sick!
Do I have to make a bomb,
then defuse it to prove myself?
Listen to yourself!
You're a ticking bomb.
This is a society that
everything is disposable after use,
including human beings.
When I read that message,
I knew
Blizzard
is you.
Anger is not enough.
To turn this rotten system to ashes,
we need to be together as one against all others,
- break all of their wings and make sure it crashes. - Courier
To see a new beginning rise behind the sun,
we seek destruction.
You finally came out from under
that "you got what you deserved" mentality.
But the price you paid
is your leg.
My dear friend,
long time no see.
I hope we can meet up and make some plans
to stop this world from getting worse.
Ma Sai Kwan?
Betrayal
is nothing new.
Humans are full of weaknesses.
But this operation is your design.
How can you beat Vendetta?
Who are you?
I don't know who I am.
I only wish to stop the terrorist attack.
Davy…
you told me where to find it.
Why did you betray yourself?
Remember what you said?
I don't remember.
What?
I want to stop the terrorist attack.
You can't!
You cannot!
I want to stop it!
You designed Resurrection Day.
Look!
The world was beautiful.
But now, it's incurable.
All systems are like a tumor.
If you have cancer,
you need chemotherapy.
Use radiation to kill all the cancer cells.
Better than waiting for death.
Waiting to die is a horrible feeling.
Scrap it and start over.
Place your men in deadly peril and they will survive.
Leave them in dire straits and they're reborn.
In the olden days,
the burning of Sodom and Gomorrah
and the world-engulfing flood.
Today,
we picked the date for Resurrection Day.
We can't stop!
I beg you! Stop the terrorist attack! OK?
I'm begging you…
Please?
Boss!
We're ready to roll.
Wait outside.
Yes!
I remember you said
waiting to die is a horrible feeling.
Now,
I'll let you get a feel for that.
"New York World Trade Center (WTC), 5 Dead Thousands Injured"
International Finance Centre (IFC) !
We're blowing up IFC.
I planned Resurrection Day.
It was my plan.
Where is the bomb?
I don't remember.
Calling Chan Sir,
Vendetta plans to blow up IFC.
We don't have details yet.
Evacuate IFC at once
and lock down the premises.
One IFC has 4 floors underground,
38 floors above ground.
Two IFC has 5 floors underground, 88 floors above ground.
With a floor area of 436,000 cubic meters
and 80 elevators,
it'll take a while to find the bomb.
Mon, get the tools.
Yes, Sir!
Everyone out!
Follow me, everyone! Go Go Go!
Everybody, hurry up!
- Yes, Sir! - Let's go!
They were so close.
They have very limited resources,
and parked the car bomb at the wrong place.
In the end,
they only blew a hole in the ground.
What they failed to do,
we'll make it right.
Today is February 26.
Resurrection Day is modeled after the 1993 car bombing
of the WTC in New York on February 26.
Back then, the terrorists parked the truck carrying the bomb
in the North Tower parking garage.
The target was the main column of the North Tower.
The intention was to send the taller North Tower
crashing into the lower South Tower.
We learnt from that incident
and decided to use C-4,
which is destructive enough to bring down the main column of Two IFC.
Two IFC would crumble towards the southwest
and crush One IFC.
Chan Sir,
the bomb should be in the garage of Two IFC,
near the main column on the southwest side.
Contact the Buildings Department for the IFC building plan.
Hurry!
Yes, Sir!
Tung Sir, here.
This bomb
is a combination device,
made up of 4 components,
with a pre-set permutation
to stop the timer.
Each component is one out of five.
That's 625 combinations.
You won't have time to disarm it.
Madam,
I'm in charge here.
I'd like you to leave.
You should both leave.
Let me die alone.
If you don't go to IFC,
a lot of people will die.
Pong Ling,
2 minutes.
If I can't do it, I'll leave.
Go!
I'm Lun Ting Pong of EOD.
Evacuate everyone within IFC vicinity.
The mall,
office building,
MTR station
and all nearby public space. Over!
EOD, split up and look for the bomb in the parking lot!
Hurry!
Evacuate everyone in the mall.
Hurry up!
Due to an emergency,
the mall will be closed.
we need everyone to evacuate at once.
Keep moving! Hurry!
You said
we should not save lives by risking our own.
Saving lives is my job.
I can be outside in 5 seconds.
If I can't disarm the bomb,
I can go for the lock.
It's a 4-digit lock. No numbers.
Red, yellow, blue, green, black and white.
6 colors.
Choose 4 out of 6 colors.
1296 combinations.
That's even harder.
Mastermind!
I like uniformity.
I hate people who change.
He really wants me to remember him.
Go for the lock.
Single color.
I'll try yellow.
Wrong.
Blue.
You never said you can use one color.
Red!
All red!
Run!
To IFC!
Time fuse 20 meters.
We need 10 minutes to clear out.
Relax! I did the Maths.
All trains heading for Hong Kong
will terminate at Kowloon Station.
No train is allowed to enter Hong Kong Station.
All trains heading for Hong Kong…
What’s happening?
We take control here.
If they use C-4 to blow up IFC,
what about Davy Crockett?
I will remember.
If nobody tries to be a hero,
we'll all get out in one piece.
Calling EOD,
the main column on the southwest side
is between parking spaces #150 and #200. Over!
Roger!
Split up to different levels.
Look for parking spaces between #150 and #200.
You two go down one level.
Fat Sze, give me the tools.
- Follow me! - This way!
Excuse me…
Over here!
Can't let them find the car.
-You can't go in. -This is locked down.
Hey!
Fat Sze!
Keep looking!
Yes sir!
Go!
What are you doing?
Stop the car!
A car just ran the gate!
Sir! Excuse me,
this area has been sealed off.
Everyone get out!
Take the booth!
Get on the ground!
Get down!
Everybody out…on the floor, now!
Get your heads down!
Everybody get down!
Open the gates.
Hurry it up!
Come on!
Come on! Hurry it up!
Tie them up!
Let's go! Give me your hands!
Shootout at Hong Kong Station.
Alpha Team, stay!
Beta Team, follow me across to Hong Kong Station L2.
Hurry, get up. Move on!
Move it!
Shoot them! Stand right here!
All cops, stay where you are!
If you take a step forward,
I will kill all the hostages.
Stay back! Don't come in here!
We will shoot the hostages!
Cops, we will shoot everyone!
Cops, stop!
Cops stop, stay back!
We will shoot you if you move forward.
What's the status?
EOD is looking for the bomb in the parking lot of Two IFC.
Terrorists at Hong Kong Station occupied L2
and put the bomb on the train.
I remember now.
Resurrection Day is not just blowing up IFC,
but also the core infrastructure of the HK Airport.
They will hijack the Airport Express.
The train has 8 cabins and will be split into 3 sections,
each carrying a bomb.
When it passes through major infrastructure, they will leave one section behind.
The C-4 on the train
will blow up Elements at the Kowloon Station and Tsing Ma Bridge.
The engine will crash into the Hong Kong International Airport.
Davy Crockett will be in the front.
The impact from the head-on collision
will trigger the wireless detonator,
and set off all the bombs simultaneously.
Davy Crockett will blow up the whole airport.
The radioactive contamination will leave Chek Lap Kok in ruins,
and unable to rebuild in at least 20 years.
Don't move!
Get down!
The terrorists hijacked the train. Over.
Any way we can intercept it? Over.
The Tsing Yi Control Center should be able to.
But Vendetta has taken over.
Over.
Chan Sir, there's a bomb on the train.
Lock down the Tsing Ma Bridge
and evacuate the airport and Airport Express.
Over.
Copy!
Due to an emergency,
everyone must leave the station at once!
and evacuate to somewhere safe.
Due to a serious incident,
please leave the station immediately!
Calling Tung Sir!
We found the car bomb.
It's clear.
I don't care how,
break into the Control Center
and stop Ma Sai Kwan's train on the Tsing Ma Bridge.
We move the car bomb out there,
then blow up both ends of the bridge
and let the train fall into the water.
This is the only way to stop radiation diffusion
and reduce casualties.
Brother Fung.
Sir, I'll go with you.
No, you stay!
Give your gear to Fung.
We have C-4,
time fuse,
detonator
and det cord in the back.
The Tsing Ma Bridge is a suspension bridge.
We split up and attach the C-4 to the 4 vertical cables
on the Ma Wan side,
then connect the det cord and time fuse
and blow it up using the detonator.
There's no gunpowder.
Here!
I'll go to the back and split the det cord into two sections.
Be careful!
Here…
Please follow instructions from ground personnel
and leave the station at once.
Pong Ling,
we use a time fuse to detonate C-4 to blow up the bridge.
But we must calculate the time we need to leave the bridge.
If Davy Crockett goes off in the water,
it'll cause a shockwave
with a lethal range of 1 km.
How long will it take the chopper to reach the safety zone?
From when you board the chopper, it'll take 30 seconds.
Stop Ma Sai Kwan's train in the middle of the bridge.
We'll take over the Control Center ASAP
and stop Ma Sai Kwan's train on the bridge.
After you reach the safety zone,
we'll re-start the train
and let it fall into the water.
Set the time fuse for 20 seconds.
Calling Lee Sir,
sniper ready.
They're shooting at us!
Find cover!
They're shooting!
I don't want to die!
Get out of my way!
Help!
Get down!
A train stopped at Kowloon Station.
Pong, there's a bomb on the train.
I don't care how,
just move it.
Copy!
Chan Sir, is there a train at Hong Kong Station?
Yes!
On the other side of the tracks.
Get me a train captain
to teach me how to operate it.
Done!
Set the C-4 on the cables.
Go!
Yes, Madam!
"Kowloon Station"
Tung Sir,
I'm pushing the train car from Kowloon Station towards Tsing Ma Bridge.
Madam, we are ready.
Three…
Two…
One…
Team B, action!
Grab the hostages!
Watch out for the hostages!
Resurrection!
Get the lights!
Police! Calm down!
Stop the train on Tsing Ma Bridge!
I'll do it.
- Evacuate the hostages. - Hurry!
Search the scene.
What happened?
What's wrong?
I can't control the train.
The train is still moving.
What happened?
Check the control system.
Hit by a stray bullet.
Is there another way?
No!
Control Center is clear.
But the control system is not working.
We cannot stop Ma Sai Kwan.
The detonator will be set up in 90 seconds.
We can get off the bridge in 90 seconds.
Ma Sai Kwan is 80 seconds away.
I'll hurry!
We have enough time to set the detonator,
but not enough to reach the safety zone.
Then you go ahead.
No!
We go together.
I can do this alone.
Why should two people die over this?
Then why should you stay and not me?
There's no turning back.
You should know. Let me do this.
Sorry Tung Sir,
we need to clear out or we won't make it.
Go ahead!
I beg you!
Buddy,
goodbye!
Pong Ling,
he's still there.
Fung!
All set!
Attention, all units!
Activate "CBRN" (Chemical, Biological, Radiological or Nuclear) emergency procedure right away!
Hong Kong Observatory,
activate the radiation monitoring system.
Leisure and Cultural Services Department,
close and evacuate all beaches.
Hospital Authority,
set up an emergency radiation treatment center.
Fire Services,
standby 24/7 with ambulances and ready to conduct search and rescue.
Information Services Department,
appeal to all citizens to watch out for TV and radio announcements
for rescue preparations.
Fung!
I'll see you in the next life.
Fung...
...remember my name is Pong Ling.
In the next life…
If memory can be implanted,
can you help me remove it?
All of it?
Except…
I'll get something to eat.
Sure. Go ahead!
Sorry! It was my fault.
It's OK.
I did it on purpose.
What do you mean?
No special meaning.
I only want you to remember me.
But I don't even know your name.
How can I remember you?
I'm Poon Shing Fung.
EODB officer.
Provided by explosiveskull
https://twitter.com/kaboomskull