Who can name all the apostles?
Yes, Deloris.
John, Paul, George...
and Ringo.
Deloris Wilson,
you are the most unruly,
disobedient girl in this school.
Now, I want you to march
right up to that blackboard...
and write the names of all
the apostles alphabetically.
This is enough.
You are hopeless.
And I wash my hands of you.
Mark my words, Deloris.
If you continue
on this disruptive track,
it will lead
straight to the devil.
Have you any idea
what girls like you become?
Whenever I'm with him.
Something inside.
- Inside.
- Starts to burning.
And I'm filled with desire.
Would it be the devil in me.
Or is this the way
love's supposed to be.
- It's like a heat wave.
- Heat wave.
- Burning in my heart.
- I can't keep from crying.
- Heat wave.
- It's tearing me apart.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
- Yeah.
- I said, oh, yeah.
- Heat wave.
Yeah, yeah
Yeah, yeah.
- I said, Oh, yeah.
- Ain't nothing but love, girl.
Don't pass up this chance.
Here's a chance
for a true romance.
Heat wave.
Nothing you can say
can tear me away
from my guy.
My guy.
Nothing you can do
'cause I'm stuck like glue.
- To my guy.
- My guy
I'm sticking to my guy
like a stamp to a letter.
Like two birds of a feather
we stick together
I'm telling you
from the start
I can't be torn apart
from my guy.
Whoa-oa-oa-oa-oa.
No muscle-bound man.
Could take my hand
from my guy.
My guy.
No handsome face
could ever take the place.
- Of my guy.
- My guy
- My guy.
He may not be
a movie star.
But when it comes
to being happy, we are.
There's not a man today.
Who could take me away
from my guy.
- What'd you say.
- There's not a man today.
Who could take me away
from my guy.
- Tell me more.
- There's not a man today.
Who could take me away from.
All right. Wrap this up, okay?
Wrap it up.
I will follow him
follow him
wherever he may go.
There isn't
an ocean too deep.
A mountain too high
it can keep.
- Keep me away.
- You better, you better.
- I will follow him.
- follow him.
Ever since he touched
my hands I knew.
That near him
I always must be.
And nothing
can keep me away.
He is my destiny
I love him, I love him
I love him.
- And where he goes I'll. - follow.
- I'll - follow.
- He'll always be my.
- True love - My - True love
- from now until for.
- Ever - or - Ever.
- Whoo!
Go.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
- Yeah.
- I'm a whole.
- Heat wave.
- Yeah, yeah. - Keep burning.
- Yeah, yeah - Keep burning.
- I'm a whole, yeah.
- Ain't nothing but love, girl.
Don't pass up this chance.
A diamond bracelet
and a pair of pants.
- Heat wave.
- Good night, ladies and gentlemen.
- You don't give a shit.
- Heat wave.
- Let's get the hell out of here.
Heat wave.
So I... I guess eating is
out of the question, huh?
Eat? Your next show
is in 20 minutes.
You still haven't told me
what she said.
- What who said?
- "What who said?"
The one with the moustache.
The one you're married to.
You are so damn hot.
And you are so full of it.
You didn't tell her, did you?
I knew it. I knew you
weren't gonna tell her.
I knew it.
I want us
to be together, babe.
Hmm.
I want us to be
an honest, decent couple.
I do.
I went to confession today.
You went to confession?
Like confession confession?
You know where you kneel in the box, you
tell the priest your deepest secrets?
Well, I did that today
for us, babe.
I told Father Antonelli
I was in love...
and that it was
a special love.
A love for all the ages
and that I want to be with her.
And what did he say?
He said that if I got divorced
I'd burn in hell for all eternity.
- Hand me my loafers, doll.
- You...
No, I... You-You can get
your own damn shoes.
So what does this...
What does this mean?
- Is this no? Does this mean no?
- No. No.
- What does it mean?
- Not no. Just not now.
Just get out, okay?
Just go.
You want me
to go against a priest?
Get excommunicated?
Okay.
I'll eat the thing you made.
- Is that was this is all about?
- No, that's not what it's about.
It's about you leaving.
Good night.
Good night!
I'll call.
You're quitting just because
he won't leave his wife?
No, not just because
he won't leave his wife.
I'm quitting for a lot of reasons.
It's something I have to do.
- What's gonna happen to the act? -What do
you mean, "What's gonna happen to the act"?
You're gonna get somebody else.
It's not a big loss.
Well, you put everything together.
You pick all the music.
You tell us where to stand
and everything.
Yeah, yeah, yeah,
I'm a real genius.
That's why we're packin' 'em in.
And don't you pack any more
of my make-up in that bag.
Don't think I don't know
what you're doing.
- What do you want, huh?
- And don't you ever knock?
Hey, girl, you ain't got nothing
that I haven't seen before, all right.
Yeah, well, stop tryin'
to memorize it.
- Hey, Michelle.
- Oh, please.
Hey, uh, Deloris, here.
This is from Vince.
- Here.
- I hope it's his dead body.
- With love.
- Oh, really?
- Yeah.
- Then why didn't he bring it down to me himself?
Oh, he wanted to, but he's
got a big meetin' upstairs.
- Hey, Tina.
- Hi.
Could you say good night
to these clowns, please?
I'm getting a headache. I don't
want them in here. Get out.
- Let's go.
- All right, I'm goin'.
Just take it easy.
Well, at least you got somethin'
out of all of this.
- Come on, Deloris, open this up.
- Yes.
Why should I open this? I don't
give a damn what's in that box.
- I don't care. - Oh, see what the
man brought you. - I want to see it.
- Why?
- Come on.
- Well, I want to see.
- Fine, okay.
Let's look and see
what it is then.
- Oh, look at this. - Oh.
- Look at this. - Check it out.
- It's mink.
- Yes!
- It's purple mink, Deloris.
- Oh.
Oh, that's beautiful!
Look.
- Oh.
- Feel.
Well, obviously, Mr LaRocca
feels he can win me back...
by sending me this
absolutely fabulous coat.
- Mm-hmm.
- Whoo!
- Put it on. Put it on.
- It's beautiful.
Well, see, some girls would fall
for that, but not me.
I think I'm gonna make him
wait a little while...
before I just
let him know that I...
What?
Connie LaRocca.
It's his wife's coat.
The man gave me
his wife's coat.
- Oh, I don't believe this.
- Put it back on.
It's yours now.
You deserve it.
No, I don't deserve it.
I haven't earned it.
You don't earn other people's
wife's fur coats.
Okay?
I think it's time to just go upstairs
and give it back to him,
get the hell out
of this dump.
How long you been
with me, Ernie?
- Um, three years, Mr LaRocca.
- Really?
Two as a croupier, one
as your personal limo driver.
Ernie, you know what's
important to me, what counts?
Loyalty, my man.
Loyalty is what
counts to me.
Well, I've been very loyal,
Mr LaRocca.
Gee, Ernie,
that's not what I hear.
I hear you went down to the
police station last night...
and talked with
Lieutenant Souther.
I hear you were there
for over three hours.
I-I-I-I went.
I went, but I didn't
tell them anything.
Again, not what I heard.
Goodbye, Vince.
I'm leaving
and don't try to stop me.
I'm going to L.A.
where it's nice and warm.
People don't need fur coats from
their boyfriend's wife's closet.
Goodbye, Vince. I'm going to Miami,
where the sun shines.
I know they're trying
to get something on me, Ernie,
but so far they've come up
with bubkas.
They called Willy and Joey in there,
but they were out in 20 minutes.
What were you doing there
for three hours, Ernie?
I know you don't think I have
any talent, Vince, but I do.
And I'm gonna leave you,
and I'm going to Chicago.
Tell me what you told Souther.
I won't be able to sleep
tonight if I don't know.
I've always wanted
to go to New York.
I know if I went to New York, I could get
some things together, Vince. I could.
I could... I could.
I could.
That's all I told him.
I swear it.
Thanks, Ernie.
Now I can sleep.
- Say good night, Ernie.
- No, no, no. That's all...
Babe. Deloris.
Deloris.
Is there a problem?
- With the coat?
- With the coat? No.
No, not with the coat.
The coat's fine. I...
It's... It's fine.
Thank-Thank you.
Is that why you came here
tonight? To thank me?
Yeah. Thank you.
And to say you're sorry, about
tonight and the things you said?
Forgotten.
Completely.
You understand me?
- Forgotten.
- Of-Of course.
It's... Of course.
It's forgotten.
That's my girl.
My girl in mink.
- Will you be home?
- Yeah. - Soon? - Yeah.
- Go ahead.
- Okay.
Hey, Vince, is she okay?
I don't know, Vince.
She seemed kind of upset.
- She did?
- Yeah.
Bring her back, now,
for a talk.
And if she runs,
then what?
Take care of it.
Deloris!
Come on back!
Deloris,
he just wants to talk!
- Which way?
- That way.
Hey! Hey! Taxi! Hey!
Hey! Hey! Let's go! Let's go!
Let's go! Go! Go! Go!
And then Vince looks at Ernie
and says, "Say good night."
And then Vince looks at Joey
and Joey shot him.
I mean, he just shot him
in the chair.
Just boom.
He blew this guy away!
Sorry I'm late.
I'm Lieutenant Souther.
- Eddie Souther.
- How do you do? I'm Deloris Van Cartier.
Listen, this guy was
a simple limo driver, right?
He was a limo driver. So maybe he made
a couple wrong turns in his life.
That's no reason to kill him.
I've never seen anybody killed before.
Except, you know, sometimes you pass on the
free-way, you see a couple of people dead.
- But it's not the same thing...
- Miss Van Cartier? - What?
You're Vince LaRocca's
girlfriend, right?
Well, you could,
sort of, maybe...
It depends on how you look at it.
I mean, the guy just tried to kill me,
so I don't think that
cements our relationship.
Well, you realize he's a major
underworld figure, don't you?
He's into drug dealing,
money laundering.
We've been investigating Mr LaRocca
for the last 18 months.
We've got videotapes.
We've got surveillance photos.
Am I... Am I in any of the...
On the videotapes?
- No, no, no. Criminal activity.
- Oh.
The tapes aren't enough
to convict him.
Apparently, there's a lot
you don't know about Vince.
I mean, the last two people that saw
him in action kind of disappeared.
What do you mean, they kind of disappeared?
What does that... What do you mean?
Well, we found a piece here
and a piece there.
But don't you worry.
Here, have a cup of coffee.
You're safe now, and we're gonna
see that you stay that way.
- That's our job.
- If you help us, we can help you.
If you testify against Vince
about what you saw,
we can put him away
for the rest of his life.
Are you crazy? You're telling me this guy is
a mad criminal, and you want me to testify?
Do you know what's gonna happen?
He's gonna track me down.
- Deloris. - He's gonna kill me.
- Can I call you Deloris?
You can call me anything you want,
as long as you keep me alive!
- We wouldn't put you at risk if
we couldn't protect you. - Right.
It'll only take a couple
of months to get a court date.
Just a couple of months?
Only a couple? Why not a year?
- How about a couple of decades?
- Two months we hide you out, then you testify.
No! No. No.
It's just for a little while,
then you can come back.
Really? What are you gonna do?
You gonna stick me in a bag and bury me?
Forget it!
If you testify,
I'm gonna put you
in the last place on Earth...
that Vince would ever
look for you.
- Nice church, huh?
- Yeah, it's very nice.
Look, what am I gonna be,
Quasimodo in the bat belfry?
- What is this?
- I want you to stay here for a while.
Where?
In the convent.
It's the safest place in the world.
- You think Vince is gonna look for you
in a convent? - No, no. What? What?
- In the what? - The convent.
- You must be out of your...
You know what? I'm gonna go back and work
this out with Vince. You're a lunatic.
I'm not gonna be in no damn
convent with these people.
These people
don't even have sex!
Deloris, Vince has a contract
out on you for a hundred grand.
- Now you've seen what he can do.
- Look...
One bullet,
that's all it's gonna take.
No, no, look. Let me
explain something to you.
Vince knows people all over
the place. You realize that.
He knows people all over the place. That means
he's gonna be looking for me everywhere.
- Everywhere but this convent.
- Oh, come on!
Nobody knows you're here
but me.
We're trying to get you a quick court
date. One month, two months tops.
I promise I'm gonna spring you
as fast as I can.
What... What am I gonna do here?
I'm gonna go crazy here.
There is nothing but a lot
of white women dressed as nuns.
I'm... What am I gonna do here?
- Pray.
- Pray?
Yes, but, Monsignor,
we are a small convent.
Surely, there are
more appropriate places.
We can save this young woman's life and
imprison a parasite all in one gesture.
My heart goes out to her,
of course.
My concern would be she might
subject the convent to danger.
The Reno Police Department assures me
you'll be protected from any harm.
They've promised to make
a generous financial donation.
And, as you know, your small
convent is in danger of closing.
Well, if they can afford
to be so generous,
so can we.
Excuse me.
Absolutely not.
I couldn't possibly.
Well, think of it this way, Reverend Mother,
she's an ideal prospect for rehabilitation.
That is not a person
you can hide.
That is a conspicuous person,
designed to stick out.
You have taken a vow
of hospitality to all in need.
I lied.
Lieutenant Souther,
everything is in order.
No, no, no, no,
everything is not in order.
- This woman does not like me.
- Deloris, these are holy people.
- They like everybody.
- I don't give a shit what you say!
- This woman does not like me.
- One month. Two months tops.
No, I'm not staying here.
Forget it. Forget it. Forget it.
I'm not staying here!
I'm telling you, I'm not...
- Behave yourself.
- gonna stay here!
What is your name?
Deloris Van Cartier.
Is that your real name?
Yes.
I happen to be a singer.
- Oh-oh. Do sit down.
- Thank you.
Look, before we get started,
I-I just want to say...
that I really appreciate
what you're doing for me.
I know it must be a huge
inconvenience for you.
Yeah, so I-I just, you know,
wanted to say thank you up front.
I also, uh, have always...
and I've said this to people...
I've always admired you people.
Nuns, I mean.
You know, you're so...
Catholic, you know.
I mean, look, you're
married to the big J.C.
I mean, you're His
old lady, you know.
It's, uh... It's an
amazing thing to me.
I mean, of course, you must be saying,
"Well, it's much better...
than being hooked up
with some kind of two-timing... ".
Please, do not smoke
in here.
Oh, I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I...
You know, I get so nervous.
I get worked up. I just... I just
had... I don't know. I'm sorry.
Look, Miss Van Cartier, we have agreed
to conceal and protect you,
which we will do
to the best of our ability.
However, it is essential
that you understand...
that you are not
in a sorority or a speak-easy.
This is a convent,
a religious order,
and there are certain rules
you must obey.
St Katherine's is a place
to commune and to pray,
and I will not tolerate any disruption
whatsoever with that communion.
Do you understand?
- Yes.
- Good.
But do you understand
I'm the victim here?
Do you understand
I'm the good guy?
I mean, they just kind of
threw me in here with you nuns.
I mean, do you get that?
I'm the good guy.
I mean, I saw a guy
get his face blown off.
So why don't you just
give me the key to my room?
I'll lay low. You stay out of my face,
I'll stay out of your face.
And I will commune my little
black ass in that room.
Can you handle that?
- I think it's a very good idea.
- Thank you.
Well, it's almost lunchtime.
Perhaps you'd like
to freshen up.
And you'll certainly
want to change.
I just hope you don't think I'm gonna
wear what I wore in Catholic school.
No, siree. No ugly
green jumpers for me.
And those stupid
clunky shoes.
Oh, with this gold thing... Could
you have it dry-cleaned for me?
Open the cabinet to your left.
You will find suitable attire.
Oh, cool.
Oh, no. No, no, no,
I can't do this. I'm sorry.
This is fine for covering a little
bulge, but now I've got holster hips.
People wish to kill you.
Anyone who's met you,
I imagine.
A disguise is necessary
to protect us all.
Now, while you are here,
you will conduct yourself as a nun.
Only I will know who
and what you truly are.
You will draw no attention
to yourself whatsoever.
But look at me! I'm a nun.
I'm a... I'm a penguin!
As from now and until you leave,
you are Sister Mary Clarence.
Mary Clarence? Like-Like Clarence
Williams III from The Mod Squad?
Mary is in deference
to our Holy Mother.
The Clarence is in honour
of St Clarence of Concordia.
There are three vows
every nun must accept.
- The vow of poverty.
- Mmm.
- The vow of obedience.
- Mm-hmm.
- And the vow of chastity.
- I am out of here with that.
Oh, oh, man.
It is necessary to eat...
- Good afternoon, Sisters.
- Good afternoon.
I apologize
for my tardiness.
I would like you to welcome
a new member to our house.
Sister Mary Clarence.
Mary Clarence comes to us from
a somewhat progressive convent.
However, she's eager to embrace
a more disciplined life,
and I am sure will make every
effort to conform to our ways.
I'll do my best.
- Would you like to be seated?
- Thank you.
- Yes, Mary Patrick?
- Reverend Mother,
on behalf of all the Sisters
here at St Katherine's,
I'd like to offer a great big hi there
and hello to Sister Mary Clarence. Hi.
And as part of the welcome,
I thought that maybe...
our new sister could offer
today's blessing.
That is very thoughtful of you,
Mary Patrick, but I really...
Oh, yeah. Yeah, I can...
I can do that. Uh, sure.
Oh, fudge.
Uh, bless us, O Lord,
for these Thy gifts which
we're about to receive.
And, yea, though I walk through
the valley of the shadow of no food,
I will fear no hunger.
We want You to give us
this day our daily bread...
and to the republic
for which it stands,
and by the power
invested in me,
I pronounce us
ready to eat.
- Amen.
Be seated.
Thank you.
Gee, what are you people,
a Pritikin order?
This stuff is terrible.
It tastes like shi...
Sisters, we shall spend
the rest of the day in silence.
- Well, why?
- Only when our lips are silent,
may our prayers
truly be answered.
Then you don't have
to eat this food.
Silence begins now...
and ends at sundown.
How can you eat this stuff?
It's terrible.
Mary Clarence,
I think you might enjoy
a ritual fast.
A ritual f... No. No, no.
I don't think I would.
I'll just put a little salt
in it. It will be fine.
Look, I'm gonna have... Someone
pass me the salt over there.
A fast, to remind you of those
who must endure without food.
I... No, I don't want you
to take...
I don't want you
to take my plate.
And silence.
How can you let them grill me
in there for six hours?
I can't control how long
they're gonna question you.
- Did you go to law school, Larry?
- Yes, I went to law school, Vince.
- Did you graduate?
- Hey, I'm a lawyer.
- Of course I graduated.
- Hey, Vince.
Nice talking to you.
See you in court.
You got nothing
on me, Souther.
And if you don't stop
harassing me, I'm gonna...
What? You're gonna what?
Nothing. Nothing, Lieutenant.
What my client is trying
to say is that...
Is that he's scared.
And you know what?
He should be.
Real scared.
See you around, boys.
Something's going on.
He's so damn cocky.
Ah, he's bluffilng, Vince.
Don't worry about it.
- You find Deloris?
- She's gone.
We don't know where she is, and she
hasn't been back to her place all day.
He's got Deloris.
We gotta get her back.
Fax her eight-by-ten
to every contact we got.
- I can't hear this.
- Deloris Van Cartier.
A quarter of a mil,
dead or alive.
This is your cell,
Mary Clarence.
- My what?
- Your cell.
Your room.
Oh, man.
No wonder you waited till now
to spring this on me.
It's like a nightmare.
Where's the rest
of the furniture?
Our lives are simple.
We have little need
for material possessions.
This is out
of the Stone Age.
- Where's the phone?
- Who would you call?
I don't know. Satan?
Your cell is
more than adequate.
Fine. What do we do now?
Pray? What?
It's 9:00.
Pleasant dreams.
W-W-Wait. Are you telling me
we go to bed by 9:00?
If I were you, I would use this time to
think about my life and its direction.
Or lack thereof.
There's nothing wrong with my life.
You know, before I came here,
I had a career, I had friends,
I had clothing that fit.
Before I came here,
I was okay.
Oh, really?
From what I've heard,
your singing career
was almost non-existent...
and your married lover
wants you dead.
If you're fooling anyone,
it is only yourself.
God has brought you here.
Take the hint.
Mary Clarence.
What?
Up and at 'em.
We don't want to be late.
- What time is it?
- Well, it's almost 5:00, Sister Sleepyhead.
5:00 a.m.?
Get out of here.
I just went to bed
20 minutes ago.
- Get outta here. Scram. - Come on. The
sun is shining. It's a beautiful day.
We are a small congregation
this morning.
Too many mornings.
Something has gone
terribly wrong.
Where is faith?
Where is celebration?
Where is everyone?
Still, rather than regret
the absence of our neighbours,
let us rejoice in the fellowship
of those present.
Our choir mistress,
Sister Mary Lazarus,
has informed me
that our choir,
while always superior,
has been toiling especially hard
on this week's selection.
Sister.
Hail, Holy Queen.
Enthroned above.
Oh, Maria.
- Hail.
- Hail, mother of mercy.
And of love.
Oh, Maria.
Triumph all ye.
Cherubim.
Sing with us.
Ye seraphim.
- Heaven on Earth.
- Heaven and Earth.
Resound the hymn.
There was a raid on a pawnshop
in L.A. this morning.
The place was fencing
stolen property.
- They found this.
- Database hoods.
What a wonderful world, huh?
"Beloved daughter missing.
Reward of $250,000."
Please find
our daughter, Angel.
"We miss her so.
Dead or alive."
Vince is getting desperate.
So where did you
stash her, Eddie?
Where did I stash who?
Wha... You're not even
gonna tell us?
I wouldn't even
tell the Pope.
I'm not gonna get this. This is
a little too complicated for me.
Don't you worry. You'll get
the hang of it. I'll help you.
Thank you.
- Are you always this cheerful?
- Am I?
- Mm-hmm.
- All right, I am. I know it.
I can't help it. I've always
been upbeat, optimistic, perky.
Even as a child,
my mother used to say,
"That girl is pure sunshine.
She'll either grow up to be
a nun or a stewardess."
Coffee?
Enough about me.
What about you?
Yes. What convent
did you come from?
I came from the convent...
of the Sisters
of the Moonlight...
in Reno.
Oh, I love Reno.
- You do?
- Yes.
Well, you-you
would have loved us.
We were... We were
a pioneering kind of order.
You know, we'd, uh, never wear any
kind of habit this tight, though.
This is really tight.
Oh, I must say, our habits do
cut you at the neck just a bit.
- Yeah.
- Hear, hear, hear, hear.
That's enough jabber. Vanity.
A progressive convent?
Sounds awful.
I liked my convent in Vancouver.
Out in the woods.
It wasn't all modern like some
of these newfangled convents.
We didn't have electricity.
Cold water, bare feet.
Those were nuns.
Sounds wonderful.
It was hell on Earth.
I loved it.
This place is a Hilton.
Sister Mary Clarence,
when did you get your call?
What call?
Oh, the call! The call!
I-I didn't know
which call you meant.
I was working... I was working
in Reno, and I got the call.
And you don't know how hard it is to get a
call until you've worked in Reno, you know.
We were just... We-We ministered to
a lot of different kind of people:
newly-weds, hookers, gamblers.
What a joy. How fulfilling to be able to
get right in there with your hands...
and work with the people.
And Reno... It's probably
bursting with sin.
It was. That's...
That's why I had to leave.
I mean, we had a hooker
living next door...
called Buckwheat Bertha
who would...
Sister Mary Clarence,
could I have a word with you?
- Who? Me?
- Yes, you.
Yeah. Excuse me.
Get on with your work.
- Quickly, please.
- I was just talking to 'em.
Precisely. Enough chatter. Chores.
Rescue me
Take me in your arms.
I want your tender charm.
'Cause I'm lonely
and I'm blue
I need you and your love too
Come on and rescue me.
Come on, baby
and rescue me.
'Cause I need you
by my side.
Can't you see that I love you
Rescue me.
Come on and take my heart
Take your love.
And comfort every part
'Cause I'm lonely.
And I'm blue
I need you
and your love too.
Come on and rescue me
Come on, baby.
And rescue me.
Come on, baby
and rescue me.
'Cause I need you by my side.
Can't you see that I'm lonely.
Yeah, I need to talk
to Eddie Souther.
Yeah, it's an emergency.
- Souther.
- Eddie! Eddie! Eddie! Eddie!
- You gotta get me outta here.
- Deloris, you can't call me here.
Somebody's gonna catch on
to where you are.
But I'm going insane here. All these
people do is work and pray, work and pray.
- That's all they do.
- Calm down!
Look, I didn't want to tell you this,
but we got some problems here.
Well, what kind of problems?
What do you mean, problems?
Keeping our witnesses alive.
I mean, we hide them,
but there's a leak in the department,
and some of them
end up dead.
- What?
- Just sit tight.
You don't seem to understand
what I'm saying.
I am in a nightmare.
This is my nightmare.
It's a nightmare, man.
Get me outta here.
I mean it. Don't call me.
It's not safe.
I'll be in touch.
Hello? Hello?
Yeah?
I-I-I brought you something.
My brother gave it to me
when I was a little girl.
I could never seem
to get up on time.
So I, um, set it for 5:00.
Out of bed,
you daisy head.
- It always made me laugh.
- Out of bed, you daisy head.
I thought, being away
from your convent,
that even someone like you
could get lonely.
Have a seat.
- So which one are you?
- Mary Robert.
You have a little trouble
getting up at 5:00 too, Mary Robert?
Oh, not now.
I get up a half an hour early
just to make sure.
It's-It's not just
the mornings.
It's that all my life...
everybody seems to be doing
or catching on to things...
a second faster
or better than me.
Yeah, well, everybody's
playing catch-up nowadays.
So, Mary Robert,
did you always want
to be a nun?
Mmm. I always knew that
that was my calling:
to lead a life of service.
But, you see,
I've always felt that there's
something inside me...
that I-I want to give.
Something that's only me
and nobody else.
Does that sound
like a terrible thing?
Like pride?
No. It doesn't sound like
a terrible thing at all.
I'm so happy that you've come
to join us, Mary Clarence.
Do you know how sometimes it's as if you
have to be yourself or you'll just burst?
Yep, I do.
Good night.
Good night, Mary Robert.
Out of bed,
you daisy head.
- Hang on.
- Hey, hey, wait up.
- Hey.
- Making me run all this way...
Ooh, nice tattoo.
Hey, Sister.
Hey, this jukebox got anything
on it from Sound of Music?
Hey, baby
What do I have to do.
- Want to dance, Sister?
- Why? You don't have any rhythm.
To make you love me too.
- You got to roll with me, Henry.
- All right.
Young man, take your foot
down off that stool.
Now, have a seat.
Have a seat.
- Baby. - Roll with me, Henry.
- Henry, hold on.
- Sit down and shut up.
- Can I have a Coke, please?
- Coming up.
- Thank you so much.
Roll with me, Henry.
Whoa, boy!
What are you doin' in here?
- I... - What are you doing?
- I thought you...
What are you guys doing?
Look, you have to go.
You have to go.
- We...
- Oh, never mind. Go. Go.
Just go that way.
Sister, expecting any more
of your friends?
Now, you guys want to tell me
what you're doing here?
Well, I-I thought that you might
be ministering to the winos,
the way that you did
in your convent in Reno,
and I thought I could help.
And I saw her leave, and it was
very late, and so I followed...
What are you doing here?
- I'm here to see a man about a
car. For the convent. - Really?
- Yes. - Did you get it?
- No, I didn't.
- I'm gonna get you outta here.
- We could really use it.
- What colour?
- Come on, come on.
Oh, a jukebox.
Oh, one song, one song.
- No, no, no, no, no, no.
- Do you have a quarter? Oh, one song, please.
Come on. He does. All right. It'll
come back to you tenfold. Thanks.
Hurry up. Hurry up.
Oh, I love this song.
Give me, give me, give me
Give me gravy tonight.
What's the matter with you?
One dance. I'll be
right back, please.
But that don't show me
that you're really mine.
Once they're dancing
when they're romancing.
So put me something
extra on the line.
- Gravy.
- On my mashed potatoes.
- Give me.
- Gravy.
Come on and treat me right.
- You're the greatest.
So give me, give me, give me
Give me gravy tonight.
All right.
But I want some more.
There's something missing
and we're on the floor.
Come on, baby
I want some gravy.
A little kiss
is what I'm waiting for.
- Gravy.
- On my mashed potatoes.
Come on. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Come on, come on, come on.
- Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes.
- Good night. - Come on!
- Go, go!
- I love this song.
We had a lovely time.
We'll be back.
- Yes, we will. Good night.
- Bless you.
You leaving?
This turns into a nuns' bar,
I'm outta here.
Yeah.
- Oh, good grief.
- Just come on. Come on.
Stop giggling. Let's go.
Quiet. Shh.
The sisters have made it clear to me that
they followed you of their own volition.
But they would never have
ventured out at all at night...
had it not been
for your example.
But, listen, they just don't want to be
stuck behind these walls all the time.
These walls are the only
protection they have.
The streets are no longer safe for them,
and they are certainly not safe for you.
These robes no longer protect
our sisters. The walls do.
I'm sorry.
You really do care
about them, don't you?
Yes, I do.
And I care about you
and your life.
I shall ask Monsignor O'Hara
and Lieutenant Souther...
to find a safer and more
suitable situation for you.
Oh, no. Come on.
Don't send me away. Really.
I mean, I'm just starting
to get the hang of this.
I mean, look, I'm not gonna endanger
anyone or anything else.
I swear. What about forgiveness?
Isn't that what you preach?
There's got to be something
around here that I can do...
that's not gonna chip my nails
or annoy anybody.
You're right, Mary Clarence.
To err is human,
to forgive divine.
You may stay.
But I shall restrict your
activities to a single task.
What's that?
Singing.
You will join the choir.
Choir? No.
You will sleep
and you will sing.
That will be your task
until you leave.
No. Uh, the choir?
I mean, h-h-have you
heard them?
The choir, Mary Clarence.
Is this the choir rehearsal?
It sure is.
Come on in, sing a spell.
- Soprano or alto?
- Whatever.
Thanks.
- Hi, Sister.
- Hello, Sister.
- 214.
Crown Him with many crowns.
The Lamb upon His throne.
- All kingdoms.
- All kingdoms of the...
Mary Clarence,
are you with us?
I don't know this one.
I... I better...
I better sit this one out.
Excuse me.
Reverend Mother says Mary Clarence
has a background in music.
Really, Mary Clarence?
Were you a choir mistress?
- Sort of freelance.
- Freelance? Really?
Oh. You don't think I see?
You think
I took vows yesterday?
I know what you're up to.
You and Reverend Mother.
Uh, what?
You're a ringer.
She brought you here
to replace me.
Out with the old.
Oh, could you help us,
Mary Clarence?
Mary Lazarus,
you're terrific,
but we could
really use some help.
- Please. You've heard us.
- We're terrible.
Please, do something for us.
- Please.
- Well, there's a word for this.
Mutiny.
So, Mary Clarence,
you think you can do better?
I believe
I'd like to see that.
Go ahead, Sister.
Make 'em sing.
Okay.
Where are the basses?
Oh, you should
be over here.
Uh, and the altos?
Where are you?
Sister, why don't you join them?
And sopranos, where are you?
Oh, you've got
to come down this way.
All right, uh...
Basses, I-I want you
to give me a D.
Altos, I want you to do
a third above that.
Give me an F sharp.
And sopranos,
uh, give me an A.
Let me have Sister Alma
play it one time...
so we all know
what we're gonna do,
and, and we'll go
from there.
Sister, will you give me
those, uh, notes, please?
Okay? On three.
One, two, three.
Okay. Okay, okay. Okay.
Very-Very nice.
Sister, what... Would you, would
you come over here, please?
Just slide right in here for me,
please. Right. Right here.
- Um, that's a powerful instrument you have there.
- Thank you.
But I think it's probably
a good idea...
if we bring you down
out of the rafters.
I mean, everybody wants
to be close to God.
I'm just not sure
you can do it vocally.
Okay, so I need you
to sing...
an octave below
where you've been singing.
Okey-dokey.
And, Sister Mary Robert,
could you, could you come
stand over here, please?
Yeah, come on over.
I noticed that, uh,
you're moving your mouth,
but nothing's coming out.
So I'd like to just hear you
by yourself, if you don't mind.
Sister Alma, could you
give me an A, please?
Alma!
Check your battery.
Give me an A, please.
Okay, wait a... Okay.
- Um, try this.
- Mm-hmm.
Close your eyes.
Visualize yourself
in a room full of people.
Lots of silverware, people
dropping stuff, talking loud,
drunks, women with,
with trays going,
"What are you gonna have?"
Your voice has to carry
over the din.
You have to get up over
all of that...
to be heard in the back
of the room, where I'm sitting,
listening, straining
to hear you.
- Okay?
- Okay.
Keep that in your mind
when we do this.
Sister.
- Sister, that's amazing.
- We call that an A with an attitude.
That's what you need. You have to
put attitude in what you sing.
You have to think about what you're
singing. It's not just quacking.
This is...
This is rejoicing.
You are singing
to the Lord.
Let's review
those notes again...
and see if we can
put it together.
Sister.
Basses. Altos. Sopranos.
On three.
One, two, three.
Oh, we did it.
We actually sang a chord.
That was exciting.
Yeah, you sang a chord
for two seconds.
The next thing you have to learn how
to do is listen to each other.
That's a big key.
Big key.
You must listen to each other
if you're going to be a group.
- I knew that.
- Mary Lazarus, I...
As soon as I walked in the door,
I knew that you knew this.
Now, you're somebody who's into
hard work and discipline, aren't you?
Of course. I'm a nun.
Four Popes now.
Four? Wow.
How often do they rehearse?
Twice a week,
a couple hours.
Not enough.
I mean, listen to them.
They really need
a lot of work.
They gotta rehearse
every day.
She's good.
Well, do you think they
really could get better?
I don't know.
They're pretty raw.
Wet behind the ears.
Oh, please, let us try.
- Please.
This is gonna be hell.
Tell me about it.
La, la, la, la
la, la, la, la, la.
La, la.
Welcome this Sunday morning,
oh, ye few, but faithful.
The choir, I'm told,
has elected a new director,
Sister Mary Clarence,
who will lead them
in "Hail, Holy Queen."
Hail, Holy Queen.
Enthroned above.
Oh, Maria.
Hail, mother of mercy.
And of love.
Oh, Maria.
Triumph all ye cherubim.
Sing with us ye seraphim.
Heaven and Earth.
Resound the hymn.
Hail, Holy Queen
enthroned above.
Oh, Maria.
Hail, mother of mercy
and of love.
Oh, Maria.
Triumph all ye cherubim.
Sing with us ye seraphim.
Heaven and Earth
resound the hymn.
Hey, what do you think's
going on over there?
I don't know, man,
but it sounds good.
- Yeah.
- Let's go.
Our life
Our sweetness here below.
- Oh, Maria.
Our hope in sorrow
and in woe.
- Whoa, Maria.
- Oh, Maria.
Triumph all ye cherubim.
- Cherubim.
- Sing with us ye seraphim.
- Seraphim.
- Heaven and Earth resound the hymn.
Hallelujah.
- Hallelujah.
Our life
Our sweetness here below.
Oh, Maria.
Our hope in sorrow
and in woe.
- Whoa, Maria.
- Oh, Maria.
Triumph all ye cherubim.
- Cherubim.
- Sing with us ye seraphim.
- Sweet seraphim.
- Heaven and Earth resound the hymn.
Girl groups!
Boogie-woogie on the piano!
What were you thinking?
I was thinking
more like Vegas.
You know, get some butts
in the seats.
And what next?
Popcorn? Curtain calls?
- This is not a theatre or a casino!
- Yeah, but that's the problem.
See, people like going to theatres,
and they like going to casinos.
But they don't like
coming to church. Why?
Because it's a drag.
But we could change all that.
See, we could, we could
pack this joint.
Through blasphemy?
You have corrupted
the entire choir!
- Excuse me. Excuse me.
- Oh. - Excuse me.
How can you say that? I...
- I've worked my butt off with these women.
- Oh.
They've given up their free time
to do this, and they're good!
I mean, Sister, we could,
we could rock this place.
Out of the question! As of tomorrow, Mary
Lazarus resumes her leadership of the choir.
Come in!
Reverend Mother, I just
wanted to congratulate you.
I haven't enjoyed mass
this much in years.
What a marvellous programme.
Innovative. Inspiring.
You're to be commended.
I can't wait till next Sunday
when the choir performs again.
Did you see the people
walk right in from the street?
That music.
That heavenly music.
Reverend Mother,
it called to them.
It... It did?
I must tell the Archbishop.
I'll send him a personal letter
describing your efforts,
your bold, new flight to keep
your little convent alive.
And you must also
include this.
This is something she would
never tell you herself...
because this is the kind
of woman she is.
Sisters, she wants us to go out into
the neighbourhood and meet the people.
- Oh, this woman.
- Oh, bless her.
Oh, there are so many problems out there
that we could maybe help with.
I mean, that's why
many of us became nuns.
Oh, it's really marvellous,
Reverend Mother.
- There's a lot we could do for them
besides pray, Sister. - That's right.
You're a pioneer.
Monsignor, surely you realize
how dangerous this neighbourhood is.
And you will face
that danger head-on.
- As if I could stop you.
- You couldn't.
You have my complete support
in this matter.
Anything you can do to revitalize
this neighbourhood would be a blessing.
Don't you just love her?
Praise you, Reverend Mother.
Just a touch of love
Just a touch of love.
Love has been on my mind
for some time now.
But you've been
the missing link.
With all that's been happening
All this has made me think.
That love is not for keeps.
- All I want is your love.
- All I need is promises.
Once is never enough.
- Open up your heart and let me in.
- Look no further.
Love has got me crying.
- Understanding my love.
- Just a touch.
Just a touch of love
Just a touch of love.
- Just a touch of love, yeah. -Just a
touch of love Just a touch of love.
Just a touch of love
Just a touch of love.
Music will light
the fires of romance.
That could be forever.
You better bat down a lover
Someone to discover.
That just a touch of love
is all I need.
- All I want is your love.
- Come a little closer.
- Once is never enough.
- Open up your heart and let me in.
- Love is burning us up.
- Love has got me crying.
- Understanding my love.
- Just a touch.
Just a touch of love
Just a touch of love.
- Just a touch of love. -Just a touch
of love Just a touch of love.
- Just a touch of love Just a touch of love.
- Yeah.
Just a touch of love
Just a touch of love.
- Give me your love, yeah. -Just a
touch of love Just a touch of love.
Just a touch of love
Just a touch of love.
- Just a touch of love Just a touch of love.
- eels so right.
Yes, the failing convent at
St Katherine's has truly come alive...
thanks to the efforts
of its popular choir.
What an amazing
turnaround story.
This convent was once alienated
from its surrounding neighbours.
- Now, as you can see, its doors are open
in an effort... - Vinny, get over here.
- To reach out into the community,
- What?
Establishing facilities
like a day care centre...
and a food kitchen
for the homeless.
- As a matter of fact, the enthusiasm...
- Vin, you've gotta see...
- these cute nuns. - generated at
St Katherine's has resulted...
- I'm shootin' pool.
- In a new sense of civic pride.
- Babe, we should send them money.
- Why all the changes?
- Well, the nuns I talked to...
- They're do-gooders.
Attribute this reach-out
philosophy to...
a new addition to the convent,
Sister Mary Clarence,
who, unfortunately,
is a little camera shy.
I'm gonna kill her.
I'm gonna kill her myself.
In related news,
the Pope visits the U.S.
And we'll have more on that
in just a moment.
- Good... Good morning.
- Good morning.
- Thank you so much.
- Good morning, Monsignor. - Good morning.
- Good... Good to see you.
- Good morning. - Good morning.
Hey, hey. What...
Are you looking for me?
What are you doing here?
- How come I saw you on TV?
- That was not my fault.
These people just showed up. But it's
been really good for the convent.
You're supposed to be
hiding out. Remember?
Bullets flying
through the air at you.
- Ring a bell?
- Yes.
But I can't talk about it now because
I have a show in five minutes.
Listen to yourself. This is
not a career opportunity.
You don't have to tell me that. This would
not be the place to begin a career.
Hey, just promise me I won't see
you on the Letterman show, okay?
Okay.
Hey, I'm worried about you.
I don't want to see
anything happen to you.
Okay. You gonna
come to the show?
Yeah, I'd love to.
This Sunday's hymn is inspired
by the lesson of Mary Magdalene.
Now, Mary Magdalene was
a young lady with a past.
Oh, yes.
And she was
no stranger to sin.
She was no stranger
to practically anybody.
Many condemned her.
The whole neighbourhood, in fact.
But one man
refused to do so.
One man said, "Hey, now,
hold on. Wait a minute."
Listen to the girl's story.
- Hail, girls.
- Hail, Mary. What's up?
Well, Jerusalem's become
a real drag. Everybody hates me.
Uh-uh. Not that guy over there.
Who? Him? They all
say he's different.
They say he's really weird.
We don't care what people say.
To us, he's always there.
Really?
Nothing you could say
could tear me away from my God.
My God.
Nothing you could do
'cause I'm stuck like glue.
- To my God.
- My God
I'm sticking to my God
like a stamp to a letter.
Like birds of a feather
we stick together
I'm telling you
from the start
I can't be torn apart
from my God.
Nothing you could do
could make me untrue.
- To my God.
- My God.
Nothing you could buy
could make me tell a lie.
- To my God.
- My God
I gave my God
my word of honour.
- To be faithful.
- And I'm gonna.
- You best be believing.
- I won't be deceiving my God.
As a matter of opinion
I think He's tops.
- My opinion is He's the cream of the crop.
- Cream of the crop.
- As a matter of taste.
- To be exact.
- He's my ideal.
- As a matter of fact.
No muscle-bound man
could take my hand
from my God.
My God.
No handsome face
could ever take the place.
- Of my God.
- My God
- My God.
He may not be
a movie star.
- But when it comes to being happy.
- We are.
There's not a man today.
Who could take me away
from my God.
Let's take it home, ladies.
There's not a man today.
Who could take me away
from my God.
Give them some of that
deep-shoulder action.
There's not a man today.
Who could take me away
from my God
I think Sister Mary Patrick
was the best.
- You were wonderful.
- I wasn't very good.
- You were fabulous.
- You were very good too. - Ladies.
- I think...
- Ladies, you were fantastic.
- Sisters, you did good.
- Fantastic. - Oh, I'm so excited.
I can't wait till Sunday
when we sing.
- I'd rather sing than do anything.
- It's better than ice cream.
- It's better than springtime.
- It's better than sex.
- Oh?
- No, no, I-I've heard, you know.
Sisters, you're truly
an inspiration.
And I've asked you here because
I bear remarkable news.
Now try to remain calm.
What I'm about to say is
nothing short of a miracle.
Well, I didn't believe it
myself at first.
Monsignor, for goodness sake,
what is it?
Oh, I'm sorry, Sister. It's just that it's so
momentous, I'm still adjusting to the shock.
The Pope...
the Pope himself...
has heard of our choir
here at St Katherine's.
And when he visits
San Francisco next weekend,
despite his inordinately
busy schedule,
he's requested a special concert
here on Sunday night.
No. No.
Oh, I'm dying. I'm dying.
Oh, Sisters. Oh, Sisters,
this is indeed glorious news.
Oh, Monsignor, we're-we're
both humbled and honoured.
And on such a supremely
solemn occasion,
I do feel a traditional
programme would be best.
You mean "traditional"
like the old way?
We're speaking of His Holiness,
Mary Clarence,
not a neighbourhood block party.
The pontiff commands
the utmost respect and humility.
Your more secular entertainments
would be totally out of place.
But-But, Reverend Mother,
everyone loves our new style.
It's brought people
back to the church.
And that's why he's coming. I mean, because
we're doing something new and different.
Well, I feel this can be
settled by a simple vote.
- A vote?
- Of course, Mary Clarence.
A convent
is not a police state.
I'm... I'm sure the sisters
are more than capable...
of reaching a mature
and dignified consensus.
Right. Now, all those in favour
of performing a programme...
of time-honoured sacred music,
a truly spiritual repertoire,
raise your hands.
All those in favour
of allowing Mary Clarence...
to select a more worldly programme,
however inappropriate,
raise your hands.
The majority has spoken.
Reverend Mother, as always,
you're a true leader...
gracious and understanding.
Oh, it's gonna be wonderful,
Reverend Mother. You'll see.
I'm sure the presentation
will be a great success.
Congratulations,
Mary Clarence.
And congratulations
to you all.
His Holiness. Now,
we've got to get busy.
Come in.
- You sent for me?
- You have a phone call.
From who?
Lieutenant Souther.
Oh.
Hello?
Hey, Deloris. Great news.
I pulled some strings. The judge
agreed to move up their trial.
We'll be in court
in a couple days.
Really? That soon?
Forty-eight hours,
you're a free woman.
Oh, gee, it's great.
Yeah, well, that's...
That's great.
Hey, well, don't thank me
or anything.
No, Rea... No, I...
It is. No, thank you.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
It's... Thank you.
Yeah.
All right. Bye.
Well, seems like your prayers
have been answered.
Uh, I'm gonna be outta here
in a week. I'm leaving.
- You're leaving?
- Yeah.
- That makes two of us.
- What do you mean?
I have submitted my resignation
to Monsignor O'Hara, privately.
I've asked to be relocated
as soon as possible.
But why?
I must go where
I can be of use.
But there's...
There's still so much
to be done here.
Look, if it's about me,
I-I-I'm gonna be gone.
Indeed.
And after how long,
a few weeks?
I have been here for years.
Well, too long, I suppose.
I've become somewhat obsolete.
But you don't have
to continue being obsolete.
Look, everything that's happening here
is-is-is a good thing.
Sister, you can still be
part of it.
A part of what?
You know, Mary Clarence, it is
one thing to rabble rouse,
to sweep into town
and declare a holiday.
You've raised
the sisters' expectations.
You've... You've excited
and confused them.
They imagine this neighbourhood to be some
sort of delightful ongoing bake sale.
Now, you and I know
things are not so simple.
There'll be disappointments
and rude shocks.
And you will have vanished.
How fortunate.
Look, I just got things going.
You are a formidable woman.
You could keep this going.
Could I?
Even if I wanted to, no.
I fear I am a relic.
And I have misplaced
my tambourine.
- Good day, Mary Clarence.
- But, Sister, I...
Good day.
- Don't peek. - How can I peek?
- You can look to the right.
- That's right, don't peek.
- Where can I look?
- You ready?
- You've got my eyes... - Ta-da!
Crazy women.
What have you done?
- What is this?
- It's ice cream.
- I know that, but...
- Well, it's a great big...
cuddly bear hug of a thank-you
from us to you.
- Not thank you to me, thank you to you.
- No, you.
I mean...
When did you do this?
This is a sin.
It's a wicked indulgence.
Didn't they have
any butter pecan?
- I hope Reverend Mother doesn't catch us.
- Yeah, let's keep it down.
Is there any syrup?
Mary Clarence,
this morning in prayers,
I thanked God
for bringing you to us.
Since you've come,
everything has just happened.
Our choir is famous, for one.
We could cut a demo.
I could learn guitar.
Yeah, anything is possible.
God works in mysterious ways.
- That's true.
- You know, uh, anything could happen.
I mean, any one of us could be transferred
out of here at any given time.
Are you leaving us?
No. Come on, no.
What are you talking about? No,
we're always gonna be together.
That's what Diana Ross said.
Oh, well. Listen, that was
a trio. We're a quartet.
- Listen. You know, it's true.
- I know that.
- I believe in things like that.
- Okay...
Just missed him.
Souther just stepped out.
I need his signature
on some things.
Uh, this stuff can't be
processed without him.
Just leave it here, Henry. Uh, I'll
make sure he signs it when he comes in.
Here.
We found her.
Beautiful work.
What's the address?
It's Church Street at 29th
in San Francisco.
Thought you were gone.
Get all the way
to the car, no keys.
Tate said to leave
the money vouchers with him.
He said you'd sign them later.
St Katherine's.
- Here's our leak, boys.
- Come on.
Plug him up!
- Get him outta here.
- Let's go, Tate.
The Pope. Tomorrow.
Oh, my gosh,
I'll be so nervous.
What if I forget the words?
You're gonna go
straight to hell.
- I'm kidding.
- Uh... - I'm kidding. I'm sorry.
Come on, Sisters.
Rehearsal in five minutes.
- Go to rehearsal. I'll be there in a minute.
- Come on. - Right.
Get in.
One, two, three and slide.
Sister, take over now.
One, two, three, together.
Left. Right.
- Oh, come in.
- Where's Deloris?
- Why? Is something wrong?
- They know she's here.
- Girls... - Oh, my goodness.
She's upstairs with the choir.
- Deloris.
- Hi.
Look, Vince knows you're here.
We gotta get out now.
Oh, but I can't go. We're-We're
singing for the Pope tomorrow.
Listen, you're gonna be singing for St Peter
if you don't get your ass outta here now.
But I... Oh...
I-I-I can't do this.
I can't leave.
It's-It's... It's like
I'm deserting them.
Hey, I think
they'll understand.
No, you don't understand.
They need me.
They need you?
A bunch of nuns?
What for? Moral guidance?
What? Make-up tips?
Let me tell you something.
We are talking about the Pope.
This means a great deal to them, and they have
worked very hard for this, and they deserve it.
Where you going?
Where are you going?
I am going to the little
nun's room, nosy.
There you are.
We've been looking for you.
- Shh, shh, shh. - Re-Rehearsal's about to start.
- Okay, okay, okay. Let's go.
- Surprise.
- Guess who?
- Rehearsal's this way, Sisters.
- Hey, Deloris.
- Hi. - Come on.
- All right, all right.
What do they want?
Who are they?
Reno scum. Come on, man!
- Come on, come on! Let's go!
- All right, all right!
Where are we going?
Sister here has got
a special command performance.
Yeah, back
at the Moonlight Lounge.
Look, why don't you just
let her go, you know?
She doesn't have
anything to do with this.
Oh, yeah, yeah, sure. So she can
run right to the cops, huh?
Look, you just go
with the flow, okay?
Relax. You do what
I tell you to do.
- Go!
- Oh! Oh!
- She's gettin' away.
- You don't even have to worry about her, okay?
- You got the one you came for.
- She's right. Let's go.
You all right?
It's okay, I'm a cop.
They've got Sister Mary
Clarence, and they've got guns.
- Where are they taking her?
- Um, they said the Moonlight Lounge.
- Come on, get out of the street.
- Okay.
- You mean they kidnapped her?
- Yes.
Two men, and they had guns.
Why would anyone kidnap a nun?
Were they Catholics?
She isn't a nun.
She's a lounge singer. Her real
name is Deloris Van Cartier.
She witnessed a vicious crime
and has been hiding in our convent.
- She isn't a nun?
- She-She lied to us?
But she was such
a wonderful nun.
Look what she did with the choir.
She made us sing beautifully.
- That should have tipped us. - Well, I don't
care who she is. We can't sing without her.
- She's our inspiration.
- Right.
Reverend Mother, please, I know
that you and Mary Clarence...
didn't always agree,
but we've got to help her.
- Please.
- We've gotta save her.
- We can't leave it up to the Feds.
- No, they'll...
Calm down, calm down.
Mary Robert, think clearly.
Have you any idea
who these two men where?
Yes. They were from Reno, and they're
taking her to the Moonlight Lounge.
Reno? Nevada.
- Mary Emmanuel, tell the Monsignor the situation.
- Yes, Mother.
- The rest of you, follow me.
It's 1,500 for the run to Reno.
That's 500 less
than I normally charge.
But-But we don't have $ 1,500.
Well, then I can't fly you
there. I'm sorry.
Look, I-I'm sorry. I-I-I've got
things I have to check out here.
Father, do not blame this young pilot
for abandoning us in our hour of need.
When he stands before You
on the day of judgement,
do not send him
straight to hell.
Please, please, do not treat him with
the same disregard that he's treated us.
Just because he can't
show charity to nuns,
try not to leave him without
rewards when he asks for them.
We know it is easier to answer
the prayers of a man...
who has answered
the prayers of others,
but if he should
come to You...
- for relief of pain or...
- Such as rheumatoid arthritis,
loss of hair, neck polyps.
Don't leave him bald
and yowling in despair.
Watch over him as he refuses
to watch over us.
And if You cannot, we know that
You will have done Your level best.
- What goes around, comes around.
- Look, Sisters, Sisters...
Hold on a second.
What did you think you were doing,
running to the cops, Deloris?
Hiding out?
Big no-no, babe.
Bet you're sorry now.
I'm sorry
for all my sins, Vince,
and I'm sorry for yours.
I loved you, Deloris.
I gave you everything:
my affection, my time,
a big-time career.
And how do you repay me?
What's the thanks I get?
Where's the loyalty?
You shouldn't have
done that to me, babe.
You'll be judged.
We all will.
I don't get judged.
Vince, she's been acting weird
since we picked her up.
It's like, uh,
she's scared of nothin'.
She's scared.
Tell the boys
how scared you are.
I forgive you, Vince.
Waste her.
It's beautiful.
And what a lovely name: Reno.
And Gomorrah.
No, she was this doll. She used to wear
this basket of fruit on her head and go...
Excuse me, Vince.
- Yeah?
- We didn't do it.
- It's done?
- Uh, not totally.
- What's the problem?
- Well, Vince, we can't waste a nun.
What are you nuts
talking about?
It's Deloris,
in a costume.
Well, Vince, now how do you know
she didn't join up...
and become a real nun
when she was there?
Things like this happen.
Because I know this woman,
in the biblical sense,
and she ain't no nun.
Now I don't want
to hear any more of this.
Go in there and do it.
Just don't come back
till it's over.
- Okay.
- It's done.
Okay, we go
one, two, three, shoot.
Wait. We don't go
one, two and shoot on three?
Get over there.
One, two, three.
- You didn't shoot.
- Neither did you.
I figured if, uh, you did,
I wouldn't have to.
That's what I figured.
Sisters, come on!
Deloris, we got it
all worked out.
- Hmm.
- Strip.
What?
Come on, come on.
Take off the, uh, nun thing.
Yeah, yeah.
The nun thing.
What is she doing?
Oh, my God.
She's praying.
Lord, I want you to forgive
Willy and Joey...
because they know not
what they do.
They're only doing what
Vince told them to do...
because Vince is too chicken
to do it himself.
So he's called upon these two men
to take care of his business.
So I want you
to forgive them, Lord.
Espectum, espertum,
cacoomb, tutu, eplubium.
- Amen.
Ooh.
Hey! Get out of my way!
- Hey!
- Ow!
You all right?
- Go-Go find Vince.
- Right.
Wait, wait, wait!
Oh, my goodness!
There it is!
The Moonlight Lounge! That's it!
Brace yourself, Sisters.
Just spread out
and look for Mary Clarence.
- Now, j... Try to blend in.
- Done.
- Over here.
- Come with me, guys.
Over this way.
Hi. Excuse me.
Sorry.
Has anyone seen a nun?
A Carmelite nun?
- No? Sure? Okay, thanks.
- Wait. No, no, no, no, no.
She's not really a nun.
See, she's just posing as a nun.
It came as a great
shock to us.
Excuse me. Excuse me.
I'm sorry. Excuse me. Excuse me.
- Place your bets.
- Red 23.
- You're sure? - Mm-hmm.
- How do you know?
- Red 23.
- Well, us too. - Here.
- Works for me. - I'm on it.
- I'm in. I'm in. - All of it.
Red 14.
I was just trying
to teach you all a lesson.
Oh! Excuse me!
Place your bets.
Ah!
Sister Mary Ignatius!
Follow me.
Block off the street, but don't
move in until I tell you.
Okay.
Nine! Pay the field. Nine.
Pay the field.
- Add the point...
- Come on. Stay with the others.
- What are you doing here?
- Well, we're saving you. Move!
- Move! - Mary Clarence, you're safe.
- What in the...
Come on! Move! Move!
- Break! Now! Break!
- Oh. - Hey, nuns.
- Joey!
- Vinny, Vinny, there's a thousand nuns here!
What do we do?
You go to the right.
You go to the left.
- I'm gonna go down the middle.
- All right.
Place your bets.
Five black. Five.
Hey, babe.
Yes, sweetheart?
No more bets. No more bets.
Fifteen black.
- Seal off the exits and get ready to move in.
- Roger.
There's another way out.
Let's go. Come.
Excuse us.
Come on. Out.
- Move in now.
- Yes, sir.
- Hey, uh, I can't see a thing.
- Willy, hit the lights.
Freeze!
Everybody!
Joey.
- Wh-Wh-Where is she?
- I'm right here.
I'm here.
Leave them alone. They don't
have anything to do with it.
Just... I'm here.
Calm down.
Joey, do it.
I can't, Vince.
She's still a nun.
She's a broad.
You got it?
Just a broad.
I guarantee you
she is no broad.
She is Sister Mary Clarence
of St Katherine's Convent.
She's a model of generosity,
virtue and love.
You have my word for it,
gentlemen. She is a nun.
You hear that?
Now, aren't you glad
we didn't shoot her?
- Don't shoot! - Drop it.
- Okay, okay, okay. - Right there! Let's go!
- The gun's down, the gun's down. -Drop
your weapon! -All right, drop it! -Okay.
- Lay it down right there!
- You all right? - Turn around.
You okay? Oh, God.
- I'm shot! Watch the arm!
- Are you okay?
- Take it easy on me.
- Come on. - Sorry.
- Things got kind of out of hand.
- Oh, just "kind of out of hand"?
Boy, am I glad you're a much better
shot than you are a protector.
But thank you.
- All right, come on.
- I was good to you!
- All right.
- We had a great thing! You sang in the hotel!
- Come on.
- Badly!
- In there.
- How could you betray me like this?
- You are nothing! - Get him out of here.
- Right, Lieutenant.
- I got two words for you, Vince.
- Mary Clarence.
Bless you.
- Just go.
- Come on.
- Oh! Hey!
- We got another...
I hold you responsible
for all of this.
For introducing a lounge act
into my convent.
For utterly disrupting our lives...
and exposing us all
to mortal danger.
Thank you.
No, no, thank you.
Thank you all.
I'm really
gonna miss you guys.
We thought you were
a nun, Deloris.
- Yeah.
- Van Cartier.
Sisters, we have
a concert to do.
I thought you were leaving.
We can't both of us leave.
I will follow Him
follow Him wherever.
He may go.
And near Him
I always will be
or nothing
can keep me away.
He is my destiny
I will follow Him.
Ever since
He touched my heart
I knew.
There isn't an ocean too deep.
A mountain so high
it can keep.
Keep me away.
Away from.
His.
Love
I love Him, I love Him
I love Him.
And where He goes I'll follow
I'll follow, I'll follow
I will follow Him
follow Him
wherever He may go.
There isn't an ocean too deep.
A mountain so high
it can keep.
Keep me away.
- We will follow Him.
- follow Him
follow Him wherever
He may go.
- There isn't an ocean too deep.
- Too deep.
A mountain so high
it can keep.
Keep us away.
Away from His love.
- Oh, oh, yeah.
- I love Him.
Oh, yes, I love Him.
- I'll follow.
- I'm gonna follow.
- True love.
- He'll always be my true love
- Forever.
- from now until forever.
- I love Him, I love Him, I love Him.
- Oh, yes, I love Him.
And where He goes I'll follow,
I'll follow, I'll follow.
- I'll follow, yeah.
- He'll always be my true love - Oh, yeah.
- There isn't an ocean too deep.
- An ocean.
A mountain so high
it can keep.
- Nothing can keep me away.
- Keep us away.
Away from His love.
- You know, you make me wanna.
- Shout.
- Kick my heels up and.
- Throw my hands up and.
- Shout.
- Throw my head back and.
- Shout - Come on, now.
Don't forget to say you will.
Don't forget to say.
- Say you will.
- Say it right now, baby.
Say you will.
- Say that you love me.
- Say - Say that you need me.
- Say.
- Say that you want me.
- You want to please me.
- Come on, now.
- Say - Come on, now.
- Say.
- Come on, now - Say
I still remember.
When I used to be
nine years old.
Hey, yeah, and I was
a fool for you
from the bottom of my soul
Yeah, yeah.
And now that I found you
I will never let you go
No, no.
And if you ever leave me.
You know it's gonna hurt me so.
- I want you to know.
- I wanna know.
- I said, I want you to know right now.
You been good to me, Sisters.
Much better than
I been to myself.
So good, so good
And if you ever leave me.
- I want nobody else.
- Nobody else.
- I said, I want you to know.
- I wanna know
I said, I want you
to know right now.
- You know, you make me wanna.
- Shout.
- Kick my heels up and.
- Throw my hands up and.
- Shout.
- Throw my head back and.
- Come on, now.
- Shout.
Come on, now
Play it, Sister Alma, yeah.
- A little bit softer now.
- Shout.
- Very quiet, girls.
- Little bit softer.
- Shout.
- A little bit louder now.
- Higher.
- Shout.
- All right now, come on, basses.
- Higher
I want you to do it.
Come on, now.
Come on, girls, yes.
Hey, here I come.
Shout, shout, shout
You make me wanna.
Hey, girls.
- You know, you make me wanna.
- Shout - Sing it, Mary Robert.
- Kick my heels up and.
- Shout.
- Throw my hands up and.
- Throw my head back and.
- Shout.
- Come on, now.
- Don't forget to say you will.
- Come on, come on.
- Don't forget to say.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
- Yeah.
- Say you will.
- Say it back now, baby.
- Come on, come on.
- Say you will.
- Say that you will.
Say you will.
Now, wait a minute.
- Who was that.
- You know, you make me wanna shout