Moonyeen, Moonyeen.
If only I could be with you.
If only I knew the way to you.
John, John..
My dearest one.
I'm always with you.
I'm here whenever you need me.
Why must I go
through this any longer?
Be patient, dear heart.
Someday, we'll be
together again.
These years have really
only been but a few moments.
And the years we must still
wait will be just as short.
Try to hear me, darling.
Sometimes you do.
Moonyeen, Moonyeen.
'Sir John, Sir John.'
I might have known
you were here.
Confound you, Ellen.
You frighten everybody away.
Now, look here, Sir John.
I've told you time and again
no good will come of you
wanting to talk with her
who's gone these 30 years.
No good?
It's the only thing
that keeps me alive.
'Uh, hello, come in.'
Beg pardon, Sir John.
Dr. Owen.
- Hello, John.
- Owen.
- Well..
- So, you're back.
Well,
that's the general impression.
Well, well,
how do you find Ireland?
Oh, great fishing,
best in years.
Oh, I missed you, John.
You should have come. Change
would have done you good.
- I don't need no change.
- That's where you're wrong.
- What?
- Well..
You know what people
are beginning to say, hmm?
Mmm, I know. They think
I'm a bit touched, eh?
Well, it's this confounded
living in the past
and trying to conjure up
ghosts, you know.
It's not doing you any good.
Still we won't talk
about that now.
That's where
you are wrong, Owen.
In the first place, I shall live
the kind of life I want to live.
Of course, John.
Heaven knows
I'm not interfering.
- I know better than that.
- And now, will you listen?
And in the second place,
I get a great deal of comfort
out of what you call
conjuring up ghosts.
You see, I happen to believe
that there are times
when Moonyeen
is very close to me.
And I shall continue
to believe so.
Whatever people may think
or say.
John, old fellow, I said
let's not talk about it.
- Mind if I take a pew, hmm?
- Sorry, sit down, sit down.
- Have a drink?
- Of course, I'll have a drink.
'Good.'
Ah, well, here we are.
- John.
- 'Mm-hmm.'
Moonyeen's sister is dead.
No.
She and her husband
were drowned a few days ago.
A squall struck
their boat off Dublin Bay.
- That's horrible.
- Yes.
And that little mite
of theirs is left
practically unprovided for.
Yes, yes, I remember.
There was a child.
Yes, a little girl.
She's a,
she's a lovable little tot.
They're, uh, they're talking of
putting her into an orphanage.
- What? Impossible.
- That's what I thought.
- Yeah.
- So, you see, I..
Now, John.
Uh, don't bite my head off but..
What would you say
to having her here?
- Here? A child in this house?
- Yeah.
Oh, don't be ridiculous.
No, count on me for any amount...
A child is what's
needed in this house.
Give you something to think
about besides yourself.
- Out of the question.
- But, John, if you...
- No, no, no, no, no.
- You see what I...
Owen, please, let's..
Let's drop the subject
if you don't mind.
John, I don't think
I realize until tonight
how much these years
have changed you.
- Oh!
- Your grief's become a habit.
You've grown selfish, morbid.
You'll be good enough not
to interfere in my affairs.
You've huddled in your burrow so
long, you've grown to hate life.
- I shall do as I...
- Goodnight.
Goodnight.
I'll do as I please.
Huh, ridiculous nonsense.
I'll manage my own life.
Nobody's gonna dictate me.
Found..
What the..
Well, what do you want?
Here, now come here,
come here, come..
- I don't think I like you.
- Well..
Oh, indeed.
I resent that.
- Why not?
- You're so grumpy.
I shall tell my daddy.
Oh!
Oh, I'm sorry.
I apologize.
I had no intention of being
disrespectful, I assure you.
Well, uh,
won't-won't you shake hands?
We haven't been introduced.
No, we haven't, have we?
Well, wh-what's your name?
Kathleen. What's yours?
Mine is John.
How do you do?
- How do you do?
- How old are you, Kathleen?
I'm five in June.
How old are you?
Me? Well, I, uh,
I'm a little older than that.
Well..
Hey, v-very pretty.
This is a new frock.
Very becoming.
And I've got on my best panties
with a little tuck.
Yes, uh, charming,
charming, uh, uh..
W-won't you sit down, Kathleen?
Would you, uh..
Would you like-like to see
some pretty pictures?
No. No, thank you.
You wouldn't, eh?
Must have had a rough crossing?
- Yes, thank you.
- Hmm.
I, uh..
Uh, would you care for some...
milk or something?
No. No, thank you.
Uh, would you, uh,
by any chance, uh..
like to make your home
with me?
- No. No, thank you.
- Why not?
- Don't you like me?
- No. No, thank you.
Oh!
I-I think I better be going now.
Well, w-won't you say goodbye?
Goodbye.
Uh..
'Mr. Toastmaster,
ladies and gentlemen'
'and Miss Sheridan.'
It is my pleasure
and my privilege
on this auspicious occasion..
- Hear, hear.
- I thank you.
to offer my felicitations
to as charming a lady
as ever graced
a bachelor's board.
- Hear, hear.
- 'Hooray!'
Hooray! Hooray!
I thank you,
I thank you, thank you.
Now, now to blow out
the candles.
Remember, you don't get
your wish
unless you blow 'em
all out at once.
Now, when I say three,
Kathleen blows.
'Ready, one, two..'
'...three.'
How's that for blowing?
'Nothing wrong
with those lungs.'
Anything else you want me
to blow out around here?
- Now, well, what's the wish?
- Yes, what is it? Come on...
Now, please,
gentlemen, don't rush me.
I wish that
you weren't so generous.
You leave me
nothing to wish for.
And what's more, you're the
nicest person in the world.
And I love you tremendously.
There, that was rather sweet
of me, wasn't it?
Yes, I think so.
Even allowing
for little exaggeration.
Why do you look at me like that?
Strange.
Every year,
you grow more like her.
- It's almost uncanny.
- Moonyeen Clare?
- Hmm.
- Oh, but she was beautiful.
Yes, she was beautiful
and charming.
You are very like her, my dear.
Thanks, darling.
There, now look at that.
You made me all weepy.
I knew it, I knew it.
I've that
confounded thimble again.
Ah-ha, the ring.
Good Lord, a wedding.
- Willie Ainley.
- Oh, help.
- 'Willie's not a bad fella.'
- Willie is a dear.
"I say, you know, Kathleen,
I'm frightfully gone on you.
I'm not a bad sort of chap.
I'm steady, I'm reliable."
Oh, come, you mustn't
make fun of Willie.
'"Oh, you could always rely
on my being'
'just as I am now.
I should never change."'
'Look here, old girl. I can't
talk the romantic stuff.'
'But I think
you are simply ripping.'
I am dripping, Willie.
No, but look here, Kathleen,
I've simply got to talk to you.
It's my last chance. You know
I'm going to camp tomorrow.
Whatever induced you to drag me
miles from home in a storm.
But the paper said fine
and it wasn't raining
when we started.
Well, what are you going to do?
I can't think.
There hasn't been a soul inside
this house in nearly 50 years.
There will be two of us
inside within 50 seconds.
Oh, my.
Isn't that a candle?
Wait a jiffy.
Willie, do you mean
to say that nobody's been
in this house for 50 years?
'Uh-huh.'
You know, Willie, there's
some sort of mystery here.
People don't go away
and leave a house like this.
'Why didn't the maid
tidy things up?'
'Put that chair on its legs,
the nighties of the furniture?'
'Well, why worry about it?'
'People were afraid
to come into this room.'
Something had happened here,
something..
Something strange and terrible.
You have got
an uncomfortable mind.
They locked the doors
and went away for ever.
As though there were a curse
on the house.
I say, you know,
you're giving me the creeps.
- Willie!
- Oh, good heavens.
- What is it now?
- A wedding invitation.
"Mr. and Mrs. Richard Clare
of Castle Clare, Wicklow
"request the pleasure of
the company of Jeremy Wayne... "
"Jeremy Wayne, on the occasion
of the marriage
of their daughter, Moonyeen
with Sir John Carteret."
By Jove, Sir John.
Moonyeen Clare,
my mother's sister.
But they never were married.
She died that year.
It was the tragedy
of Uncle John's life.
Strange.
Do you suppose it could be
linked in some way
with this house?
With this man?
- Beats me.
- Look at this.
When Jeremy Wayne got it,
he crushed it in his hand
and threw it away.
Why would he do that?
Probably he was blotto.
He's emptied half the decanter.
Don't be an ass, Willie.
It's as clear as day.
'Jeremy Wayne.
He loved her too.'
I know what happened
in this room.
- He killed himself.
- What?
That's why they closed the doors
and left things as they were.
He couldn't face life
without her.
They found him here.
'Just a log.'
Don't you think perhaps
we'd better get out of here?
Shh. A carriage.
Do you suppose
it's a real carriage?
Shh.
- How do you do?
How do you do?
- Uh, ghastly weather, isn't it?
- Ghastly.
- Yeah, ghastly.
You were caught
in the storm, I suppose.
Yes. Yes.
Yes.
Pardon me if I'm inquisitive
but are you, uh,
are you stopping here?
Oh, dear, no.
No, I-it was raining
very heavily.
We were standing under a tree
and the lightning hit
the next tree and, uh,
a-and killed two cows.
Cows? What cows?
Yes, two cows.
No, three.
Yeah, I saw the bodies.
Oh, so then we broke in
to get out of the storm.
Yeah, we were, we were all wet.
Oh, yeah?
I wish the place
were more comfortable for you.
Oh, I am glad
you were able to make the fire.
Yeah, uh, thank you,
thank you, I can do that.
Oh, thank you.
Oh, I'm afraid
you've got a cold.
Yeah, I wish I could
offer you something warm.
Excuse me. You mind
if I take this for a moment?
- Well, really...
- I, uh, I shan't be long.
- Who on earth is he?
- I've a pretty good idea.
- Well..
- Watch him.
Did you see the way
he looked at that silver?
Oh, don't be silly.
- 'Oh, boy.'
- Shh!
Got something under his arm.
The very thing for you.
Old port.
Look.
- 1847.
- 47?
That's the best I could find.
A-any old port in the storm.
Perhaps, we should introduce
ourselves.
- My name's Ainley.
- Oh, I'm pleased to meet you.
Well, you surely don't
intend to open that.
- Do you?
- I'm going to do my best.
But, uh, really, you know,
it isn't your property.
That's a nice point,
but I'll take it up later.
Do you realize
that stuff's worth
three or four pounds a bottle?
Ah, it ought to be pretty good.
Well, are you going to sit there
and be a p-party to this?
- I thought of doing just that.
- There we are.
Oh, you mind?
- Thank you.
- Not at all, not at all.
Oh, just a very little.
That's enough. When!
Fellow criminal.
- Won't you join us?
- Certainly not.
Oh!
How, uh, how about a toast?
- I know one.
- Yeah?
Here's to your health,
your honor
and the health of all your
descendants, great and small.
That's a mighty handsome toast.
It's an Irish toast,
the best I know.
Now, you keep as young
and as pretty as you are
until doomsday.
And never forget the man
who wished it.
I wonder now as I look at you,
have we never met before?
No, I guess we haven't.
I shouldn't have forgotten.
Could you be Irish too?
Yeah, I could
if I saw enough of you.
Well, if you're not Irish,
you're American.
- How do you know that?
- Oh!
- By the way you said ghastly.
- Now, how should I say it?
Well, if you mean
how do I say it, ghastly.
- Ghastly.
- No, just ghastly.
- Ghastly? No?
- No, no, like this.
- No?
- No.
Afraid not.
Oh, never mind.
We, we won't worry about it.
Ridiculous.
Mm, what I've been missing
all these years
not ever drinking uncle's port.
Mm-hmm.
I think you're making
a mistake, Willie.
I don't think I am.
Oh, uh, sit down, old boy.
Sit down, please.
Tell me, what are you
doing in England?
- I came over to join up.
- But it's not your war.
Well, I'm half English,
and a scrap's a scrap.
I like that.
Do you know
this is scandalous of us?
- But I don't think he'd mind.
- Who?
Why, the owner, Jeremy Wayne.
- Isn't he a romantic figure?
- Yeah, grand.
I love that devil-take-you look.
Do you know
you don't look unlike..
- That's my father.
- Your father?
'Cause I'm Kenneth Wayne.
Well, this is romance.
You're telling me..
- Why, hello.
- Hello, Mr. Wayne.
- Isn't this nice?
- Eh, great, great.
Gosh, I-I just happened
to be taking a bicycle ride
around the country.
All alone?
How too bad.
'Oh, yeah, just all alone,
you know.'
Oh, you see, I always take
an extra bicycle with me
in case anything happens.
Why, of course,
how stupid of me.
Yeah, I might possibly
run into some man who, uh
wants to take a ride with me.
Or some lady?
You, uh, you know any ladies
who like to ride bicycles?
I couldn't possibly interest
you in a horse, could I?
Oh, I have lots of them
in my stable.
- Oh, is this where you live?
- Mm-hmm.
Oh, what a coincidence
that I should just happen
to be sitting on your wall.
A charming coincidence.
Gee, it's a shame
that you live there, you know?
I mean you, uh,
you seem so human.
I hope you're not going
to run away from me
because of where I live.
I thought you Americans
were democratic.
Well, it's sort
of a shock to, uh
find out that Cinderella
is really a princess.
But I turn back into a pumpkin
at midnight.
Well, I wasn't sure
that it was your house.
I mean when I saw you in it,
I, uh, still had hopes
that you might just
have been visiting.
In it?
When did you see me in it?
Oh, last night.
You watched me
from the outside last night?
Well, just till you went to bed.
I-I mean,
till you went upstairs.
Well, I'll be darned.
A window peeper.
Oh, no, I wasn't peeping.
No, I was just looking.
See, there's not much to do
around here nights and, uh
I sort of wanted to see
where you live, you know?
- Oh!
- Oh, well, anyway.
I might have known
it wouldn't work out.
So you wanted to see
where I live, mm?
- Yeah.
- What do you mean not work out?
Well, a princess wouldn't
wanna go bicycle riding.
No?
But Cinderella might.
H-here, wait, let, wait,
let me help you.
I haven't ridden in years.
Here, oh!
Window peeper.
- Some more tea?
- Mm-mm.
It's mighty good tea.
- Not as good as I can make.
- No?
- I make very good coffee too.
- Mm. Can you sew on buttons?
Mm-hmm. Darn socks and I-I'm
very nice with children.
You know, you-you'll make
somebody a good wife.
Thank you, sir.
That I will, sir.
- Uh..
- What?
Oh, I suppose I'll have to go
home and get dressed for dinner.
Oh, no, not yet.
Well, we-we've just come here.
We've been here for three hours.
- Oh, no.
- It has been fun, hasn't it?
Oh, it's been swell.
I never knew that
bicycling could be so enjoyable.
Oh, yes, there's nothing
like a good bicycle.
You know, it's a little
like that old song
"A Bicycle Built For Two."
- I don't know it.
- Well, neither do I.
I mean,
it's-it's sort of a song.
I see, about-about
a bicycle built for two?
Yes. Yeah.
Gee, you're a great girl.
Well, uh,
have some more tea, hm?
What's doing that?
France.
- Guns.
- Mm-hmm.
Gee!
Alright, alright,
alright, don't get impatient.
I'll be over there in a month.
- A month?
- Mm.
Oh!
Is there anything else
I can get you?
Oh, no, thank you. Thank you,
Mrs. Crouch. It was lovely.
- A month.
- Well, just about. Mm-hmm.
Oh, Mrs. Crouch, uh,
I'm afraid we're going
to have to stay for dinner.
- Dinner, sir?
- Mm-hmm.
Oh, I don't serve dinner, sir.
Oh, well, it, uh, it, uh
looks too much like rain
to risk going out.
You see, Miss Sheridan here
had an aunt who-who caught cold
in a rainstorm once
and-and almost died.
- Oh, that's too bad.
- Mm-hmm.
But it isn't going to rain, sir.
Oh, but you can never can tell.
Please, Mrs. Crouch,
just something easy.
Or we can cook it ourselves.
Just some chops
and maybe a steak.
Have you, have you got any ale?
And how about
a little salad, huh?
I don't know.
'Cause I think love is..
Do you know what love is?
What?
Well, of course, there's..
There's different kinds of love.
I know but...
we were talking about..
real love.
Yeah.
Real love..
lasts forever.
- Yes, I know but...
- There are no buts.
'I know what I'm talking about.'
'Love is..'
'Love is something you feel.
It just happens.'
'You can't do anything
about it.'
'If I love somebody...
I'd love him forever.'
To Major Owen, RAMC.
Well, I never saw the child
drink port before.
- In your honor, sir.
- Oh, thank you, my dear.
A soldier, a gentleman,
but a miserable chess player.
Absolutely untrue,
isn't it, Kathy?
- What vintage is this?
- Huh?
Uh, Coburn's '96,
if it really interests you.
'96, hmm, not bad for new wine.
- Pardon?
- Not bad, eh?
Oh, listen to the girl.
Coburn's '96, not bad.
I don't mean it's not good but
it doesn't compare with the '47.
Hmm, '47?
What do you know about the '47?
Well, I had a glass of it
the other day.
- Oh, you did, eh?
- Mm-hmm.
- Who gave it to you?
- A man I met with Willie.
- Aha! What man?
- Yes, come on, Kathleen.
I'd like to know a man
with a bit of '47.
Could we meet him?
- Oh, yes, I suppose so.
- Come on, out with it.
Well, Willie and I
went into an old house
to get out of the storm
the other day.
- Whose house?
- Um, just a big, empty house.
Oh! I smell a story in this.
Well, there's no sense
of making a mystery of it.
- It was the old Wayne house.
- Wayne house.
You know that old, deserted
house back of the maid's
new road. Not a soul
been in it for 50 years.
And then quite unexpectedly,
in walks the owner from America.
What?
He's back. Jeremy Wayne.
Oh, no, Uncle John.
Not Jeremy Wayne.
Jeremy Wayne is dead.
This is his son.
He came to join up.
Dead?
- Uncle John!
- 'John! John!'
Owen, what is it?
What did this Jeremy Wayne do?
- I can't tell you.
- But in heaven's name, I...
That's his wish, Kathleen.
You must forget it.
Forget it? How can I, Owen?
You must tell me.
- No, I can't.
- Then I must ask him.
Oh, no.
You must not, please.
You don't know
how it would hurt him.
- I know...
- Oh, don't insist, my dear.
It's better so.
Believe me.
Won't you come in, dear?
I'm sorry I said
anything that hurt you.
Kathleen, this young man,
this Wayne.
He's in the army, you say?
Yes, he's in Camp
It's just half an hour
from here.
Oh, but let's not talk
about him, dear.
I should prefer that
you don't ever see him again.
Uncle John?
Why mustn't I see him again?
He's really awfully nice.
I think you'd like him. We've
become rather good friends.
- Friends?
- Yes, and I'm sure...
Be silent!
You sicken me.
When did you meet this man?
- A week ago, almost.
- Have you seen him since?
- Yes.
- 'How often?'
- Why, quite often.
- Kathleen?
You must promise me
never to see him again.
I can't promise.
I want to see him.
- Why shouldn't I?
- Are you in love with him?
Are you? Answer me?
I don't know, I..
If I am in love with him..
I don't know,
he's not in love with me anyway.
At least,
we've never said anything.
I only know I can't bear the
thought of not seeing him again.
I'm sorry, Uncle John,
I can't help it, I..
I just can't.
Listen, my child.
I'm going to tell you something
you should have known long ago.
It's been my fault, I suppose.
But I hoped
I never would have to tell you.
I hoped I never would have
to live it all over again.
It's almost 50 years ago.
I can see it
as if it were yesterday.
This garden, a June night..
the same scent
of roses on the air.
Excitement.
People coming and going.
Little lanterns among the trees.
And from the ballroom,
the sound of an orchestra.
It was the night
before our wedding.
I remember it so well.
The house was filled
with people.
- Sweetheart.
- Oh, ho ho.
- This is our dance, isn't it?
- Is it? I forgot.
Of course, it is. Come on.
Oh, where on earth
have you been?
Yes, what kind of a best friend
are you, eh?
Uh, John,
you don't deserve this.
I'm sorry, old man,
but you don't.
I know it, I know it,
but it's too late now.
- Crazy! Absolutely crazy!
- Well...
Hasn't said a sensible thing
all evening, Owen.
Can we blame him, hmm?
To tell you the truth, I'm not
making much sense myself.
I've never been so happy.
- You had a drink yet, Owen?
- Oh, yes.
I stopped for a quick one
at the Georgian Dragon.
- Oh, you did, eh?
- Well, no, no more, John.
- Go on.
- Oh, no, well..
Oh, by the way, uh,
Jeremy Wayne was there.
Oh, why didn't you bring him
along?
Well, he was
in pretty bad shape, John.
Drinking more
than was good for him.
Yeah, he takes it pretty hard,
doesn't he?
Poor devil.
Well, I can't say
I blame him either.
You know, Wayne's a wild
sort of fellow, John.
I'm a bit worried about him.
He was making vague sort
of threats against you.
Yeah, you know what that is?
That's-that's that
Georgian Dragon brandy.
Pretty dangerous stuff.
Do you remember the night when
you wanted to marry the barmaid?
After just two glasses of it.
Oh, we have had some
good times, haven't we?
Haven't we? Oh, my God.
And don't you think
they-they're gonna end
either, you blithering idiot.
Not, but, um, seriously, John...
Now, drink it.
Go on, drink it.
Alright.
I want to get back to Moonyeen.
I can't bear to let
that girl out of my sight
for more than a minute or two.
Ssh! Listen!
* There's a little brown road
winding over the hill *
Uh, j-just look at that now.
* To a little white cot
by the sea *
* There's a little green gate *
* At whose turnings I wait *
* While two eyes of blue *
* Come smiling through *
* At me *
* There's a gray lock or two *
* In the brown of her hair *
* There's some silver
in mine too *
* I see *
* But in all *
* The long years *
* When the clouds
brought their tears *
* Those two eyes of blue *
* Kept smiling through *
* At me **
I promised him I'd tell you
he was here, Miss Moonyeen.
But I wouldn't see him, miss.
Not if I was you.
Quite right, Mary,
you go back into the house.
But I don't think
he's quite himself, miss.
- I'll tell Sir John.
- No, no, Mary. You mustn't.
Oh, Jerry, I knew
you couldn't let me get married
without coming to wish me joy.
What's the matter, Jerry?
What is it?
- You know what it is.
- Come in, we're expecting you.
- Oh, no, you're not.
- Please, Jerry.
Don't act like this
on the night before my wedding.
You don't need to remind me
what night it is.
Jerry, dear,
we're not going to go
all over that again, are we?
As though
I weren't tortured enough.
you weren't driving me mad.
That's not quite fair, is it?
You look so beautiful
in that dress.
Thanks, Jerry.
I had an awful time
getting it to fit.
I was so afraid it was going
to be an utter failure.
Oh, Moonyeen, Moonyeen.
Oh, Jerry.
Please, don't.
Haven't you any pity
for a man in hell?
Oh, Jerry, dear,
you mustn't. Get up.
You're not going to marry him.
All my life, I've loved you.
Jerry, it isn't easy for me
either to have you say
things like this.
I'm so fond of you.
It was understood between our
families that we were to marry.
It was understood by everyone.
Yes, but, Jerry,
this needn't mean the end
of our friendship.
Nothing should end that.
After all, girlhood and boyhood
sweethearts don't always marry.
Hmm, girlhood and boyhood
sweethearts.
You were such
a cunning, little boy.
And you were such
a beautiful, little girl.
Now, we mustn't ever
let anything spoil that.
Don't you see what I mean, dear?
Tomorrow you'll be in his arms.
This man you're marrying
what right has he
to take you from me?
Why is he better than I?
What is there in me
that's wrong?
Nothing, Jerry, nothing.
Is it because I drink?
I drink because I'm unhappy.
And I'm unhappy because of you.
This other man, he has
no faults, he's perfect.
But I tell you,
he shall not have you.
The man doesn't live
who can take you from me.
The man will not live
who takes you from me...
Jerry!
I'm marrying John tomorrow.
I'm marrying him
because I love him.
I loved him
from the moment I saw him.
I shall always love him,
because he stands for everything
that's beautiful,
and fine, and true.
And even if he didn't,
I should still love him.
Mmm!
Moonyeen.
Ah, good evening, madam.
If you're not busy
tomorrow afternoon
how do you like to marry me?
What's the matter, dear?
Is something wrong?
- No, nothing.
- Something I've done?
Something I've said? 'Cause
if it is, I-I didn't mean it.
No, John, dear.
Hold me close.
- Anything about the wedding?
- No.
You're not unhappy, are you?
How could I possibly
be unhappy tonight?
- You're a funny little thing.
- Am I?
- 'Moonyeen!'
- 'John!'
'Where are they?'
Shh! Don't let's answer them.
Well..
You know sometimes,
I-I get a little scared.
How on earth did we two
ever happen to get together?
I know, to think
that out of all the millions
of people in the world.
Can you imagine what fun
it's going to be in this house?
- Oh, darling.
- Just you and I.
Everything's fun.
I'm so excited
about going to Paris.
- Are you, dear?
- Mm-hmm.
You know I know a marvelous
restaurant in the Rue Vavin.
- You do?
- Yes, you wait.
Oh, God, what's the use
of going to Paris?
Hmm, what's the use
of doing anything?
Except sitting here
the rest of our lives.
Except the food's
awfully good in Paris.
It's gonna be
a beautiful honeymoon..
spent in a restaurant.
Mm, darling.
- Like my ring?
- It's a beauty, isn't it?
Belonged to
my great-great-grandmother.
- Really?
- Mm-hm.
I say, let's practice, shall we?
With this ring, I thee wed.
This was pretty good,
wasn't it, huh?
Alright, maybe I better practice
dropping it once or twice, huh?
Look, there-there's really
nothing to this getting married.
You see how easy it is?
I-I can do it with my eyes shut.
With this ring...
I thee wed.
- You know, this is fun.
- What on earth are you doing?
It's fun opening
my eyes and seeing you.
Wouldn't it be marvelous
if every time I open my eyes
for the rest of my life,
you-you were there?
I will be.
And always as beautiful
as you are tonight.
Well, after I get the ring on,
what happens next?
- Mm?
- You kiss me.
Oh! That-that's going
to be very difficult.
- Hello, dearest.
- Hello, my sweet.
Tonight is the last time
we ever have to say goodbye.
- Isn't it?
- Yes.
Never any more partings.
- No more separate plans?
- No.
No different thoughts.
Just we two...
made one.
- Forever.
- And forever.
Amen.
- 'Moonyeen.'
- 'John.'
'Moonyeen!
Where the heck is she?'
Will thou have this man
to thy wedded husband
to live together
after God's ordinance
in the holy estate of matrimony?
Will thou obey him and serve him
love, honor and keep him
in sickness and in health
and forsaking all other,
keep thee only unto him
'so long as
you both shall live?'
I will.
- Wayne!
- Jerry!
- 'At my wedding.'
- There will be no wedding.
Be silent, sir.
Are you mad, Wayne?
Get out of here!
You took her away from me.
But, by heaven,
you'll never have her.
No, Jerry, no!
After him!
He went this way.
Come on. Go on.
Catch him fast.
He's probably around the lake.
Come on.
Moonyeen.
But surely you can do something?
You must do something.
- John?
- Yes, dear.
It hurts. Make it stop.
Are you alright?
Yes, dear, of course.
Am I?
Is it..
It's nothing, darling.
Owen will help you.
John..
Darling..
Wear..
the ring.
Dear?
Dear, don't be sad.
Our love could never die.
- John, where are you?
- I'm here, my love.
Darling...
don't leave me.
Don't leave me.
John..
isn't it a pity?
For me too, it was the end.
She lay white and still
in my arms.
She was dead.
All that I lived for was gone.
It was the end.
I came back alone to this house.
All gay with flowers for her.
I sat alone where I sit now
the whole night through.
Poor darling.
I've sat here many times since.
Whenever I'm in trouble
or sorrow, I come here.
For it's here
that she returns to me.
Year after year, she has come.
Always when I needed her
she was beside me,
she was here in this garden.
I know, dear, I understand.
Kathleen, tonight you told me
that Jeremy Wayne was dead.
- I'm sorry I didn't kill him.
- Uncle John.
After the police
had given up the search
I tracked him for years through
half the ports of South America.
For years, I hunted him
in my dreams.
I killed him in my dreams.
Now, he is dead.
And his son..
His son!
But Kenneth
never knew his father.
He was a baby when he died.
But, Kathleen, listen..
you must promise me
to have nothing more
to do with the son of that man.
You mean, it's..
- It's never.
- Never.
Kathleen?
Yeah, I promise.
- Uh, good evening.
- Good evening.
- Is, uh, Miss Sheridan home?
- No, sir, she's out.
You told her I called Wednesday?
- Oh, yes, sir.
- And, uh, and Friday?
She was sorry to miss you, sir.
Oh, is she?
Well, uh, I guess I'll wait.
- But really, sir...
- I'll-I'll wait.
He won't go.
What's the matter
with you, Ellen?
I didn't want
to interrupt you, sir.
- It's for Miss Kathleen, sir.
- Oh, uh..
It's the man from the canteen,
miss. He's here again.
Man from the canteen?
What's he doing here
at this hour of the night?
I better go and see
what he wants, dear.
I won't be a minute.
Very peculiar.
- Hello, Ken.
- Why wouldn't you see me?
- I can't tell you here.
- 'Ellen! Ellen!'
- Who's that?
- That's my uncle.
He mustn't know you've come.
Why not? What's wrong?
What's it all about?
We can't talk here, Ken.
I guess I shouldn't have come.
Oh, please, don't think that.
We'll get away from the house.
Yeah, I suppose he's right.
Certainly is great to find out
that your father
did a thing like that.
I'm sorry, but...
I had to tell you.
Oh, sure, it's, uh..
Well..
There's...there's really nothing
else we can do, is it?
No, I guess the whole thing
was cockeyed anyway
with me going to the front
so soon.
Besides, we...we hardly know
each other, do we?
No, this, uh..
poor-boy-rich-girl thing's
usually a bust anyway.
Yes, I guess we were just
as lucky to stop it now.
- Weren't we?
- Yeah.
It's a pretty close shave
though, we..
We might really have a, got a..
Yes.
Well, it was nice
to have known you, miss.
- If you're ever in Cleveland..
- Cleveland..
That sounds so awfully far away.
Uh, I promised.
Yeah, I know.
I'm sorry.
- Goodbye.
- We don't seem to be..
- Oh, we don't, do we?
- If we are in love?
- Oh, we can't be that, can we?
We mustn't see each other
though.
- Or must we?
- That wouldn't be right.
Except that as long as
I'm going to France...
But wouldn't it be easier
if we didn't...
- I don't know if it would...
- We can't just..
- We aren't children, are we?
- Oh, that's right, we..
We've got to use our heads,
but..
- 'Well..'
- Hm? What?
This is a douche of a game
with you going to sleep
after every move.
I wasn't asleep.
Even if I were,
I could beat you.
By the way, where does Kathleen
keep herself these days?
Oh, heaven knows. Why?
Well, haven't seen
much of her lately.
Nobody has.
Canteen keeps her pretty busy.
- I see.
- 'Hmm.'
The canteen.
Worse than ever today.
Those guns must be
over 100 miles away.
And still they go out
in thousands to fill the gaps.
I thought
I'd never get away today.
- Same here.
- Am I very late?
- Only a minute.
- A minute's a year.
- Hello, darling.
- Hello, you.
Sweet..
Glad to see me?
- Now, what do you think?
- I don't know.
Oh! Good heavens.
Look at that spread.
Those big sticky buns.
I've already had one tea.
Oh, well, pretend to eat,
darling
or you'll break her heart.
Oh, good afternoon,
Mrs. Crouch.
Good day, miss, I'm bringing
the tea, fresh made.
Ah, sinkers.
They're not sinkers, sir.
They're donuts.
- Oh, yeah.
- There.
Now, I've just got
to get the scones.
- Scones?
- They're in the oven.
Well, now let me see.
What may I help you to?
A radish? A sinker?
Uh, neither, if you please.
- Yeah, uh, neither.
- If you please.
Yeah, if you please.
Well, how about a cookie?
You pick me out
a nice, slender one, please.
- How about that one?
- Ah, thank you.
- Darling.
Hey, Kathleen..
- Kathleen..
- What is it, Ken?
We're, uh..
We're pushing off.
When, dear?
- Tonight.
- 'Here we are.'
And piping hot,
and they're good.
Though I said it, I shouldn't.
I'm sure they are.
Thank you, Mrs. Crouch.
My mother taught me to bake.
My word, she was a one to bake.
And her dumplings, oh!
You just put your fork
into them and they went, pfft!
Eh?
Well, I dare say
you'll be wanting to be alone.
If there's anything at all you
want, just call me, will you?
Yes, thank you.
Ken, how can they?
You're not half-trained.
I know, I guess
they need more men.
Yes, but..
so soon.
Well, I'll get leave,
you know, darling.
Of course.
- Well, uh..
- Let's be nonchalant, shall we?
Naturally.
- Allow me.
- Many thanks.
No use.
I feel like one
of Mrs. Thingummy's dumplings.
I've-I've gone pfft!
Kath, sweet.
Oh, dear, no.
Oh, no, darling, don't. Please.
I'll be back, you know.
Ken, just how long have you?
We've got to make Dover tonight.
We have a day's leave there
and then, we're off to France
the next morning.
Couldn't you get leave now until
the time to leave from Dover?
Well, only if..
only for something
extra special.
Take me to Dover with you...
tonight.
Have you thought, darling?
It's only a few hours.
Then I'll leave you...
and I may not come back.
But we shall have had
those hours, dear.
It will help me to wait.
And if it's all we ever have..
it will help me to live.
I shall have been...your wife.
My wife.
Darling.
I love you.
Uh, Ken, go back to camp.
Get leave to join the draft
at the boat.
Tell them
you're gonna be married.
I'll throw some things in a bag,
then you come call me.
Yeah, sure. I'll be with you
half an hour.
Sweet.
Oh, what-what about your uncle?
What will you tell him?
I'll tell him the truth.
- I must now.
- He'll never consent.
Whatever happens, darling,
I'll be waiting.
Pray for me.
Mrs. Crouch.
- Uncle John?
- Uh-huh, what, darling?
There's something
I must tell you.
What is it, my dear?
I've broken my promise to you.
What-what promise?
I've been seeing Kenneth Wayne.
We love each other.
We're to be married.
- Married.
- I meant to keep my word.
I tried. I really tried.
He called several times,
and I refused to see him.
Then when I did see him at last,
it was..
it was only to explain.
I should never have promised,
Uncle John.
I loved him from the first.
He's splendid and fine.
Won't you try to forget
what his father did?
Won't you meet him,
just for my sake?
He's going to the front.
We've only tomorrow..
We're to be married
before he leaves.
I'd sooner see you dead.
Excuse me, Sir John.
- Miss Kathleen?
- Ask him to wait, Ellen.
No, bring him in here.
- Uncle John, please...
- Bring him in here.
'This way, sir.'
Good evening, sir.
I'm Kenneth Wayne.
My uncle wanted to see you.
It's, uh, it's alright?
I'm ready to go with you.
I hope you understand, sir.
I understand only one thing
about a Wayne.
What's that?
The quality of your breed
is not to take its medicine.
That's why your father took
the life of one person
and ruined that of another.
He couldn't take his medicine.
I don't think you have any right
to put it like that.
Kenneth, I'm going with you
just as I promised.
If she marries you,
if she becomes your wife
just as you're leaving,
and you never come back
you'll have smashed
into her life
for a few futile, cowardly hours
because I shall never forgive
any part of it.
I'm coming back,
and I'm going to make her happy.
It's the only thing in the world
I want to do.
You ought to forget and forgive,
and try to help us.
When I forget, it will be
because I'll be dead.
'If he takes you from me,
then he can take care of you.'
That's my last word, Kathleen.
I shall not change it.
Come on, let's get out of here.
We can get the next train and
be in town in time for dinner.
We mustn't wait a second, dear.
- We have so little time.
- Kathleen, we can't do it.
I'd be an utter cad. I've
nothing but my shilling a day.
Oh, we can talk about that
in Dover.
You're not coming to Dover.
He meant what he said.
He wouldn't take you back, and
day after tomorrow, you're...
I don't care what happens
day after tomorrow
anymore than I care
what happened 50 years ago.
- Oh, darling, I love you so.
- Is that all?
All?
- Don't you want me too?
- Oh!
I want you.
I'm not ashamed to say it.
I'm yours, you're mine. I want
that to be true before you go.
D-darling, I-I can't.
I'd have no piece of mind.
Oh, Ken, don't send me away.
We may never be together again.
We will regret all our life
that we wasted these last hours.
I can't, Kathleen.
It wouldn't be fair.
- Oh, Ken, if you love me...
- Kathleen.
- Would you listen to me?
- No!
I won't listen.
I won't. I won't.
But, dear, please be reasonable.
Gee, this is our last half hour
and we've wasted in an argument.
I can't take you from comfort
and security
and leave you with nothing.
I can't do it.
Oh, well, I can't force you
to take me.
You haven't convinced me at all.
But of course, if you,
you don't want me?
Oh!
Oh, darling.
Darling, uh..
- Ken.
- Hmm.
You're right.
I've known it all the time.
- I've been an awful prune.
- Oh, no, darling.
- No, you haven't.
- Yes, I have.
You're far from a prune.
By the time
I get through with you
you won't be fit
to fight anyone.
You're telling me?
That is sweet.
Come on, darling,
I've got to get going.
The train leaves at ten after.
Uh, no, dear, at twenty after.
After.
Will you, uh, will you
see me to the station, hmm?
I don't think I could, dear.
All those people, I..
I know I'd disgrace you.
Oh!
Better say goodbye..
now.
- Goodbye.
Oh, Ken, I can't let you go.
I can't.
Oh, darling, you're not gonna
start this all over again?
No, dear, I love you,
I can't help it...
But, darling, it's the war.
And I'm in it.
Then why can't you take me
with you?
If I don't go,
I'll get court-martialed.
- Oh, I don't care if you're...
- Oh, for the love of my..
I'm afraid
she isn't coming back, John.
She couldn't do that to me.
I don't believe..
'Kathleen.'
Kathleen.
Well..
Because of your threat..
he wouldn't marry me.
He's gone now.
He may never come back.
If God's just, he never will.
John! John, what devil
has got into you?
Go after her. Beg her
to forgive you if she ever can?
- I haven't asked your advice.
- I'm giving it.
That boy you wished dead
is a fine chap.
I met him several times
at the depot.
One of the best.
So, after all
we've been through together..
you're on his side too.
I'm on Kathleen's side
and I say you're wrong.
You're doing a wicked thing.
And one day,
you'll bitterly regret it.
Just a moment, Owen.
You say I'm doing a wicked thing
because I can't take the son
of her murderer to my heart?
Well, I can't.
I may be all you say
but at least I'm loyal to her
which is the best I know
and I shall continue
to be so till the end.
And who pays the price
of your loyalty?
You must think of the living
as well as the dead...
You've said enough, Owen.
You're willing to sacrifice
every decent human sentiment
to a bitter memory
that should be forgotten.
Owen, if you can say that..
If that's how you feel..
I don't think you and I
can go on as we have done.
Do...you mean that, John?
I never meant anything so much.
It's...it's been a great
many years, John.
I've said my last word.
Moonyeen.
Moonyeen?
Where are you?
'John, I can't get
through to you.'
'Your hate is standing
between us.'
I need you, Moonyeen.
You must come.
If I could only reach you, dear.
If I could only make
you understand
that they love each other..
as we did long ago.
He may never come back
to her, John.
If you build a barrier
between those who love..
you'll stand between
your soul and mine..
for all eternity.
Beloved?
Beloved, can't you hear me?
Unless you drive this hatred
out of your heart
unless you right this wrong..
why, you can never
come to me.
Never!
Never...never.
Why have you deserted me?
Will it never stop?
- I can't bear it!
- Kathleen!
I'm sorry.
Ken! Oh, Ken!
Oh, Willie!
- Hello, Kath.
- Hello.
I thought, perhaps, you might
be looking for me.
My mistake, Kathleen.
I'm so glad to see you, Willie!
Don't you look well?
Oh, please forgive me for not
answering your last letter!
Or the one before that?
You're a fine one.
You are.
Oh, I'm so sorry.
Oh, that's alright, Kath.
I really didn't expect you to.
Well, I suppose I'd better
be barging along.
All the luck in the world, Kath.
Thank you, Willie.
I'll see you again sometime.
See ya.
'Fall in, men!
Stay-stay calm!'
- I've six cases tonight, sir.
- Very good.
'Alright.'
That's it.
Oh, there...careful.
- 'Orderly!'
- Sir?
Careful, now.
Careful.
Take your time.
Alrighty.
So sorry, boys.
Here we are, sir.
Take it easy.
I'll fetch you a cab
or something.
Oh!
'That's all of it, I think.'
'Wayne!'
Kenneth Wayne!
Who is it?
Oh!
Oh, hello-hello, doctor.
Well, it is..
It's good to see you again.
Nice to have you back. Splendid!
Listen doctor, will you
do me a favor?
Will you, for heaven's sake,
look at my legs
and stop being
so nice about them?
Of course! You're, uh..
You're coming up
to the hospital!
Oh, no! No.
I'm discharged.
- Splendid!
- Yeah.
Then you can stay with me.
I know of someone who's waiting.
I'm sailing
for America tomorrow.
- Tomorrow?
- Yes, tomorrow.
I just came down to...get
some things from the old house.
But Kathleen..
Do I look like a man
who wants to see a girl?
She, uh...she loves you, Ken.
She loves me, does she?
Well, what of it?
She'll get over it, won't she?
You want her to get over it?
For heaven's sake, doctor,
use your head.
Yes, yes, yes!
Let her get over it!
You're a doctor.
Give her pills!
Love is a disease, isn't it?
Cure it. Cut it out of her!
I'm afraid, it is not easy.
Alright, it is not easy.
So what?
Tell her I'm a dirty swine.
Tell her I'm going
back to America
to marry a million dollars...
tell her I got married
to mademoiselle from
Armentieres. Tell her anything.
Oh, but it means
so much to her, Ken.
Why not just see her?
Why not?
Because I haven't got the..
Because I'm shot to pieces.
Because I'm still in love
with her, if you must know.
And, now, will you, for the love
of Judas, let me alone?
Let me alone!
Captain Wayne, sir!
Captain Wayne.
- Orderly!
- Sir?
'Kenneth!'
- Take it easy.
- Now, up with him.
- That's right.
- Give me that.
- That's it.
- Steady, now, Ken.
Gimme-gimme-gimme that foot.
- Here you are.
- There we are.
Oh, you wait here, sir.
I've got a carriage waiting.
I'll get it.
I'll-I'll-I'll walk to it.
- Now, Wayne..
- Well?
- Well, you see, doctor?
- Yes, I see.
Hey, now.
I'm sorry, I...I blew up
like that.
Oh, please!
Thanks, doctor.
Goodbye.
And...forget what I told you.
Forget you saw me.
We certainly had great luck
with our girls, didn't we?
'Here we are, sir!'
'All that dust down there'
'is enough to choke ya.'
I've packed up the few things
you wanted, sir.
- Anything else?
- No, that's all.
- Come on, let's get going.
- Righto.
Oh, beg your pardon, sir..
but just now, a most
extraordinary thing happened.
Yeah?
I was down in the cellar..
and I accidentally
ran into a..
a few bottles
of very old port.
1847.
Uh-uh, do we take it?
- Well, what do you think?
- We take it!
Shan't be a minute.
Pack it up.
What time is the train?
Ten five, sir.
Then you better make it snappy.
Snappy is the word, sir.
Well, old man..
we've got an hour.
Let's sit down
and feel sorry for ourselves.
Here's to your health,
your honor
and the health of all your
descendants, great and small.
That's a mighty handsome toast!
It's an Irish toast,
it's the best I know.
Now, you keep as young
and as pretty
as you are...until doomsday.
And never forget the man
who wished it.
'Oh, Ken!'
'Ken!'
Kathleen, hello!
Oh..
Oh, it is you.
God!
I can't believe it!
Darling, I knew you'd come.
I knew you'd come.
Oh, sweet!
It's-it's so wonderful
to have you in my arms again.
I-I-I waited so long.
And darling, and how are you?
How are you, dear,
sweet, poor darling?
Let me look at you.
I wish I wasn't crying so much,
I could see you properly.
Oh, darling..
Uh-uh, sweetheart,
are you glad to see me?
- You haven't said so, you know?
- Of course, I am.
Oh, darling...of course you are.
You know, I went down to
the station, I didn't find you.
I must have missed you,
somehow or other.
I was so frightened. Oh..
But here you are..
you are here
and-and you're alive
and that's all
that matters, isn't it?
How did you know I was here?
I...I saw the light
in the window, dear.
I just took a chance,
I ran up here all the way.
My heart was pounding, I was
so afraid I wouldn't find you.
- So you ran all the way?
- Yes, I ran all the way.
I broke the record!
Oh, uh, what do you say,
we-we sit down?
- Shall we?
- Oh, darling.
Oh!
- O-o-over here, see?
- Alright.
When did you get in?
Why didn't you let me know?
Why haven't you written
all these months?
Oh, I lost your address, now..
Lost my address?
I thought you'd lost
an arm or something.
You didn't-you didn't
lose an arm, did you?
No, I don't think so.
- Lose anything else?
- Huh?
- Lose your heart?
- Oh, hundreds of times.
Liar, mine's still here, too.
It's so excited, my heart.
It's so happy.
Darling, is your heart
happy, too?
Yeah, I-I don't see why not.
It's been such a long,
long way to Tipperary.
- Such a long time to wait.
- Yeah.
But now there's no reason
why you..
I mean, no reason why I..
why you and I..
Because you have
come back to me, dear.
You know, I sort of thought
that maybe you
wouldn't be here
when I got back.
That's a strange idea.
Why not?
Well, I don't know, everything
else in the world's so changed
I...I sort of thought
maybe you..
might not still be so crazy
about-about this place and..
Why, I love it here.
You know that.
I wouldn't trade it
for anything in the world.
Oh, Kenneth,
what are you driving at?
Want me to live somewhere else?
You know I'd live anywhere
in the world with you.
But you..
- You like it here, eh?
- Yes.
Oh, that's fine.
Dear, that's fine.
Maybe-maybe I was right
that day that I..
I made you go back
to your uncle
when you wanted to come with me.
Well, maybe, but..
Oh, don't let's talk
about those things now, dear.
You're back...and that's all
that matters.
By the way, how, uh...
how-how is your uncle?
He hasn't changed
about you, dear.
- But neither have I.
- Hasn't changed, eh?
Still nursing
that old sorrow of his?
But we are not gonna
let that make
the least bit of difference,
now, dear.
See, it...must be great
to be like that..
love one woman all your life.
Why...yes, it must be.
How's everything else been?
How's, what's his name, Willie?
Did Willie get back alright?
Oh, that's good, that's good.
You know, Willie-Willie
might be just a type at that.
Willie would love somebody..
all of his life.
Ken, what are you talking about?
- I-I'm just rambling along.
- Well, will you stop?
Just reminiscing. Gee, we had a
lot of fun here, didn't we?
Remember the day we met.
Right in this room, wasn't it?
- Yeah, a lot of fun.
- Yeah.
Gee, how badly we felt
that afternoon I
we found out I was shoving off
for France?
Oh boy, was that love
or wasn't it?
Kenneth?
We certainly took it seriously
that little affair of ours.
To bad, we had to go
to war and grow up.
Kenneth, what are you saying?
What are you trying..
What do you mean,
"Little affair of ours?"
- Ken, what's happened to you?
- Well, I've-I've been to war!
I know you've been to war
and I've been waiting for you
because I love you.
And I thought you loved me.
I thought you wanted me.
I, uh..
I'm sailing for America..
tomorrow.
What do you mean?
Alone?
Alone.
But, Ken, I am...I'm ready
to go with you, dear.
Oh, you're joking.
Don't joke, dear.
Don't scare me...
Alright, Kathleen,
let's not-let's not..
When a thing's over,
it's-it's over.
Oh..
it's over.
I see.
It's over.
Then why did you come here?
Did you wanna make sure
you didn't love me?
Well...I hope you're sure now.
I hope you'll forget all about
our little affair.
Forget that I loved you,
that I waited for you
that I would've
waited for you always.
Kathleen, I've-I've changed.
Yes, that's right.
That's certainly right.
Four years and..
well, you change.
Yes, of course. I know.
Of course, you've changed.
I'm sorry, Kenneth, I..
I didn't mean to throw
myself at your head.
I didn't mean to embarrass
you like this.
I've been quite stupid,
haven't I?
Taking it for granted
that you'd still be..
Well I...guess there's not much
more to say, is there..
except goodbye?
Goodbye, Kenneth.
'Here we are, sir.
Anything else?'
Take it easy, sir.
Steady now.
Steady.
Kenneth Wayne is just
as welcome here now
as he was four years ago.
And no more.
John, John, old friend,
you can't do this.
You're hitting a man,
when he is down!
You've got to tell her
about him. I can't do it.
I can't take the responsibility
of sending her to him
if you won't help.
John...he's leaving in an hour!
Let him go.
Is that plain?
You've chosen to empty your life
of everything, but hate.
Well...I believe that same hate
will be around you
in the hereafter
'and the sweet soul of Moonyeen
will never get through it.'
'I believe this, John,
and I beg of you'
I...I beg of you
that you'll do something
about it.
Now, John...now!
Kathleen..
Kathleen?
Where have you been?
Have you seen him...
Kenneth Wayne?
Have you?
I'm not quite sure.
I went up to his house.
Do you think that was..
I'd give a great deal
if I hadn't.
Badly smashed up?
No, not physically, but..
Oh, I don't know what to think.
He doesn't seem the same to me.
Seems to have forgotten
that we were ever..
that we..
I don't know what to think.
So he ended it, eh?
Well, perhaps it's for the best.
You'll get over it, my dear.
You didn't.
But it's not the same, is it?
You knew that somebody
loved you.
You were sure of it.
You had that memory.
I have nothing.
I thought I was sure of it.
Now, I..
I have nothing.
His train leaves at 10:00.
Oh, I wish he were gone!
I can't help hoping
the maddest things.
If a car were to drive up..
and if it was he..
come back to me..
that gate would have opened.
He would have come
into this room.
But, you don't understand that,
do you?
Oh, yes, I understand.
You know, it's the little things
his laugh..
the crazy things
he said and did.
He was absolutely crazy,
you know? Doesn't make sense.
Absolutely crazy.
She said that once about me.
It's no use.
I'll always love him.
I'm just that sort of a fool.
I have no pride.
I'd love him, whatever he'd done
however bad he'd treated me.
And if he'd died..
I'd always have loved him..
all my life..
as you loved her.
Kathleen..
My child..
Kathleen, listen.
I better tell you this.
He's wounded.
You mean, Kenneth is wounded?
Yes...badly.
Wounded?
Oh, no!
Why didn't he tell me?
He didn't think
he had the right.
Owen saw him at the station.
Then that was why..
Oh, but doesn't he know
I'd love him even if..
God, my poor darling!
Then he does love me,
he does love me!
As if anything else mattered,
anything else in the world!
The train leaves at 10:00.
Oh, is that clock right?
I must catch him!
Kathleen!
I...I hope..
'I-I-I should like it if..'
Do you think
you could possibly..
come back here again?
And bring him with you?
Oh!
We'll both take care of him,
won't we?
Owen!
Hello, Kathleen!
- What is it?
- Go to Uncle John, quickly!
- Oh, hello.
- Oh!
Well..
Kathleen seemed to think
you needed me.
Anything wrong?
Wrong?
Uh, not with me!
Where is Kathleen?
She seemed in a hurry.
She's gone down to the station.
She seemed anxious to get there
before the London train left.
Oh!
She'll be coming home?
They'll be coming home.
They?
That's what I said.
Oh!
I see!
Well..
Well, I'll be jogging along, hm?
Uh-uh, would you, uh..
would you care to play
a little chess?
I mean, now that you are here.
Oh, I don't mind if I do.
Hmm..
Forgotten your chess, hm?
Forgotten more
than you ever knew.
Ah!
I wonder if she'll get
there in time.
We'll soon know.
John..
I know of someone
who would be glad
of what you've done tonight.
Yes.
She is glad.
I know.
Oh, uh..
By the way..
have I apologized
to you, Owen?
Apologize?
For what?
- Right you are.
- Mm-hmm.
Almost too dark to see.
'Well..'
I would like to play one game
and have you keep awake
till the end.
Hm?
Good old, John.
John?
John!
- Moonyeen?
- John!
You've come back to me.
No, darling.
You've come to me.
It's been so lonely without you.
I've missed you so much.
You know..
I almost made an awful
mess of things.
No.
You must forgive me,
dear, this time.
I'm getting very old.
Old, darling?
Why, look.
Oh!
Why, then..
is this what
they call, "dying?"
- It's nothing, is it?
- Nothing, dear!
And everything.
We're together now, forever.
And forever.
Come.
Watch Movies, TV Series & Live Sports
www.admitme.app