[ roar of a crowd ]
[crowd cheers]
[roar of a crowd
grows louder]
[wooden planks
creak and rattle]
[crowd cheers,
swords clash]
[evil laugh]
Uh! Uh!
[roar of the crowd]
Raaarrhh!
Come on!
[crowd howls]
Uh!
Yeah!
[evil laugh]
Rrrrah!
[breathing hard]
[protesting crowd]
Oh what do you
know about it?
Just fucking go!
Hold your
fucking tongues!
Let the roman
have his say!
Thrace
and the republic
Have known
their differences.
We've not always
been as brothers.
But let us put
aside such matters,
Uniting in just cause.
You pushed
your way into our land,
And now you stand
asking for our help.
Your hand extended?
I extend no hand.
I am here merely to inform.
Mithridates
and his greeks
Attack from the east...
Encroaching
from the black sea.
Far removed
from our villages.
True. But the getae
Take advantage
of the distraction.
Their barbarian
hordes amass to the north.
Barely half a week's
March from your villages.
How many?
Thousands.
[ yelling ]
Align yourselves
with rome!
Pledge your service
to the auxiliary
And join
us in our campaign!
To what end?
To what end?!
Victory.
And how
is it to be measured?
The getae have raided
our villages in the past.
Raped our women.
Killed our children.
Each time
have pushed them back.
Only to see them return.
He speaks
out of turn.
Yet the truth
falls from his mouth.
If we are
to align with rome,
The purpose
must be clear.
The getae dead.
All of them.
Dead. All of them.
[crowd roar their approval]
The council has decided?
We go to war.
I've asked the gods
to bless your sword.
Once the getae
are wiped from our lands,
There'll be no reason
to ever pick it up again.
And what would my husband
do without it in his hands?
Grow crops.
Raise goats.
Make children...
You'd fight no more?
Forever.
To be by your side.
How soon do you March?
First light.
Then come to bed.
If one night is
all we have left...
I should
make the most of it.
[birds chirping]
Be strong my wife.
I woke expecting
my wife beside me.
She rose
early to pray.
That her husband
would stay with her.
I thought
were in agreement.
We were.
Were?
The gods came to me
last night.
In my sleep.
What did
they show you?
My husband
on his knees,
Bowing before
a great red serpent.
The life draining
from his veins.
What meaning
did you take from it?
A warning.
If you go to war,
You are destined for
great and unfortunate things.
The getae worship
the mountain wolf.
They place
no faith in snakes.
It was just
a dream.
And if it isn't?
I gave my word,
sura.
Blood and honor.
It speaks to the man.
Nothing will keep me
from returning to your arms.
Not the getae.
Not the romans.
Not the gods themselves.
The nights grow so cold.
What am I to do
without you in our bed?
Lift your dress.
Keep me close to
your thighs,
The thought
will warm us both.
Kill them all.
For you.
Charge!
[barbarians howl]
Rahhh!
Urgh!
Hold the line!
Raaa! Urgh!
I'll fuck your women!
I'll fuck them all!
Ahhh!
Where the fuck
are the romans?
Show the cunts no mercy.
Uhh!
Yaaah!!
Ahhh!
Raaa!
Romans! Forward!
[horn blasts]
Where are you going?
Little late.
They'd just
get in the way.
[low murmur from camp
clanking of pots]
My own shit
would taste better!
I cook what
they give us, drenis.
Guts and bones!
While glaber and his
romans feast on meat.
We're the last to eat,
the last to share the spoils.
But always first to
be sent against those
barbarian cunts!
Maybe legatus fucking glaber
rolls out of his nice warm tent
And finds his thracian
dogs've returned to the wild.
[men roar in agreement]
Uh hum.
Something to add,
little man?
A word.
Which word might that be?
The one I gave
the romans.
And my body
and blood with it.
We all did,
to push the tae back.
We can defend
our own lands!
We gave our word.
In my village such
a thing still bears meaning.
Your village.
Is that why you're here?
To defend your village?
Or maybe you're trying
to impress that sweet taste
You're always going
on about, with stories of war.
[laughter]
Struckhe mark near,
did I?
Words and honor,
my great fat ass!
All comes back 'round
to a pair of tits
And a tight
little hole.
The legatus is here.
The legatus
needs volunteers
To scout beyond
the forward line.
You. Tactical
report by sunrise.
Or go without rations.
"please" would have done.
We'll finish
this discussion later.
And if we're dead?
Then my boot will find
your ass in the afterlife.
[laughs]
[giggles]
Ilithyia.
What if I'd been
an assassin?
I'd be a widow.
What's the respectful
period of mourning
Before I could remarry?
You overstep.
Women are forbidden
within the encampment.
I was discreet.
Not you?
Your man helped wisk
me through the sentries.
After I threatened
to run naked through the camp,
Screaming
he laid his hands
On the wife
of the legatus.
Does your father
know you're in thrace?
Please. He's too
busy colluding
With the other
corpses in the senate.
He thinks I'm still
lounging at the villa in capua.
Far too arid.
Hasn't rained
there since last forever.
You should have written.
You would have
told me not to come.
I'm in the middle
of a war.
I brought you a gift.
Something
to remind you of rome.
Sestii wine!
Let me fill up
your cup
While you tell
me about your little war.
Too brief a tale.
Mithridates and his army
of greek whores
Press the legion in the east
by the black sea.
Here I sit.
Protecting the
northern border...
Of the land
of piss and shit
From simple
barbarian raiders.
Mithridates.
Victory against him
Would have your name
on every roman's tongue.
Cotta leads
the assault.
He steals your laurels.
He's the consul.
Theft is his privilege.
Father will be
disappointed.
He secured this position
for you to shine.
And here you sit.
Eclipsed.
I'm doing what I can.
Of course you are.
I just
Wish you were back home.
Father's planning
a full day
Of spectacles
and gladiators!
It's the talk of capua.
I hadn't realized
elections were nearing.
Never too
early to campaign.
If things were
heading better,
You could
be by his side.
If.
So serious!
Bad for the humors.
Come. You haven't
tasted your gift yet.
[ struggling ]
[dogs bark and men
shout in distance]
They're breaking camp.
Frightened
little gashes,
Running away with their cocks
between their cheeks.
Retreat would
take them beyond
The mountains
to the north.
Their tores bear west.
West?
They're swinging
around to attack the
villages below the pass.
Our villages.
Slippery little cunts.
They break for the
mountain pass here.
It will take
them four days at most,
To reach the villages below.
Food. Supplies. Women...
All unprotected.
It's a simple thing
to be turned in the
mountains at night.
Perhaps I should
send a roman
To properly
assess the situation.
Send the gods themselves.
They'll report the same.
Dismissed.
If we March
by midday we can easily...
Dismissed!
The barbarians head west.
So it appears.
Further yet from
mithridates and the greeks.
And the glory
you deserve.
Return to capua.
And my father?
How will he measure the man he
so blessed with his daughter?
A colossus, towering
above the enemies of rome.
Pompous, arrogant,
roman boy-lover!
All but called us liars.
How are you certain?
You heard at he said.
"turned in
the mountains at night!"
Like he's speaking
to children!
No, no about the boys.
How do you know he favors them?
Now who's having a laugh?
Well there is this tickle
at the back of my throat.
That would be the cock
glaber just forced down it.
If he wants to send his
own men let him.
Won't change
the direction of the getae.
Glaber is the most
dangerous kind of fool.
One with a title.
Truth. But perhaps
he has better sense
When it comes to wine.
[chuckles]
You stole his wine?!
Only borrowed it. Plan
to piss it all back shortly.
[sound of
sharpening sword]
[a piercing horn]
Up.
Uh. Fuck your mother.
The romans sound the call.
Fuck the romans.
And their fucking horns.
Up drenis, you
drunken goat.
The legatus
has gained his senses.
Is there any wine left?
Your belly holds the sum.
It may return
the balance presently.
How far to
the mouth of the pass?
Three days by foot,
If we March with meaning.
A drink would spur
my intent.
My village is
only a ways further west.
My wine is yours
after we--
West?
We March east,
to challenge mithridates.
Did the legatus send his
own men to scout the front?
How the fuck
should I know?
They blow their fucking
horns, a roman dog barks
And the gods shit on me.
Welcome to
the fucking auxiliary.
[sigh]
A word, legatus?
Move to formation.
Advance east.
Surely you mean west,
as the getae advance.
Mithridates
and the greeks are
of pressing concern.
You have aligned
yourself with rome.
I am its body and voice.
We March east
to the black sea.
Fall to formation.
No.
You would defy
an order from your legatus?
I gave my word
to defend against the getae.
Not to March east
to attack mithridates.
You will March
where you are commanded!
Urgh!
Kill them!
Urrr!
Wait, wait!
Urgghh!
Haaa!
Throw, damn you.
Yah!
What have you done,
you stupid shit?!
He did what he had to!
Break and
go your way!
West if your
lives are there.
If not,
I could give a fuck.
Ohh!
What of the legatus?
Leave him in the mud.
Um! Go.
[birds singing]
No! Ah!
[screams]
Urghhh!
[ yelling ]
[ screaming ]
Yah!
[ grunting ]
Urgh!
Rrrraa!
Uh!
Oh god, oh my god.
[cries in the distance]
The village...
[cries and
screams in the distance]
We have to go. Now.
They haven't followed.
You were right.
I never should've left.
You had given your word.
The fault lies with the
romans in breaking theirs.
You're hurt.
It's nothing.
Let me see.
Sura.
Your tone
is disquieting.
You should be
used to it by now.
I'm all right.
Of course you are.
Hold still...
It's gone, isn't it?
The village.
Everyone we knew.
We'll move south.
I had people there once.
The getae
won't venture that far.
Not to the risk of
thinning their numbers.
And the romans?
Their concern rests
mithridates to the east.
South it is.
I wish I had
been a thousand men.
You did what you could.
You came back.
For me.
Knowing it
could mean your life.
There is no life
without you.
[horse snorts]
[ screaming ]
My tribune dead.
Half the auxiliary deserted.
Now orders recalling
me to rome.
All from your hand.
I own my actions.
But my wife...
Has been condemned
to slavery,
Courtesy
of her husband.
No! No! No!
The shadow
of rome is vast.
And you, thracian,
Will die under it.
[thunder. Rain]
[water splashing]
[vomiting]
Good of you
to join us.
Thought you were
dead there for a while.
He smells dead.
Stupid fuck.
Argh! Ahh!
Easy, easy.
You've been out for days.
[waves crashing]
We're at sea?
Upon the adriatic.
Bound for capua.
Sura...
Your woman?
The romans took her.
Best to forget her then.
[waves crashing]
[gasps]
What if I'd been
an assassin?  [giggles]
Father's in town.
He'll be back shortly.
How shortly?
He's not very happy
with you.
And his daughter?
She missed her husband.
But fears his reappearance
has come too soon.
The games your father
presents the people of capua.
They begin tomorrow.
The feast is tonight?
That's to his
purpose in town.
I would have a
word with him.
It will take more
than one to regain his favor.
The senate chamber
is full of whispers
Over your
...Early return.
Cheers of the crowd
will still their tongues.
Cheers? How will you
draw them, short of victory?
By giving them something
few have ever seen:
Thracian blood,
spilled in the arena.
When the hearts
of the crowd...
And the senate
will beg to follow.
Get out of my sight!
Inbred shit whores.
I should sale the
lot of you to the mines. Out!
Father's returned.
And in a fine state.
If he refuses
to aid my intentions...
He refuses his
daughter nothing,
When pleaded
with teary eye.
[music, drums]
[crowd claps and cheers]
Good citizens of capua!
Revered guests!
A debt of gratitude
for partaking
in this celebration...
Of the family name
of albinius.
Albinius!
[cheering and clapping]
Your attendance honors
the memory of my elders,
Gone too soon from
the realm of the living...
And the joy of a daughter,
yet so full of life.
I repay your kindness
with gifts of water!
Carried from rome
Where the gods have seen
fit to keep the drought at bay!
And gifts of blood,
to be spilled in the arena!
[crowd cheers]
Quintus lentulus batiatus!
Step forward.
[crowd cheers and claps]
Present your gladiators.
In honor
of senator albinius
And the people
of capua, I give you barca!
The beast of carthage!
[ crowd reacts ]
Yet his ferocity pales
against the titan of the arena!
The god
of blood and sand!
Crixus!
The undefeated gaul!
Gratitude to batiatus!
And now to
marcus decius solonius,
And his offerings!
[crowd cheers]
In honor
of senator albinius
And the people of capua.
I give you six
of my finest men!
Behold arkadios!
Scourge of athens!
Preening shit eater.
A mockery
to the profession.
A mockery is it?
Oh, you disagree?
Let it pass.
We're guests
of the senator.
He's invited us
to sit in the puinus tomorrow.
As consolation!
Only two of my
men have been retained
To fight
in tomorrow's games!
While solonius
secures half a dozen
Of his ill-trained
simians.
That man has fingers in
all the proper assholes.
He wiggles them
and everyone shits gold.
[ clapping ]
Gratitude to solonius!
But water and games are
distant praise, for the city
That has held the name
albinius as its own.
More is deserved!
And the gods
have seen fit
To deliver it in the form
of my daughter's husband,
Legatus claudius glaber.
[crowd cheers]
Newly returned from
the savage lands of thrace!
[crowd cheers and claps]
More gifts for
the people of capua!
Six thracian jackals!
Deserters from the war against
the barbaric getae!
To be executed ad gladium
in tomorrow's games!
[crowd cheers and claps]
Well?
Um!
He is well received.
Ask favor
for him again,
And your tears will
fall short of notice.
Right now to
more music and drink! Um!
[music plays]
Thracians.
Between those animals
And solonius'
inferior offerings.
A mockery,
on all accounting.
Glaber mentions execution.
Perhaps a word could
lend our men to the task.
The position has
been occupied.
Good solonius! I was
just marveling at your wares!
Oh and I at yours...
Oh you flatter.
No, I appreciate.
Good to lay eyes,
old friend.
I feared for a time
you would be excluded.
Games absent batiatus?!
A dawn without the sun!
Ah, crixus and barca.
Two fine entries.
They should
provide distraction between
The more important bouts.
The senator beckons.
If I miss you at the
games tomorrow, lucretia...
Well its unlikely.
We've been invited to sit
in the pulvinus.
The pulvinus?
With the senator?
A great honor.
I'll enjoy
your company there.
I shall witness his
heart on a day.
Parted from
his chest.
And I shall grip
the knife.
I've never beheld
such sights.
Nor will you again.
[crowd howls]
[key turns in lock]
[crowd roars]
[ yelling ]
[ gurgling ]
The crowd approves his gifts.
As do we all.
I've withheld something
of note for the last...
[trumpets sound]
[crowd murmur]
[ breathing hard ]
Ready?
Thracian cunt.
[gates open]
Yaaaa!
[crowd boos]
[crowd disapproves]
The odds seem
out of favor.
This thracian caused
rome a great disservice, father.
His cowardice
led to mass desertion.
Is his life
not ample repayment?
He must be
humiliated in example.
Solonius was
kind enough to offer
His services in this act.
[crowd boos]
[ sighs]
give the command.
Crowd: No!
Ah!
Uh!
Gladiator [laughs]
[crowd boos]
A mockery.
Be still.
[snake hissing]
[heavy breathing]
[growls]
Sura's voice:
Kill them all...
Yaaa!
[ crowd chanting ]
kill.
[ chanting ]
live, live!
Well this presents
some difficulty.
The sentence
of death holds.
But to defy the wishes
of the crowd,
It's not wise.
Even for a senator.
He gave me grievance,
I will not see him freed!
A solution, perhaps.
If you will entertain,
legatus?
The thracian shown
promise in the arena albeit
Against solonius's
inferior stock,
I have a batch of new recruits
arriving tomorrow.
If I were to purchase
this man in addition
To be trained at my ludus
in the gladiatorial arts,
Why in his condition,
I doubt he'll survive
to the quarter moon.
[ chanting ]
live, live.
We will be merciful, hm?
And by such,
gain the favor you seek.
What name does
the man carry.
I never cared to ask.
The way he fights,
Like the legend
of the thracian king of old.
[ cheering ]
Spartacus he was called.
People of capua!
This man,
this spartacus,
Has proven himself
in the arena
For this
legatus claudius glaber and I
Grant him--
Life.
[ chanting ]
spartacus!
Spartacus, spartacus!
Spartacus,
spartacus!
[ continuing to chant ]
Sync by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com
Adjustment by Revan
www.tv4user.de