Tonight was your first time
at the club, wasn't it?
No, I've been there
a few times before.
Really? How come
I haven't seen you?
I noticed you the first
night I walked in.
You always stand out.
Well, thank you.
How come it took you till
tonight to talk to me?
You're not shy, are you?
Maybe a little.
Are you okay with this?
Just taking off with
someone you hardly know?
I trust myself.
What do you mean?
Well, I believe in human nature.
You know, that
people are basically good.
You're right, most people are.
Tracie. You spell that
with a "Y" or an "I-E"?
"I-E Guys are always
assuming I'm a "T-R-A-C-Y. "
How I hate guys who assume.
Me, too.
- You look like a James.
- Nope, just Jim.
- How about Jimmy?
- No, just Jim.
Oh, come on, you are shy.
Look, uh, there's something
I have been meaning to tell you.
I think you have beautiful hair.
- Oh, you think so?
- Yeah.
Brown Bag, this is Brown
Bird, we have audio-visual.
Do you think it's sexy?
Brown Bag, close into one click.
Oh, yeah. There's nothing sexier than
short hair on a beautiful woman.
What is it about big
hair that turns men on?
What is it about big hair
that turns guys on, anyway?
Bad taste.
Look at me. I want
to see your eyes.
Innocent, just the way I like them.
That's him. That's our man.
Car is registered to a Jim Gelway.
Brown Bird, this is
Brown Bag. Move in.
He's testing, Tracie. Tell him
he's got the Midas touch.
You got the Midas touch.
That's 'cause I'm
God's gift to women.
And you know what I think you are?
I think you're a
natural-born cocksucker
and I think it's time you did
what you were born to do.
No.
What is this?
- What the fuck is this?
- Oh, shit!
- Fucking bitch!
- Bust him!
Brown Bird, Brown Bag, move in!
Take him! Take him now! Now!
Pull your vehicle to the side
of the road and keep your hands
- where I can see them.
- Fuck!
Police! Pull over, now!
I got him, Alex.
Call for help, now!
Tracie! Hold on! Don't move!
Stay where you are! Stay still!
Tracie, hold on, we're
going to get you!
- Come on, guys!
- There's nothing to hook on to!
- Give me a hand!
- Hold on!
Alex?
Tracie!
- Hey, Hannah.
- Hi, Megan.
I hope we don't have
that big math test.
- Jezzie.
- Hey, Megan.
Jezzie, guess who called
me again last night?
Oh, let's see, um...
Ah! Good morning, Dimitri.
Hey, Megan, I downloaded some really
cool GIFs. You want to see them?
Yeah, sure. What are they?
We'll see inside.
Agent Flannigan.
Control, check in
Starodubov and Rose.
Check!
Hey, Jezz, what do we call
the Ruskies these days?
Russians, former Soviets? I forget.
New World Order, Devine.
Get used to it.
Charles Lindbergh, Lucky Lindy,
or The Lone Eagle, as he was called,
is our subject today because
he was the first man to what?
- Megan?
- Fly over the Atlantic?
Very good. First man to fly solo,
non-stop from New York City to Paris,
and that was 1927. An
astonishing accomplishment.
Which brings us to
today's assignment.
Let's see which of you can
navigate, or fly, if you will,
from our home base to
our hero's website here
in the fewest number of links.
All right, and you're off.
That's very clever, Dimitri.
Megan, might I have
a word with you?
- Save me a seat, okay?
- Okay.
Come to my office.
Take a seat.
Now, Megan, you know I understand
the particular pressures of your life.
Your father being who he is.
The enormous expectations, all adds
up to rather a lot, doesn't it?
- Yes, sir.
- Mmm.
But none of that excuses your
breaking the honour code.
What?
I know all about you
and Dimitri, Megan.
We don't tolerate
cheating, now, do we?
Cheating? Mr Soneji,
there's been a mistake.
We only pass notes, you
know, jokes and stuff.
Megan, before you go any further,
best have a look at that.
Mr Soneji?
Yes?
This essay, it isn't mine.
Beg your pardon?
What do you mean?
Oh, my...
Oh, dear girl, I'm...
Oh, dear, dear...
Gary, why is the door locked?
Oh, my God! What happened?
She's collapsed. She's just
collapsed. I'll tell you what,
you stay with her,
I'll get some help.
Okay. Megan? Hey, sweetheart,
can you hear me? Megan?
- Hey, Jezzie.
- Hi, Kila.
- Hey, Hannah, where's Megan?
- She's with Mr Soneji.
Control, I'm en route
to Soneji's classroom.
I'm sure it's just a
meeting that went long.
Well, it's against procedure.
Mr Soneji should know better.
His office.
Mr Soneji? Secret Service, open up.
Mr Soneji?
Do you have a key?
I'm sorry, there seems to
be something stuck in here.
Stand back.
Control, shut down. Stop all
vehicles. Lock on Soneji and Rose.
So, how many of these
boats you have to make
before you become shipshape?
I have never seen a man work
so hard at looking busy.
Alex, it's been eight months.
It's time you forgave yourself.
Vickie,
you know that forgiving yourself is
the one thing a person cannot do.
Choose to make contact.
We are currently trying to
put the pieces together
as to how and why this man
would murder a teacher
and kidnap a young student.
Here's a photograph of
the missing student.
Megan Ann Rose is 12 years old.
Blonde hair with hazel eyes.
She's 3'5" tall, and
weighs about 52 pounds.
She was last seen inside the school,
with the suspect, around noon today.
We have just received information that
senior FBI and Secret Service officials
have arrived at the family
home of Senator Rose.
We will go there live as soon
as we have our satellite feed.
Technicians are setting up extra
telephone lines at the Rose home,
all in preparation,
should the kidnapper...
Mom...
Please.
I want to go home.
The FBI and police are on the
lookout for this man, Gary Soneji.
This is a recent
school photograph...
We only know that
he has disappeared
with the 12-year-old daughter
of Senator Hank Rose,
how and why is on the mind of...
Police are trying to find
out who this man really is,
his motives for killing
teacher Amy Masterson
and the kidnapping of Megan Rose.
We go back live to join
reporter Alison Peretsky,
who has been at the scene since law
enforcement officials arrived.
Thank you, Jamie.
It's now approximately four hours
since this tragic story unfolded...
Yes?
Mom...
Please.
I want to go home.
Hello?
You tuned into me, Dr Cross?
That sounds like Alison
Peretsky at WNKW Action News.
Gary Soneji?
That'll do for now.
How did you get this number?
Unlisted numbers? Come on,
Alex, there's no such thing.
It's all out there in the air, you
just have to know how to grab it.
Hey, how do you feel about my
kidnapping being bigger news
than your little tragedy
there with Jim Gelway?
You know, you really ought to give an
interview about what happened that night.
You know what they say about
sharing your pain, it's
very cathartic.
Thanks, but I'm doing okay.
Well, see, now, that's good
to hear. That's very good.
I thought for a while there you
wouldn't be able to get your act back
together and that
would be a great shame.
I have been planning
for a long, long time
to involve you in the fate
of our Little Miss Muffet.
Megan.
Do you have trouble
saying her name?
First name rapport? Is that
Hostage Negotiations 101?
Now, come on, Alex, you can do
better than that, can't you?
Do you think you're going to dissect
me in three blinks of an eye?
I'm not that easy.
But with a little patience
and a little help,
you just might profile me to a T.
What makes you think
I'm interested?
They say that when
I die, the case will die.
They say it will be like
a book that I closed.
But the book, it will never close.
Very poetic. What the hell is it?
Uh, I have left you something for
your visit with the Roses tonight.
You'll find it in your cold,
corrugated
mailbox.
It's time to get back
to work, Dr Cross.
I have been planning
for a long, long time
to involve you in the fate
of our Little Miss Muffet.
Megan.
Do you have trouble
saying her name?
Sorry, Detective,
this is a federal case.
I've been invited.
Bobby. Sir, we have a
detective down here
who may have a piece of
evidence pertinent to the case.
Alex?
Special Agent Craig. Well, I'll be.
Dare I ask?
In my mailbox.
Anything else?
That'll get you inside.
Terry.
Get this to McArthur.
- Who's in charge?
- Ollie McArthur.
Pedigree FeBe, made his bones busting
wackos in the Seattle office.
Soneji. Clean?
Clean? Squeaky. Fibres look
generic, fingerprints, nada.
The whole school's a
goddamn forensic vacuum.
All he left us was one very
neatly strangled teacher.
Heads are gonna roll
at the Secret Service.
Oh...
Jezzie Flannigan, Alex Cross.
Agent Flannigan was in charge of the
Secret Service detail at Cathedral.
- Dr Cross.
- Agent Flannigan.
I've read your books on profiling.
Obviously not close enough, but...
Kyle, this shoe was IDed by
the Roses. It's Megan's.
Dr Alex Cross, Special
Agent in Charge...
- Oliver McArthur.
- How do you do, sir?
Alex, I'll catch you later.
- Forensics.
- Yes, sir.
The Senator and Mrs
Rose are through here.
But before we talk to them,
have you any idea why
Soneji is involving you?
Not at all.
This way.
Excuse me, shouldn't Agent
Flannigan be in the room with us?
Not a good idea.
Miss Flannigan is not welcome.
But she's a material witness.
She failed the Roses and
she failed the Service.
I think Agent McArthur has a point.
No, he's missing the point.
You saw Soneji every day, five
days a week for how long?
Two years.
You have no idea how much
you know about this case.
Agent Flannigan...
They say that when I die,
the case will die.
They say it will be like
a book that I closed.
But the book, it will never close.
Very poetic. What the hell is it?
I have left you something for your
visit with the Roses tonight.
You'll find it in your cold,
corrugated mailbox.
Well, for what it's
worth, that's Soneji.
His speech pattern's the same.
Is he, um...
Are we dealing with a sex maniac?
Someone who might, you know...
No, sir.
This man has no such
interest in your daughter.
She's merely a means to an end.
What do you mean?
I see no standard procedure
in anything he's done.
I disagree.
This is a professional kidnapping.
It's going to be about money.
Which is good.
But you're saying it
isn't about money?
I think he wants to draw this out.
From what he's said,
whatever his motives,
it's very unusual.
What did he mean about the book?
That it will never close?
I honestly don't know.
Well, I think I do.
Let me tell you what this
Gary Soneji is up to.
The last thing he wants is
good crisis management.
What he wants is to confuse.
Rancour, mixed signals,
disorientation, those are his tools.
So he calls a local cop.
A damaged cop shouldering
some heavy baggage.
He's using Dr Cross
as his messenger.
Excuse me, the man that kidnapped
our daughter didn't call you,
so your agenda is what, to
insult the man he did call?
- Mrs Rose, I never intended...
- No, you wait a second.
A mad man has our daughter
and for some reason he
contacted this man.
Do you know why?
No, ma'am, not yet.
Hello.
You okay?
You, uh, got any tips for
helpless situations?
Well, you could smoke
a carton a day...
or you could bounce back.
Yeah, well, I don't see
anywhere to bounce to.
Like to get out of here?
Can I ask you something?
Sure.
What did McArthur mean when he
referred to you as damaged?
Last summer I let a sting
operation get out of control.
My partner was killed.
Hey, Megan. How are you?
Lovely to see you.
Do you recognise my voice?
It's me.
Mr Soneji.
Mmm-hmm.
I brought you that.
A lovely cup of tea with honey.
I know your throat is sore.
It'll make you feel better.
There you go.
It's all right.
You have nothing to
be scared of, Megan.
I'm not scared.
Good.
But you're wondering
what's going on.
I know what's going on,
you're a kidnapper
and you're a sick weirdo.
Megan, you're the most
opinionated girl in my class.
- Think you got that from your mom?
- I want to go home.
You Will.
Just promise me you're going
to behave yourself, okay?
That's all.
Now, listen, if you need to use
the bathroom, or anything at all,
just press that, okay?
I want to go home! Now!
Look, I brought you
some fresh clothes.
Please! Mr Soneji, please!
This is a fine gun.
It's Turkish.
Handmade, 1924.
That is nice.
My daddy won it in a game
of poker. Aces and Eights.
Dead man's hand.
That's about as much as
I know about my father.
Have a seat.
Do you know of any relationship
between Amy Masterson and Soneji?
Amy? No way.
Why do you ask?
He strangled her.
It's an act of passion.
That's a demonstration of will.
A message.
Take me seriously. What do you see?
- Dr Cross...
- Alex.
Alex, women's intuition, third eye,
sixth sense, whatever
it is, I don't have it.
Sure you do, you just
don't look at it right.
Every face has two aspects.
Now try looking at it down the
middle one side at a time.
Would you say this
man was confident?
Yeah.
- Narcissistic?
- I wouldn't know.
- You ever see any flashes of hatred?
- No.
- Anger?
- Hostility?
- No.
Look,
everything about him was right.
He was always patient.
He was pleasant.
He had a sense of humour.
I mean, he was the perfect teacher.
What do you see?
I see...
No, I mean about me.
What do you see about me?
And that's why you're
here, isn't it?
To size me up?
Evaluate your primary
material witness?
I see that you're about
to start an argument.
I need to help get her back.
What makes you think
I want a partner?
- You don't.
- That's right.
- I can understand that.
- No, you can't.
Can I tell you why I don't care?
Shoot
Look.
When I was assigned to Cathedral,
it was a job I didn't want.
It's a far cry from working
rope-lines or flying Air Force One
but I have been there
for three years.
I have been responsible for
Megan for three years.
And that little girl means more
to me than even a partner.
Can you understand that?
I suppose so.
But even if I say no anyway,
you'll probably just follow
me around wherever I go.
So, if it's a choice between having
you as a partner or as a stalker,
I guess I'll take my
chances with a partner.
Thank you.
The student drop-off is there.
That's my morning post.
Student sign-in.
Cameras are there,
there, there and there.
Motion sensors all
around the periphery.
Foolproof way to
keep the kooks out.
Exactly, we were always looking
in the wrong direction.
Which door did he go out?
Uh, that one there. It's a straight
shot to his parking space.
Let's go in.
- His classroom.
- Mmm-hmm.
He was teaching the kids how everything
on the Internet is connected.
- Alex, you got a sec?
- Sure.
Listen, I think turf wars
are a total waste of time.
If I was out of line
last night, I apologise.
Don't. I've been there.
- Anything you need, you let me know.
- Sure, Mac.
Doctor Cross, you might
want to see this.
- This is Megan's desk?
- Yes.
What are you doing?
Scoping GIFs. Graphic
Interchange Formats.
They're all stego-encrypted.
Somewhere among the billions of
zeros and ones making up this image
is a string of text.
I know about this, it's the cutting-edge
method of passing notes in class.
It's driving the teachers nuts.
How long before you can access it?
Oh, try never.
You don't crack stego
without a password.
Would you take me to his office?
Oh, when you find Soneji,
ask him for the password.
He planted a monitoring virus
on the girl's hard drive.
Every keystroke Megan hit,
Soneji was recording it.
Good move, Jezz.
Angling for a position with
the DCPD. I like that.
Dr Cross, Agent Ben Devine.
Agent Devine is security
systems supervisor.
Well, for now.
We are going to be
thrown to the wolves
as soon as they find Megan
Rose dead in a ditch.
Now what makes you so sure
that's what's going to happen?
Me getting fired or
the girl in a ditch?
Sorry, I'm having a
pessimistic day.
Tell me, Soneji, did he...
Did he ever show any interest
in what you do? How you do it?
The man never talked to me.
I never talked to him.
Well, thanks for your time.
Hello.
What?
What do you think that is?
- An empty frame.
- Mmm-hmm.
Otherwise known as...
A missing picture.
You onto something?
- A missing picture.
- Mmm-hmm.
Our Mr Soneji has a
sense of humour.
He didn't just kidnap a little girl,
he turned it into a game.
Okay.
Let's see what you
know, Mr Lindbergh.
- My, my.
- What did he get?
Dr Cross isn't in
cyberspace any more,
you're at a live site looking
through a video camera.
Those arrows down there move it.
Where are we?
I would guess we're
in Soneji's home.
Now we're supposed to
find out where that is.
Oliver McArthur's office.
Yeah, it's me. Hold on.
How about the files?
There.
- On the wall.
- There's a...
Can you zoom in there?
Yeah.
Jonathan...
- "M"...
- "E".
- Hold on. Hold on.
- "L"?
You can't move that around,
can you? It's stationary.
Go back.
No, there's something somewhere
else. I'll guarantee it.
- Right there.
- There.
- What?
- You can zoom.
Focus. There.
Bingo.
- M-E-R...
- Mere?
Mercusio.
M-E-R-C-U-S-I-O.
- 14-32... 35.
- 35.
- Granville.
Gary Soneji is also known as
Mercusio, Jonathan,
1435 Granville Street.
Well done, Alex.
In! In!
Cover up. Zoom in! Left!
Eyes open!
There.
Not until we get the go-ahead.
Turn it out to the roof.
Yeah, he's still dusting.
His surveillance was
better than ours.
He's been at this for years.
Imagine the patience.
The dedication.
You sound like an admirer.
Well, he's...
He's like a spider.
And I happen to like spiders.
He's got an elaborate
setup, here, boss.
You want to see how he
stayed clean at school?
It laminates a plastic
veneer over your hands.
Look at this.
Foam rubber. Looks like he was
wearing prosthetic appliances.
I understand the Secret Service
are being cautious tonight.
Th ere is speculation that a
full investigation is underway
into how Gary Soneji was
able to kidnap a student
from right under their cameras.
Yes, Kevin. One of the
Secret Service agents...
Evening. What's the problem?
Help! Help me!
You've got a Rule 21
problem, no running lights.
Again? I just replaced
the fuses yesterday.
Help! Help!
Sir, no running lights. You're
going to have to follow us in.
Help! Please, help me!
Well, let me see what I can do with
the fuse box. Hold on. Hold on.
I'm in here, help me!
I've been kidnapped, help!
Help!
How's that?
Thanks a lot, fellas.
Help!
Help me, please!
Help me!
"...and before the hood
was pulled over his head,
"he bragged to his executioner,
"'They think that when I die,
"'the case will die.
"'They think it will be
like a book I close.
"'But the book,
"'it will never close."'
Soneji was quoting the final words
of Richard Bruno Hauptmann.
I'm sorry, I don't follow.
1932. The infant son
of Charles Lindbergh,
America's greatest
hero, was kidnapped.
When Bruno Hauptmann was arrested,
what followed became known as
"The Crime of the Century."
I believe that Soneji wants
to do the same thing.
You think we're dealing
with a copycat?
Something like that.
Dr Cross.
What does he want from you?
He's brought me in
and left this trail because
he wants me to make sure
that he's properly appreciated.
And in order for him
to achieve this,
he has to kill Megan?
No, no. Not necessarily.
The death of the Lindbergh
baby was accidental.
Nevertheless, it's critical
that we pull his strings.
The more we make him
a living legend,
the more likely he is
to keep Megan alive.
Dr Cross, you've been
brought into this case,
what can you tell us
about Gary Soneji?
I can tell you that Soneji
is very determined,
obviously highly capable
and we consider him a
serious adversary.
What about Megan Rose?
Megan Rose is Gary Soneji's ace.
As long as he has
her, he's in control.
Sir, would you assign as
many agents to this case
if she wasn't a Senator's daughter?
The size of our task force is a reflection
of who Gary Soneji is, not Megan Rose.
Mr Soneji?
You can parse the
words if you'd like.
Hello.
I need to go to the bathroom.
All right. Be right there.
No, not at this time.
Come on.
Hey!
Help!
Please, help!
Help me, please!
Help!
Help me!
Help, please!
Please, help me!
I'm coming!
Hold on!
Help! Help me!
No!
No! Please!
Please!
No! Help me! Please!
No! Please!
Here. Here.
This'll keep you warm.
There you go.
Megan, you promised me you
were going to behave yourself.
Because of you, what you've
done, that man is dead.
Now, promise me...
Promise me you're going to
be a good little girl, okay?
Say, "Yes, Mr Soneji."
Yes, Mr Soneji.
Okay.
Now let's go have that cup of tea.
I'd say eight hours.
About 9:00 a.m.
Slugs are large calibre.
Shots hit him here, here.
Kill shot tapped him,
crown of the head.
This here is Thomas
Mathias, he found all this.
This way.
She's not in the water, Jezzie.
Soneji still has her.
- There is no way of knowing that.
- Well, think about it.
Megan is precious cargo.
Soneji is not going to let some
twist of fate bring her harm.
Right?
But why Megan? Why her?
Come on.
- Where are you going?
- Back to the city. We'll talk in the car.
You asked, "Why Megan?"
And that's the question we should have
been asking right from the start.
Why Megan?
Who is Senator Hank Rose?
- He's...
- Nobody.
Most people don't
even know who he is.
Never heard of him. Couldn't
pick him out of a line-up.
This case is front-page news now,
where will it be in two months?
A Year?
Oblivion. Know why?
Because Senator Hank Rose
is no Charles Lindbergh.
- Well, okay, then, who is?
- Ah...
There is the troublesome question.
Come on, Jezzie.
Two years, five days
a week. You know Soneji.
Who's a bigger fish
than Megan Rose?
Dr Cross, Agent Flannigan,
we appreciate your concern,
but Dimitri is fine,
and our security services are
most capable of protecting
the son of the Russian president.
Can we at least talk to him?
Nothing would please us
more than to be of help.
But speaking to Dimitri right
now would be inappropriate.
Thanks for your time.
What?
Well, McArthur is drag
netting the bay, right?
And, I mean, he's not
really missing us,
so I was thinking maybe we
could just stick around and,
you know, scope out
the place a bit.
Agent Flannigan, are you...
Are you suggesting a stakeout here?
Yeah, you know, stale
coffee, some doughnuts.
No, no, no. That's a first-class
stakeout, Agent Flannigan.
What you are talking about
here would be no frills.
You'd only get to think about
stale coffee and doughnuts.
Well, I can handle it if you can.
I get the feeling
you've done this a lot.
Oh, yeah.
Every chance I get.
Especially when it's cold and wet.
No parking here.
We are on the clock, Officer.
Everything okay?
Everything is all right.
What's the problem?
Go ahead, Jezzie.
What?
Have one.
Thank you.
Alex, that's Dimitri.
Jezzie, it's him. It's him!
Soneji!
Hold it right there!
Jezzie, shoot the tyres!
Jezzie!
Police! Don't shoot! Don't shoot!
Jezzie, you're going to
get Megan back, right?
Yes, we are. I promise.
Use this to get Mr Soneji.
I will.
Thank you.
You talk to Hal, I want you
to bring him up to speed.
Well done, guys.
Avert an international crisis
and paint Soneji into a corner.
Not bad for a night's work.
Incoming, Soneji ditched the
patrol car near Reno Park.
Hijacked a tan Sierra. Put one
bullet in the driver's head.
Last seen heading toward Route 50.
Annapolis. I knew it. 75,000 boats.
- Other marinas?
- We're here, dead fisherman here.
These, all the marinas, all locked
down, patrol boats in each of them.
All right, listen up.
We got to move fast.
Roadblock Route 50 and triple the
surveillance in the harbours.
I want two choppers on the
pad in five minutes. Let's go.
Son of a bitch.
What's wrong?
I blew it, that's what's wrong.
I had a shot right before
he hit the hydrant.
But instead of pulling the trigger,
I was thinking. I was thinking!
Yeah, you were thinking of the
possibility of your shot going astray
and blowing Soneji's head
off, in which case...
We would never find
Megan. I know that.
Well, then, don't beat
yourself up for being prudent.
Alex, you don't get it. I was trained
to shoot first and think later,
- and I...
- Jezzie, for heaven's sake.
If you hadn't convinced
me to stay there,
Soneji would have two
victims instead of one.
Plus we'd have an international
incident on our hands. You did good.
- Yes, but still...
- You did good.
- Anything?
- No, not yet.
We're sitting on the area.
Chief, Soneji's on the phone.
- Soneji?
- Detective Cross?
I want to explain how
the agenda's changed.
You're going to bring me
$10 million in diamonds.
Point five carat, colour D, clarity
SI2 in a thermos in nine hours.
If the stones are rigged, laser
tagged, irradiated, the girl dies.
Does that penetrate?
It does.
I'll call back. 4:00 p.m. sharp.
He beat the trace.
The clock's ticking, people, let's
move this downtown. Let's go.
Dr Cross?
I'm here.
The Watergate. 20 minutes.
There's a package for Mr Antwerp.
Okay, people, let's move.
Don't lose me, kiddo.
You won't even see me.
I'm on police business.
Keep it here, please.
Eddy, this way.
Hi, how are you?
Do you have a package
for Mr Antwerp?
Yes.
Yes, sir.
Over there. That one.
Cross.
Leave the phone. Leave the car.
Pennsylvania and 6th. The fountain.
Fourteen minutes. Run.
Thanks.
Mac, you there?
- Alex.
- He made me ditch the car.
Looks like it's a running game.
I'm on my way to
6th and Pennsylvania.
I'm left and behind you, Alex.
Bearing onto Pennsylvania.
- Cross.
- 12th and Madison.
Twelve minutes will
get you there. Go.
Unit 3, loop on 23rd Street. Unit 6,
take K Street and double back.
You've got four units on top, Alex.
Cross.
Four minutes. Union
Station. Main entrance.
Jezzie.
Union Station, main entrance.
It's rush hour. He's
drawing him into a crowd.
Hey! Hey!
Don't answer that!
I think it's for me.
Cross.
- Cross.
- Keep this phone. Take the Metro.
Platform A. You got
two minutes. Go.
Jezzie, Metro,
downstairs, platform A.
Cross.
Go to the centre of the platform.
Track 15. Go.
Go to the first car.
You there yet?
Yeah, I'm there.
Go to the left side.
Open the window.
These windows don't open.
You're smart, Detective.
Improvise. Quickly.
Police officer, everybody down!
Get down, everybody down.
Come on, out of the way.
We're ready. All right. Now, throw.
We can neither confirm nor
deny that Gary Soneji
was involved in the incident
on the MTA train this morning.
We've heard rumours
that a ransom was paid.
Can you comment on this?
I can't comment on any of that.
What about Megan Rose?
I'm not going to go into
any details at this time.
What do we know about
Soneji's state of mind?
I'm not going to comment
on his mental stability.
You can draw your own conclusions.
Now, Senator Rose has agreed to
make a statement, but he's not...
- What's up?
- ...going to answer any questions.
The file on Soneji, is it
still on your kitchen table?
Yeah, why?
I'm going to have
another look at it.
This business about
the diamonds, money,
I didn't see it coming.
And the feelings of
absolute helplessness.
I am grateful that the FBI is here
with the objective expertise required
to find out where my daughter
is. Secondly, I now...
This is worse than killing time.
Yeah, but you'd be
amazed at how often
the small, neglected things
become the most important.
I've just got the feeling
we are missing something.
Maybe I'm in the
wrong line of work.
Maybe I should take on
something less challenging.
You do what you are, Jezzie.
You mean, "You are what you do."
No, I mean, you do what you are.
You're born with a gift.
If not that, then you get good
at something along the way.
And what you're good at,
you don't take for granted.
You don't betray it.
What if you do betray your gift?
Then you betray yourself.
That's a sad thing.
- Who is it?
- Police.
Gary Soneji.
Hi, Alex.
Now, right hand,
thumb and forefinger.
Just give me the gun.
Alex, you can't shoot me.
You'll never find Megan.
Sit down, Alex.
I'm a little concerned,
Alex. I'm a little...
I'm a little worried that you...
You don't really care to
understand me any more.
That you won't paint
an accurate portrait.
And I need you to convince
me that I'm wrong.
Well, in order to do that, we're going
to have to talk about Megan Rose.
No. No, no bargaining, Alex.
No cheap interrogation techniques.
It's transparent and it's clumsy.
This is between me and you.
I want you to see.
I want you to look inside here and
tell me what the fuck you see.
I'm a gift to you, Alex.
I'm a gift to you.
And you are beyond pitiful if
you cannot understand that.
I'm living proof that a mind...
The mind is a terrible thing.
I see you've got your
sense of humour back.
Yeah.
I wondered what happened to
it during the ransom drop.
The ransom drop.
That was a well-earned $12 million.
Twelve million.
Senator Rose says he
can pull strings.
Says he can fix it so you keep
the $12 million and walk.
All you have to do
is return the child.
Where is Megan?
Where's Megan?
Where's Megan? Where's
Megan? Where's Megan?
She's trapped on my boat,
Alex, isn't that right?
Or maybe she's stuck in
a warehouse somewhere
or floating in a river.
Swinging from the end
of a rope. Buried alive.
I envy her.
What would life have been
like with parents like that?
Come on, Gary. Blaming your
parents for what you are?
I'm not blaming them, Alex.
They've been punished already.
Oh?
I burned down the house
while they slept.
I was 15 years old.
Was it what you expected?
Not really. It was
a new experience.
What, killing?
No.
Being in the newspapers.
So, in your opinion, Doctor,
were my actions triggered
by nature or nurture?
If you want me to
be brutally honest,
I think you just have a morbid
desire to burn in hell.
We're done for today.
I'm taking her with me.
You're not taking her anywhere.
I'll send her back to you.
You just tell me which
piece you want first.
Oh, shit!
Damn it!
Alex!
What...
What have you done?
Residents of this normally quiet
suburb are still in shock
as news of the shooting
of Gary Soneji,
who is America's most wanted man,
filter through their community.
Apparently Soneji attempted
to confront or even harm
members of the kidnapping
taskforce hunting him.
So he came after Jezzie
as payback for Dimitri.
Ostensibly, yeah.
That's how you want it on record?
Yeah, for now.
Here they come.
Dr Cross, tell me you have at least
an idea of where my little girl is.
I'm sorry, sir, I can't.
You kill the one man
that has the answers,
and you're telling me
you haven't a clue?
Not one clue?
The man walked in the fucking room
- and you shot him!
- Senator.
Standing in his shoes, I'd
have done the same thing, sir.
Well, that's your job, not his.
He's supposed to
find my little girl,
not shoot the man who
knows where she is.
Senator.
It's not over.
The book is not closed.
Alex.
Thank you for saving my life.
Goodbye, Jezz.
You want to hear
something funny, Mac?
Sure, cheer me up.
I congratulated Soneji
on scoring $12 million.
You mean $10 million.
Exactly.
He had no idea what
I was talking about.
I know you. You work at my school.
Eat your food, Megan.
Alex, where is this going?
We've been through these tapes
backwards and forwards.
I can't see how this is
helping us find Megan.
Do you know what I see, Mac?
Someone was onto Soneji long
before we ever heard of him.
Look at this. What do you see?
Agent Devine hauling ass
out to the front gate.
Mac, he could have shut this whole
place down from right there.
Now you want to tell
me why he didn't?
Good God!
Devine was in on it with him.
Then when Soneji hit the embassy,
he pulled a double-cross.
He ran his own ransom.
No.
Soneji was a loner.
An accomplice would
have been beneath him.
I'll tell you what happened.
Soneji was hoodwinked,
and so were we.
Details are still emerging,
but this much is clear,
the manhunt that began over a
week ago in the nation's capital
came to a violent end
late yesterday...
with the death of kidnapper,
Gary Soneji. In this...
Don't move.
Turn around, hands on
the wall, feet apart.
Hi, Jezz, where did you come from?
You know something, Devine?
You're pretty stupid.
Your car in the driveway,
the TV so loud you wouldn't be
able to hear a SWAT team come in.
- What are you doing?
- Shut up!
Where's Megan?
She's in the barn.
She was so doped up,
I don't think she even knew
I took her off the boat.
She's still alive?
You were supposed to dump her in the
river after you got the diamonds.
Yeah, well...
Maybe killing a kid is something
I'm not prepared to do on my own.
Anyway, today, tomorrow, it's still
going to look like Soneji killed her.
She can't die after
Soneji, you idiot!
It doesn't make any
difference, you know why?
They're never going
to find the body.
Okay. I'll go do it now,
will that make you happy?
Yeah, it would.
Wait.
Can I see them?
Hey, do you realise that
we spent an entire year
following Soneji's every move?
I think we deserve these.
That beats the hell out of a
Secret Service pension, huh?
Hmm.
Profiling the profiler.
Kidnap from the kidnapper,
that's brilliant.
You are a genius, Jezz.
Genius has nothing to do with
it, I'm just good at what I do.
Well, it didn't hurt that everyone
else involved was a complete half-wit.
You think Alex Cross is a half-wit?
You really believe that he
shot Soneji to save my life?
Cross pulled the trigger
because he knew Soneji
didn't have Megan any more.
What are you saying?
I'm saying that sooner or later
he's going to figure it out.
He already knows Soneji
didn't run the ransom.
He is onto us already, isn't he?
No, he's not onto us.
But I think he's onto you.
It's Turkish.
My daddy won it in a game of poker.
It's about as much as I
know about my father.
Megan?
Megan, it's me, honey.
Jezzie?
Jezzie! Jezzie,
I'm in here! Jezzie!
Open up, honey. I'm gonna
take you home. It's all over.
Yeah, sure, just hold on a second!
Jezzie?
Yeah, honey?
What happened to that other guy?
He's dead, Megan.
You're safe now.
Open up.
Jezzie?
Yeah, honey?
Why isn't there
anyone else with you?
Megan, it's me.
Now don't be scared of me.
Open the door.
Megan, I'm going to ask you one
more time to open the door.
Right now! Open the door!
Megan, open the door, honey!
Listen to me! Open the door!
Megan, open the fucking door!
Open it! Bitch!
Stop it!
Very clever, Megan.
Come on.
Jezzie?
It's over.
Drop the gun.
Alex.
How did you, um...
Aces and Eights, Jezzie.
Plus your timing was a little off.
I watched the tapes.
You and Devine could have
stopped Soneji at the school.
Just like you could have stopped
him at the Russian embassy.
But you had a different agenda.
You know something, Alex?
When you said you do what
you are, you were right.
I'm living proof.
Put the gun down, Jezzie.
Would you kill another partner?
You're not my partner.
You all right?
You are a very brave girl, Megan.
Who are you?
I'm a policeman.
My name is Alex Cross.
I'm a friend of your parents.
Can you take me to them?
Nothing would give
me greater pleasure.
Could you...
Thanks.