My friend gets another one, too!
How awesome!
Shot! Shot! Shot! Shot! Shot!
Shot! Shot! Shot! Shot! Shot! Shot! Shot!
One more! One more!
- Come here!
- No.
- Come here.
- No, no. Okay.
- You'll get a shot.
- Okay.
You have to drink it.
- Come on!
- Do it!
Hey!
Do you want some? Here you are.
Shitty little critter.
SORRY. I HAD TO LEAVE EARLY. KIM
Where were you last night?
- Didn't you go home? Did you sleep here?
- What?
Oh, yeah. Thank you.
Franny?
Holly.
Holly? Holly!
I want to go back and put on
the leggings with the stars.
We just spent half an hour
trying to find the right leggings. No!
You don't need to shout, Mom.
I'm sorry. I've got something
really important to do today.
- She's blinding me.
- We'll get the Wonder Woman costume later.
- I'm such a good friend.
- I know. Thank you.
Oh, no! No! No! No!
Shit.
The door. The door!
The door's stuck!
Oh, Shit!
The door's stuck! Oh, my God!
I don't want to be stuck in here!
Okay...
Okay.
- Franny'? Are you okay?
- Yes. Yes, I'm fine.
I'm fine.
- The damn door was stuck.
- You just need to twist it.
See? It twists.
"The deerjumps high and wide, but, well,
why not, it's got nothing to hide", right?
What's up with you?
This can't go on.
I've got enough "half" women here,
working part-time and such.
Heinze's getting married
and she'll be having kids.
Then she'll be off work
and all that drama.
So, I need women like you,
but I need you to give 100%.
- So, you'll be taking time off.
- Yes.
- What?
- You'll be taking time off.
No, no... I don't need to take time off.
You need to take a break. Do whatever
it is you need to do that will help you.
Go to a spa... Have a manicure
or a pedicure. Some "me" time.
No. Believe me, I don't need...
I just haven't
slept for a while. That's all.
It's not a problem.
Ms. Kinnert, let me rephrase that.
You're no use to me here
with your panic attacks.
They're not panic attacks.
It's just stress.
Do you know how to read?
"Strength doesn't mean
doing everything yourself.
Strength is about asking for help."
So, take some time off.
Stand up for purple, Ms. Kinnert.
My phone!
Ms. Kovnatzky.
Please, follow me. This way.
The "haute de fleur bouquet prestige".
With this, you'll shine next to any man.
We have cars waiting outside
your kids' school
and your house at Stresemannstrasse 233.
We're listening in to the police radio,
so, if you sound the alarm
or call for help, they're dead.
Put the necklace in this,
close the jewel case
and once I'm gone,
you'll put it away and wait.
Got it?
Smile.
Hey, you!
Stay where you are!
Lower your weapon!
Scoot over.
Okay. Start the car.
Wait!
...Ku'Damm. Nothing to report.
...heading north.
Nothing to report. We'll keep driving.
Okay. Now.
Stop the car.
That way.
You'll be free to go soon.
Hey! What are you doing?
- I have to...
- Hey!
- Stop the car!
- I have to...
I just have to... No!
- Give me that! Give me...
- I must...
- Give me that!
- My phone! No! Give me my phone!
I didn't see you. I can't remember faces.
I've already forgotten yours.
Are you nuts?
Shit!
What? Are you going to puke now?
- Keep driving then.
- Okay.
Oh, God!
Timmsen!
Our hostage is Franziska Kinnert.
Her photo is being sent to the press.
We'd like to know why
the security freak decided to draw a gun.
On a pedestrian zone.
Damn rednecks. Amateurs.
- And the perp?
- She was bluffing. There were no cars.
- She acted alone.
- Are you impressed or something?
- What?
- Why are you all fidgety?
What? No. No. What I meant was that the...
We don't have a clear shot of her face.
- It reeks of perfume here.
- Ingrid.
- What?
- Well...
Finally.
Take a hike.
- Happy?
- Did you call me here?
Yep. Lucky you. You're on my team.
- Out of the question.
- It's perfect for your helper syndrome.
Take those stripper clothes off.
Lost your sense of humor?
You really want to be on patrol
for the rest of your life?
- I know you.
- Would that be all?
Come on. Yippee ki-yay?
You can't leave me alone with Timmsen.
Every idiot can be on patrol.
- Drive up there.
- Okay.
Stop the car.
Get out.
Open it.
Empty the contents
of the canister in the car.
- Take off yourjacket and throw it inside.
- Okay.
Okay.
Over there.
Come.
Hey, Leine.
Sorry. I had something to attend to.
Don't ask. She had to "work".
We can't take a baby on patrol!
I didn't want a child.
She went off the pill.
"It gives me depression."
Now the depression is in the back seat.
- Where to?
- Lietzensee Lake.
Someone's throwing stones at ducks.
Or throwing ducks at stones. I'm not sure.
You saw me, so I can't let you go. Hop in.
I can't.
- I lose my cool in confined spaces.
- Get in.
- Your mom should.
- What?
I'll knock you out
to make it easier for you.
Okay, yeah.
Okay.
The money first.
Greetings to Frank Gatsky.
What was that?
- I'm just the hostage!
- Hostage? What hostage?
Are you screwing with us?
Do you work for Gatsky?
We're out.
Hey, hey, hey!
I'm the hostage!
- Don't shit your pants because of Gatsky.
- Bye.
No! No! No! No!
Shit!
I'm just the hostage. I'm the hostage.
I'm the hostage! I'm the hostage!
I'm the hostage! I'm just the hostage!
Oh, God! Oh, God! Oh, God!
I'm just the hostage.
Oh, God! Oh, God! No! No! No!
Oh, God! No! No! No!
I'm the hostage.
No! No!
What's wrong with you?
Do you want to die? Do you?
Do as I say and if you move
as much as an eyelid, you're dead!
- Do you understand?
- Okay. Okay.
Fuck!
If I can't smoke, I won't say a word.
This is about your daughter
who's been taken hostage...
Coco Chanel could smoke where she liked.
Chanel was...
Sorry, but there's no comparison there.
Why is that? Why is that?
- I raised a kid on my own...
- Give her a lighter.
- I don't have one.
- Go get one. And an ashtray.
Yes, Sir!
- What's your profession?
- I'm a nurse.
- Hmm.
-"Hmm"? What's with the "hmm"?
- Beoause you think I failed as a mother?
- Have you?
Are you taking me for a fool?
I already said everything
to your dumb colleagues on the phone.
My daughter left home when she was 16,
and we haven't been in contact since.
And why is that?
- Do you have Children?
- No.
Then stop looking down on me and annoying
me with that hypocritical look of yours.
- Finally!
- Here you are.
My colleague will be taking over.
Let us know if she gets in touch.
Of course.
- Are you out of coffee?
- W hat?
Coffee?
No, Kim.
Look after her for a bit longer.
I'll pay you for it.
I can't right now.
I don't know how long.
No, it's okay.
You can't take her there now.
You can't take her to Bim Bum Land.
Okay, I'll come by. Yes, I'll hurry.
Kim, wait!
I need you to get something for me.
Okay. Great. I'll text it to you.
Please, be quiet. I have to think.
Why are we here?
- What's going on?
- You're staying here.
What? Why?
Wait, you can't just...
When will you be back?
You are coming back, right?
You can't just leave me here!
- What if something happens?
- You'll be out of my life.
Stop! Come back!
You can't just leave me here!
I'll scream until someone hears me.
Quit that! I'll come back for you.
You're lying!
You're going to leave me here to die!
I'll scream until the cops come.
I'll tell them everything!
- Oh, God! No!
- Shit.
Hello?
Mom!
Come here!
The perp may have stolen jewelry
worth half a million euros
according to
Ingrid von Kaiten, head of...
Oh, God!
Oh, God. I can't take it anymore, Harry.
I can't take it anymore.
What's wrong with her?
Don't tell me this is normal!
- Oh! What's up with her?
- Ask her.
- Her poop was green.
- Was it foamy?
- What?
- Her stool.
- No.
- It's fine, then.
Everything except purple poop is normal.
- Careful there. Careful.
- See? Everything except purple is normal.
Oh, no...
- What?
- Quack, quack.
- Are you stalking me?
- Have you made a decision, wimp?
Find yourself another gorilla.
Am I invisible?
You're not.
Why doesn't she let the hostage go?
- No idea. Maybe she's not a hostage at all.
- Yeah, you should go investigate.
- What's the plan?
- To dye your hair.
What? Why are we dyeing my hair?
Because they'll recognize you
and I can't have you with me.
Where will we dye it?
No. No. No way.
Forget it.
I'm not sticking my head in there.
It's full of truck driver pee.
I have to try and find
a new buyer because of you.
And I hate not being prepared.
I have no idea what you just said,
but I'm not dying my hair.
- You're a real top prize, aren't you?
- Why'? You in a rush?
That was really fucking mean of you!
- Don't! I hate when people are too close!
- Oh, really?
You have aggression issues.
Stop crying. I had no choice.
How can we prevent your panic attacks?
Your mom has panic attacks.
It's just stress.
Pull yourself together.
You might not believe it,
but I'm the only person you have.
Yippee...
I play "Banana Kong" when I'm stressed.
-"Banana" what?
- Don't you speak English?
- I'll shoot you if you call someone.
- I know.
- What are you doing?
- Playing...
- With sound?
- It's calming.
Okay. I'll do the talking
and you stay quiet. Got it?
If they ask, we're partners
and we work for Gatsky. Okay?
- Who's Gassky?
-"Gatsky". Our protection.
If they realize we're just
two girls on our own, we're screwed.
What?
I've Changed my mind.
I'm out.
Pull yourself together!
Oh, God! Does Brad Pitt live here, too?
What if he asks me something? I can't lie.
Okay. Get down. Down.
Thank you.
- Who's that?
- Shit.
What are you doing?
- Give it back!
- Shut up. You're staying in the car.
It's Mel.
- Sweetheart!
- I've got something for Enno.
It's worth 500, but it's yours for 300.
- And it's from Gatsky?
- Yes.
It's not my field of expertise.
Who says it's real?
- I do.
- Oh...
It's now or never. If you're in,
then Gatsky will have more deals for you.
300,000.
Look what I found.
Hey! Let her go. Come here.
- Boo!
- Hey! Quit that!
Why are you sweating? Scared?
Don't be scared of me.
- I told you to leave her alone.
- We're just chatting.
We're with Gassky! Gassky's team.
Gassky's team...
Let her go.
You're not Gatsky's team.
Come on! Come on!
Shit!
This way.
Get in! Get in!
Oh, God! Oh, God!
Shit!
You dirty rabble! Shit!
Oh, God! Oh, God!
Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you.
I emailed you
the information about our hostage.
Oh, God...
It's your hostage.
What do you want?
Oh, my God, Leine! We were a good team.
Don't be like that.
For one mission that we messed up?
It wasn't a mission. He was my friend.
Have you been to his house?
To see his wife and kids?
No. That's not really your thing, is it?
Look at what I've sent you.
I'm not your partner anymore. Get it?
Finally!
I know that, you asshole.
Fuck!
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Kim, are you okay? Is Holly okay?
No, everything's fine.
I just wanted to make sure.
What's wrong? What was that?
What's wrong?
Please, tell me...
- Piss off!
Piss off! Piss off, dammit!
Leave me alone!
What?
What... What do you mean?
Just go. Piss off!
But... I don't know where we are.
Where shall I go?
No idea. Home?
Don't start crying now...
I can't stand your crying.
But... You can't just
tell me to go, just like that.
I'm sorry that you're
in this mess because of me
and I'd really like
to make it up to you and help you.
You can't help me.
"Strength isn't doing everything alone,
but about asking for help."
What?
"Strength isn't doing everything alone,
but about asking for help."
- Where did you hear that shit?
- From some "say 'yes' to a 'no'" calendar.
I'm not going.
Sorry for getting you
involved in all of this.
It's not so bad.
I had no plans anyway.
What's your name, anyway?
Mel.
Mel? "Mel" like "Mel Gibson" or something?
Yes, that's it.
442. Disorderly conduct at "Desiré".
Could you go check it out?
Sorry.
Yes, we're on our way.
What?
- Where to?
-"Desiré".
"Desire"? It's in the sticks.
Who keeps filing complaints?
'Ll
I can't take her to "Desire .
She'll be traumatized.
Take the baby and go. I'll go alone.
Thank you. I've read that
whatever happens in your first two years,
becomes so ingrained
in your subconscious...
She'd become a prostitute.
- I owe you one.
- Close the door.
- I will.
- Close the door, okay?
- Say "bye".
The door...
My name's Franziska.
- Great.
- But call me Franny. I hate my name. I...
- You look like shit.
- Oh, really?
Did it... Did it...
Didn't it turn out well?
Careful.
- Hey, Mel.
- Hey.
- Have you also done all that?
- Stay here and don't do anything.
- Don't talk to anyone. Got it?
- Yes. No talking.
- Why is she here?
- Gatsky will be happy.
Tarek, calm down. The guy's been banned.
You can't keep causing a fuss.
Coco. Harry's thirsty. Get him a drink.
- You look like shit.
- Yeah, thanks.
Get yourself a missus.
Your bad mood is too much to handle.
What about you? Go get Changed.
I'm all done.
- Is she new?
- Who'?
- Her.
- What? She's way too old and has no tits.
I'll go get my things. Don't go anywhere.
I don't want to harm your kid, of course.
I'm not a monster.
How did you imagine it?
You want to stop working for me,
take on anyjob you can and go solo?
And you use my name?
I need the money.
What's your plan?
I want out. I want to stop.
I want out of here.
Come on, Ingrid.
Mel'?
It burns! Fuck!
I can't see!
It's simple.
It's the same as always.
If I'm involved,
then I want my share. 50/50.
Those are the rules.
But you already know that.
I can't give you your share.
I don't have it. I've lost it.
- What?
- I've lost it, okay?
Then make sure you find it.
I want my share.
If you don't, you'll be my woman at last.
For her, I'd make an exception.
I miss you so much.
Stop.
Think about it.
Could you make us a drink?
- What's that? I can't see.
- Sit down. Come on.
It burns. It burns. It burns.
Thanks, it's been lovely,
but I'm in a rush.
Stay here.
Okay. Yes, okay.
But I don't want to talk.
I've got nothing against strippers.
I really don't.
You're cute, but I don't have any money
and you must be expensive.
Yeah. Drink something first.
Your outfit looks so fake.
It's such a turn-off.
I'm not a stripper. I'm a police officer.
Yeah, right.
I bet you have handcuffs and a loaded gun.
Flirting isn't your thing, is it?
Excuse me.
- It's okay.
I'll CONTACT YOU
REGARDING YOUR HISTAGE
- Hey!
- Where were you? I was looking for you.
- Franziska!
Hey, Harry? Hello?
Harry? Hello?
- What? He was a stripper!
- He knows your name!
- No, he doesn't!
- He just said it! He's a cop!
I left you alone for five minutes!
- He started it! It wasn't my fault!
- Are you crazy?
Sorry. You can trust me.
Normally, I'm reliable.
Shit! I'm leaving a trail!
- Get in and drive!
- Why me again?
- I have no idea! It won't go into gear!
- Are you nuts?
- The handbrake is on!
- What's wrong with it?
The handbrake!
- Shit! You're so aggressive!
- Go left.
- Yes, I know.
- Just drive!
Turn right.
See? He was a stripper.
- Oh, God! That wasn't him! It wasn't!
- Stop the car!
Oh, God! We can't just leave him there!
What if I've run him over?
Calm down. I'll go check.
- You stay here.
- Okay. Okay.
Come on. Move.
- Are you done?
- I don't know. Is he alive?
No, he's all crushed.
Tell her you're alive
or she'll puke all over my car.
- I'm still alive.
- Louder.
I'm still alive!
I'm so sorry I ran you over.
- You didn't.
- I didn't mean to. I even liked you.
Must've been a road bump. It wasn't me.
- I panicked...
- You didn't run me over.
- I've never done that before.
- Just a bump.
Enough!
Tie his hands behind his back.
But...
- Do it!
- He's a cop!
You have to do something
about your aggression problem.
You two a team?
- No.
- Why was she alone in the club then?
I told her that if she ran off,
I'd find her and kill her.
Find his cell.
I'm sorry. You're bleeding.
Yep.
Back left pocket.
Back left pocket!
You can't take a cop as a hostage!
Why is he on my case then?
Why is a cop on my case?
- Why all the shouting?
- So you can hear me!
There's no need to shout at me!
- How did you know we'd be there?
- I didn't.
- So you were there out of frustration?
- That's shockingly true.
I was just on patrol.
What's Kaiten like?
The task force boss.
You'll be meeting her soon.
- I'll be right back, okay?
- Okay.
Okay, then.
- Okay, then... Undress.
- Very well.
- Wait. I've nearly got it.
- Yeah, yeah. Calm down.
Okay.
Are you the brain or the body?
I haven't figured it out yet.
Am I the Hulk?
I know, darling. It won't take
much longer. I'll be home soon.
Hey! Don't cry.
I'll sing you a song.
What would you like me to sing?
I'll sing you the tramp song, okay?
Are you all tucked in?
Okay.
Once I had my own house
Now the subtenants are throwing me out
I'm a rascal, a rascal
A slovenly rascal
I'm a merry tramp
Once I had my own bathroom
From now on
I'll be doing it in a bag, I presume
I'm a rascal, a rascal
A slovenly rascal
I'm a merry tramp
You have to be careful now.
- Are you always so rough?
- I'm sorry.
- This might hurt.
- What might?
- Fuck!
- Vodka?
- Yes.
- Okay.
Okay.
- Will it even go through the skin?
- Move over.
- W hy'?
- Move away.
What are you doing?
Hey! Stop it!
- Untie me.
- Sit down!
Untie me!
You want to help her?
I'm trying to save you!
Can I have a sip?
- I hate cats.
- W hat?
My mother gave me a cat so I wouldn't
feel alone at night when she wasn't there.
She always bit my feet,
and every time I hid,
she'd scratch at the door. 80 creepy!
- I couldn't sleep until Mom was back.
- Where was she?
I told you. On the other side of the door.
- Oh, God!
- No. I meant your mother.
Oh! I have no idea. Looking for men.
- She thought that would fix her life.
- Maybe she didn't want to be alone.
Alone with you.
Oh, that's awesome!
Are you for real?
Why? It's great.
Please, don't...
Come on! Come on!
Come on! Come!
Come on!
Timmsen!
- You'll be the end of me.
- I can't reach Leine.
- What does he have to do with this?
- I checked his cell data.
Of course you did! Just like that.
He called and sent me a cryptic text.
"It's about your histage". I don't get it.
He never calls at night.
Something's wrong.
Yeah... He meant to write "hostage".
- What?
- He meant to write "hostage".
He mistyped it.
He meant to type an "0" instead of an "I".
- He was at "Desire' .Gatsky owns it.
- You mean "Desire" .
Okay...
Frank Gatsky.
He's in the club business.
He was in Luckau-Duben prison
between 2005 and 2009.
For robbery.
He specialized in robbing... jewelers.
We have to go.
Okay. Where to?
And him? Does he have to pee?
Do you have to pee?
Shake it well.
Franny!
Did you lay me on top of the cop?
- Should I be worried?
- What? No. I won't start anything with him.
- Why should I? You nuts? He looks like...
- Can I trust you or not?
- Yes, you can trust me.
- Good.
What do we need these for?
Did you think
we'd just sit and drink coffee?
- Thank you.
- Thank you. Bye.
- It's all too brutal.
- You wanted to come along.
- I don't even know how to shoot.
- I'll teach you.
Oh, right.
Got it. Yes.
Okay.
Very good. Okay. Thanks.
No video surveillance at the gas station.
But we know what they bought.
If it was even them.
Plastic gloves,
bananas, cola, shoes, size 7...
Kinnert's size. They've checked.
- He gets to drive that and I get a Golf?
- What? Who?
Isn't it great?
We sacrifice our lives and drive VWs.
Mercedes. We drive a... Mercedes. It's...
Oh! Aren't we going to go inside?
Was he here yesterday?
Ingrid...
Tell us, or I'll stick it right in
and you'll be swallowing bullets.
Got something to say?
I don't understand a word.
He was at the bar
and then ran after Gatsky's ex.
- What's her name?
- Mel! That's all I know!
Mel. "Mel" like "Mel Gibson" or something?
-"Melanie"?
- Oh, Timmsen. You're so sweet.
Since we're talking, who's this Gatsky?
- Nobody.
- Your mom's a nobody.
Were you an item?
We get the diamonds and he gets his share.
50/50. That's the deal. Now, shut it.
-50/50?
- W hat?
- We do the dirty work and he gets 50%'?
- You're so clueless.
- And you can't negotiate.
- Shut up.
Okay, but I have
to do something first. Careful.
- Thanks.
- Welcome.
Is he being sprayed, too?
There was a hole.
Sorry.
Regarding that "nobody"...
Will he just let you 90
once you've given him his share?
- One can't leave such an association.
- Association?
- Gang, mafia... Whatever.
- He won't harm me.
Were you an item?
- It's complicated.
- Your mom's complicated.
- All that mom-talk is so awkward.
- Your mom's awkward.
I feel embarrassed for you.
- Your mom's embarrassed.
- His name is Frank and we were an item.
-50% is too much.
- You'll negotiate next time then.
Okay. Your mom's a chicken.
- I'm hungry.
- We only just ate!
What a wonk.
Yo! Melanie Rossbach.
Oh, yes. Of course. Listen up.
She was put into a home at five,
parents lost custody,
she didn't finish school, etc.
She worked for Gatsky
in one of his "security" companies.
- Is she in the system?
- No.
- Okay. You can leave now.
- Okay. Oh, she has a 5-year-old daughter.
Lucky kid.
I'll go check the workshop.
Can I leave you two alone?
Sure.
What?
Nothing.
What workshop?
Why are you still only on patrol?
Can I have some, too?
Sure.
What's your plan?
Got any gunshot wounds?
Is that why you're only a beat cop?
I don't talk about that.
Are you sad you're just a beat cop?
When this is over, want to meet up again?
We could go for dinner or to the movies.
I mean, what are your plans?
Hello.
He always does that.
When he drinks, then...
She doesn't talk to strange men.
Women can be bad, too, you know.
Yes, but I didn't like him.
Wait a sec.
Why don't you have the key on you?
- Hi.
- Detective Squad.
I'll call you back. Oh, God. Stop!
Bring in the forensic dudes.
Hello! You can't just...
Hello? Hello!
Have you even got a search thingy?
- Where's Ms. Rossbach?
- No idea.
How long have you been
looking after her kid?
What happened? I have no idea.
I'm having a mental blackout.
What's going on?
Don't touch me! Has something happened?
We met at the playground.
That was yesterday.
She paid me for looking after Holly.
Waiting for someone?
Are you going on holiday?
Did your Mom ask you not to tell anyone?
Will she be coming back?
Here's your frog.
I almost feel sorry for her.
So, she didn't mean it
and accidentally took a hostage?
- No, but take a look around.
- Quit winging.
Send her pic to every motel, hotel
and campground in and around Berlin.
How did you know I was here?
Relax. Let's go grab a bite.
Get in. Come on.
A new dress? But why?
No one watches you on TV anyway.
I bought it so I could be prepared.
We're out of candy.
There's some toffee in my pants.
...a one-of-a-kind company.
Isn't that great?
- There's some toffee in your pants?
- Yes.
Some toffee.
I don't believe in horoscopes.
Yet, you believe that a girl in Playboy...
- There's no toffee in there.
- And these are not my pants.
Let's take a look at your horoscope.
When's your birthday?
We've sat here before. Remember?
On these same seats.
This is where I first saw you.
That was a long time ago.
Made a decision yet?
I'll have your share tomorrow.
You think you can manage on your own.
Call home. The cops were there.
Enjoy your gin and tonic.
Fuck it.
- Untie my hands so I can use them.
- I like it like this.
We can run off together.
Untie me.
They all still think you're a hostage.
Do you always talk so much?
Seriously, now...
What will happen once it's over?
Think she'll take you with her?
I'm not in the mood anymore.
Sorry.
Okay, Kim. Who was there?
Kim, calm down. There's an envelope
with 1,700 euros in Holly's case.
Take Holly to Bim Bum Land
tomorrow morning with her case.
Repeat what I said. With her case.
Okay.
Put these on. We're off.
I didn't untie him.
- What are those for?
- He won't run.
Because you took his dick hostage?
- Why are you being so bitchy?
- What's the plan?
Quit it. This isn't
some sort of adventure trip!
Are you really taking her with you?
- Why are you so flustered?
- What is she to you?
- Is she your chicken?
- Chicken?
No, she's not.
- What chicken?
- To distract them and get shot instead.
- Am I your chicken?
- You're nothing to me. This was a mistake.
You don't know what it means to be needed.
You throw yourself at men.
Did your mom teach you that?
It's all mom's fault.
Why blame yourself?
You'd rather spend your life running.
That's right.
Ms. I've-Seen-It-All.
I'm not as stupid as you.
At least I put a condom on them
and don't have an abandoned child.
Hey, sweetheart. It's me.
Nice piece.
Know what one can do with it?
Give me the code to the safe.
You're quite a funny
pussy commando, aren't you?
Fuck, man! Are you nuts?
Are you crazy, you cunt?
- God! Stop it!
- The code.
I don't know it!
13-07-19-00! Shit! Fuck!
Shit! Oh, man!
- Why are they loose? Are they all there?
- Cunt!
- You've already called me that.
- You slut!
I'll get you! You cunt!
- Okay. At what time exactly?
-11 pm.
- Hey.
- Forensics are on their way.
They're useless, anyway.
They had pizza.
Stay calm. Stay calm.
I'm going to remove the tape now.
Don't scream.
You really think I'll let you go?
Hand over the diamonds.
"I'm big, strong Mel.
I can do everything alone.
I'm made of steel.
No one can help me.
Especially not someone
with a pussy name like 'Franny'.
My name is Mel, like Mel Gibson."
Oh, my God. What was that?
- What was that?
- Shit.
What happened to Mel?
Okay...
I'm unarmed.
- Nice and easy.
- Hands on the car.
We must go to her.
We have to get her out of there.
- When I say "now", start running.
- Okay.
Just run, okay? Now!
- You've been shot!
- Just a flesh wound. Come on.
Come on.
Behind that.
- Okay. Stay here.
- Okay.
Okay.
- Harry, she moved! I must go to her.
- Hey! Wait...
Get out of here! Go!
I'm here. I'm here. I'm here.
Where's your gun?
Where's your gun, Mel?
Fuck off!
Fuck off! Fuck off!
Oh, God!
Screw it.
Is he dead?
He's dead.
He's dead. Do you hear me?
It's all over.
- I'll call an ambulance.
- Okay.
- You must pick Holly up from Bim Bum Land.
- What?
You must pick Holly up from Bim Bum Land.
Ingrid, it's Leine. There's been
a shooting at the abandoned power station.
I wasn't able to until now.
Come on.
Come on. Come on.
Come on. Come on. Come on.
Why explain now? Just come here.
Come on.
Hey! Hey! Hey!
What are you doing?
- I'm getting her out of here!
- No, you're not!
You were simply a hostage.
You can just walk away.
- I'm sorry.
- What's wrong now?
We have to pick up her kid
from Bim Bum Land.
Bim Bum Land? What's Bim Bum Land?
We have to pick up her kid
from Bim Bum Land!
Put her legs in the car.
- Okay. Close the door.
- No.
I can't protect you anymore.
Shit!
This is just shit!
Timmsen!
Send their pictures to every hospital.
I want to know if two women ShOW up.
- They killed Gatsky?
- Self-defense.
- Are they working together?
- No idea.
Don't bullshit to me. Are they?
Who cares what I say?
You never listen to me.
What do you want from me anyway?
I'll call you back.
I need to get back to work.
- Happy shopping!
- I know.
- Shall I take your case?
- No.
She's coming out without the kid.
Are you hurt?
But a friend of mine is.
I need your help.
- What's up, pumpkin?
- Kinnert's mother... Isn't she a nurse?
Timmsen!
Give her one every six hours.
Keep an eye on the wound.
You need to keep an eye on it.
A doctor has to look at it.
By tomorrow. And Franziska, you...
Hey! Bingo!
An ambulance has gone missing!
Wait a sec.
- Hey, Timmsen.
- What is it?
- Give me your phone.
- Huh'?
Hey. I need you to do me a favor.
Franny?
Yes?
They know who I am.
You have to stop.
I'm not going to stop. Screw that!
I've got the diamonds.
We'll get Holly and we'll manage somehow.
I bet they've got Holly by now.
Oh, God!
Oh, God.
Highway 101 is closed off.
Get ready to raid the vehicle.
Lower your weapons!
They have to lower their weapons!
Relax. They won't shoot.
- Franny'?
- Stop bugging me. I'm negotiating.
What are you doing?
Ingrid!
The call center received a call.
It's Kinnert
and she'll only speak with you.
We need a radio here, damn it!
- Ingrid von Kaiten. Who am I talking to?
- This is Franz/ska Kinnert.
The hostage-taker wants to
talk to you alone in the ambulance
or she'll shoot me.
I'm scared.
Your mom's scared.
And the mother is involved
in a police investigation?
- Yes, but that's all I can say.
- And, if I may ask...
No! You may not. That's the thing.
What are you staring at?
Yes! Men are fathers too!
Come along.
Awesome outfit, by the way.
- You can't go in alone!
- Leine.
Can I go in there alone?
- Yes.
- Anything else you want to tell me?
Be nice.
Ingrid von Kaiten.
I'm unarmed and coming in.
What's your ideal scenario?
What's yours?
Why isn't anyone saying anything?
We can't hear anything, damn it!
It was a stupid idea! Let's go in!
Leine!
Shit!
It's showtime, ladies.
Ready?
- I hear something!
- There's a video.
He sent it to her, as a threat.
Frank Gatsky?
Yes.
I wanted out,
but he wouldn't let me go.
He blackmailed her.
Into robbing the jeweler?
Yes.
Let's go, Timmsen.
Just send the paramedics.
What? Why?
I'll fill in the gaps in the story later.
You'll still have to be arrested.
Have a lovely evening, ladies. Bye.
There's nothing there for you.
You were right. I feel sorry for Rossbach.
- But they're all loose!
- Too bad for the insurance.
They were robbed. Isn't that funny?
Yippee ki-yay.
Motherfucker...
Thank you.
Annett! Stop hiding.
You're taking over. I'm out of here.
SIX MONTHS LATER
Look who's here!
- Mom!
- Oh, my God! Come here!
You've grown so much!
- I missed you.
- Mom, I was here only yesterday.
- What's that?
- Why'?
- Are you for real?
- Yep.
Think I gave them all to Kaiten?
That's a bad deal.
I told you I never wanted
to see one again. Do you ever listen?
I earned it. I have needs.
- You're so annoying.
- Your mom's annoying.
Oh, my God!
I'll drive.
- Why did you even want them?
- To go to Sweden.
What? Sweden? Why Sweden?
- I wanted to build a campground.
- A campground?
- Yes.
- In Sweden?
- That's so corny.
- Your mom's corny.
- So corny.
Your mom's corny.
Subtitles: Georgina Avgerinou et al.
Eurotape - Nordkurier Mediengruppe - 2019
Watch Movies, TV Series & Live Sports
www.admitme.app