- Yes, Whiteacre?
- I'm sure you're not aware of it, Captain,
but Private Ackerman has been badly beaten
fighting the biggest men in the company.
Yes?
He's been seriously hurt, and I'm sure
now that you know, you'll wanna stop it.
You're quite right, Whiteacre. If I knew,
I would stop it. I'd be obliged to stop it.
- But then, I don't know.
- You know now, sir.
What's the matter with you? Ackerman
isn't one of those rich Broadway producers
you have to suck around.
He's just a dogface. Get some sense.
I think you'll have to stop it, sir.
You know, the colonel had a phone call
about you out of channels from Washington.
Very much out of channels.
To transfer you to Special Service in London.
It's up to me to approve it or disapprove it.
I still think you'll have to stop it, sir.
I know the colonel would.
All right, Whiteacre. I'll spell it out for you.
You go to the colonel,
and you won't get your transfer.
And you'll have to be five times more soldier
than any man in this outfitjust to stay alive.
Now get out.
Rickett.
Get rid of him. Today.
- Send his papers through.
- Yes, sir.
Well, I hope you're satisfied.
This makes three beatings in a row.
Almost had him, though.
- How'd he look?
- Who? Cowley?
- Yeah.
- Better than you do.
What are you tryin' to prove?
- Nothin'.
- Well, why are you tryin' to kill yourself?
I like to fight.
I'm tired of watchin' you
get your brains beat out.
Look, if you fight Brailsford,
you're on your own.
- Sorry.
- That's OK. That's all right.
- Michael, I can lick Brailsford.
- Well, I don't care.
It's important to me. It's the last fight.
- This whole thing has got you crazy.
- Maybe.
- Oh, excuse me, men.
- Yes, Lieutenant?
- I'd like to speak with Ackerman.
- Certainly, sir.
You'll be around?
Mm-hm.
Cigarette?
Thanks.
Oh. Sorry.
Ackerman, I've been watching the sick book.
You're the most... accident-prone soldier
in the entire United States infantry.
I'm careless, sir.
Saturday nights in town, you're careless.
Every Saturday night. On weekdays, you're
on the roughest obstacle course in the post.
Without stubbing your toe.
Now, why don't you level with me?
I know you're fighting. I think I know why.
This is something for the colonel to handle.
Just gimme the word.
Besides, you're getting licked.
You're no good to us punch-drunk.
I appreciate it, Lieutenant.
Thank you. But this is my business.
- Whiteacre?
- Yeah.
I been looking all over for you.
Your orders just came through.
You got 40 minutes
to make the train to Washington.
Thanks.
He's all yours, medic.
Don't fall! Don't fall! Don't fall! Don't fall!
Don't fall!
Come on.
Leave it alone.
You'll get dirt in it.
Ready! Hut!
- Attention, roll call. Abbott.
- Here.
- Acaro.
Ackerman.
Ackerman!
Any of you men seen Ackerman?
Abbott, did Ackerman
sleep in his bunk last night?
I don't know, sir. I didn't notice.
Donnelly, did he?
Eyes front, you.
Well, Donnelly?
I don't know, sir.
He's at the opposite end of the barracks.
I warn you, men, I want
a straight answer from the next soldier.
Cowley!
No, sir.
He didn't.
Nobody deserts this company!
When they find him, I don't want him
in the stockade, I want him right back here.
- He's mine.
- Yes, sir.
Gentlemen.
Your attention, please.
The briefing will begin.
Gentlemen, I will come
directly and frankly to the point.
You have heard rumours
that our position is deteriorating.
It is.
An American fleet of tremendous strength
is believed to be approaching Tunisia
to attack us from the rear. The British are
about to launch a massive frontal offensive.
The Resistance in Stalingrad
has bled our fuel and ammunition
in unexpected quantities.
We must therefore
prepare for a breakthrough.
For the present,
this information is for you only.
Air attack!
Dismissed.
- Damn you, keep awake!
- I am awake.
Well, stay that way! Talk to me!
See that you don't fall asleep.
What do you want me to say?
Anything, anything. Just talk!
All right.
How far... how far do we have to go now?
About... 400 kilometres more.
Seven hours.
I think I must sleep.
If you sleep, you'll wake up
in a British prison camp. Come on! Talk!
I wish I was in the mountains,
where it is so cool and peaceful in the snow.
So wonderful to feel the wind in your face.
Clean and nice.
And I like the smell of smoke in the winter,
coming from the wood... in the fireplaces.
Talk about something else!
Talk about women!
Women! Women!
I have a French girl - Françoise -
and I think I can love her.
- Was she beautiful?
- Yes, she was beautiful.
And I wish I was with her,
and not on this motorcycle,
because I am... I am sick of Africa.
And I am sick of the great German army.
- And I am sick of doing my duty!
- I should have shot you.
What?
I said I should have shot you!
I ought to shoot you now!
You'd better learn to drive this first.
You will destroy us!
Men like you poison an army.
You let discipline slip a little one day, a little
more the next day, and soon you are nothing!
You are not able to fight at all!
I should have shot you!
- Ja,  why didn't you shoot me, then?
- Because I was an idiot!
Yes! You recognise that you are...
you are still infected
with decent human feelings.
- Oh, shut up!
- And you hate that in yourself, don't you?!
- Shut up! Shut up!
- You hate that...
Hello.
I wanna kiss you.
Why didn't you tell me?
I couldn't.
Besides, there's a law
against harbouring deserters.
You're not a deserter. The army lawyer
told me you gave yourself up.
Are you all right?
Yes.
Noah...
you know what they're asking me to do?
Sure. Sure.
The lawyer said if you
go back to your old company,
you won't go to prison.
Mm-hm.
I'm not tryin' to tell you what to do.
You do what you have to.
Stand up.
Honey! How long is it?
- What?
- How long is it?
- Five months.
- Five months!
Why didn't you tell me?
I could've written you, I guess.
I... I had to work this out myself.
The doctor said I should
stay in bed for a while.
I did.
I guess that's why I didn't write you.
I wanted to make sure it'd be all right.
I don't want this to influence you
one way or the other.
Are you glad?
It's wonderful.
Absolutely... wonderful!
Time's up.
Don't worry about me.
I'm going back home. Don't worry at all.
I'm not worried.
Can you imagine?!
Listen.
Go to the lawyer and tell him I'll go...
anyplace they wanna send me.
- All right, soldier.
- OK?
I love you.
Not only are you a disgrace, but your actions
have caused a black mark to be made against
this company and against me personally.
I'm gonna see that you erase that black mark.
I'm gonna make a soldier out of you
if I have to break you in half to do it.
Yes, sir.
You'll get no passes.
You'll be on KP every day for the next week.
Also, you'll have the same cot
and the same men around you.
You'll have to make sure any punishments
handed out to them aren't caused by you.
Yes, sir.
Now get out of here. I don't want
to see you in this room again.
Yes, sir. Thank you, sir.
-  Captain.
- Yes?
This is Major Price. The colonel
requests that you report to his office.
I'll be right there, Major.
You wished to see me, sir?
There are many kinds of officers
that we get in a war.
Men like Green, Emerson...
and a few officers like you.
Fortunately, a very few like you.
Sometimes we find you out.
Occasionally, we don't.
In your case, we've been lucky.
I've just completed an investigation of the
reasons for Private Ackerman's behaviour.
- Sir, I can explain. You see...
- I hope you can.
I'll read you the charges that'll be brought
against you at your court martial.
"That said officer wilfully persecuted
Private Noah Ackerman
by ordering mass punishment of his entire
company as a means of disciplining him."
"By wilfully and knowingly permitting
savage beatings to be inflicted upon him
by members of his company."
"By attempting to blackmail Private Michael
Whiteacre, who interceded on his behalf."
Do you want me to go on?
I thought not. I've preferred
these charges against you,
and... I officially serve you with them now.
Hey! Hey, you guys,
I think I've just seen a ghost.
I don't see anything.
- I think it's Ackerman.
- You're crazy. He's in New York, livin' it up.
- It's somebody who looks like Ackerman.
- Nobody looks like Ackerman.
All right, you guys, make room for one more.
I've just found a pigeon with 20 bucks.
Come on, whose bet?
Five? You're outta your mind!
- Good afternoon.
- Good afternoon, Captain. May I help you?
Yes. Do you have
a Captain Hardenburg in this section?
- Yes, he's here.
- Would it be possible to see him?
- Are you a friend of his?
- Mm, yes.
- Very good. He's right in there. Go right in.
- Thank you.
- Captain Hardenburg?
- Is that you, Diestl?
Yes, sir. I was just released from my hospital
this afternoon, and I came to say goodbye.
That's very nice of you.
- Well, are you feeling any better, sir?
- Ja.
- Better each day.
- Good.
But they tell me I will be here for six months.
Six months? Well, I'm sorry
that it will be so long for you.
Why sorry?
It gives me the opportunity
to think of the future.
I plan to go into politics.
Oh, yes.
My face will be a reminder of what
I have given for the fatherland.
It will stand me in good stead...
with our audiences at public meetings.
Well...
You know, sir, that... they do
remarkable things nowadays with...
Yes, remarkable. Remarkable.
Glass eyes, plastic noses.
Reconstructed cheekbones.
I have written to Gretchen in this
kind of detail, to prepare her for it,
and she has assured me she's proud of me,
and it will make no difference.
Gretchen... is the name of my wife.
Yes, I know.
How do you know?
Ah, yes, you delivered a package for me.
She is quite handsome. Isn't she?
Yes, sir, she's quite handsome.
She will be very useful to my career.
What I would like you to do for me is...
visit her again,
to reassure her.
I know it's a great deal to ask,
to speak for a man to his wife
under these circumstances,
but I want her to hear from
a third party that I am... salvageable.
Yes, l-l-I will be glad to do that.
Thank you. Thank you, Diestl.
Now...
come closer.
Yes, sir.
Are we alone?
- Yes, except for...
- Yes, yes. It's all right.
I have one more favour to ask of you.
I want you to bring me a bayonet.
- A bayonet?
- Yes, yes. A bayonet.
- Well, I think...
- What is the matter with you?!
Not for me.
For him.
He has no hands left. Or anything left.
He wants to die. I have promised him.
He whispers to me
when we are alone.
And he can hear.
He's a watchmaker... in Nuremberg.
Specialist for stopwatches.
He has three children. And he wants to die.
Where is my hand?
Approximately over his heart.
Good.
That's where I will place the bayonet.
We have practised it every night for a week.
Come back tonight with the bayonet.
Diestl, will you bring me the bayonet?
Yes, sir.
Goodbye, Diestl.
Goodbye, sir.
Yes?
It's, uh, Christian Diestl.
Who?
Christian Diestl.
Hello.
Oh. Lieutenant.
- Yes.
- Come in.
How are you?
I'm all right. And you?
Forgive me. I must look awful,
but I haven't slept for so many weeks.
We've had so many air raids.
Come in. Excuse me.
They come over two, three times a night.
You can't imagine what it's like.
The soldiers at the front
would strike under such conditions.
I mean it. There's no heat, no light.
Oh yes.
I remember. Sit down.
Thank you.
Did you bring any food from Russia?
- Africa.
- Of course. My husband's company.
Ja.
All I have left is some kümmel.
No, no. Thanks.
Do you hear from your husband?
He killed himself.
- He what?
- He killed himself.
With a bayonet.
I have the letter somewhere.
He asked me to come here
and speak to you for him.
Perhaps it's just as well.
He wanted to come back here.
Naturally, I didn't encourage him.
I spent a whole night
composing the most tactful letter.
I told him, of course, he would be better off
in some permanent veterans' hospital.
What are you doing now? For heaven's sake,
Christian, be a little realistic.
You people are getting stranger and stranger.
Stay a little while.
Maybe I can find some vodka.
I'll make myself pretty for you.
Christian?
Christian!
- Brandt.
- Christian, how wonderful to see you again!
It's good to see you, Brandt.
- Oh no!
- I can't believe it!
It was bad, huh?
No. They moved us around
a little bit, but, you know, it's...
Listen, now-what's the matter with you,
being so near the front, Brandt? What... huh?
You know me. It was a mistake in the orders.
What are you doing here?
Are you stationed here?
No, I am waiting for transportation.
I'm trying to get to Paris.
Come on, I'll buy you a drink.
- I see you are a captain from taking pictures.
- It's an outrage. I should be a major.
You've no idea how glad I am to see you.
I'll take that,
and bring us some glasses, please.
I've been here for two days
waiting for somebody to go to Paris.
- Listen, what are you doing in Paris, Brandt?
- My headquarters are there.
This is your headquarters-with
blonde hair, who likes goose liver?
- Yeah, yeah. That's the one.
- In other words, you have no orders?
- Only a desire.
- Ja, ja.
Look, Christian, I've also managed to
acquire a little French car all my own.
- This follows naturally.
- Yes, but look.
I wouldn't last an hour before somebody
requisitioned it, but you have combat orders.
- With you, there'd be no questions asked.
- You have this car here, just...
Ja,  just near here, in a little stable.
- Well, we go now, we take the car.
- All right, let's go.
Why don't you have dinner
with Simone and me tonight, huh?
That would be very nice, Brandt,
but I think I must report.
Oh, report in the morning.
You need some rest.
- Brandt, do you ever see Françoise?
- Why, of course.
She's living with Simone now.
- She is living with Simone?
- She has been for more than a month.
Brandt, would you like to have dinner
with Françoise and me tonight?
Very nice. We'd be delighted.
Simone!
Simone?
Simone.
Darling.
It's been forever.
Hello, Françoise.
Hello.
Come in.
I'm an American officer!
Oh, my wonderful friends, I want to thank you
for this beautiful night. I love you for it.
And now, I'd like to make a little toast.
Farewell, Captain Brandt
of the army of the Third Reich!
You're drunk, darling. Say good night.
No, no, no, no. Christian understands me.
Good night, Captain Brandt.
Tomorrow you awaken to your new life:
Monsieur Brandt, citizen of the worid.
Isn't he funny? He has such ideals.
Sit down, Simone. Sit down for a minute.
Christian, I... I know you don't approve,
but listen to me for a minute.
Tell me, are we civilised human beings,
or are we wild beasts?
A human being knows when he has lost,
and he tries to save himself.
When you are put into the army,
you are expected to risk your life,
but you are not expected
to just throw it away.
After all,
in any war, Christian,
after all the arms and the legs
have been... blown off,
it doesn't really matter,
because nothing really changes.
Good night... my dear friend.
Françoise...
be good to him, ja...
because he is the best of the best.
- All right, all right.
- Ja.
Come on.
Christian.
You...
You won't report him?
No.
Thank you.
You're not the same.
When you are...
When you are in a hole...
filled with your own excrement
for days on end,
and when you see the faces
and the bodies of the men you've killed,
you change.
And when you're out there like that,
when you have to live with death every day...
for so long...
you have to keep something in front of you,
or you would go insane.
And so I was...
I was always afraid that...
I had just invented you.
Oh, but I am real.
Yes.
Christian...
please stay.
There isn't anything for you to fight for.
There never really was.
Christian...
you're not the golden warrior any more.
And soon...
you will be just another refugee.
Don't throw this away.
Please.
I think...
I think I've come too far.
What are you staring at?
The faces of the generals. I don't like 'em.
If there is one thing I cannot stand
it's enlisted men, with their air
of injured moral superiority.
They don't look like they could lead
you up the walls of a German fortress.
Don't you worry, honey. They're not gonna
lead you anyplace outside of a London bar.
- Let's not start that again.
- All right.
Go on, dear.
Whoops. Here comes another big man.
No, no, no. Sit down, sit down, soldier.
How are you, Margaret?
I'm all right, Sam. So far.
They are a little early tonight.
Oh. Private Whiteacre,
I'd like you to meet General Rockland.
Sam, huh? Nice to know you, sir.
Thank you. Come on over to the bar.
Bring your friend.
In a little while. Thank you, Sam.
How long's this been goin' on?
- Wouldn't you like to know!
- And a general, too.
Johnny One-Note.
Always criticising officers.
Always turning down promotions.
Why do you insist on staying a private?
Guilt, I guess. You know, Dr Freud
would say I'm punishing myself
because I'm stayin' outta combat.
Because I'm letting Noah Ackerman
do my fighting for me.
- If you wanna personalise it.
- Well, then, get into it.
Stop feeling so guilty.
It's getting a little sickening.
I'd rather be guilty than dead.
Go on, see Sam.
These things get any closer, I'll probably
chicken out and make a spectacle of myself.
Go on, see Sam!
Go on!
- You would, too!
- Let me go.
You stay here.
What are you tryin' to do, get yourself killed?
General, will you do somethin' for me?
Will you?
- I dunno. What is it?
- Can you send me back to my old outfit?
- Where are they?
- They're fighting in Normandy.
Well, I suppose so. Why don't you just
put in a request through channels?
I don't wanna wait that long.
All right.
- Give me your name and your serial number.
- Yes, sir.
Thank you, General.
Thank you.
Well, now you've done it!
We're practically in a foxhole right now.
- That's what you wanted, isn't it?
- Michael, you stupid idiot.
That isn't what I wanted. You don't
have to get killed to keep me loving you.
I won't get killed. Believe me,
I'll have the deepest foxhole
and the biggest helmet in the whole infantry.
No you won't. I'll talk to him.
Don't. Margaret, please.
Come here.
Now let that be a lesson to you.
Margaret, I... I have to do this.
I know I'll chicken out afterwards,
but... by that time it'll be too late.
I'm... I'm scared.
- Ah, don't be scared.
- I am. I wish I hadn't...
I'll come back. I have to come back.
How else can I marry you?
- Mornin'.
Here it is.
Also, the mail may be slow,
and I don't want you to worry.
I can't tell you where I am,
because the censors wouldn't like it.
If it's not too private, could you read it to us?
Yeah.
"The photograph was wonderful."
"I'm delighted with my little girl,
and I can see that she is a fine child,
straight of limb, quick of mind."
"I promise to return to both of you
with a whole body and a whole heart,
no matter what happens."
"I shall return to tell her stories at bedtime,
to feed her spinach, and to teach her
how to drink milk out of a glass."
"To take her out in the park, and tell her
the names of the animals in the zoo."
"To explain to her why
she must not hit little boys...
and why she must love her mother
as much as her father does."
Write me... my darling.
Write me. Write to me, please.
Write me. Love...
"Noah."
They're gettin' close.
Look, I want no firing-no matter
what happens-till they move up.
Oh, no. No shootin'. We're only
artillery observers, you know.
I can hear the old man. "You boys
go on ahead, see what we have to clear out."
"It's easy. It's like takin' a walk
on a peaceful Sunday mornin'."
What are they doin' out there
on a peaceful Sunday mornin'?
Bless you.
Mother. Mother!
Mother!
Here they come. Put your guns on 'em
and make it count. Now!
Don't bunch up down there!
Grenade!
No sense in putting it off.
We're French-fried if we stay here.
We'll have a few minutes before they
reorganise. Who wants to go first?
We'll leave by twos and threes. We'II...
dissolve the detail in twos and threes.
No need to tell you to be careful.
Well, who's goin' first?
Look, when you get through the Germans...
Well, I wish I could tell you
where our lines are.
But... don't expose yourself
till it's absolutely necessary.
You don't wanna get shot by your own men.
Somebody better go now.
- All right.
- Yeah.
I'll go too.
Ohhh!
What's... what's the matter?
It's all right. It's all right.
OK?
- What you doin'?
- What do you mean? Get your stuff off.
- Not me. I can't swim.
- Well I can't swim either.
- It can't be too deep.
- There's Krauts all around us.
- We'll sit here and wait for 'em.
- Those are our guys across there.
The minute we hit that water,
they'll spray us like sittin' ducks.
- Shut up and get outta your gear.
- I'm takin' off nothin'.
- You can't stay...
- I don't know what you're doin',
but I'm not doin' it with you.
You're nuts. I can't swim!
- Shut up!
- Get outta here.
- I'm ready.
- Let's go. I'll go first.
It's gettin' deep.
Wait... wait a second. Wait a second.
Just dog-paddle. Take it easy. OK?
Hold on to me.
Just hold on.
Hey! Not here. Not here.
Hey! Hey! Here.
Is it bad?
- No?
- No.
Don't try to move.
Hey!
Hey, you guys!
Cut it out! Cut it out!
Hey! Will you quit shootin'?!
We're Company C - Charlie Company.
There's only two of us.
And he's wounded.
Gimme a hand!
Gimme a hand, will ya?!
- You got dog tags?
- Sure I got dog tags!
- Your name?
- Ackerman. 3974287.
OK?
All right, keep your shirt on. We're coming.
Take it easy, now. Be careful.
Easy. Easy.
Thanks.
This here's Red Dog Four. Yeah, a couple
of guys from C Company just come up.
Ackerman and, uh...
- Burnecker.
- Burnecker. Burnecker's wounded.
Ackerman ain't got no clothes.
Better get some up here.
Ask him if, uh, Lieutenant Green showed up.
What about Green?
Uh-huh.
Yeah, I got ya.
Yeah, they're all OK. They just barely made it.
How was it out there?
- They're sendin' up some dry clothes for you.
- I found some schnapps. Get you warm.
Hm.
Huh?
Oh, Michael.
How'd you get here?
I have a friend that's a general. I'm pretty big
behind the lines, you know. Put these on.
What's the matter?
They're still, uh... Hey, uh...
Could one of you, uh...
pass the word down the line
to hold fire for, like, ten, fifteen minutes?
What gives?
There's a guy over there
that we left over there.
Vernon, go down the line
and tell those trigger-happy Joes
if they see a derričre in the canal,
it's one of ours.
- Who's out there?
- Cowley.
Oh, Cowley. Good.
- Yeah. Except he can't swim.
- Even better.
Look, you don't owe him anything. Nothing.
No, I don't.
You've just been out there.
There are plenty of other guys.
How about you, son? You look fat and sassy.
Wait a minute. I just got here.
Besides, I'm a coward.
Cowley?
What do you want?
- Come on, let's go.
- Will you leave me alone?!
Cowley, it's not deep.
Damn you, it's not deep!
The guys are waiting for us. Now come on!
No. No, I'm not goin'.
- OK.
- Wait.
All right, Noah?
- I'd like to speak with your commandant.
- Ja, Kapitän.
Enter, Kapitän.
- Yes?
- I was wondering if you had some food, sir.
We have no food. We have already
been cleaned out by deserters.
I am not a deserter.
My company has defected, I am without
command, and I have not eaten in two days.
Forgive me, Captain. Sit down,
pour yourself some coffee.
It's a relief to find someone who still
has some sense of discipline left.
How close are the Americans?
Well, I think they are - I don't know -
five minutes or five hours.
- I'm sorry, that's all that's left.
- Thank you.
Everything is gone.
Colonels and generals... passing by,
snatching the food out of my hands.
Throwing away their uniforms.
Unbelievable. My men are running, too.
This organisation is falling apart
in front of my eyes.
I'm sorry.
Are you hurt?
No.
I can see you had a bad time.
Well, so did I.
I have my wounds, too,
even if you don't see them.
Running a concentration camp is not a picnic.
With all the gas chambers, target ranges,
doctors with their experiments.
I had an extermination quota
of 1500 people a day.
Jews, Poles, Russians, French.
Political prisoners.
And I had only 260 men to do it.
I managed it. Then they sent memorandums,
inspectors-running, shouting.
In Auschwitz, they kill 20,000 a day.
I know who it is. It's Berlin again.
For the fourth time today.
Yes?
Yes.
Very near. A few miles.
I told you. All right, I didn't tell you.
I told whoever it was that called.
I have ten men left.
How can I kill everybody in the camp?
Don't you understand? The equipment
is not working. Nothing is working.
I don't care what they did in Buchenwald!
I am here alone, and I have no personnel left!
You know what this is, this phone call? They
want me to kill every man, woman and child
in the camp before the Americans get here.
6,000 people.
And the man who asked me to do this...
this same man will walk the streets, free.
And they will come to him, the Americans,
the Russians, and he will say
"I never heard of concentration camps."
He will say there never was a national policy
to kill 12 million people-the SS invented it.
Nobody in the government ever heard of it.
I'll be here, trying to explain to the Americans.
You know, the Americans may not
understand what they see here.
They may not know that a German officer -
our kind of officer -
does what he's ordered to do.
Well...
We at least know... what is important.
The courage to stay and face the enemy,
and the honour to be able to say
"I have done my duty for the fatherland."
What's the matter?
My God...
Captain, this is the mayor of the town
we came through on our way up here.
He says he can send
a gang of civilians in to help us.
As I was telling the sergeant, we have heard
that some of your most important generals
and newspapermen are on the way up here.
I can provide you with my townspeople,
who will help you to clean up this place so...
Yes?
Excuse me.
My name is Joseph Silverson. I am a rabbi.
Yes?
I do not wish to annoy the officer,
but I have a request to make.
Yes, what is it?
Thousands have died here.
More will die tonight, tomorrow.
I'm sorry, Rabbi, we're doing all we can.
Of course. I know that.
There's nothing to be done for them.
Nothing material. We understand that.
All efforts must be for the living.
What I am asking for is a... luxury.
Yes?
I ask to be permitted to collect all of us -
the living and... those without hope -
and hold a religious service. A service for
the dead, who have come to their end here.
There has never been
a religious service for us in this place.
Captain, I don't like to intrude. I understand
why the rabbi has made this request,
but this is not the time for it.
I'm a European. I understand things
perhaps the captain doesn't understand.
If you allow this gentleman to hold
the services, I'm obliged to warn you...
there will be riots,
the other prisoners will not stand for it,
and the generals who are coming
will not like what they see.
The, uh, the other prisoners will not stand
for it? And the generals will not like it?
That's a fact. I guarantee it.
I'm going to guarantee something myself.
I'm going to guarantee that you...
you hold your services.
I will also guarantee that machine guns
will be set up on the roofs of the buildings,
and anyone who attempts
to interfere with those services
will be fired upon by those machine guns.
And further, I guarantee that if you ever come
into this place again, I will break your neck.
That is all.
Thank you very much... sir.
Ackerman, you're not needed around here.
Go take a walk outside the camp.
Thank you, sir.
Whiteacre.
How do you feel?
Fine. Fine.
I never... Did you ever
imagine it could be like that?
No.
My father's brother died in one of those...
- Did you see them?
- The ovens?
- Yeah.
Did I ever tell you about my father?
No.
When that guy started to talk to Green...
I could've gone and blown my brains out.
- I felt the same way.
- And then...
- Green said "I guarantee. I guarantee."
- I got a lotta hope for Captain Green.
You know what? When this war's over,
Green is gonna be running the worid.
There are millions of him. Millions!
They're human beings! There are millions
of them! They're gonna run the worid!
Kraut!
Hey!
Visiontext Subtitles: Kerrie Slavin
English SDH