Who's in your urn?
Baili.
Wu Wanli,
you little bastard!
I'll tell your Dad to kick your ass!
Liu Shaoazi,
This one's for ratting me out to my Dad!
Wu Wanli,
get over here.
You have a gun?
I'm so scared.
You're quite heavy-handed.
Does it ring any bells?
Let go of me!
Little Bun,
who am I?
Qianli.
Dad!
Mom!
Qianli...
Qianli came back!
Dad,
Mom.
Baili... is gone.
Baili.
Eat.
Qianli,
you eat too.
What are you doing
Mom.
In the army?
I'm the company commander.
How many people do you command?
About 150.
You're a high official!
Yeah, a high official.
I heard from Limpy Chen down the river
that the government
allotted us 0.39 acres of land.
In 1947
when we fought in Mengyin County,
I saw a house with a front and back yard there
with flush gable roof
and purlins.
The eave can accommodate
five nests of swallows.
Our family has been floating on the water
for generations.
When we build a house there,
the villagers would certainly
see us in a new light.
Mom,
here's my subsidy.
If we start building on February 2 next year,
we can finish by the beginning of winter.
When I come back again,
we can find
a good wife for Wanli.
You're leaving again?
You're still going into battle?
Mom,
the war is already over.
There aren't any battles anymore.
No more battles.
Show me your gun.
Let me see it.
Don't point the gun at anyone.
I told you not to point the gun at anyone!
Order from the Corps Headquarters!
Attention all!
Who's Wu Qianli?
Present!
Emergency!
Your leave is canceled.
Report for duty first thing in the morning.
Roger that!
Qianli.
I'll come back by the beginning of spring.
Okay.
I'll build the house when I come back.
I want to go into battle with you.
Baili said
he and I fought enough for our family.
You don't have to join the army.
Little Bun,
wait till I come home.
Go back now.
"September 15, 1950"
"Incheon, Korea"
Since July 7 this year,
U.S. General MacArthur,
leading Marine forces,
announced war on North Korea.
In sweeping speed, U.S. Air Force
carpet-bombed the total terrain of the enemy.
Victory is estimated in the
brief span of a few weeks.
This is AFNK.
Bring in the latest news from the front.
We're close to the Yalu River
southwest factory zone.
In position,
target locked,
ready to drop.
Proceed with the mission.
Copy.
Base control, this is Blade Team.
We are over the shooting zone
crossing the Chinese border.
All targets are open,
request action to be confirmed.
Over.
Blade Team.
Just take 8 wings to the second location
Our mission is to cut off their supply line
by any means necessary.
Over.
Blade Team, copy that.
"Antung Chinese Border"
Enemy plane!
"Wolmido Island, Incheon"
Perfect photo op for the press.
Is this a part of
MacArthur's next presidential campaign?
You think he'll become president after this war?
He's already tried twice.
Not a chance.
Look, it's the puking bears.
How are you gonna get on the boat back home?
If you're gonna barf, do it out of sight.
Don't embarrass the regiment.
You remember what our regiment
did in Siberia, World War 1?
And when we helped stop the Japs
in the Philippines in World War [1?
Our legacy, man!
Don't worry, boys,
this place ain't no Normandy.
This was a cakewalk.
Let the 1st Marine Division
prance around for the reporters
and we'll show these leathernecks
what a real battle looks like.
We will take Seoul back
and make Korea whole!
And I guarantee you,
this will be a fast war.
God willing, it will be over by Thanksgiving.
General,
does making Korea whole
mean that American forces
will cross the 38th Parallel?
If this is the best thing for Korea and the world,
then God will lead our path!
Are you confident about this operation, General?
Have you underestimated Kim [I-Sung?
He has Stalin and Mao behind him.
I never underestimate my foes.
I have my track record.
A stellar 1st Marine Division
and the best damn generals and soldiers
on the face of God's green earth.
I believe we will succeed.
I reckon we will have this
wrapped up well before Thanksgiving.
General,
you read my mind.
"BEIJING October 4, 1950"
September 15 to 19,
over 70,000 well-equipped U.S. soldiers
landed on Incheon.
By September 28,
the Korean People's Army
retreated to the North of the 38th Parallel.
The more serious matter is,
MacArthur visited Taiwan
as early as July 31.
According to our reports,
the 13th U.S. Air Force
will enter and be stationed in Taiwan.
This is the biggest
move of the U.S. in that aspect
since the 7th Marine Fleet
put a lockdown on Taiwan
on June 26 this year.
This is a complete violation of
the statement that the U.S. government issued
on January 5 this year.
On October 3,
which was yesterday,
the 1st Cavalry Division and the 24th Division
of U.S. Ground Forces
were completely assembled
and ready to head north
across the 38th Parallel at any time.
This completely crossed our bottom line.
Did you all hear that?
If they cross the 38th Parallel,
are they going to cross the Yalu River too?
In fact, by being stationed in Taiwan,
the U.S. army has already invaded our territory.
They are now assembling forces
on the Korean Peninsula
and threatening our national security.
"October 5, 1950"
"3.00 AM"
Uncle Peng.
Anying,
is the Chairman asleep?
Not yet.
Dad guessed you would be here
and told me to wait for you at the door.
"Library of Chrysanthemum Fragrance”
Come in.
A number of battleships will be deployed
to join the United States Seventh Fleet.
Chairman.
Meanwhile, America will strengthen its
military power in Taiwan.
Peng,
you're still awake?
What do you think about this situation?
I want to hear your thoughts first, Chairman.
The country is newly established
and thousands of things are waiting to be done.
If it's for our current situation,
I really don't want to fight this war.
But if it's for the future
and the peaceful development
of our country over a few decades or a century,
we must fight this war.
The foreigners look down upon us.
Pride
can only be earned on the battlefield.
I agree.
I support your decision to aid Korea.
I'm relieved.
Chairman,
I'm thinking,
we should have an army
on the eastern front as well.
It can be stationed at the Lake Changjin
to fight against the U.S. army.
Uncle Peng.
Let me guess.
I know what you want to say.
Let me be your first soldier,
Chief Commander Peng.
You have two brothers.
One of them is lost
and still yet to be found
in Shanghai,
right?
Yes,
in Shanghai.
The other one is sick.
You are the only one
who can stay by your father's side now.
Uncle Peng.
That's why you really shouldn't go, son!
Hundreds of thousands of civilians' children
are going off to war on one command.
Why shouldn't I go?
Peng,
let him
go with you.
Right now, the most important thing
is that on our western flank,
I Corps with the 1st Cavalry and 24th Divisions
will cross the 38th and take Pyongyang.
Mother, this is Fortune 7 Squadron Leader,
heading 359-er.
We've reached our IP.
Beginning bomb run at Target "Cast Iron".
Time over the target, estimated one minute.
In the meantime, the current plan
calls for us to take the port city of Hungnam
and drive north-west to the Yalu River.
Keep in mind
we'll be separated from our forces
at the Lake Changjin.
The U.S. Army marched north
and crossed the 38th Parallel.
The Yalu River is right in front of them.
If we ignore them,
our domestic and foreign enemies
would think we are weak and gullible.
We are in the same boat.
The comrades of Korea are asking for our help.
Thus,
throw out one punch now
to avoid a hundred punches in the future.
I declare
to appoint Comrade Peng Dehuai
as the Chief Commander of the
Chinese People's Volunteer Army
as well as the Political Commissar
to lead the army on this operation abroad.
"Eastern Front U.S. Temporary HQ"
Gentlemen,
our tanks have crossed the 38th
and our enemies have been overwhelmed.
Seems to me that victory has been set in stone.
It's time for us to plan our next move.
General,
the Air Force has taken control of the air space.
The 10th Corps has taken Hungnam Harbor
and we're ready to advance the Yalu River.
Sir, did the president really order us to
proceed to the Yalu?
Mr. Truman doesn't send orders,
only suggestions.
So what about Communist China?
They've deployed their soldiers
and they're attacking our boys.
How should we respond to this preemptive warning
and their actions?
General Walker,
we command well-trained soldiers,
not peasants.
If we're to end this war,
we must strike while the iron is hot.
"Volunteer Army HQ Taeyu-dong, Korea"
Commander,
we received a telegram.
The U.S. mechanized forces continued to
head north at a rapid pace.
If this carries on,
the enemies will soon be right at our doorstep.
Commander Peng,
the U.S. 1st Marine Division has already
landed at Wonsan.
Their division commander Major General Smith
is leading their 25,000 heavily-armed soldiers
to assemble from the eastern front
toward the Lake Changjin.
They want to form a pincer attack
with their forces on the western front
to achieve their goal of
fully occupying Korea.
Report to the Chairman immediately.
I intend to gather our forces on
the western front first
to defend against the U.S. army.
At the same time,
request the Central Military Commission
to send the strategic forces to Korea immediately
and block the enemy
at the Lake Changjin on the eastern front.
Yes.
Send a telegram to Commander Peng
explaining that Kanggye and the Lake Changjin
should be taken care of by
Song Shilun's 9th Corps.
Their mission is to lure the enemy in
and seize the chance to annihilate them.
How many Type 38 Rifles do we have?
Sixteen.
What about Sten 99s?
We got them all.
Bring them all back.
Yes.
Company Commander,
Yu Congrong is brawling with some people.
With whom?
People from the Artillery Battalion.
Don't move.
Speak louder!
I can't hear anything.
You just do not capable.
Get down.
Yu Congrong!
Yang,
what's going on?
Battalion Commander Yang said...
Be quiet!
Company Commander.
Battalion Commander Yang said
the battle in Chenguan Village
caused the 7th Company
to have too many casualties.
It's no big deal even if we won.
If it wasn't for the Artillery Battalion,
we couldn't even enter the battlefield.
They should be
taking the credit for the victory.
Battalion Commander Yang,
our 7th Company seized
8 out of the 11 cannons
for your Artillery Battalion.
We supported you,
didn't we?
You are really something.
What a great honor to end up with
SO many casualties!
What did you say?
Wu Qianli!
What are you doing?
Attention!
Division Commander,
we are planning a party
with the Artillery Battalion.
Stop fooling around,
the Commander is here.
Attention!
Commander,
I'm Wu Qianli,
Company Commander of the 7th Company.
I've heard of you.
The hero of our 9th Corps.
Your 7th Company is quite famous.
People call you the 7th Interpenetrating Company.
The Corps' Party Committee
was supposed to issue a pennant to you,
but now it'll have to wait
until the end of the war.
Yes!
Salute!
At ease!
Comrades,
I met a boy
here today.
He insisted that your Division Commander
allow him to enlist in the army.
The Division Commander asked him,
"Why do you want to be a soldier?”
He said,
"My Dad said
the Communist Party
and Chairman Mao
allotted land to our family.
But someone is here
to take the land away from them.
We can't let that happen.”
That's how it is.
We just triumphed over the entire nation.
Before we even had time to rest,
the imperialist U.S.
started a war with Korea
at our northern border.
They intend to spread the heat of war
to our newly established China.
What should we do?
Fight!
That's right!
Chairman Mao and Chief Commander Zhu
ordered our 9th Corps
to head north,
resist U.S. aggression, aid Korea,
and defend our country!
Resist U.S. aggression and aid Korea!
Defend our country!
Go, go, go!
Our troops will run toward the sun.
Standing on our motherland's ground,
we are the hope the people long for.
Nobody can shoot us down.
Wu Qianli!
Present!
Bring the 7th Company back.
Yes!
He's the boy the Commander just mentioned.
He said he's Wu Qianli's little brother.
I'll hand him to you.
Yes!
Get in there!
How did you find this place?
I secretly followed you.
How did you find the Division Commander?
He must be a high official if he's in a car.
You stopped the Division Commander's car?
I want to be a soldier.
Do Mom and Dad know?
No.
Get out of here!
Go.
All companies to the designated location!
Load the supplies!
One, two, three, four!
Mark time!
141 soldiers should have
reported to the 3rd Company.
130 soldiers actually reported for duty.
The rest are on their way back.
258 soldiers should have
reported to the Artillery Battalion.
221 soldiers actually reported for duty.
157 soldiers should have reported
to the 7th Interpenetrating Company.
Commander!
Mei Sheng from the 7th Company reports for duty.
157 soldiers should have reported
to the 7th Interpenetrating Company.
157 soldiers actually reported for duty.
Fall in!
Yes!
Company Commander,
I need to pee.
Report before you speak.
If you need to pee,
do it here.
Qianli.
Company Commander,
I can do it now!
Don't touch me.
Go away.
You already left the army. Why are you back?
Someone might feel uneasy without me.
You mean me?
I read the newspaper as soon as I got home.
Luckily,
I haven't filed the paperwork for my discharge.
I rode the bike for 12 hours
to get back here.
You should give me a massage when we're aboard.
Sure.
What are you doing?
Wait!
Someone seize him!
Order!
All units on board!
Yes!
On board!
Wu Wanli,
get down!
This way!
Hurry!
Over there.
Company Commander.
Here.
Get up there.
Come on,
Everyone here?
Yes!
"The 9th Corps will head to China-Korea Border"
"after training and consolidation in Shandong.”
That new recruit will be listed
under the Artillery Platoon.
Make an entry and register him later.
No.
We are not short of soldiers.
His name is Wu Wanli.
Please instruct him.
We are about to go into battle.
How am I supposed to teach him?
Teach him the same way
as you taught me.
Teach him how to survive.
Lei.
You stay with Platoon Leader Lei.
What are you looking at?
Why?
Are you shy?
Why do you want to be a soldier?
So my brother will take me seriously.
What are you talking about?
You're only tough enough
when your enemies take you seriously.
When will I get my gun?
You want a gun?
Seize one for yourself on the battlefield.
Isn't that right?
Yes.
Congrong.
Ping He, take this.
Your daughter?
Eight years old.
Four plus four equals seven to her.
Why did you bring back all your medals?
You're afraid of losing them?
If I leave these in Shanghai,
my family will miss me so much.
My wife rode her bike for
over 100 li to send me off.
She cried all the way.
She asked me when I would come home.
My parents
didn't persuade me to stay at all.
I promised them I would go home by Spring
to build a house for them.
He's too serious. Stop teasing him.
Come on,
little brat.
Let me introduce everyone to you.
My name is Yu Congrong,
The 1st Platoon Leader of the
7th Interpenetrating Company.
The enemies are usually ahead
when other people charges.
When I charge,
the enemies are ahead,
behind,
and all around me.
How's that?
Don't grab for a weapon.
You must regain the respect you lost on your own.
The person I'm introducing next is
the Artillery Platoon Leader.
I'm Lei.
Baili and Qianli
are all trained under him.
Remember,
in the 7th Company,
he's the daddy.
He's Daddy Lei.
Call him Daddy Lei.
We're going to battle again.
What are you thinking?
What about you?
The reoccurring fear of the battlefield
is just like what's written in the books,
the fear you feel as a new recruit.
It feels
just like that.
Stop fighting
if you can't win.
Let go of me!
I'll Kill him!
The one behind you is
our sharpshooter, Ping He.
Attention!
Get back here!
Where are we?
The 7th Interpenetrating Company!
The 7th Company
isn't supposed to be like this.
Am I in the wrong carriage?
I asked Yu Congrong
to test his character.
Qianli.
They are bullying me.
Bullying you?
Fight back then!
They outnumber me.
All the enemies the 7th Company comes across
outnumber us by a few times.
Can you go tell the enemies
that they outnumber us?
We're now holding an enlistment ceremony
for Comrade Wu Wanli.
Salute!
At ease!
Yu Congrong.
Here!
You're a seasoned comrade.
Tell Wu Wanli
how Company Commander Wu Baili passed away.
Yes.
Company Commander Wu Baili
actively attacked the enemy
with a small group of soldiers at Huaihai.
After overtaking the enemy bunkers,
he passed away
while protecting his comrades-in-arms.
What did the 7th Company do
after he died?
The 7th Interpenetrating Company
annihilated
and took captive
the enemy soldiers that
outnumbered them by six times.
The enemy bunkers that were supposed to
hold up our troops for over a year
only held up the 7th Company
for half a day.
Our frontline lies
behind enemy lines.
We may lose many, but because of that sacrifice,
the entire army's casualties are minimized.
We shouldn't brag about this.
The most important thing is to hang on.
We cannot be careless.
The U.S. army we are going to face
has the best equipment in the world.
This battle
will be extremely arduous.
But we need to strive for victory.
Do you understand,
Wu Wanli?
Wu Wanli,
you are now
the 677th soldier
of the 7th Interpenetrating Company.
You might say,
"There aren't so many people.
There are only over 100 here."
We are counting every soldier
since the establishment of the 7th Company,
including those who have died
or been discharged from injuries.
And now you are one of us.
I'm the 135th soldier
of the 7th Interpenetrating Company,
Mei Sheng.
The 221st soldier,
Yu Congrong.
The 280th soldier,
Ping He.
The 335th soldier,
He Changgui.
The 572nd soldier,
Li Chizheng.
The 657th soldier,
Liu Zhiyi.
The 533rd soldier,
Ba Long.
The 565 rd soldier,
Xuan Qiang.
The 162nd soldier,
Wu Qianli.
The 161st soldier,
Wu Baili.
The 17th soldier,
Lei Suisheng.
What about you?
Let me tell you again.
There is no need.
He will remember when it's time.
I just wish he would...
I don't wish anything from him.
Wu Wanli,
you're afraid the seasoned soldiers
won't accept you.
let me tell you.
You will only know whether they accept you
when you get on the battlefield.
An egg that's been cracked from the outside
is destined to be eaten.
If you can crack the egg from the inside,
you might be an eagle.
I have an announcement:
due to Comrade Wu Wanli's violation of discipline
and the disturbance he caused,
the original plan
for the weapon presenting ceremony
has been canceled.
Dismissed!
I quit!
You never wanted me to be a soldier.
Fine,
I'll leave!
Wu Wanli
Stop moving!
Don't stop me!
Do you want to die?
Stop moving!
You will stand right here as your punishment
until the morning.
Take this.
Your brother agreed.
Remember,
never point the gun at your own people.
You'll take the bunk on top of mine.
Let's go.
The Company Commander told me
to stand until the morning.
It's not time yet.
You and your two brothers
are all so stubborn!
Bun...
So good.
Time to eat!
Hey, what are you doing?
Bullets.
Go away!
You didn't give me any bullets yet.
Where are the bullet heads?
I'll give them to you when we get to Korea.
Don't forget.
"Ji'an East Station Chinese Border"
Station Master,
where did you lose your arm?
Jinzhou.
Squad Leader!
Cut that out.
What do you want? Out with it.
I heard it's extremely cold across the river.
That's all you're wearing?
Why didn't you change into
padded uniforms in Shenyang?
There weren't enough.
Otherwise, we wouldn't need to bother you.
This is all of the insignias and badges
for all the officials and soldiers
of the 7th Interpenetrating Company.
We are turning them in by order.
If you can stay for two more days,
the 50,000 padded uniforms will arrive.
Let me, let me.
The 7th Interpenetrating Company is ordered
to transport 20 radio transmitters to Korea
and wait for orders there.
We guarantee that we'll complete the mission!
Wu Wanli,
look.
U.S. aircraft!
It's a U.S. aircraft!
A scout aircraft.
Get on board!
Thanks, bro!
The padded uniforms!
Take the padded uniforms!
Yu!
Let's go!
Hurry!
The padded uniforms!
Let's go now!
Hurry!
7th Company, get on board!
Get on board now!
Hurry, hurry!
- Where's Wu Wanli?
- Wu Wanli!
- Hurry!
- Get on board!
- Is everybody present?
The 2nd Platoon present!
The 3rd Platoon present!
Company commander, look!
Take the Padded uniforms!
Hold on!
Padded uniforms!
Get back!
Don't come anymore!
It's dangerous!
Catch them!
Watch your step!
That's enough! Don't throw any more.
Caution!
Padded uniforms!
Catch them!
Thank you!
Take care.
Get back!
Thank you!
Qianli,
I saw someone who was killed by a bomb.
Without the radio transmitters,
we can't communicate with the central government
or the frontline troops.
Just like if we don't have maps,
there's no way to fight a war.
Commander Peng,
the additional military radios
have been loaded onto the train at Ji'an.
The 9th Corps is responsible
for escorting them to the volunteer army.
What about the cipher clerks?
They will arrive at the same time.
"China-Korea Border Yalu River Bridge"
Why did the train stop?
Track repairing ahead.
Rest on the spot for 30 minutes!
Take a 30 minutes break. Alright.
Comrades, time is valuable!
Come on!
Speed up.
Who is that?
Tan Ziwei, the 3rd Battalion's commander.
He's from our company.
He's the 160th soldier.
He enlisted at the same time as Baili.
Baili?
Yes.
He used to be the sharpshooter of our company.
An undefeatable hero.
Battalion Commander,
the Division Commander wants to see you.
Platoon Leader,
are we there?
Yes, we just passed the Yalu River.
What?
The bullet heads.
Oh, that.
I'll give them to you when
we get on the battlefield.
Come on, come to the back with me.
They are all sharpshooters.
Who's better, Ping He or him?
Who's better, your brother or him?
Nonsense, I have two brothers.
Two against one.
What's that?
Not gonna tell you.
I've just spotted a troop train.
Wheelhouse, this is Summer 19.
We spotted a train loaded
with North Korea troops
stopping in the valley.
Get inside now!
All units get on board
and get equipped!
All companies grab supplies
and get off the train!
Decentralize and spread out in battalions!
Take cover and cut through Nangnim Mountains
and reassemble at the Lake Changjin!
Take the radio transmitters first,
cipher soldiers get off the train now!
How are you on ordnance?
I've still got a few GPs left over.
Drop them on the train,
eliminate that target.
The other two twenty-sixes can return to K-2.
Wanli,
go grab the food rations!
Retreat!
Retreat from the train!
Stop unloading! Retreat!
Hurry! Hurry!
Shan, take some more!
Okay.
Wanli,
stop taking supplies, go!
Wanli!
Qianli!
How can you run
while carrying this much?
Toss them!
Toss them now!
You want to be the target?
Heading 185, altitude 350.
Maries are armed.
Check the gears.
Instructor,
our radio transmitters and
cipher soldiers are fine.
Great.
The enemy planes
will patrol this area for sure.
There are few plants and
no shelters nearby.
The most urgent thing is
to find a place to hide first
and then continue marching in the dark.
After crossing this river,
there should be places to hide.
To make it fast,
this is the only route we can take.
On guard, 1st Squad.
The rest take a break.
Wanli,
why are you keeping so many shell cases?
Platoon Leader said he'll give me the bullet heads
when we get to the battlefield.
He lied to you.
This is just a bunch of useless shells.
Really?
Why would I lie to you?
Great marksmanship!
That's nothing.
You haven't seen me skipping stones.
Did Platoon Leader bully you again?
When I first join the Company,
he bullied me a lot.
Let me tell you,
his right ear is nearly deaf
because of explosions.
I always scold him near it.
You should try.
Such a liar,
hope you get burnt by the cigarette.
You bastard!
Platoon Leader.
Company Commander is looking for you.
Wait for me here.
Apologies.
My mistake.
It's the left ear.
Don't be mad anymore.
You're really something.
Of course.
Each platoon shall
proceed in the 466 battle formation.
Protect the radio transmitters and cipher soldiers
in between the 2nd and the 3rd platoons.
Fighter planes!
In which direction?
Right ahead of us.
We don't have time!
Take cover!
Get down!
Don't move
or we'll all die!
They're back.
Did they notice us?
500 meters.
350 meters.
200 meters.
We can't shoot!
With an altitude of 30 m and north wind,
I can hit it.
I believe you.
But the other one will call for more fighter planes.
Damn it Dutch, let's call it.
I'm not seeing anything moving down there.
I'm starting to worry about
ice forming around my cannons.
Hey,
you see those stiffs?
How about a gun run?
Haha,
10 bucks says I strafe"em better!
Alright!
They made a turn.
You owe me 10, Dutch!
Damn it!
Again, make it 50!
How far have we gone?
We can't die here!
Come on,
let's kill those bastards!
I'm gonna Kill you!
Come on!
The 1st and the 2nd Platoons, take the right.
The 3rd and the 4th Platoons, take the left.
Follow my orders!
Escort the radio transmitters
and cipher soldiers away first!
Roger!
Groundhog 2, Groundhog 4, this is Groundhog Leader.
Form on me.
7th Marines TAC-P reported troop
concentrations South of the 25-Northing.
Solid copy.
Live targets this time!
Let's tear them up!
You got it!
How are the radio transmitters and cipher soldiers?
8 damaged and 12 still usable.
Luckily, the cipher soldiers are all fine.
A soldier should never put his gun on the ground.
What is this?
I'm not telling you.
Qianli,
Zhang Xiaoshan has died.
You'll experience things like this
very often in the future.
Where's his hometown?
Yimeng Mountain in Shandong Province,
Linyi City,
Gu Town.
He is two months younger than you.
Let's go.
We might encounter enemies ahead.
Don't be a show-off.
"Nangnim Mountains"
Sir, I am not detecting any
radio transmission activity here.
Impossible!
With that many Chinese soldiers on the move,
they have to be communicating with each other.
I know they're down there.
This is the last grid square we haven't covered.
One o'clock. Fly lower to take a look.
Wing 2, you take the east side of the valley.
Open the door.
Sir,
the wind is too strong out there.
Open the door!
Lieutenant, take us lower!
Negative, sir!
It's too dangerous!
Lower!
Give me the camera.
Lieutenant, take us to the next zone!
Stop!
Company Commander,
there's gunfire on the other side of the mountain.
Notify the Political Instructor.
Roger.
Looks like it's our comrades.
It's our comrades indeed.
They are pinned down by the Americans.
The enemies are so powerful.
If we don't help,
they won't survive for more than 20 minutes.
You two keep going with the radio transmitters
to Taeyu-dong.
Make sure you arrive on time.
Yu Congrong, Ping He,
and the 1st Squad stay with me here.
Give me one of your Artillery Squads.
I will have 3rd Artillery Squad follow you.
Let me join the fight.
This is the first time we fight
head-to-head with the U.S. Army.
I should be here.
Plus, I've studied English for
two years by myself.
Request approved.
Fire!
Move back! Move back!
Attack!
Cover them!
Where's my M20, goddammit!
Fire!
Move! Move back!
Move back!
Go get the higher point
and take out the mortars!
Attack!
Ji Chungeng from the 6th Company
of the 172nd Regiment!
This is Wu Qianli from the 7th Company,
the 1st Storming Regiment.
Our mission is to blow up the U.S. signal tower,
cut off the connection between U.S. frontline
and headquarters in Lake Changjin!
The enemy firepower is too fierce
and we are suffering heavy casualties!
Our dynamiter was Killed right
by the cowshed in front of the tower.
Platoon Leader,
Wu Wanli disappeared!
Tell them to stop ahead.
Yes.
Everyone stop!
Is he falling behind?
Like hell he's falling behind!
That little bastard!
Lei,
listen.
These are reinforcement troops.
What should we do?
We can't let them pass.
Stop them right here.
Arrange for one team to escort the
radio transmitters and cipher soldiers ahead.
Tanks have limited sight.
We'll occupy the commanding heights.
The tanks can't touch us there.
The mortars need to concentrate firepower
and take out their troop carriers first.
Why are you here?
Don't come up here!
- There's another one, get him!
- Where?
Two o'clock, keep shooting!
Who told you to come up here?
Get inside, now!
Yu Congrong!
Yes, sir!
Let's go get the dynamite pack!
Roger!
Ask the rest to set the defense
and save the wounded!
Hurry! Go there!
Ye, the knife!
Platoon Leader.
Take cover!
Fire!
Ambush from the hill!
Strike!
Fire!
Find some cover,
get me the positions of those gook mortars!
Move! Move!
Retreat! Retreat!
Lure them up the hill!
Grenade! Hurry!
Go!
Yu Congrong!
I'm okay!
Ah!
Don't come over!
Go!
I'll go divert them!
Listen for my gunfire!
Roger!
Watch your back!
Instructor, problem solved.
Stab him!
Stab!
Yu Congrong!
Cover me, I am going after him.
Grenade!
Come here!
Crouch down and don't move!
Hurry up!
Over here!
Stay low.
Stevens!
Nine o'clock, take them out!
Got it!
Company Commander!
You stay right here and don't go out there.
Remember!
Here's the grenade.
Count to five and release it.
Okay.
Keep up the rate of fire!
Get ready.
One, two, three!
In the air?
One more time!
Yu, take your man and go blow up the signal tower!
Yu Congrong!
Hey Third, push up the embankment!
Push up, push up the embankment!
Move! Move!
Chaos Company,
assault through the ambush!
Tank 1-1 and 1-2
push to the tower!
Go to hell!
Goddamnit!
My bow gun is jammed!
Company Commander!
Company Commander Wu, two U.S. tanks
and a dozen infantry soldiers
are heading this way!
Yu Congrong, the U.S. tank we seized from
the Battle of Southern Shandong,
do you still remember how to use it?
Yes!
Shit, I can't see anything!
Me neither, what was that?
Stop!
Hang on tight!
I can't stop it.
Ah!
You okay?
I am fine.
Let's get out.
43...
26,
27...
36,
37,
38,
39...
Attack!
Watch out!
Run!
Shit, we gotta get out of here!
Go! Go! Go!
It's Daddy's fault.
I hope our next generation
no longer has to live through war.
Why didn't you abide by orders?
How can you come here on your own?
I want to be with you.
That's your reason?
Because you're my brother.
Are you hungry?
In the army,
you must abide by orders.
Your comrades-in-arms might die
for your mistake if you act on your own.
Do you understand?
Go write a self-criticism.
What's self-criticism?
"U.S. Airport Hagaru-ri, Eastern Front”
Hagaru-ri HQ,
Whirlybird 1, over.
Go ahead, Whirlybird 1.
Where do you want us to set down? Over.
Go to Pan 1, over.
Received, out.
Attention!
At ease.
Sir, here is the report.
Sir,
General Almond is here.
Attention!
General Oliver Smith,
what the hell is that airstrip out there?
I'm building an airport.
Because it's essential if I'm gonna be responsible
for all the lives here.
One coffee.
It's a fatal mistake to fight a war
without the will to win it, period!
Take a look outside, General.
Our soldiers are trapped between
hellish mountain ranges
and freezing temperatures.
And now, we have reports
of hostile Chinese in the Yunshan.
Your orders were to move forward!
This is not gonna be the fast war
that MacArthur expected.
This war is on a schedule!
And your task is to keep it,
Smith!
On the subject of tasks,
I'm the chief of this task force,
Edward.
Where's the coffee?
When this all ends,
you are going to face the consequences.
Yes,
we all will, Edward.
We all will.
November 25,
my men will be up on the western line.
And if you don't show up,
I will have you scalped!
I will scalp you with my own hands!
One lump of sugar, sir?
Ping He, Changgui.
Standby.
Are you guys hungry?
Of course.
Bear with it.
Our own people.
I see that.
Senior Officer,
the 7th Interpenetrating Company is here
to deliver 12 radio transmitters
and 4 cipher clerks by order,
please check them.
Li, show the cipher clerks in first.
Yes.
Comrades, bring the radios in.
Yes!
Guys, come with me.
Liu, take them to get some rest.
Yes.
Thank you, Senior Officer.
Wu, please come with me.
Thank you.
Let's go.
Ouch!
You won't die.
What are you writing?
Yu, Yu!
Comrades,
let me read it for you all.
It's Comrade Wu Wanli's self-criticism report.
No, no,
it's a self-O report.
I didn't listen to Leader Lei's O.
I went to O my brother.
I O. I won't do it again.
Political Instructor,
our little comrade is growing up.
Nice attitude,
but there's no sign and it doesn't count.
Sign it then.
If you peck and crack the egg from the inside,
you may have a chance to lay more eggs.
Get out of here!
And you.
You little bastard,
who are you to make fun of someone else?
Comrades,
Comrade Yu Congrong
was so afraid that he peed his pants
the first time he went into battle.
It was me who washed his pants for him.
I can testify to that.
Everyone, leave your ripped
or dirty clothes here.
Change into these clean clothes.
Thank you for your concern, comrades.
You've worked hard.
Dachuan,
pick out three clean uniforms
and take the cotton out
to make first-aid pads.
Share the rest with our comrades.
Wounded soldiers have priority.
Yes, wounded soldiers have priority.
Working on that little house of yours again?
If I can't come back,
hand this to my parents.
They can't read.
Ask the teachers in the village
to read it for them.
This is taboo.
Change it. Cross it out.
You didn't have that little triangle
on the diagram before.
What is it?
I buried Baili there.
Let me see it.
This is nice. This is nice.
Comrade, do you have enough to eat?
Yes.
We have more here if you want.
Yu,
how many Americans does one
have to kill to be a hero?
Just two?
Add a 0 behind it.
I have to kill 20 to be a hero?
You are already a hero
if you've been on the battlefield.
Who is he?
Are you staying at my house or not?
No.
You have no one at your hometown
in Yimeng Mountain anyway.
If you live with me,
you can take Baili's room.
You can get married
and have two kids there
with your future wife.
It looks like a pigsty.
I'm not going.
It's good if it's a pigsty.
Lei,
if you raise pigs,
you can live a good life.
Plus,
there's food and accommodation.
You'll live a happy life.
Fine, I can go.
Political Instructor,
which one is Company Commander Wu?
Come on.
Commander Wu,
he is looking for you.
Hi, Commander Wu.
Hi.
I'm Secretary Liu from HQ.
Hello.
It's been tough for you.
It's my duty.
But your company is departing again.
We received a telegram from our superiors.
The eastern and western fronts will start
a general assault together.
The superiors ask the 7th Company
to arrive at the 1100 highland in
Sinhung-ni of the Lake Changjin.
When should we leave?
Attention, all.
In 5 minutes, we will be leaving.
Get ready for departure.
Yes!
Hundreds of thousands of civilians' children
are going off to war on one command.
Why shouldn't I go?
Peng,
let him
go with you.
"The 9th Corps heads to Lake Changjin"
"The 9th Corps Frontline HQ Chengfang-dong, Korea"
" -31 ° c "
Order from HQ,
before we arrived at the designated location,
Execute standard radio silence procedures.
Did we send the padded uniforms
to the combat units yet?
No.
Without air supremacy,
it's very difficult to guarantee logistic support.
Plus, our fleet suffered a bomb attack again.
Tao Yong,
we must find any means possible
to send the padded uniforms
to our frontline units ASAP!
We can't let our soldiers freeze to death
on the battlefield.
How many days will our food ration last?
If we eat one potato a day,
it would last us to Sinhung-ni at the most.
We should find a way to save some
for the wounded soldiers.
Take these potatoes.
Okay.
Take them.
"November 23, 1950"
No cutting, wait your turn.
Get out of here.
Come on... I just want bacon.
Pass them.
Here's a soft one.
So much for Donald Duck home by Thanksgiving.
He sent his Christmas wish list instead.
I don't have a goddamn thing
to be thankful for this Thanksgiving.
That's some list,
but all I want to do is go home.
Qianli,
can I ask why you always bullied me
when I was little?
Did 1?
Yeah.
Mom used to give me
all the good things to eat.
Once you were born,
that wasn't for me.
Ping He,
do you still want to tell the truth about Baili?
Keep it in your heart.
Watch it, old man.
Sir, we have news from the Air Force.
My family makes cheese broccoli for Thanksgiving,
you want to come and join us next year at home?
I will, man.
If we make it home.
Attention!
At ease.
Sir.
With no signs of our enemy,
our pilots reported there
was signal interference
every time they flew over this area.
Here?
Yes, sir.
"November 25, 1950"
I don't believe it!
You have to leave!
Deng Hua!
Shut off the radios!
Yes!
Shut off all the radios!
Gao Ruixin!
Here!
Did you bring the map?
Yes.
Let's go.
The enemy planes are here!
- Retreat immediately!
- Hurry!
Get into the air-raid shelter!
Hurry!
- Boy.
- Hurry!
Those in the back, keep up!
Coming!
Hurry, keep up!
What's wrong?
Hurry, hurry!
There's still a map on the wall.
We don't have a lot of large-scale maps.
Take this!
Second Squad,
proceed with the mission.
Commander,
we lost communication with Taeyu-dong.
Chief Commander Peng,
these were left behind by the martyr,
Secretary Liu.
Deputy Commander Deng,
we don't have any info about Secretary Liu.
Who was he?
What was his full name?
Deng Hua.
The day after tomorrow,
which is November 27, 1950,
the 9th Corps will begin their general assault
at the Lake Changjin.
Do they...
Do they know what to do?
Yes.
Give me a new command post!
Yes!
Currently... the 38th, 39th, and 40th Corps
have already assembled at the Chongchon River.
You must complete deployment at the
Lake Changjin war zone quickly.
In two days,
the eastern and western fronts will begin
their general assault at the same time.
Song Shilun, remember.
Remember!
Strike them as hard as you can!
The 20th Corps shall separate
and surround the enemies
in Koto-ri, Yudam-ni, and Hagaru-ri.
Make sure the 27th Corps focuses their firepower
to annihilate the U.S. army in Sinhung-ni.
Yes!
After the 27th Corps destroys
two large clusters of enemies,
immediately destroy the airport in Hagaru-ri
and cut off the enemy's aerial communication.
Yes.
Meanwhile, stop the enemies
from reinforcing the north.
Yes.
Where is the 27th Corps right now?
They've already reached the designated location.
Command the 27th Corps to take cover and stand by
so that we can prevent the enemy
from escaping south
Where is the 26th Corps now?
According to the original plan,
they are 100 kilometers outside of Koto-ri.
Command the 26th Corps to
immediately march 50 kilometers
towards Lake Changjin.
Yes.
The 20th and 27th Corps
immediately get ready for the battle
and act simultaneously with the western front.
Begin the general assault
at 4:30 pm on the 27th!
Yes!
What is the lowest temperature tonight?
40°c below zero.
We are not only fighting against the Americans.
We are also fighting against God.
General, we have reports of
Chinese attacking in division strength
in both Tokchon and Nyongwon.
That's far more than G2 has estimated.
Four other outfits are
also being decisively engaged.
The entire front is under heavy attack, sir.
Where do they come from?
Do they fall out of the goddamn sky?
We don't know sir, but the reports are pouring in.
"Lake Changjin, Eastern Front"
Move, move, move!
Hey, get more light in there!
"The 9th Company of the Volunteer Army"
Did we receive a command?
You there
Pick up your feet
Hustle up!
Get those crates over here!
Move faster!
Get some more!
Right there!
Stack them up boys!
Come on, pick it up!
Hurry up!
No, I don't see any sign of enemy.
Damn soldier, this ain't North Korea.
This is the North Pole.
"The 7th Company of the Volunteer Army"
Let me hold that for a while.
What are they singing?
Don't fall asleep.
Wake up.
Merry Christmas.
What does that mean?
It's an American holiday
that happens before the New Year.
It's called Christmas.
What is it?
To be so happy.
Their lives aren't so merry after all.
That MacArthur even said they were going to
cross the Yalu River before the New Year
so their soldiers could go home for the holiday.
Bullshit,
they want to go home for the holiday?
I'll give them a reason to go home.
Do you miss mom?
Qianli,
when Baili died,
were you by his side?
He lost the bottom half of his body
from the explosion.
I couldn't even
stuff his intestines back inside,
no matter how I tried.
He said
he was cold.
I held him in my arms.
His lips
were purple.
I couldn't stop
his bleeding.
He asked me
to help him take his life.
Qianli,
let me stay by your side.
If...
I end up like Baili,
you can help me too.
Okay.
"November 26, 1950"
How's it going?
Tanks,
Half-tracks,
and HQ.
From the marching direction and speed
of the 31st Corps led by the U.S. army
we can predict that
the enemy's HQ
will be established around
the 1100 Highland.
They are known as the Polar Bears.
They fought in Siberia in WWI
and in the Pacific in WWII.
This is their trump card.
We'll show them
how tough our fists are then.
Why hasn't anything happened?
Do you think something went wrong?
The 59th, 79th,
and 89th Divisions arrived in Yudam-ni on time.
The 80th and 81st Divisions
are in position in Sinhung-ni.
What's the speed of Smith's corps?
3 kilometers per day.
They are moving at a snail's pace.
According to their line of march and geography,
Smith's corps will surely be stretched out.
Then we can break their lineup
into a few sections.
We must annihilate Smith
at the Lake Changjin.
Let's wait.
The 1100 Highland is right ahead of us.
If we make it there before sunrise,
we can block the U.S. army's route.
Let's not waste our time here.
Notify all units. Get ready to head out.
Yes.
Gather your gear and get ready for departure.
Attention all! Get ready to depart.
Lei.
I saved this just for you.
What do you want for it?
Why do you have such a nasty mind?
The situation with the Polar Bears is...
a tough battle.
Can you let me have Wanli?
You're the one who handed him over to me.
Now you want him back.
What are you up to?
He throws with unerring aim.
That's useful to me.
Take good care of him.
When this war is over,
he will become my godson.
I'm expecting him to take care of me
when I get old.
You old bastard,
if he's your godson,
what should I call you?
Call me Dad.
I'll break those aged teeth of yours.
Remember,
as soon as the battle begins,
you stick by your brother's side.
He's more witty and canny than a rabbit.
Bullets don't tend to get him.
Don't be a show-off.
Okay.
Let's all try to fight this war nicely.
Those in the back, speed up!
"November 27, 1950"
Commander,
Smith's corps haven't arrived yet.
No more waiting.
Begin the general assault
in 5 minutes.
"Sinhung-ni, Lake Changjin"
What?
Have we been discovered?
No.
We're about to initiate the attack.
Attack!
Get on the truck!
Enemy attack, code Red!
Lock enemy assault position.
Sir, they are coming from everywhere!
Dinner is served!
Load the cannons!
Ready,
fire!
Attack!
Ammo supply!
Move, move, move!
Need more ammo!
Never see ammo go this fast like before!
Ammo supply!
You gonna pick that up, Glover?
Yeah, I got it, I got it!
All right, we gotta move!
Prepare the second load!
They are coming!
You guys think we're gonna make it for chow time?
Shut up, Costello!
We're gonna be lucky if they
don't roast our turkeys for dinner.
Hurry!
Hurry! Right here!
Two in the front and three in the back. Hurry!
Take cover! Take cover now!
Target the center watchtower!
Copy!
Ready, fire!
Lei, where are your mortars?
Hang on. Hang on.
Hang on.
Lei, great job!
Who called me?
I didn't.
Hurry!
All tanks defend the headquarters!
Jesus, Sunny.
Go! find the American flag!
Destroy their HQ.
Yes.
Sir, the Air Force is on its way!
The enemy is closing in!
Emergency orders are required, sir!
Aim right at them!
Hurry!
Send the ammunition to them!
Hurry up!
Yes.
The tank is coming!
Go that way!
Find cover!
Hurry, take cover!
Go!
Bazooka!
Here!
Run!
Leave me!
Hang on!
Go!
Don't fall asleep, bro. Wait for me.
Dachuan! Dachuan!
Attack!
Charge!
Watch out!
Up there!
Spread out!
Grenade!
1, 2, 3! Go!
Rush forward!
Fight!
Bro!
Spread out!
Get down!
Hurry!
Grenade!
Get back!
Take cover!
Get on! Hurry!
Get in the truck!
Stop them!
A fool who risks his neck
will never be a hero!
Stay calm!
You must stay calm on the battlefield!
I order a full retreat!
Give the order!
All units fall back!
Burn everything!
Let's get out of here!
Go!
They are going to retreat!
Stop them!
Fall back!
Sir, the vehicle is ready!
Go!
Back up!
What are you doing?
Only 8 more! I'm about to reach 20!
Some shots must be fired.
Some shots can be saved.
All units, move it to the position.
Wait for the order.
I repeat.
Move! Move! Move!
All units, move it to position.
Wait for the order.
I repeat.
Sir, calling from Sinhung-ni
demanding immediate reinforcements.
They are in urgent retreat.
Landman,
get reinforcements to Sinhung-ni. Move!
"Hagaru-ri"
All units consolidate immediately
and count inventory.
The 2nd Company of the 3rd Battalion,
stay on guard.
Stay alert in all directions!
The 3rd Platoon and the 6th Platoon,
defend the southwest direction.
Call him Old Company Commander.
Old Company Commander.
Not you.
Didn't I tell you?
I got it,
the undefeatable hero.
Wanli.
How old are you?
Nineteen.
Little brat,
have you seen any enemy aircraft?
The plane opens its butt end
and pours down bullets and bombs.
After that, our men in yellow uniforms
will drop one after another.
What should we call those brothers
who were Killed in action?
What should we call those
who froze to death
after marching for 6 days and nights
without any food or sleep?
What about those who ran to 10 meters
in front of the enemy
just to toss their hand grenades?
They were killed.
What should we call them?
There aren't any heroes
who will never freeze to death,
let alone ones who will never be killed.
A soldier only lives for honor and glory.
What should I call you?
The 677th Soldier,
Wu Wanli.
"Wan" means ten-thousand.
Watch out.
Sophisticated.
U.S. Aircraft are here!
Bazooka!
U.S. Aircrafts!
Find cover!
God save us!
Spread out!
U.S. bomb!
Are you alright?
What's your name?
Officer,
I'm the 280th soldier of the 7th Company, Ping He.
FX Bomb!
Spread out!
They're going to bombard us!
FX Bomb!
Spread out!
IS sighted, vision clear.
Ready to drop. Over.
Enemy planes! Spread out!
I'll send their FX bomb back to them!
Bastards.
Everybody says that...
Everybody says that
Yimeng Mountain is the best.
The scenery is beautiful
on Yimeng Mountain.
Lei!
Lift the car.
It hurts.
It so hurts.
Don't...
Don't leave me alone here.
Why do you want to be a soldier?
So Qianli will take me seriously.
What are you talking about?
You're only tough enough
when your enemies take you seriously.
"Lei Suisheng.”
Lei,
It won't hurt anymore.
You've done well, Lei.
Let me.
When I was back home last time,
every time I went out on the street,
people would nod and smile at me.
I didn't know them,
but they recognized my army uniform.
Before I left home,
my daughter asked me,
"Daddy, why must you fight this war?"
If we don't fight this war,
our next generation will have to fight it.
We are risking our lives
to win them a peaceful life.
My mom kept gazing at me
without saying a word
when I left home.
I know
she didn't want me to leave.
My wife said
when I came home again,
I had to teach our daughter how to do the math.
We have to win the war
and bring them home.
"Hagaru-ri Airport U.S. Army's Grand Retreat"
Sir!
Your chopper is here, sir.
You can leave anytime.
The 5th and 7th Regiments aren't here yet
and this will be an important evac route.
The supplies are on board now.
Okay, get ready.
You send that chopper to evacuate the wounded.
Those men aren't out of danger yet!
Hey, clear out! Clear out!
Let's get out of here!
"The U.S. Marine retreats
from Hagaru-ri towards Sumun Bridge,"
"passing the 1071 Highlands on the way."
"The 3rd Company of 58th Division
of the Volunteer Army"
"warded off many charges from the U.S. Marine."
Move out now! Incoming! Incoming!
U.S. Aircraft are here!
Take cover!
Get down!
Comrades,
hang on!
Battalion Commander,
we've already warded off an attack
from the enemy again.
Our Company Commander said,
We must fight!
Hand grenades!
Who has more?
Comrades,
we've already stood our ground for 24 hours
and warded off 7 attacks from the enemy.
Even if we are down to the last one,
we will never let the enemies
pass under our feet!
Fight to the death to defend our front!
"I don't believe in
missions impossible to complete.”
difficulties impossible to overcome."
"I don't believe in
enemies impossible to defeat.”
"Yang Genet"
"The 1st Marine Division of the U.S. Army"
"Retreating towards the Hungnam Port"
Sir, you got to see this.
Show me.
Fighting against men with
such strong will like this
we were not ordained to win.
"December 24, 1950"
"105,000 soldiers of the U.S. 10th Corps
evacuated from the Hungnam Harbor"
"The 9th Corps occupied the Hungnam Harbor"
"The Battle of the Lake Changjin
set a perfect example”
"for annihilating a U.S. reinforced regiment”
"during the War to Resist U.S. Aggression
and Aid Korea,"
"causing the U.S. main force...
on the eastern front to encounter”
"'the greatest setback in the history
of the Marine Corps'."
"During the second battle in the War"
"to Resist U.S. Aggression and Aid Korea,"
"the 9th Corps achieved major strategic results
on the main battlefield"
"at the eastern front during
the Battle of the Lake Changjin."
"While acting in cooperation with our army
at the western front,"”
"these brave soldiers completely shattered
MacArthur's presumptuous plan to"
end the war before Christmas' and sent
the 'United Nations Command' led by the U.S."
"From the Yalu River back to the
other side of the 38th Parallel."
"The battle completely tipped
the scales of the Korean War"
"and laid the foundation for the final victory of
the War to Resist U.S. Aggression and Aid Korea."
"Over 197,000 heroic Chinese people
sacrificed their lives during the war."
"More than 300,000 heroes including
Yang Genet, Huang Jiguang, Qiu Shaoyun, etc."
"As well as nearly
6,000 meritorious units emerged."
"The great spirit from the war remains timeless!"
"The mighty martyrs of the PVA
will never be forgotten!”