The assistant warden wants this one
out of the block early.
Wants to get it over with fast.
Okay. Let's do it.
Hey, wake up. It's time.
Wake up. Let's go. It's time.
This is it.
7474505B.
- What wing?
- Maximum wing, Block 9.
Standard release?
Parole, three out of five.
Good behavior.
Give me a minute.
One Timex digital watch, broken.
One unused prophylactic.
One soiled.
Boots, black.
Belt, black.
One black suit jacket.
One pair black suit pants.
One hat.
Black.
One pair sunglasses.
Twenty-three dollars
and seven cents.
Sign here.
- What's this?
- What?
This car.
This stupid car.
Where's the Cadillac?
The Caddy.
Where's the Caddy?
The what?
The Cadillac we used to have.
The Bluesmobile.
I traded it.
- You traded the Bluesmobile for this?
- No, for a microphone.
A microphone?
Okay, I can see that.
- What the hell is this?
- This was a bargain.
I picked it up at the Mount Prospect
City Police Auction last spring.
It's an old Mount Prospect police car.
They were practically giving them away.
Well, thank you, pal.
The day I get out of prison...
my own brother picks me up
in a police car.
You don't like it?
No, I don't like it.
Car's got a lot of pick-up.
It's got a cop motor,
a 440-cubic-inch plant.
It's got cop tyres,
cop suspension, cop shocks.
A model made
before catalytic converters...
so it'll run good on regular gas.
What do you say?
Is it the new Bluesmobile, or what?
Fix the cigarette lighter.
What are we doing here?
You promised you'd visit
the Penguin the day you got out.
Yeah. So I lied to her.
You can't lie to a nun.
We gotta go in
and visit the Penguin.
No fucking way.
Who is it?
Jake and Elwood.
Come in.
Hello, boys.
Nice to see you.
Please, have a seat.
No, boys.
Come over here in front of me.
I want to see your faces.
The county took a tax assessment
of this property last month.
They want $5,000.
Won't the church pay?
They would if they were
interested in keeping the place.
But they aren't.
The archbishop wants to sell this
building to the Board of Education.
What will happen to you?
I'll be sent to the missions--
Africa, Latin America...
- Korea.
- Forget it!
Five grand? No problem. We'll have it
for you in the morning. Let's go.
I will not take
your filthy, stolen money!
Well, then.
I guess you're really up shit creek.
I beg your pardon.
What did you say?
I offered to help you.
You refused to take our money.
Then I said,
''I guess you're really up shit creek.''
- Christ, Jake, take it easy, man.
- Elwood!
- Ow! Shit!
-Jesus Christ!
- Shit!
-Jesus!
- Shit! Goddam it!
- Son of a bitch!
You fat penguin!
Fuck this!
You are
such a disappointing pair.
I prayed so hard for you.
It saddens and hurts me...
that the two young men
whom I raised...
to believe
in the Ten Commandments...
have returned to me
as two thieves...
with filthy mouths
and bad attitudes.
Get out!
And don't come back...
until you've
redeemed yourselves.
Boys, you gotta learn
not to talk to nuns that way.
Curtis!
- You look fine!
- Good to see you!
Buy you boys a drink?
Boys, things are bad.
They gonna sell this place
to the Board of Education...
and I'll be out on the street.
That money's got to be in the Cook
County Assessor's Office within 11 days.
They wouldn't turn you out,
would they?
Shit. What's one more old nigger
to the Board of Education?
Curtis, you and the Penguin
are the only family we got.
You're the only one
that was ever good to us...
singing Elmore James tunes and
blowing the harp for us down here.
Well, the sister was right. You boys
could use a little churching up.
Slide on down
to the Triple Rock...
and catch Reverend Cleophus.
You boys listen
to what he's got to say.
I don't want to listen
to no jive-ass preacher...
talking to me
about heaven and hell.
You get wise.
You get to church!
All I'm saying is,
we got to figure out...
some way
to get that money honestly.
That could be a problem.
Like the Penguin says.
We got to move toward redemption.
We got to go to church.
''We got to move toward redemption.
We got to go to church.''
Bullshit.
Come on.
And now, this week's sermon...
is from our beloved,
the Reverend Cleophus James!
And now, people--
When I woke up this morning,
I heard a disturbing sound.
I said,
when I woke up this morning...
I heard a disturbing sound!
What I heard
was the jingle-jangle...
of a thousand lost souls!
I'm talking about the souls
of mortal men and women...
departed from this life!
Wait a minute!
Those lost, anguished souls
roaming unseen over the earth...
seeking a divine light...
they'll not find
because it's too late!
Too late! Yeah! Too late
for them to ever see again...
the light they once chose
not to follow! All right!
Don't be lost
when the time comes!
For the day of the Lord cometh...
as a thief in the night!
Amen
Say amen!
- Let us all
- All go back
- To the old
- Old landmark
As we stay
in the service of the Lord
- Let us preach
- Preach the word
- Got to preach
- Preach the word all the way
Do it, know it, feel it
Jake, are you all right?
Alleluia
The band.
Do you see the light?
What light?
Have you seen the light?
Yes!
Jesus H. Tap-Dancing Christ!
I have seen the light!
The band!
- Praise God!
- And God bless the United States!
Stay in the service
of the Lord
Yea, Lord
We'll put the band back together,
we do a few gigs...
we get some bread.
Bang-- five thousand bucks!
Well, getting the band
back together might not be that easy.
- What are you talking about?
- They split.
They all took straight jobs.
Yeah? So you know
where they are.
You said you were
keeping in touch with them.
I got a couple of leads,
a few phone numbers.
But, I mean, how many of them
visited or even wrote you?
They're not the kind of guys
who write letters.
You were outside.
I was inside.
You were supposed to keep
in touch with the band.
I kept asking you
if we were gonna play again.
What was I gonna do,
take away your only hope?
Take away the very thing
that kept you going in there?
I took the liberty
of bullshitting you. Okay?
- You lied to me.
- It wasn't lies. It was just bullshit.
- Shit.
- What?
- Rollers.
- No.
Shit.
- What? What did I do?
- You failed to stop at a red signal.
The light was yellow, sir.
May I see your license, please?
Goddam it!
I haven't been pulled over
in six months.
I bet those cops
have got SCMODS.
State County Municipal Offender
Data System.
Elwood, we show your license
currently under suspension.
Step out of the car, please.
First you trade the Cadillac
for a microphone.
Then you lie to me
about the band.
Now you're gonna put me
right back in the joint!
They're not gonna catch us.
We're on a mission from God.
We are in high-speed pursuit
northbound on Courtland Avenue.
Black-and-white 1974 Dodge sedan
with Illinois plates.
Request assistance.
We'll be all right if we can
just get back on the express way.
This don't look
like no express way to me!
Don't yell at me.
What do you want me to do,
motor head?
Try not to be so negative
all the time.
Why don't you offer
some constructive criticism?
You got us into this parking lot, pal.
Now you get us out!
You want out
of this parking lot?
- Will there be anything else?
- Do you have Miss Piggy?
- There's pants and burgers.
- Yeah, lots of space in this mall.
Disco pants and haircuts.
Baby clothes.
This place has got everything.
New Oldsmobiles
are in early this year.
Pier 1 Imports.
Oh, shit!
They broke my watch!
I'm gonna catch that sucker...
if it's the last thing
I ever do.
Nice place, huh?
Hey, Sam.
Hey, Lloyd.
- Anybody call for me on the phone?
- No. No calls.
Some guy left his card.
Cop. Said he'd be back.
This here's my brother, Jake.
He just got out of the joint.
He's gonna be staying with me
for a few weeks.
Yeah. Okay.
Did you get me
my Cheez Whiz, boy?
Well, it ain't much,
but it's home.
- How often does the train go by?
- So often you won't even notice it.
What are you doing?
Making dinner.
Want some?
Tomorrow we got to get
the band back together.
I'm gonna quit work
in the morning, first thing.
And how are you going
to get to work...
Mr Lead Foot, Mr Hot-Rodder,
Mr Motor Head?
Those cops took your license away.
They got your name,
your address.
No, they don't got my address.
I falsified my renewal.
I put down 1060 West Addison.
That's Wrigley Field.
I gotta hit the sack.
Hey, you sleaze! My bed!
This, gentlemen, is the elegant
abode of one Elwood Blues.
Thanks, Mr Mercer.
- I kinda like the Wrigley Field bit.
- Yeah, real cute.
Hi, Sam.
Hi. Has my friend arrived yet?
He failed to report in yesterday.
I don't want trouble.
Tell us where they are,
and there'll be no trouble.
Stand back.
It's almost 9:00.
We've gotta go to work.
Hello, Elwood. Sit down.
What's on your mind?
I gotta quit.
Why is that, Elwood?
I'm going to become a priest.
I'll call payroll and have them get
your severance pay ready.
- Good luck.
- God bless you, sir.
thank you.
- What's this?
- This is the last known address...
of Bones Malone
and Blue Lou Marini.
The Lord works in mysterious ways.
- Mrs Toronto?
- Tarantino.
Ma'am, do you have a Thomas Malone
or Louis Marini living here?
Not any more.
They moved out a long time ago.
I don't take in boarders any more.
- May we come in, ma'am?
- Please.
Did they leave a forwarding address?
A phone number?
Did they live quietly?
What were their personal habits?
They were good boys...
but they made
a lot of racket at night.
Are you the police?
No, ma'am.
We're musicians.
Mr Man!
- Yes, ma'am?
- They left this card. Maybe it'll help.
Thanks.
thank you. You're marvelous.
thank you. I'm Murph,
and these are the Magic Tones.
Steve ''The Colonel'' Cropper,
Donald ''Duck'' Dunn...
Willie ''Too Big'' Hall
and Tom ''Bones'' Malone.
We'll be back with the Magic Tones
for the Armada Room's...
two-hour disco swing party
after this short break.
Till then, don't you go changing.
So you're out. You're free.
You're rehabilitated.
What's next? What's happening?
What you gonna do?
You got the money you owe us,
mother-fucker?
Let's get something
straight here.
The reason he got locked in the slam
in the first place...
was for sticking up a gas station
to cover you guys.
You're kidding.
He pulled that job to pay
for the band's room-service tab...
from that Kiwanis gig
in Coal City.
- You did?
- That's right.
So I don't want to hear
any more of this small-change shit.
We're putting the band
back together.
Who here at this table
can honestly say...
that they played any finer
or felt any better than they did...
when they were
with the Blues Brothers?
You were the backbone...
the nerve centre
of a great rhythm-and-blues band.
You can make that live,
breathe and jump again.
Murph and the Magic Tones?
Look at you in those
candy-ass monkey suits.
And I thought
I had it bad in Joliet.
At least we got
a change in clothes.
You're wearing the same shit
from three years ago.
Jake ain't lying, though.
We had a band powerful enough
to turn goat piss into gasoline.
We'll never get that fat sound again
without more horns.
We'll never get Mr Fabulous.
- Where is he?
- Forget it.
Mr Fabulous is the top maitre d'
at the Chez Paul.
He's pullin' down
six bills a week.
- Matt Murphy got married.
- Where is Matt ''Guitar'' Murphy?
He opened a restaurant with his old lady
on Maxwell Street...
and he took Blue Lou with him.
You'll never get Matt and Mr Fabulous
out of them high-paying gigs.
Oh, yeah?
Well, me and the Lord...
we got an understanding.
We're on a mission from God.
Mainly French cuisine.
No, sir. Mayor Daley no longer
dines here. He's dead, sir.
Private dining rooms
are available.
Oh, no. It was supposed to be
five years.
Didn't you get five years?
No, sir, not you.
And your name, sir?
Rizzolo, for eight at 11:30.
thank you.
Mr Fabulous,
how marvelous it is to see you.
- You're looking younger than ever.
- Wait. You guys can't come in here.
Nonsense, my dear fellow.
My brother and I
have come to dine...
to celebrate my early release
from the service of the state.
Wait. Let's talk outside.
- Let's have a cup of coffee outside.
- Why, heavens, no.
We seek a full meal and all
the compliments of the house.
Come, Elwood.
Let us adjourn ourselves
to the nearest table...
and overlook this establishment's
board offare.
Good evening. Chez Paul.
Wait! Hey!
Sir, do you mind calling back
in about five minutes, please?
We'll have a table
in a few moments.
Excuse me.
Give us a bottle
of your finest champagne...
five shrimp cocktails
and some bread for my brother.
We have a Dom Perignon '71
at $120.
That'll be fine, pal.
Seriously, the food here is really
expensive. The soup is fucking $10!
Let's go outside.
I'll buy you a cup of coffee.
We're putting the band
back together.
- Forget it. No way.
- We're on a mission from God.
Hold it. Hold it.
What's this?
Waiter? Sir?
Please, waiter?
Yes, sir? How are your salads?
The salads are fine.
It's just that we'd like
to move to another table...
away from those two gentlemen.
Why? Have they been
disturbing you?
No. It's just that--
Well, frankly,
they're offensive-smelling.
I mean, they smell bad.
Excuse me. I'll see if I can locate
another table for you.
thank you.
Wrong glass, sir.
How much for the little girl?
- The women? How much for the women?
- What?
I want to buy your women.
Your little girl. Your daughters.
Sell them to me.
- Sell me your children.
- Maitre d'!
Cut it out. The owners are gonna
ask me to call the cops.
- You wouldn't do that to me, would you?
- He just got outta Joliet.
He's on parole. You can't
call the cops on him, man.
- We're putting the band back together.
- I said no.
Absolutely not!
How much for your wife?
We're putting the band back together.
We need you, man. We need your horn.
I really can't.
We got everybody except
Matt ''Guitar'' Murphy and Blue Lou.
- We're getting them next.
- No way.
If you say no, Elwood and I
will come here for breakfast...
lunch and dinner
every day of the week.
Okay. I'll play.
You got me.
Sir?
White men!
White women!
The swastika is calling you!
The sacred and ancient symbol
of your race...
since the beginning of time.
The Jew is using the black...
as muscle against you.
And you are left there, helpless.
-Fuck you!
-What are you gonna do about it, withy?
-Just sit there?
- Go back where you came from!
Of course not!
- Son of a bitch!
- You are going to join...
with us...
the members of...
the American Socialist
White People's Party:
an organization of decent...
law-abiding white folk...
just like you.
Go to hell, bastards!
Go to hell!
I pledge allegiance to Adolf Hitler...
the immortal leader of our race.
To the order for which he stands.
One great cause.
Sacred and invincible.
Hey, what's going on?
Those bums won their court case
so they're marching today.
- What bums?
- The fucking Nazi party.
Illinois Nazis.
I hate Illinois Nazis.
Heil Hitler!
Ten-hut!
- Gruppenfuehrer!
- Yes, sir!
Get that car's license plate number.
We're gonna kill
that son of a bitch.
Come on home, babe
Oh, come on home, woman
Oh, come on home, pretty baby
I love you
When she walk that walk
And talk that talk
And whisperin' my ear
Tell me that she love me
I love that talk
That baby talk
When she talk like that
I can't take it like that
Come on home to me, baby
Walk your walk
Talk your talk
Talk your talk, baby
thank you, ladies and gentlemen.
That was ''Boom, Boom,''
a song that I wrote back in the '50s.
- No, you didn't.
- It was a hit.
- Yes, I did.
I wrote ''Boom, Boom''!
- Can I help you, boys?
- You got any white bread?
Yes.
I'll have some
toasted white bread, please.
You want butter or jam
on that toast, honey?
No, ma'am. Dry.
- Got any fried chicken?
- Best damn chicken in the state.
Bring me four fried chickens
and a Coke.
You want chicken wings
or chicken legs?
Four fried chickens and a Coke.
And some dry white toast, please.
You all want anything to drink
with that?
- No, ma'am.
- A Coke.
Be up in a minute.
We got two honkies out there
dressed like Hasidic diamond merchants.
- Say what?
- They look like they're from the CIA.
- What they wanna eat?
- The tall one wants white-bread toast.
- Dry. With nothing on it.
- Elwood!
And the other one wants
four whole fried chickens and a Coke.
And Jake! Shit!
The Blues Brothers!
- Hi, Jake!
- Matt! How you doing?
- How was Joliet?
- Oh, it's bad.
On Thursday night
they serve a wicked pepper steak.
Can't be as bad as the cabbage rolls
at the Terre Haute Federal Pen.
Or that oatmeal
at the Cook County slammer.
- They're all pretty bad.
- Matt--
Me and Elwood--
we're putting the band back together.
We need you and Blue Lou.
Don't talk that way around here.
My old lady--
- She'll kill me.
- Ma'am, you gotta understand.
This is a lot bigger than any domestic
problems you might be experiencing.
Matt, what the hell
is he talking about?
- Don't get riled, sugar.
- Don't you ''sugar'' me!
Now, you not going
back on the road no more.
And you ain't playing
any more two-bit, sleazy dives.
You're living with me now...
and you're not gonna go sliding around
with your white hoodlum friends.
But, babes! This is Jake and Elwood!
The Blues Brothers!
The Blues Brothers! Shit!
They still owe you money, fool!
Ma'am.
Would it make you feel better
if you knew...
that what we're asking Matt to do
is a holy thing?
You see,
we're on a mission from God.
Don't you blaspheme in here!
Now, this is my man,
my restaurant...
and you two are gonna
walk right out that door...
without your dry, white toast...
without your four fried chickens...
and without Matt ''Guitar'' Murphy!
Now you listen to me!
I love you.
But I'm the man
and you're the woman.
And I'll make the decisions
concerning my life!
You better think about
what you saying.
the consequences of your actions.
Shut up, woman!
You better think
Think about what you're
trying to do to me
Yeah, think
Let your mind go
Let your self be free
Let's go back
Let's go way on back when
I didn't even know you, you couldn't
have been too much more than ten
I ain't no psychiatrist
I ain't no doctor with degree
It don't take too much high IQ
to see what you're doing to me
You better think
Think about what you're trying
to do to me
Think
Let your mind go
Let yourself be free
Freedom
Yeah, freedom right now
Hey, think about it
You, think about it
There ain't nothing you could ask
I could answer you, but I won't
But I was gonna change that, I'm not
if you keep doing things I don't
Think about what you're trying
to do to me
Damn it
Let your mind go
Let yourself be free
People walking around every day
playing games and taking scores
Tryin' to make people lose their mind
Now, be careful you don't lose yours
You need me
And I need you
Without each other
there ain't nothing either can do
- Yeah, think about it, baby
- What you trying to do to me
To the bone
Think about it right now
Oh, freedom
You, think about it
There ain't nothing you could ask
I can answer you, but l won't
But l was gonna change my mind
if you keep doing things I don't
You need me
And I need you
Without each other
there ain't nothing either can do
- Think about it, baby
- What you're trying to do to me
To the bone, man
Think about it, baby
- Yeah, right on
- To the bone
- For deepening
- To the bone, for deeps
Deepening
Right now
Think about it, yeah, yeah
To the bone
For deepening
Think about it
To the bone
Don't give me the Blues Brothers
You had better
Stop and think about it
Think
Let's boogie.
Well, go ahead, damn it!
Shit!
Pardon me...
but we do have a strict policy
concerning handling the instruments:
An employee
of Ray's Music Exchange...
must be present.
Now, may I help you?
Ray, it's me. Joliet Jake.
I once rented some column speakers
from you...
for my band-- The Blues Brothers.
Hey, Ray. It's me. Murph,
of Murph and the Magic Tones.
Remember me?
I bought three Fender amps.
- Oh, we sell a lot of amplifiers.
- Not like these. They were beautiful.
- Upholstered with thick, red shag.
- Right!
I remember now.
I'll buy them all back for 350 a piece.
Three fifty?
I paid 800 each
not six months ago.
You know-- depreciation, man.
Ray, we're here to buy stuff.
We need pianos, amps, mikes--
the works.
Go on! Get!
Breaks my heart:
a boy that young going bad.
Tell me a little
about this electric piano.
You have a good eye, my man.
That's the best
in the city of Chicago.
- How much?
- Two thousand bucks and it's yours.
You can take it home with you.
I'll throw in the black keys for free.
Two thousand
for this chunk of shit?
Come on, Ray!
Really, Ray. It's used.
There's no action left in this keyboard.
Excuse me.
I don't think there's anything wrong
with the action on this piano.
Well, I heard about the fella
you've been dancing with
All over the neighborhood
So why didn't you ask me, baby
Didn't you think I could
Well, I know that the bugaloo
is out of sight
But the shing-a-ling's
the thing tonight
But if that was you and me
out there, baby
l would have shown you
how to do it right
Do it right
Twisting
Shake it, shake it, baby
Here we go loop-de-loop
Shake it out, baby
Here we go loop-de-lai
Bend over
Let me see you shake your tail feather
Come on
Come on, baby
Allright
Do the twist
Do the fly
Do the swim
And do the bird
Do the duck
Do the monkey
Watusi
And what about the frug
Do the mashed potato
What about the bugaloo
Oh, the Bony Maronie
Come on, let's do the twist
Twisting
Shake it, shake it, baby
Okay, man.
We'll take these axes.
Naturally. And as usual,
I gotta take an IOU.
You guys go inside.
Get yourselves a bite.
I've got to make a phone call.
Does this phone call
concern our first gig?
Have I ever lied to you?
What are we gonna do, man?
We don't got no gig.
How much money you got?
- I got a quarter.
- That's enough for a phone call.
Come on.
- What are you doing?
- You said we were gonna make a call.
I said I was gonna make a call.
Who are you gonna call, Jake?
Do you remember Maury Sline?
Sline? Booking agent?
What about him?
He got us some good showcases
in the old days.
He got us the Morgan Park.
He got us the Ticktock.
I got him laid.
He owes me.
Give it a shot.
There's got to be at least
seven dollars' worth of change here.
Sir.
- What did you find out?
- Okay.
I called a friend
at the Motor Vehicle Department.
That license plate is like a rash
all over the computer.
The car belongs
to a known traffic menace.
- What's his name?
- His name is Elwood Blues.
He's got a record a mile long.
And he's a Catholic.
- Did you get his address?
- Of course.
1060 West Addison.
Let's go.
Anybody with that kind of record
is gonna make a mistake.
I want all party members
in the tristate district...
to monitor the city, county
and state police on their CBs.
Mr Blues is gonna fuck up.
And when he does...
he better pray the police get to him
before we do.
We been in this car for three hours now.
Where is this place?
I told you it'd take
a little while to get there.
- What's the name of the place?
- The name of the place is--
Bob's Country Bunker.
- Here we are.
- Bob's Country Bunker?
The sign says, ''Tonight only,
the Good Ole Boys.''
Blues Brothers! It should read,
''Tonight only...
the Blues Brothers'
triumphant return.''
Must be some kind of mistake.
You guys unload the stuff.
Elwood, come with me.
What can I get you boys?
You thirsty, hungry
or just driving through?
Maybe you'd like a beer
or something a little harder?
We happen to make
the state's best pepper steak.
No, thank you, ma'am.
We may be sucking back
a few beers later on.
We'll be here all night.
You see, we're the band.
You are?
Gee, that's nice!
Hey, Bob, this is the band!
All right!
What kind of music
do you usually have here?
We got both kinds.
We got country and western.
Jake, are you sure this is the place?
Yeah, sure. This is the place.
- Hi! You the Good Ole Boys?
- That's us!
The rest of the band's
in the parking lot getting our stuff.
Well, I'm sure glad
to have you boys here.
I'm Bob and this here is my place.
Well, it's a beautiful place, Bob!
I guess you wanna get your steel guitars
and everything set up on stage.
Claire, get up and turn those stage
lights on and get these boys going.
Chicken wire?
What do you say
we have a sound check?
Excuse me, sonny. I'll give this
to you. You're the tallest one.
Okay. What is it?
That there is a list
of the songs...
that you boys
will be playing tonight.
I don't think we know
any of the songs on this list.
This list doesn't mean anything.
They're just requests.
Do our regular set.
First tune.
''Give Me Some Loving.''
One, two--
One, two, three, four.
Shit!
What are those damn freak
pecker heads playing?
Good evening, ladies and gentlemen.
We're glad to be here tonight.
We're the Good Old Blues Brothers
Boys Band from Chicago.
We hope you'll like our show.
I'm Elwood. This is my brother Jake.
Well, my temperature's rising
And my feet on the floor
Crazy people knockin'
'Cause they want some more
Let me in, baby
I don't know what you got
Better take it easy
'Cause this place is hot
And I'm so glad we made it
That ain't no Hank Williams song!
Give me some loving
Get off the stage!
Everyday
Why'd they turn off the lights?
- Maybe they blew a fuse.
- I don't think so.
Those lights are off on purpose.
We gotta figure out something
these people like, and fast!
I got it. Remember the theme
from ''Rawhide''?
Old favorite. Rowdy Yates.
- What key?
- ''A.'' Good country key.
''Rawhide'' in ''A.''
Rollin', rollin'
Though the streams are swollen
Keep them dogies rollin'
Rawhide
Through rain and wind and weather
Hell-bent for leather
Wishin' my gal was by my side
All the things l'm missin'
Good vittles, love and kissin'
Are waiting at the end of my ride
- Move 'em on
- Head 'em up
- Head 'em out
- Move 'em on
- Head 'em up
Rawhide
Cut 'em out
Ride 'em in
Ride 'em in, rawhide
Theme from the TV show ''Rawhide.''
thank you.
We'd like to do a favorite of the horn
section. We hope it's one of yours.
Sometimes it's hard
to be a woman
Giving all your love
To just one man
And if you love him
Oh, be proud of him
'Cause after all
He's just a man
Stand by your man
Give him two arms to cling to
And something warm to come to
When nights are cold and lonely
Stand by your man
And tell the world you love him
Keep giving all the love you can
Stand by your man
And show the world you love him
Keep giving all the love you can
Baby
Stand by
Your man
Well, folks, it's time
to call it a night.
But do what you feel,
and keep both feet on the wheel.
You don't have to go home
but you can't stay here.
So, till next time:
- Move 'em on
- Head 'em up
Rawhide
- Cut 'em out
- Ride 'em in
Ride 'em in, rawhide
Let's get the hell out of here.
Shit, I wanna tell you, that's some
of the best goddam music we've had...
at the Country Bunker
in a long time.
Well, sorry we couldn't remember
''The Wreck of the Old 97.''
Why, hell! You guys can learn it
next time when you come back.
Bob, about our money for tonight.
That's right.
Two hundred dollars...
and you boys drank
$300 worth of beer.
When we first came in...
the bar lady never charged us
for the first round.
So, like, we figured
beer was complimentary for the band.
Well, I'll just go out
and take up a collection from the boys.
I sure would appreciate it.
I say this trip is nowhere, man.
I say we gotta quit.
What? Quit?
I wish you guys
would make up your mind.
Otherwise I gotta call Mr Ronzini at
the Holiday Inn to get our old gig back.
Back at the Armada Room?
Listen, they want us
to pay for the beer we drank.
So you'd better split.
The next gig is gonna be dynamite!
Huge! You'll see.
I say we give the Blues Brothers
just one more chance.
Why not? If the shit fits, wear it!
Scoot over, goddam it!
Boys look a little upset.
Hey, man. Don't worry.
We got a couple of days.
We'll get the Penguin's tax money.
I mean, look. We got an appointment
to see Mr Sline tomorrow.
Everything's gonna be all right.
Let's skate.
Goddam it.
Excuse me. Are you
the Good Ole Boys?
That's right. I'm Tucker McElroy,
lead singer, driver of the Winnebago.
I'd like to talk to you,
but we're running very late.
I'm Jacob Stein, American Federation
of Musicians Union, Local 200.
I've been sent here to see
if you're carrying your permits.
Our what?
Your union cards.
May I see your cards, please?
Suppose we ain't got no union cards,
and we go in and start playing anyway?
What you gonna do about that?
You gonna stop us?
Stein!
You gonna look funny trying to eat
corn on the cob with no fucking teeth!
Listen, let me talk to Bob,
the owner.
See if we can put your band
on contract waivers for tonight.
I don't want you to move
from this spot.
Just let me handle this.
We'll talk to Bob.
Get in the car and start her up.
You know you boys owe me
a lot of money for that beer you drank!
- Goddam it!
- Bob, we loved playing here tonight.
My brother's writing out an
American Express traveler's check...
to cover the bar tab.
I sure would appreciate it.
I'd better check up, see how he's doing.
I have to sign it too.
I usually sit in the car and write it
out on the glove compartment lid.
Need a pencil.
- Were them guys from the union?
- What the hell, ''union''?
Those boys skipped out of here
owing me a lot of money for beer.
What the hell are you guys
all dressed up for?
We're the Good Ole Boys!
You're the Good Ole Boys?
''A.F.M.'' Shit!
Our Lady of Blessed Acceleration,
don't fail me now!
I don't believe it!
It's that shit-box Dodge again.
The bastards are ours now!
Holy shit!
Boys, you in big trouble.
Maury, you owe me.
We'll play anywhere, anytime,
for anybody.
Put us in the Double Up Lounge, or
the Morgan Park Theatre, or the Crystal.
We always knocked them dead
in those joints.
Discos. They're all discos.
Singles. Mixed singles.
Gay singles.
These people like to dance
with each other.
We are a dance band.
I don't know, boys.
I just don't know.
Times have changed,
you know what I mean?
What are you guys gonna do?
The same act?
You wear
the same farkakte suits.
You'll scare people away.
Don't you ever wear blue jeans
or jump suits...
like Wayne Cochran
and the C.C. Riders?
You gotta come through for us.
We need 5,000 bucks fast.
Five thousand bucks?
Who do you think you are?
The Beatles?
You know the size hall you gotta work
to take in that kind of money?
We'll fill any hall in the country.
You guys familiar
with the Palace Hotel ballroom?
- Never heard of it.
- Nice place up north.
Built in the '40s
on Lake Wazapamani.
That seats 5,000.
You guys fill that place,
you can make 5,000 bucks, easy.
- Book us for tomorrow night.
- Hold it! Tomorrow night?
A gig like that, you gotta prepare
the proper exploitation.
I know about that stuff.
I been exploited all my life.
Forget it. There's no way
with you guys. Forget about it.
Say, how's Mrs Sline?
I might have some information
she'd like to know.
You blackmailing me?
If you wanna put it that way.
Maury, we need this gig!
We're on a mission from God.
Get us the hall, and I guarantee
we'll pack them in for miles around.
What do you say?
Okay. I'll get you the Palace Hotel.
I'll print up show bills. I'll make
the place look real pretty, okay?
I don't think you guys
are gonna gross dollar one.
But if you do, I want a taste
of the gig, okay?
Thanks, Maury.
Let's go, boys!
Listen, you boys heard me talk
about Jake and Elwood.
They used to live here,
just like you.
And I used to sing to them,
just like with you.
Tonight Jake and Elwood are going out
to sing and play...
to raise money
to help you children.
Your lazy butts are in this too!
So get up on that wagon.
We're going up north
to put the word on the streets.
Tonight only,
the fabulous Blues Brothers...
Rhythm and Blues Revue...
at the Palace Hotel ballroom,
Route 16...
Lake Wazapamani.
The fabulous Blues Brothers...
Show Band and Revue.
There you go, boy.
All right, man!
Check it out!
- Tonight only!
- From Chicago!
- The Blues Brothers.
- Rhythm and Blues Revue.
One night only!
The fabulous--
Blues Brothers Show Band
and Revue.
You! On the motorcycle!
You two girls!
- Tell your friends!
- Free parking.
Two-dollar cover charge only, folks!
- That's a lot of entertainment.
- For two dollars.
Will you please put this in the window,
'cause it's real important.
Tonight only, from Chicago...
the fabulous Blues Brothers...
Rhythm and Blues Revue...
for your dancing pleasure.
And it's ladies' night tonight.
at the Palace Hotel ballroom.
''Tonight only, the Blues Brothers...
genuine Rhythm and Blues Show
and Revue.
Palace Hotel ballroom.
Tonight only.''
How we doing?
So far we covered Lake, McHenry...
and part of Du Page County.
Good. Let's get to the gig.
What is it?
We're out of gas.
Oh, shit.
Wow! A classic. What a room!
This place is gonna swing tonight.
It's a fucking barn.
We'll never fill it.
We've gotta fill this hall tonight.
A lot of young children
are depending on it.
Young children?
What do you mean?
Jake and Elwood are donating
the band's share of the door money...
to pay the taxes
on the St. Helen's orphanage...
in Calumet City.
What?
- We're out of gas.
- Yep. Mind if we fill her up?
Nope. I said ''we're'' out of gas.
Tanker truck's late.
Should have been here two hours ago.
It's always late on Thursdays.
I guess we'll have to wait.
Excuse me, sir.
Yes, you. Could you fill it up
with premium, and check under the hood?
Sure.
You want I should wash
the dead bugs off the windshield?
No. I'm in kind of a hurry.
Where in the hell are they?
So maybe you'd like to come by
and see the show.
I'm awfully sorry, but I do have
a prior dinner engagement.
Thanks, Marvin.
Get me Troopers Daniel and Mount.
I don't see those Blues Brothers.
We'll wait.
Okay, you're all set.
That'll be $94.
Here's 95.
thank you.
Okay. And that's a dollar change.
- Oh, keep the change.
- Thanks.
So, look. If your date...
don't work out tonight
for any reason...
there's a motel
up on the interstate.
Maybe we could, say, meet...
around midnight?
I'll think about it, Elwood, okay?
Bye.
Son of a bitch!
Come on!
We're really late.
You'd better step on it.
I always like to perform
for angry mobs.
You can't quit now.
What can they be doing?
My head hurts.
That Night Train's a mean wine.
You'd better get bright!
We got a show to do.
Then we gotta figure out
some way to collect that gate money...
get it to the County Assessor's office
as soon as they open in the morning.
We want the show!
Gentlemen, I'm leaving.
Man, we were so close.
Hey, you guys know
''Minnie The Moocher''?
I knew a hooker once
named Minnie Mazola.
No! The song ''Minnie the Moocher.''
- Yeah. So what?
- Hit it!
Hey, folks, here's a story
'bout Minnie the Moocher
She was a low-down hoochie coocher
She was the roughest, toughest frail
But Minnie had a heart
As big as a whale
She messed around
with a bloke named Smokey
She loved him
though he was cokey
He took her down to Chinatown
And he showed her how
to kick the gong around
She had a dream
about the King of Sweden
He gave her things
that she was needin'
He gave her a home
built of gold and steel
A diamond car
with the platinum wheels
This is glue. Strong stuff.
What the hell are you doing?
This can is from
a surplus disposal run.
Fifteen overcharged ounces
of pure, uncompounded...
isopropyl butane monosulfate.
When combined with oxygen
and a little heat...
it will cause a rapid expansion.
Poor Min, poor Min
- Let's take them!
- Wait a minute.
I've never even heard
these boys sing, all right?
All right.
They're not going no place.
All right, cover all exits! Let's go!
Come on! Hurry up!
Move it!
Who wants an Orange Whip?
Orange Whip?
Three Orange Whips.
Excuse us.
Good evening, ladies.
One, two,
one, two, three, four.
Now, ladies and gentlemen, it is the
distinct pleasure of the management...
to present to you
the evening's star attraction.
Here they are, back after
their exclusive three-year tour...
of Europe, Scandinavia
and the subcontinent.
Won't you welcome
from Calumet City, Illinois...
the show band
of Joliet Jake and Elwood Blues.
The Blues Brothers!
One, two.
One, two, three, four.
We're so glad to see
so many lovely people here tonight.
We'd like to welcome
all the representatives...
of Illinois' law enforcement
community...
who have chosen to join us in
the Palace Hotel ballroom at this time.
We certainly hope you all
enjoy the show.
And remember that
no matter who you are...
and what you do
to live and survive...
there's still some things
that make us all the same.
You. Me. Them. Everybody.
Everybody
Needs somebody
Needs somebody to love
Someone to love
Sweetheart to miss
Sugar to kiss
I need you, you, you
In the morning
When my soul's on fire
Sometimes I feel
I feel a little sad inside
When my baby mistreats me
I never, never
Find a place to hide
I need you
Sometimes I feel
I feel a little sad inside
When my baby mistreats me
I never, never find a place to hide
I need you
People, when you do find
that special somebody...
you gotta hold that man,
hold that woman...
love him, please him,
squeeze her, please her!
Signify your feelings
with every caress.
Because it's so important
to have that special somebody...
to hold, kiss, miss...
to squeeze and please!
Everybody needs somebody
Everybody
Needs somebody to love
Someone to love
Sweetheart to miss
Sugar to kiss
I need you, you
In the morning
When my soul's on fire
When there ain't no one around
I need you
thank you.
That was for Wilson Pickett.
This is dedicated
to the late, great Magic Sam.
One, two.
One, two, three, four.
Come on
Baby, don't you wanna go
Back to that same old place
Sweet home Chicago
Six and three is nine
Nine and nine is eighteen
Look there, brother, baby
and see what I see
- The Mafia's after us now.
- You guys were hot!
You were great!
I've got to record you.
- Bullshit.
- I don't bullshit.
I'm president of Clarion Records...
the largest recording company
on the eastern seaboard.
- So what?
- Here's $10,000.
An advance on your first
recording session.
Is it a deal?
Yeah. Sure, it's a deal.
Yeah. Sure, it's a deal!
Listen, all these cops out here--
they're waiting for us.
We gotta get out with nobody
seeing us. You know a back door out?
Sure. I used to be head bouncer here
back in the '70s.
There's an electrical service duct
behind your drummer's riser.
Do us a favor.
Take $1,400 and give it
to Ray's Music Exchange...
in Calumet City,
and give the rest to the band.
- You got it.
- Thanks.
Bye.
Me and Elwood are gonna make a break
for it. You and the band keep playing.
- Something's wrong.
- Where's Jake?
Where'd they go?
I sure hope this thing
leads someplace.
Elwood, we're gone, man.
Who is that girl?
Well, Jake.
You look just fine down there...
slithering in the mud
like vermin.
No problem.
You're not gonna get away from me
this time.
Check that out! Let's go!
It's good to see you,
sweetheart!
You contemptible pig.
I remained celibate for you.
I stood at the back
of a cathedral...
waiting, in celibacy, for you...
with 300 friends and relatives
in attendance.
My uncle hired the best
Rumanian caterers in the state.
To obtain the seven limousines...
my father used up his last favors
with Mad Pete Trullo.
So for me, for my mother...
my grandmother, my father,
my uncle and for the common good...
I must now kill you
and your brother.
Oh, please don't kill us!
You know I love you, baby! I wouldn't
leave you! It wasn't my fault!
You miserable slug!
You think you can talk your way
out of this? You betrayed me!
No, I didn't. Honest!
I ran out of gas!
I had a flat tyre!
I didn't have money for cab fare!
My tux didn't come back
from the cleaners.
And old friend came in
from out of town!
Someone stole my car! There was
an earthquake! A terrible flood!
Locusts! It wasn't my fault,
I swear to God!
Jake, honey.
Let's go.
Take it easy.
You're now going to
totally demolish that car.
You want to maybe consider
going after the Blues Brothers?
It's 106 miles to Chicago.
We got a full tank of gas,
half a pack of cigarettes...
it's dark
and we're wearing sunglasses.
Hit it.
Shit, man. Can't this damn thing
go any faster than this?
Bob, I think I've got
a little problem.
Goddam, boy.
Shit.
Don't you say a fuckin' word.
All units, we have a ten-seven-niner.
Officers are in pursuit:
a black-and-white
1974 Dodge sedan...
southbound on 47.
Respond to signal, ten-seven-niner.
Occupants of vehicle:
one Joliet Jake Blues...
one Elwood Blues.
- Considered extremely dangerous.
- Gruppenfuehrer!
Jake, I gotta pull over.
Southbound on State Highway 47.
Hi! Wanna hand me the mike?
Thanks a lot.
This is car--
What number are we?
Five-five.
Car 55. We're in a truck.
Signal ten-seven-niner
still engaged.
Vehicle traveling southbound
approaching Chicago city limits.
Commander advises will contact
Chicago precincts...
for a local intercept.
Maintain pursuit.
Use of unnecessary violence...
in the apprehension
of the Blues Brothers has been approved.
Well, this is definitely
Lower Wacker Drive.
If my estimations are correct...
we should be very close to
the Honorable Richard J. Daley Plaza.
- That's where they got that Picasso.
- Yep.
Son of a bitch!
There they are.
- Oh, no!
- What the fuck was that?
The motor. It's thrown a rod.
- Is that serious?
- Yep.
Faster.
Holy shit!
I've always loved you.
There it is!
Come on!
Sir, where's the office
of the assessor of Cook County?
Down the hall. Turn right.
Take the elevator to 1102.
thank you, sir.
Excuse me.
Did you see two guys...
with black suits and hats,
one carrying a briefcase?
Yeah. I just sent them down there.
thank you.
Hold the door.
Let's go.
Can I help you?
- This is where they pay taxes, right?
- Right.
This money is for
the year's assessment...
on the St. Helen of the Blessed Shroud
Orphanage in Calumet City, Illinois.
Five thousand bucks.
It's all there, pal.
Stand back!
Fire!
And here is your receipt.
Warden threw a party
in the county jail
Prison band was there
and they began to wail
The band was jumping
and the joint began to swing
You should of heard those
knocked-out jail birds sing
Let's rock
Everybody, let's rock
Everybody on the whole cell block
Was dancing to the jailhouse rock
Spider Murphy played
the tenor saxophone
Little Joe was blowin'
on the slide trombone
The drummer boy from Illinois
went crash, boom, bang
The whole rhythm section
was the Purple Gang
Let's rock
Everybody, let's rock
Everybody on the whole cell block
Was dancing to the jailhouse rock
Sad Sack was sitting
on a block of stone
Way over in the corner
weeping all alone
The warden said
Buddy, don't you be no square
lf you can't get a partner
use a wooden chair
Let's rock
Everybody, let's rock
Everybody on the whole cell block
Was dancing to the jailhouse rock