I believe the harder
time is to wake up in the morning.
Those first moments
before I remember who I am...
instead of
remember me...
Who I was.
Mother, there is snow
in Mt. Tom.  Will still be there
on the weekend.
Do not make me go to school today.
It's the first day of snow.
There is snow on Mount Tom.
Want to get some more sleep?
I can not delay on the first day of class.
Everyone will go skiing, except me.
Oh, I wanted to go, too.
Get out of here!
Mother!
Want to please
find Gary.
The reverend called tonight
and said his class...
will be full this year.
Good morning, children.
Good morning.
I am Jill Kinmont, your teacher.
Then my mother puts me in the
chair in the morning.
And I stay all day.
Until she takes me out at night.
Do you stay in the chair all day?
I stay.
Are you never going to the bathroom?
All the time.
I have a catheter inserted into me.
A probe that stays
inside me...
attached to a bag stuck
in my leg.
See. Here is the place.
Wow, what a beautiful thing.
What is the best way to fish for trout?
With a harpoon.
Great. How do you
write harpoon?
Come on.
You can fish the trout.
A-R-P-A-O
It was almost, it was almost certain.
But in the end it is no.
Do you know how to write?
Edie?
- A, til, O.
- Right.
So how do you
write harpoon?
- Me, me, me!
- Everyone.
A-R-P-Ã-O
Right.
No, no one will want to marry you.
Do not you?
Of course, she is beautiful.
But she can not dance or anything.
Has anyone ever asked you?
- He asked for what?
- In married.
- Yes.
- Who?
You do not know.
If he asked,
why did not you accept?
I always think
I have overcome everything.
That no longer hurts me more.
Suddenly everything comes back.
Here in Bishop, more than
anywhere.
Because here I can raise my eyes
and see the snow.
I am Jill Kinmont
and I am a skier!
A WINDOW FOR HEAVEN
Here, look at it here.
The most beautiful thing
that I have ever seen.
The fastest skier in the world.
Buek, the crazy dog
is his nickname, because he...
is a crazy person.
And they say he's trying to kill himself.
- Is it? Well, that's what they say.
What if he dies before we meet him?
What if he kills himself before
joining the team?
No you will not.
- And if he dies? We will not know.
- What is this?
- Anything.
Ah, what is this, come on.
Let me see.
- What is this?
- Anything.
Girl.
Oh, it's Dick Buek. I got a letter
from him this morning.
Did not you know?
We have corresponded ourselves
for a long time.
He's crazy to meet me
when joining the Olympic team.
Of course!
But he is too old.
You must be about 22 years old.
Besides, I'm in love with another guy.
Oh is it? And who is the lucky one?
James Dean.
Attention, I want
all listening.
A.J?
We have our
first competition of the year...
this weekend, or next weekend.
In general I take the best
skiers to these races.
But this time I decided to take everyone.
Herbie, do you want to stop
with these hands?
I did not do anything.
Herbie, take it easy.
What did I do wrong?
As if he did not know.
You do not stop with those hands.
Lie, they're still.
It's okay. Can someone change
place with Gil?
I change.
Audra Jo!
- How wonderful!
- Wow!
A.J. return here and
take your skis.
Thank you.
Herbie.
Herbie, tell her to come back
and get the skis.
Let's all be together
, okay?
As far as I remember,
everything I wanted...
It was skiing.
It was not just a sport, it was a way of life.
Our coach was
David McCoy.
A former champion who gave
to our Gym the...
team level
first line.
And now the number 74, Boulder.
Colorado.
Our most difficult opponent was
the team from Boulder, Colorado.
Led by a real
hall named Buddy Werner.
Ready for the start
No. 46 of Bishop, California.
Ten seconds.
Skeeter Werner of
Boulder, Colorado with # 6.  One, already!
The best
team of Colorado skier was...
Skeeter Werner. And began
a personal war for...
prove which team
was the best.
Paragraph 14, ten seconds.
Alda Jo Nicholson,
Bishop, California.
- Five, four...
- Number 14.
Three, two, one, already!
This is your second
year of competition.
Last year she finished
fourth in the...
Finals in Z'berg, California.
No 89, ready for
the start.
At the starting spot,
Jill Kinmont, No. 89.
Jill can still reach it.
Skeeter beat me...
for only five seconds.
Ten seconds!
Five, four, three,
two, one, already!
- Jill goes, goes!
- Go!
Jill Kinmont, No. 89,
Running Incomplete.
Beautiful. Do you want me to take
a picture of you?
I bit my tongue.
Who ordered to leave
out in the race?
Wonder why
you burned?
My coach will tell me, thank you.
Skinny is gravity.
It's so much more powerful than you.
The less you fight it, the faster it will go.
Do I know you?
No.
Raises.
What are you, doctor?
No. Look, keep your hands right in front of you.
What do these initials mean?
That's my name. Bend like this
and release the body.
Gravity works...
- Mike?
Ankles, knee, back
, elbows.
Is Melvin? Mark?
Make you
a projectile.
Do you want to learn to
ski or not?
Look, I'm sorry. But I do not take ski lessons...
with anyone not.
I am Jill Kinmont and it happens
that I am the best skier...
My God! It's the crazy dog Buek!
We now have the first
placed, Skeeter and Buddy Werner.
I had met Dick Buek.
And I thought my life would never be the same.
But summer has come and
all the fantasies...
they had to be put aside.
My family ran
a ranch named Rockin K.
And during the summers we all worked on it.
That was it.
- I can not believe.
My best friend
was Audra Jo Nicholson.
We were inseparable.
- He is looking at us. Look at his face.
There was nothing we did not
know about each other.
No dream we did not share.
But our biggest dream was skiing.
We lived always in the hope
of some day to participate...
Olympic team meetings.
Hey, J.
Are you awake?
Can I talk to you?
I'm so tired.
But you just
will listen.
It's okay.
I've been thinking about luck.
Why does luck always walk with me?
Everything I wanted, I always did.
Have you ever felt this?
Once in a while.
E...
I begin to think if...
I am not one of those
people who were born with luck.
If I'm using all my luck at once.
What do you think?
I think I'm sick.
What happened?
I have a horrible headache
.
You did not catch the sun
too much A. J.?
Want an aspirin?
I already have.
It was too much sun
that you took.
Improved?
Continue.
Do not know...
I wonder if...
I'll go back
to see Dick.
What do you think?
Jose?
A.J? Are you alright?
Jose? Are you alright?
Guys, call a doctor,
there's something wrong with A. J.!
What did the doctor say?
I think it would be better
you guys get my car...
And come back, okay?
But what is it?
They think it's polio.
You must go now.
Coach!
Can you give her that ring?
And tell her that
I love her.
Really.
Josie.
We go together
the Olympics.
You will be fine.
We go together.
You will be fine, Jose.
You will be fine.
After Jose got sick
I wanted to ski for both of us.
And I trained that summer
more than in any other.
Is it really him?
He is. He landed his
airplane practically...
in Dave's backyard. I saw you from the highway.
I thought he was going to fall.
But when I got there - it was coming out of the...
Crutches plane.
Of crutches?
I swear to God.
He was flying the crutch plane.
Why?
The leg, it broke the leg.
Did not you know?
She left in all the magazines.
He was on the
motorcycle at 150.
He hit a trailer
of camping and...
flew in through one window and out the other.
They thought she had died
and even covered his face.
Have you ever imagined?
He did not know anything.
That's what you get
for living in the woods.
You're not kidding me- no, right Linda?
Cheating? I swear.
Look at his plane, son of a bitch.
- Hi, girls.
- Hi.
What happened?
It's just that we were
going to school, so...
We decided to give a pass here.
And knowing what time will
be the training.
In the usual time.
I did not say that
would be the usual time?
= 15:30.
I do not know why she insisted
on passing by?
- Hi!
- Excuse.
Hi.
- I'm Linda Mayer.
- Hi, beautiful.
I've read a lot about you since
you started skiing.
I wrote you a letter to the hospital.
Ah, this is an old friend of mine.
Old friend of mine too.
Do you know her?
Everything that she knows, I taught.
Listen to girls, you're not going
to be late for class, right?
Come on Jill, we'll be late.
You can go,
find you later.
What story can this be?
That you can go.
Then...
Would not you like to take a walk?
Ok.
Do you think she's on the plane with him?
It's best to call
David McCoy.
- We can cross here. You will not.
Give up to
betting race.
Why do you do these things?
Do you want to kill yourself?
I've heard of the crazy things you do.
Freefall with parachute
found in trash cans.
Motorcycle racing
like crazy.
Do not believe everything you say.
- Why, Dick?
- Because what?
Why do you want to die?
- Are you worried?
- Do not play.
I'm wondering.
I do not worry about it.
Oh, yes. Here I am.
And I am nothing.
I studied until high school.
No thought
important in the head.
But I live.
No matter what I do,
I end up standing again.
I do not know why
good people die.
And I keep living.
You are a good person.
Yes it is.
And how do you know?
I know I care
with you.
So it should be good.
You find me funny.
I think you're beautiful.
You too.
Yes it is.
Dick.
Please stay alive.
Winter of 1955.
We were there for a
year of the Olympics.
And everyone who wanted to
if they were classified would have...
they finish the season
among the first.
E at the starting spot,
or No. 32, Allan Freeman.
Four, three, two, one, already!
Listen, you can not see it very well.
So then, let go.
But be aggressive until
the end, okay?
Ten seconds.
And with No. 89, Jill Kinmont.
Three, two, one, already!
As the
dispute escalated...
greater was my
determination to win.
I won the regional
tournament more trophies...
than I had won
in a year.
And No. 89 was beginning to draw attention.
Excuse me.
- Wow, you were great.
- Thanks.
- Let's see what it was...
- Hey Buddy, how about putting...
the arm on her waist?
Ask her if
she will leave.
The best was Jill Kinmont.
You leave?
In that wonderful year
Buddy Werner has obtained many...
victories like me.
And for all the places we were
going to, we all wanted...
We started dating.
But I kept thinking
in Buek and during...
That winter I searched for him.
- Account for me.
- IT IS.
- Is it really?
- Yes.  Look who's here, the Buek.
Who is that
blonde with him?
Must be someone's daughter.
They say they are engaged.
- Hi, how are you?
You do not want to play a game?
- Give it some time. Okay, bye, Dick.
Hey, Dick. How did you break your arm?
Dancing with a
heavy girl.
I know you, do not I?
Yes.
- Hello Buddy.
- Hi.
I want to introduce you to
you my fiancée.
Hey, Dick Buek! How's it going, man?
Are you reminded of Charlie last winter?
- Yes, of course. Come on, I'll buy you a beer.
Come on, you talk to
these guys later.
Hey.
If there is anything wrong,
I would like to help.
- Good race!
- Too!
Listen, you take it easy
this time.
You're good on the front, right?
So do not try
no record.
And do not forget that
tree, right?
Come on, there. Capriche,
have fun and...
Hold the lead.
89, ten seconds.
At the starting spot, Jill Kinmont,
With No. 89.
- The skier of the year. Four, three, two, one, now!
When the season was
nearing the end.
Buddy and I were invited
to train in a special field.
Preparing us for the last
great race of the year.
It was called, snow bowl.
And it was held in Alta, Utah.
If I won there, I would be qualified
for the Olympics.
Come on Jill, stop with the jokes.
Jill, let's go back.
Come soon,
let's get down.
February 1, 1955.
The Snow Bowl would be
within a few days.
And the experts bet that we would both win.
Will both of you go to the Olympic games together?
Have both of you ever fallen in a dispute?
Listen, I'll talk to you later.
I get distracted from
_ time to time I fall.
And you think it will be very difficult?
How about competing with
all favorites?
Thanks.
- Good luck.
- They are awesome.
Flight 32, coming from
Los Angeles, landing...
through gate four.
David.
And then? Did you have a good trip?
She will be doing a lot
well, of course she will leave.
This reception was a beauty, was not it?
It is divided into three parts.
You have to go slowly at first.
But it will have to increase
well the speed...
when entering the middle part
.
There's the ditch they call a corkscrew.
On that side.
Then comes a relatively easy
voucher.
And already will have arrived.
Look, the race will be won
or lost right there.
There in the corkscrew.
There is a rise. A steep climb up before him.
So if you get into it
too fast, you will...
upload with everything.
Therefore, decrease there.
- Right.
Wait a little, that
is Andrea Mead Lawrence.
It is decreasing. You're slower, right?
Okay, it was almost perfect,
you saw?
She lost some time, but
managed to control himself, understood?
Now go ahead and do
your training, okay?
My main opponent
was a girl named...
Andrea Lawrence.
Great skier from the east
who needed to beat the...
Race as much as I do.
But after seeing her train I
concludes that he could beat her.
She was decreasing a lot
in the corkscrew and it was there...
that I could beat it.
- Jill!
- Buddy!
- I wanted to wish good luck. Also for you.
- Take.
- What is it?
- I want you to stay with you.
- What is?
Saint Kitts, for luck.
- I have to go.
- Jill.
I want to go to the
olympics married.
With me And with whom would it be?
I do not know. I'm a heap of nerves.
Now I have to go.
I love you.
I love you, too.
We meet there
down, right?
Right.
And we talk about
that there too.
- Right.
- Good luck.
With the No. 14 by the
male division, Bob Lowner...
in his first race.
- See that. How he fell.
Right and left.
Carpenter and Walsh...
have already hit a record. And the
two main competitors...
Andrea Mead Lawrence and
Jill Kinmont are still going to run.
At the starting spot,
Andrea Mead Lawrence...
with number 6.
Go Andy!
Yes, we are ready.
Three, two, one, already!
And here she comes - coming down very well.
It will be difficult to beat her.
Half the race is over.
Next competitor, No. 89,
Jill Kinmont.
You can win the race.
You have to win, right?
Be sweaty, use your head
and watch the mountain.
Are they all ready?
- Yes.  - Chronometrists too?
Yes, all set.
Everything ready for the
skier No. 89.
- Yes, everything is ready.
- It's ok.
Ten seconds!
Ten seconds.
Five, four, three,
two, one, already!
Empty the lane, please.
Empty the lane.
It's okay. They're already doing it.
Yes, they are.
Empty the track. Want to
Empty the track, please.
Do you feel pain in some place, Jill?
I do not feel anything.
Can you feel your toes?
No. Jill, it's David.
We will take care of her.
Jill, I want you to listen to me.
Try to stay calm.
These people will take care of you, okay?
I'm going down to the bottom
and I'll see you from here.
- Are you okay?
- Right.
Don, Jake, take her by the arms.
Sam. You take
by the legs.
Skeeter, you hold your feet.
Let's straighten it out. Careful and slow.
That's right. It's only gonna take a minute.
Hold on, Jill.
Straighten up and her leg
a little longer, Skeeter.
It's okay. When I say three, let's get her up.
Slowly. One two Three.
Slow down, that.
So. Cover it now.
Ready?
One two Three.
Slow down, be careful.
Try to keep it level.
So. Caution.
Back, please. Please, back.
Driver. How long will it take?
You are very bottled.
It may take hours.
She will not succeed.
David, I will not die.
I want you to hear me.
This is Jill Kinmont.
And she will not die. You understood well?
My head. What's in my head?  It is the traction.
Jill.
You will be
good Jill.
Are you listening to me?
Do not look at me like that.
Sleep, Jill.
Close your eyes and sleep.
If I sleep,
do not agree more.
You will heal yourself, Jill.
Yes you will.
Help me stay awake, Buddy.
Help me stay awake.
There was a fracture with
displacement of the spine...
at C5 level.
In simple language,
means that...
Her neck broke.
And the marrow was
entirely broken.
And is there a cure?
It will merge.
But that's not the same thing as healing.
- What is the...
- Prognosis?
Yes.
At this point...
It is a matter of speculation.
We will have to wait...
she tells us.
In the meantime, all we have to do is wait.
And twist.
Wait for her to walk?
Let her live.
One, two, three.
Who is there?
Hi, I'm your doctor,
Dr. Pittman.
There is blood in your shoe. Oh, it's life.
I hope it is not mine.
Wait outside.
- Jill. Mom, come here.
- Oh, Jill.
- I do not see you.
- Can you turn it on? We turn now.
Please do not cry, Mom.
His eyes are filled with water.
Do not cry too or
will wet my whole face.
No, just with eyes.
It hurts the head.
I'm almost done.
And come back again.
Great.
Nurse.
Thank you.
- It's bad, no.
- Why do you say that.
I suspect smiling doctors.
Want to hear about it?
Of course.
Nothing seems to have been left here below.
No movement, no feelings...
of any kind.
If the fracture had been
a fraction below.
You would have lost the
use of your hands.
But if it had been
a fraction above...
You would have to live
in a steel lung.
- How long?
For me to get well.
- Jill.
- Dr. Pittman.
- You do not understand. And not you.
I have a mania, you know.
How much do I want some...
thing, I can.
I understand this, but...
No, you do not understand.
I'm going to walk out of here.
And if you tell someone who will
be the opposite...
I'll leave you
with your face to the ground.
Hi.
How are you feeling?
- Very well.
I'm coming home.
So I decided to go
here and tell you that...
if you need anything, anything...
same, just ask me
for them to call me...
Then I'll see what I can do.
I think they
are very competent.
They are doing a good job.
Yes. Look at this mess.
Yes, I saw this.
How is Anie getting successful?
He was already successful before.
She won
many races.
She is a good skier.
Great skier,
great skier.
You have practically everything here, no.
David, David.
David.
Everything is fine.
It's... alright.
I see you soon.
= Bye.
I felt very much to be
_ obliged to leave...
Before you woke up.
But I intend to compensate
this by spending the rest of my life...
Seeing you wake up and go to
sleep in our own bed.
Can not imagine how
I was excited...
When I read
that you will...
When I read that you are going
to go back to skiing.
But I knew you would not settle for less.
When I can
join enough money...
to visit you. You will walk to me...
And to my arms. And we'll go walking together.
With love, Buddy.
He is wonderful.
Yes it is.
And you are a
lucky girl.
Is here the crippled sector?
A.J? Mom, it's A.J.!
Audra Jo!
In the flesh.
Look at you,
on crutches.
Queer, right?
No, fantastic.
Unbelievable.
Come here, Josie.
Come here.
- How did you get here? I got a ride.
How crazy.
- Oh really.
I took a ride with my
therapist, his family lives here.
And he is handsome. What do you think?
I think it's sensational.
- Open your mouth.
- No.
Good...
I have to go.
Do you want to see me again?
Jill. Good friends are the ones
who tell the truth.
What do you want me to do?
Stop trying?
Who gives up?
What do you want? The Academy Award?
I want to walk.
What is so important about walking?
For God's sake. A three-year-old
child can walk.
Because I can not walk.
I can not even move.
So take it, Jill. Admit it.
Stop playing heroin.
I remember very well that you
wanted to be a hero.
At that time many people laughed at you.
Yes. But I did not tell anyone
who was going to climb Everest.
Advice from a
veteran cripple.
You have to know what you are.
And say what you are.
Before you set out to
work with little...
That remains of you.
Audra Jo. What if there was nothing
left of me in the end?
So you'll have to learn
to paint with your teeth.
What happened to you?
The same thing that will happen
with you.
There's only one thing that kills
the cripples.
It is not to value
to themselves.
You still have
your arms, Audra Jo.
Great, we go to the center
of rehabilitation and I show...
someone who has no face
or a child in...
a steel lung.
Enough.
So stop moaning
the loss of your medals...
Olympic and thank God for still
having your head.
Anything else
is superfluous.
- Audra Jo.
- What?
I could have won.
Did you know that?
Beaten or what?
The Snow Bowl.
The Cup of the Snow...
Was not this tournament that
ended your career?
An iron disposition, to
declare from the bed of a...
hospital she
will go back to skiing.
They say that you will
go back to ski.
And you will.
You will come back
to ski.
In the spring I was transferred
to a hospital in Los Angeles.
And that began work
to find out what I had...
and what I did not have. Now, deeper.
Likewise, Jill.
Now continue.
Continue pulling
safely.
Keep your head to the front and
keep pulling.
I started getting familiar
with words like extenders,
Flexors, deltoids, trapezoids.
And I exercised more than I have
exercised in my entire life.
Continue, that's right. So, Jill. Is very good.
Very good indeed.
Now, stretch very slowly. Slowly. Like this.
- Hi, I'm Dr. Enders. Hi, Doctor.
- I can save your time.
- Ah yes.
I have biceps, but I do not have triceps.
Deltoids, but not pectorals.
Just a little bit of
pectoral on the left side...
but not much.
I believe it's a bit unusual
, but it was a fracture...
cross, so the left
side is a bit stronger.
Oh, yes. And how do you feel?
I'm fine, and you?
I want you to squeeze your fingers now.
Very well. I want to feel pressure on my finger.
It's okay.
Push.
Push. Not the arm, Jill. He's moving his arm.
Great, try again.
Push.
- It's still your arm.
- Right.
Let's try more
once.
Ok.
Now try not to look at your arm.
Just look at the board
and let's see what happens.
Now, just worry
with your shoulder.
Let your shoulders do
the move up and...
and gravity will do the rest.
Come on. That.
More with the shoulder.
We are going well.
More strength with
the shoulder, more.
So.
You can.
- Come on, come on.
- That.
- Come on!
- Continues!
- Let's go!
- Come on!
- Push!
- Do it!
- How am I?
- You look beautiful.
Go there and see how
I get the distance.
Oh, it's wonderful.
Where are the fried potatoes?
- They are on your lap.
- Can go.
Hi.
Enter.
You look beautiful.
- Do you think? Yes.
Oh, Buddy, I miss you.
I was homesick too.
Can you kiss me?
Are you okay?
I am wonderful.
I tried to write
every week.
Did you try?
Well, I just tried.
Want to see something exciting?
If you want to show me.
If you want to see it.
That's what I came for, was not it?
Go there and
look here.
Will not you need help?
Are you sure?
Go there and look.
It's okay.
Now feel.
Come on, I'm waiting.
Hold your breath and
do not say anything.
This requires a tremendous concentration.
Come on, Jill.
I've been waiting for it for a long time.
It's okay. Watch with
attention because the hand...
is faster than
the eye.
And neither broke.
Did not you see what I did?
It was the hardest
so far.
Jill.
Are not you going to walk?
Walk?
- It's...
I thought you were...
No.  I will never walk again.
Buddy phoned a week later.
I never heard from him again.
How about taking her home for a while?
Physically she is more
capable than ever.
It would be a good rest
before it was transferred...
to the California Rehabilitation Center.
That's another problem, Dr. Enders.
She does not want to go to the
Rehabilitation Center.
Every time I mention
the Rehabilitation Center...
She says she does not need
nobody to teach...
How to sell pencils.
What do you want?
It's time for the injection.
Injection of what?
Of what you most need, my dear.
Oh, my God. I do not believe it.
Well, you'd better believe girl.
And get your ass off that bed.
- What are you doing here? You have a coat?
- What are you doing here? Taking you.
Where is this bottle connected?
She is permanent.
Then she goes along.
- Who is this? My only friend.
Dick. I can not be removed in this way.
Who said that?
- The doctors.
Well, doctors do not know anything.
Dick!
Listen, one more word of yours and
I pat your ass.
And I would not feel anything.
You'll be glad you do not feel it.
Jesus, you are heavy.
- You're totally crazy.
And you were not the first to notice.
- Good morning.
- Good Morning.
Dick, please,
watch out for the ladder!
Dick, stop, please. Dick, this is crazy!
Open up wings, it will pass
a paraplegic.
Buek, the signal will open.
No one runs over a
wheelchair.
Will open!
Open it, what will you do?
What are you doing?
It's okay. I have a few things to say to you.
But she needed a little privacy.
Why do not you say
to your bride?
Because I do not have
bride, she did not want me.
I do not blame her, because
I would not either.
Oh is it? For it is better to think twice...
about this because you
will get a damn job...
To attract lovers
lying in the drug of that...
hospital bed, made
a lot of clay.
Ah, poor thing. And mourn
rather than maybe...
get some idiot
like Buddy Weber...
Feel sorry for you.
Oh, you've talked too much.
I've heard.
No, you did not hear everything.
Because I'm going to stay here...
Until you get the hang of it.
You understood.
I do not care about you
not being able to ski.
And it matters little to me - you can not walk.
I do not care if you
creeps around...
made a gecko.
This will not make me feel pity for you.
You are too presumptuous,
to think that I need you.
I do not care if
you need it or not.
I have nothing better
to do with you.
This is a public road, come on!
Oh, I'm sorry, I do not
understand what you're saying.
Do you want me to check the oil?
Are you going crazy, boy?
What the hell did you decide to
do with my car?
Move away from there.
This is a particular
property.
You can not do this.
Get away from that car, boy.
Wait a little.
The oil is low.
What? I changed the oil last week.
You are crazy, are you?
Look here, boy.
Put that in place.
Or I'm going to get out of here.
I will inform the authorities.
I will sue you.
This will not be
_ like that, boy.
Ready. Are not you going to pay me now?
I want my money
.
WELCOME JILL.
GOOD TO SEE YOU.
I get off the plane and suddenly
we were surrounded by...
a lot of men
with machine guns.
They thought we were spies.
Wow, machine guns. Did you hear that, Father?
What are your plans, Dick.
I say about the future.
Well, I do not have any.
I live one day
at a time.
Jake, cut the meat for me?
Cut yourself.
We can not spoil it.
That is her problem.
As I said. I was sitting there in the woods.
I did not know any of those people.
They did not know what government I was.
They arrested me for... -
I think I stayed there for a couple of days.
Finally I got to go from Ô hitchhiking to Acapulco.
- Take it easy, let's take it easy.
- I'm afraid.
I am holding you.
There is no danger.
Dick. Ah yes, look there.
See? There is no danger.
I think that's enough. Wait, Bill.
Father, leave him alone.
He knows what he's doing.
You have no way.
You.
You do not want to wet your hair, do you?
They're already wet, Dick.
They are already wet.
Come on, extend your arms.
Put your arms here.
Like a boat. I'm scared, Dick.
Dick.
Dick, come here.
Do not leave me here alone.
Please,
I'm scared.
Dick, please.
Dick, I'm slipping. Dick, Dick!
Dick, I'm slipping, Dick.
Jill!
Calm down, I got you.
Is everything okay?
Calm down.
Are you okay? Ok.
I'm sorry.
Was inadvertently.
It was not meant to be.
I just wanted to see how you did it, that's all.
Are you okay?
Excuse me.
- Because, Dick. I did not mean it.
What do you think?
I do not know.
I already have the house
all in the head.
No stairs, only ramps.
All things in the kitchen
in low places.
Up to the sink, 60 cm high.
Yes. I can not have children, Dick.
I already thought of that.
I...
I do not feel anything.
From the neck down.
So I do not know how we'll make love.
Not only that we will do.
You'll want more than me.
The people of arranja.
No, you were going to get tired.
It would come out to give its
turns with...
No, never again. I'm going to get a job.
I will not do that.
For God's sake. Someone has to do this to me.
What is it?
You will tell me.
Why are you so reluctant?
- I know.
There must be something...
something that avoids...
that I am so...
= = Useless.
It seems we have
the same problem.
Clear my nose.
Okay?
Only if you say you love me.
I love it.
I Love.
I'm going to build that house.
Okay?
What if you do not want it...
I can find another
crippled to live there.
It's okay.
Are you listening?
It is the bell of the Indian reservation school.
- Which tribe?
- Paiute.
Do you know anyone there?
No.  We had two in
grammar classes, but...
They were very quiet boys.
Yeah, usually they are.
Why did you ask?
Have you ever been there?
No.  You mean you lived in this city all your life...
- and did not go there even once?
- Never.
Good, so I guess
it's time for you to go.
I do not understand.
Why does no one help them?
Because they are busy
trying to organize...
their own lives.
Why do they stay in this place?
Why do not they leave?
They have no other place to go.
The problem is the teachers, Jill.
They pay almost nothing
to those who teach...
in indigenous reservations.
So good teachers go to places like Los Angeles.
But that is not fair.
Many things are not fair, my dear.
I at least had a chance.
But those people do not have...
the least chance.
Mother, father. Dick let me fly the plane.
- What? I left nothing.
See if you do not get me in trouble.
I did not,
I swear.
- Did you revise it?
- To go away.
Where?
- Home.
Are you leaving?
You did not expect me to stay forever, did you?
It will only be,
for a while. Jill.
Why did not you tell me?
It was so fast.
You will have to
do the rehabilitation.
I'm going to build the house.
And in the spring...
Spring is far away.
Time passes so quickly.
Dick.
Do you want to stop? So you're going to
make me cry too.
It's good to have friends who
can make us cry.
Not everyone has
friends who do this.
Okay, you'll be fine.
You will be fine.
Take it easy, take it easy.
Calm down, that.
Calm down.
I'll be right back.
Okay? You are OK?
Okay?
Okay!
Jill, you will love
this place.
It does not look like much
with a Rehabilitation Center.
If it looks like one more
great party.
It is one of the most participating.
You will meet the other
inmates, they are great.
Fantastic.
Well, they are strangers,
at first.
But as soon as you
know better,
will like them.
Personally, this is Jill.
Jill, these are Keny, Cookie,
- Neil. Welcome to the circus.
Bill, George...
Pat!
And there are Willis and Lee.  Lee Zadroga.
Bill? Did you see the play he did?
- It was Willie Mays!
- Duke Snider!
It was who?
- Duck Snider!
- Willie Mays! Duke Snider, right?
Over the shoulder,
over the shoulder.
I think it was the
Duke Snider!
Charlie how can you compare a
white with a black?
I can, that's why I say it was Willie Mays.
Jill was a famous person. Someone here knew that?
What did you do, Jill?
He did nothing.
Her photograph left
on the cover...
From the magazine of popular mechanics.
Yes. She was the cripple of the month.
- Will do what, now?
- I do not know.
Try to be useful.
Useful how?
Try to teach.
For example.
And after that she will try to
be a neurosurgeon.
She was skiing.
It was America's hope in the Olympics.
Well, she can hold the skis
in the chair and go back to ski.
And then, Jill.
Are not you going to say anything?
Maybe she can not say anything
without the press nearby.
You know, it's a
famous girl.
Jill. On basketball court
we thought of...
fact that we were
something.
We always left the court
very happy.
And one of the guys from the team
made a joke saying:
Why are we happy? We beat a bunch of cripples.
It's beautiful in this chair.
I love this chair. It's a wonderful world!
Hey, wait there guys.
She's only been here for...
a few hours, and therefore,
we will handle, right?
She's still wanting
sympathy, Ken.
You know
sympathy in the dictionary...
is not it? Between
_ grave and suicide.
They live in a very isolated
world here.
Newcomers
are a threat.
Especially those who come with great ideas.
What is so great about wanting to teach?
This has already been attempted.
There is not a single school
in the country that accepts a...
teacher in chair
of wheels.
Why the paraplegics and the quadriplegics can not...
nor sign up to
get the certificate.
- It's not fair. Of course it's not fair.
But the world out there -
imagine that if the feet...
They become paralyzed,
the brain also remains.
So there is a lot of lost potential.
People who swallow
defeat because it is...
tucked in so hard
throat down...
that do not swallow,
are choked.
With you not happened?
Well, in a way it's much easier
for me than for them.
They will be paralyzed
forever.
- And you walk again? No, I'm going to die.
They gave me a
year of life.
So time is so precious to me.
I can not allow myself to lose it.
And what do you do with your time?
I am studying.
University.
I'm doing masters.
And will it end?
I will get very close.
What are you going to do?
With?
Now, when are you going to start studying?
They would not accept me.
My gym notes
were bad.
Look, listen to something.
When the body goes away, the mind can compensate.
Do you understand this?
It's like a blind man who suddenly
the hearing gets sharper.
I already understood.
But how will they know?
I'll tell them.
I recommended Audra Jo and Cookie.
I can do the same for you.
I can hurt you.
My brain has always been the weakest
muscle in my body.
Then, force, exercise,
place under training.
Are you okay?
Say you're fine.
Ok.
Uh, what a day.
- Now it's my turn.
- Oh yes.
- Are they ready?
- You are ready?
Do you think I'm what, Tarzan?
Look, the secretariat is there,
just ahead turning right.
Are you seeing those columns?
It will be all right.
You will see.
- Will it? Of course.
You have to stay calm. It's ok?
- I'll carry the bags.
- Right.
- You can go.
- It's ok.
- What class.
- Of course.
You are next.
Thanks.
Ready. Come on, skinny.
Let's see how much
you weigh.
Beware, huh.
Come on, come on.
Calm down, girls.
There's a way we can get out of this.
Tell me which one?
But what is it? A show of freaks?
We should charge
tickets.
And that has an idea much more popular
than in taught...
When I was learning about this subject.
Do not try to write down what he says,
just the important points.
Summarize or use
single words if necessary.
And the way we knew it was because a man...
Called Goldsteen took a
pipe and on the sides the paste...
The most important thing
started to happen...
were the children.
There were dozens of them in the
Rehabilitation Center.
And I began to cling to them,
and them, to me.
Then, Timothy Tom was very skinny.
But in the Christmas season.
When everyone leaves...
in search of a turkey,
No one wanted Timothy Ton.
And he was free.
When you do a
writing test, you have to...
Write as a writer.
Make each sentence say exactly
what you intend.
If you have a great idea,
make a great sentence.
If you have not, do not.
Simple.
You're right, John.
It really does look like a bouquet.
But it is pronounced Bouquet.
I like more
of bouquet.
Me too. But if you say so...
Nobody will know what you're talking about.
Because they do not write right.
- This is complicated.
Do you understand what I say?
Jill, I wanted you to be my teacher.
You know what. I really wanted to be.
- Do not do this, Jill.
I have nothing else to lose.
Yes. Faith in humanity.
Are you wanting to lose your teeth?
I put the denture.
I can tell you what he's going to tell you now.
He tells me in
first hand.
You all have been an inspiration to me.
Absolute inspiration.
You have been an inspiration to me.
The way you persist
despite the shortcomings...
It makes me feel good
small, actually.
We talked about the
certificate of completion.
I know. But unfortunately
would be a waste of time.
I can not grant it to you.
I have all the time in the world.
But my responsibility
is to teach something...
you can do.
I can teach. I know I can.
No school
will accept you.
Not without certificate of completion.
Of course they will not.
Not the certificate.
Be realistic is your...
is your disability.
At that time, in my life.
My only handicap is you.
I want you to know that
how I feel.
I am a man who, after all,
likes challenges too.
And what are these challenges?
Ora...
The position I occupied was a
considerable challenge.
In what sense?
Well...
I had to fight, and fight
very hard.
Do you know what it is to fight
for a piece of cake?
Try any time without hands.
What does one thing have to do with the other?
Ever tried to slide to
the seat of a toilet...
without using your legs?
Without knowing exactly if
is in the right place or not...
for not being able to feel the
porcelain underneath.
Miss Kinmont.
Do not try to flatter me.
I'm just trying to
show that...
Have you ever felt an itch on your
nose and could not...
- achieve it to scratch?
- Enough!
Not enough, no sir.
Do you want to listen to the
respect of challenges?
I teach you the meaning
of the word.
It's okay. You have proved your thesis.
Let me introduce
mine.
Paraplegics are not accepted
as teachers in absolutely...
No school in this country.
Unless you find
one who wants to hire you...
I will not allow you to receive
the certificate of completion.
Do you allow me to?
You have my word
of honor.
The school I had in mind
and that no one could imagine...
It was the Indians' school there
in my town, Bishop.
I went there and said that if they
wanted teachers...
Qualified would have to accept me as I was.
What did they say?
They said yes. She's going to
be the teacher.
Come on.
It was the beginning.
I started a new life.
You could depend on me again
same time again and...
open my way.
Dick. Hey, are you okay?
Yes, that's okay.
I want you to come to my birthday.
Your birthday?
Is not it great for
birthday parties?
I have something to tell you.
Speak!
Can not, just say
when you come.
- I will not wait. You'll have to wait.
Jill, help me to
understand this.
You make a
long distance call...
To say no-can talk to me.
What is happening with you?
Jill?
Hello?
Hello? Hello?
Okay, I say now.
I love you and I want to marry you.
I will charge this.
Do not start this party without me.
Very well, Linda. Soft, like that.
While waiting for Dick,
I went back up the mountain.
And there, in full
snow station...
I saw perfectly that life had
gone on without me.
Okay, you have to
keep them straight, right?
And work with your knees,
okay?
Who would believe that.
What are you thinking about?
That I am a
lucky girl.
Calm down. He'll be there soon, teacher.
It will be difficult to call you that.
- More gifts?
- More gifts.
But you will not open
none of those present...
while it does not arrive.
Any sign of the red baron?
Soda Springs Airport?
I wanted to know if you
can tell me when...
Dick Buek took off.
Two days? No. It's that we're
waiting for him here...
this morning, just this.
I'm sure
he will arrive. Thank you.
HAPPY BIRTHDAY JILL.
He is the best pilot in the whole
world, do not you think?
I'm sure he caught a storm.
It should arrive soon.
He really likes to
scare people.
Yes. This guy loves dramatic entries.
Hello?
It's him! It's Mr. Buek,
of Soda Springs.
He did not leave the house.
He must have come back.
Yes. It's from here. Hello, Dick.
It is Dick's father.
He wants to talk to you.
Someone takes me outside.
Bobby, take me out there, please?
- I'll go with you.
- No mother. I prefer to be alone.
Hello. Yes. This is Bill Kinmont.
Oh, yes.
I get it.
I... I'm sorry.
Very much.
Yes, I tell her.
Can we do anything?
We loved him very much.
We will miss you a lot.
- Has anyone asked? You asked for what?
- In marriage.
- Yes.  If asked, why not accept.
It's time for us to come back.
Let's go, kids!
Let's go!
I try to avoid this, but sometimes,
everything comes back to my head
And when it comes back, I remember
of the words that Dick Buek...
He told me about the last time I saw him.
How happy I am to have met someone like you.
It's awful to have to say goodbye.
Jill Kinmont is now teaching elementary
school in Southern California
She died in 2012 at 75 years old.