Sergeant David Budd,
Metropolitan Police.
British Transport Police have put out
an alert on a possible suicide bomber.
Don't do that! Please don't do that!
Please just stay still.
You have children? Yes. I do, two.
That's Ella. She's ten.
Charlie. He's eight.
The Government is intent on
forcing through a beefed-up
Regulation of Investigatory Powers
Act, RIPA-18 as it's being dubbed,
spearheaded by you.
Only those intent on acts of
violence have anything to fear.
I want you right beside me,
not because it's your job,
but because it's our choice.
This is a very, very dangerous
politician.
Someone who must be stopped.
Despite the heroic efforts
of our emergency services,
the Home Secretary, Julia Montague,
succumbed to her injuries
and was pronounced dead
a short while ago.
Someone tampered with my gun.
The police searched your flat.
If they found an illegal firearm,
they'd seize it,
they wouldn't just change out
the bullets for blanks.
The PM's asked me to step up
to Acting Home Secretary.
Now, it goes without saying,
I'd never wish in a million years
to assume this role under
these circumstances.
There's a simple, plausible story
for you to stick to.
And you will stick to it.
Finally.
We've got your shooter.
Sergeant Andrew Apsted.
Served in Helmand Province,
two tours.
This could be the original
bomb-maker.
The war in the desert, we've brought
it back to the streets of Britain.
Andrew Apsted.
We need more on him.
Who he joined the Army with,
who he served with.
And where did he get that rifle?
A PSL, with no history.
Traceable back to me.
Maybe I can make a couple of calls.
I thought they were sending you
a cab? Yeah.
I don't need their shitty cab.
Chanel Dyson was the late Home
Secretary's PR, until she was fired.
Thank you for being such
a sweetheart that day.
You're very welcome.
Just cos I was going to suggest
a drink.
The male subject has been identified
as Luke Aikens.
Aikens is believed to be
a senior figure in organised
criminal enterprises.
Nadia, we're desperate to find
the person who's been creating
these devices.
Is this the man your husband met?
Only problem is they know about you.
That'll be David Budd.
He's the only one who challenged me.
In her hotel room a few days
before she was killed,
the Home Secretary received
a visit from Longcross.
He supplied her with an encrypted
file of kompromat
she subsequently shared
with the Prime Minister.
She offered them greater powers
in return for the
compromising material. A series
of scandals, all covered up.
A sexual assault.
Drug addiction.
Financial impropriety.
Last night, I learned they relate
to the Prime Minister.
It looks like they're convinced
the kompromat wasn't with
the Home Secretary at the time of
the explosion.
It's still out there.
They seem pretty sure if anyone
knows where it's hidden, you do.
Julia Montague's home was
thoroughly searched,
all of her devices seized.
There was no tablet found.
TV REPORTER: Six long weeks
have passed since the incident
that triggered the current
terror alert...
The Metropolitan Police remain on
the highest level of vigilance,
responding to terror alerts
on a daily basis,
most of them thankfully
false alarms...
The police and Security Service MI5
stand at an almost
unprecedented level of alertness
to a home-grown terror threat,
yet still there have been no
further arrests, no breakthrough,
and the assassination of
Home Secretary Julia Montague rem...
VOICEMAIL: Hey, David, it's Chanel.
Um, it was really lovely
to run into you.
I meant it about that drink, may...
David!
I was getting worried you were
never going to call me back.
Anything to play hard to get.
Well, let's meet up.
I know just the place.
Ma'am.
As you were.
Ma'am. Deepak.
Sorry, nobody told me...
I wanted an update.
Yes, ma'am.
We've now interviewed all
the security staff on duty
the night before the bombing
at St Matthew's College.
They all claim not to have witnessed
any kind of break-in or intruder.
"Claim"?
The bomb didn't plant itself, ma'am.
Maybe we're looking at bribery
and/or intimidation.
They also needed access to the CCTV,
to delete part of the recording.
This sounds like a new line
of inquiry.
Yes, ma'am.
Luke Aikens.
We're exploring whether he
could've played a role in the
assassination of the Home Secretary.
Possible motivation being to prevent
increased scrutiny
into criminal communications.
RIPA-18?
Yes, ma'am.
Aikens is a significant player in
organised crime, and as you know,
ma'am, he's always successfully
avoided criminal charges.
"As I know"?
Er, yes. I saw in the file.
You led the Organised Crime Unit...
..across the investigations
into Aikens' activities.
Well, that was some time ago.
Why wasn't I informed earlier about
this new line of inquiry?
I'm sorry, ma'am, I...
Who initiated it?
I'm acting on information
from David Budd.
Every step forward,
we take one back.
Something happened, boss?
There's always been whispers
Luke Aikens had senior officers
in his pocket - officers prepared
to sabotage investigations into
his criminal empire.
Our officers?
There's still so much of the
Home Secretary's assassination
we can't put together, but a lot
of it can be explained
if all along there's been
an inside man...
..or woman.
You made it!
Never one to turn down a free drink.
We have a table downstairs,
if that's OK?
It's your manor, your rules.
What would you like to drink?
Er...
A beer's fine, please.
Oh, cheap date!
The same again, please.
But we'll have them downstairs.
Sure, Chanel.
Welcome to my manor.
Actually, it was good running
into you.
Because here we are.
That too. I...
When you finished at the Home
Office, I heard a few things.
About me?
Yeah, about you.
They were always beefing me.
What was it this time?
That your money comes from companies
registered offshore.
So?
I think there was a concern these
companies weren't fully legit.
Listen, David, you're not
a business person.
And I'm certainly not.
I have clever people to do all that
for me.
So, we could sit here and talk
about corporate law all night
and neither of us will be any
the wiser.
Fair point.
Paid for with Nazi gold.
Thank you.
Cheers. Cheers.
What?
Just trying to figure you out.
Well, depending on who you talk to,
I'm either deceptively deep
or deceptively shallow.
Either way, you're deceptive.
What's wrong?
I'm sorry...
Well?
A...belt on the right-hand side.
We don't normally allow coppers.
And we definitely don't allow THEM.
Makarov, is that right?
Looks like someone's been talking.
Well, you go around asking for
a PSL,
it's going to come to my attention.
You supply Andy Apsted?
Tell me one thing.
He come to you,
or did you go to him?
Well, here's a question for you.
Is that thing loaded?
What do you think?
It's what it's loaded with
that matters.
You swapped in the blanks?
Apologies, everyone. The lad's just
had too much to drink.
Try not to let it spoil
your evening.
Sarge, you're going to want
to log in to Thornton Circus.
We've got something
on Andrew Apsted. Yeah?
Boss.
We've completed cross-checks on
everyone Andrew Apsted served
alongside with in the Army.
Apsted was posted
to Helmand Province
with 16 Engineer Regiment in 2009.
Now, there were a number
of operations carried out
alongside the Royal Albion Regiment.
And serving in the Royal Albion
at that time was, um...
..was David Budd.
Shit.
Yeah.
Yeah, it gets worse.
Budd went back to Julia Montague's
house and broke in
via the back entrance -
that's unguarded.
I mean, he appears to have keys.
He must've secretly got them cut
when he was her PPO,
which is suspicious enough
in itself.
I mean, he was only on the premises
for one or two minutes,
which means he knew exactly
what he was after. Yeah.
The kompromat.
You were right, boss.
There's been an inside man
all along.
The fucker has played me
since day one.
He's played us all.
We're going to be the ones
to bring him in.
Let's find the bastard.
POLICE RADIO: Observations for
a male wanted in connection
with the murder of Julia Montague.
Police Sergeant David Budd,
IC1 male, early 30s, dark hair.
Subject may be armed
and is extremely dangerous.
Repeat, David Budd is to be treated
as extremely dangerous.
Mrs Budd, do you know the name
Andrew Apsted?
No.
Apsted and David served
in Afghanistan together.
Apsted had a history of
post-traumatic stress
and took his own life.
One of our current lines of inquiry
is that Apsted and your
husband were accomplices in
the Thornton Circus attempt
on the Home Secretary's life.
No... No!
Dave would never...
David has lied and lied
to all of us, you included,
and our priority now is to bring him
safely into custody.
Has he said anything to you that
might shed some light on his plans?
Um...
Well, he did say one thing
the last time I saw him,
which really worried me.
He said he needed to act now
"before it was too late".
I...
Is he in danger?
Mrs Budd, I believe what David meant
by "before it's too late"
is before his link to Andrew Apsted
was detected.
Hence all the lies
and the betrayals.
Now, I'd like you to accompany me
to Walworth Police Station
to help with our inquiries, OK?
Vicky, Ella and Charlie are safe
and well, no sightings of David,
but we've dispatched an officer
to the school for
safeguarding purposes. No.
Dave would never hurt the kids.
Never.
Who would he hurt?
Madam, don't be alarmed.
Please can I use your telephone?
Please, I just need some help,
ma'am, please.
Madam, stop! Police officer.
I understand the state I look.
My name's
Police Sergeant David Budd.
Do you have a mobile telephone,
please? Uh...
All I need you to do is call 999
and hold the phone on speaker
so I can contact
the Police Operator.
The call's free of charge.
Madam, it's an emergency.
Please.
Thank you.
Emergency, which service
do you require? Police.
Putting you through now.
Police, what is your emergency?
PS David Budd, using a member of
the public's phone,
I am Status Zero on
Saltmarsh Street.
Can you confirm your name, please?
Police Sergeant David Budd.
Units are on their way, PS Budd.
Please return the phone
to the member of the public.
What's going on?
Shit.
Obs on David Budd.
Saltmarsh Street.
Received. Saltmarsh Street,
blue-light it.
What's going on?
I need your full cooperation, Vicky.
This could turn into
a negotiation situation.
Control Trojan,
stand by for sit-rep.
Did you see where he went?
Extend the search outwards.
Come with me.
Trojan sit-rep -
unarmed, clear to enter.
Sarge.
PS Mason, ma'am.
Lorraine Craddock, Budd's boss.
I'm hoping I can talk him into
cooperating.
Ma'am.
Ma'am, DS Rayburn, SO15.
I've got Budd's wife with me.
I'm cooperating. Don't shoot!
Armed police! Hands in the air!
Don't shoot! Hands in the air now!
I can't! David, please do as we say!
No-one needs to get hurt!
I need to explain!
Raise your hands!
David, please. Raise your hands!
Final warning!
RAISE YOUR HANDS!
Shit!
Pull back!
Clear the area!
David, don't move!
Stay perfectly still!
It's a dead man's switch!
Anything happens to me,
it'll go off.
Control, active message.
RADIO: Go ahead, Trojan.
I didn't do this!
You need to believe me.
Subject armed with PBIED,
require safe route.
We need Expo here and a negotiator.
Ma'am.
Control, Charlie Yankee Five Seven,
request Expo and negotiator
to Saltmarsh Street.
I didn't do this!
I was put in this vest!
We need to get him away from
all these buildings. Agreed.
We need to move you to
a less built-up area!
It's a DMS.
Don't shoot!
You need you to comply right now!
I AM COMPLYING! Do not shoot!
Turn around slowly with your hands
in the air.
RADIO: Trojan, route via
Saltmarsh Mews.
Wait!
Taking the street to your right,
walk there slowly now.
Control from Trojan, active message.
Request directions to safe area.
Just keep moving.
No sudden moves.
RADIO: Trojan, destination is
Pope Square,
approximately 500 metres south-west
of your position in Saltmarsh Road.
Armed police, get back!
Left turn into Pope Lane, followed
by right turn into Pope Square.
Traffic control and air ops
covering the route.
Received.
Keep walking!
Sir, we're just tapping
into the CCTV camera now.
Get out of the park!
Keep it moving!
Keep moving.
As far away from the buildings
as possible.
Control, Trojan.
Subject now confined to Pope Square.
Require critical shot authorisation.
Received, stand by.
He's saying it's trigger-activated.
Are we safe to get a radio to him?
Ma'am?
If we're going to get him
to surrender,
we'll need to be able to talk.
David, I'm going to lay the radio
down for you, OK?
Do not move yet!
OK!
Bring the wife, just in case, OK?
Got the radio? Cheers.
Stay still until I tell you.
OK.
Pick up the radio!
Back to back on 2.
David, please listen to me
very carefully.
I really hope this can be resolved
with no-one getting hurt.
For your own sake,
for your family and colleagues,
please give yourself up.
Ma'am, I've tried
to remove the vest.
It's booby-trapped with co-ax
connectors across the clasps.
They're wired to the control unit.
I give you my solemn promise
your previous good service
and the effect of your recent
traumatic experiences
will be taken into account.
Ma'am, you're not listening to me.
I was knocked unconscious.
When I came round I was in this vest
with my thumb taped to the DMS.
David, you've got to be
straight with us.
You hid your relationship
with Apsted.
You hid your involvement in
Julia Montague's assassination.
I had nothing to do with
Julia's assassination, nothing!
I tried to save her!
David, you've betrayed
everyone's trust.
We won't be fooled again.
I'm telling the truth!
I'm sorry, David.
I did my best for you.
What? Your best? What are you doing?
This is an SO15 operation.
Ma'am, what are you doing?
David, let's try
and stay calm, yeah?
David, are you receiving me?
Vic, get away from here!
Dave, they want me here.
Get away!
Just get Expo here, Louise,
please, get me out of this thing.
Stay still and keep your hands
where we can see them.
My hand is on the DMS.
What's the matter with you?
Are you blind?
No, David.
I'm being set up!
The people that did this to me,
they're the ones who killed Julia!
OK, David.
Louise, I know I betrayed
your trust.
I lied about Andy Apsted.
But if I'd come clean,
I'd have been the fall guy
and the people
that really killed Julia
would have gotten away with it.
I didn't wanted to lie. I had to!
David, please,
just do what they say!
She's fine.
David, you need help, please!
Vic, I'm telling the truth!
Trojan, Control.
Go ahead, Control.
Message from SFC.
Critical shot authorised.
Received.
Line of fire, behind me.
I know I lied, I hid things,
but you have to understand
I had nothing to do with
Andy trying to kill Julia.
Nothing to do with the bomb
that killed her.
I wanted to know who did it.
I don't know who did it!
It was Security Service,
Organised Crime, terrorism -
that's what I was trying
to find out.
Pictures up.
RADIO: Also an SO15 DS
awaiting Silver to Status Six.
Control, Silver seconds away.
Get me live with the field. Sir.
DAVID: I know you think I'm lying...
Any RT revealing
what he's told them so far?
No, sir. Get this blown up.
Sir. ..the conspiracy, whatever,
to kill Julia.
There was security pictures
of St Matthew's College.
They knew about
the Home Secretary's itinerary.
By me, sir.
Silver, Status Six.
Control, received.
Boss. Any idea what kind of
explosive's in the device?
Not yet, no, boss,
and I wouldn't hold much store
in Budd's answers either.
It's been a stream of bullshit
since day one.
All right, Louise, I hear you, but
let's lower the temperature a bit.
What channel? Two.
David, Deepak Sharma, receiving?
Receiving.
What can you tell us
about the PBIED?
It resembles the device
worn by Nadia Ali
during the 1st of October attack.
How can you be so sure?
I saw hers up close
before it was con-exed.
The HE, the detonators,
the control unit.
Mine appear exactly the same.
You understand our doubts here,
mate? Our inquiries have led us to
the probability of an inside man
within the force
who conspired in
the security breaches necessary
to assassinate the Home Secretary.
I'm not the inside man!
But here you are,
wearing the exact same PBIED
employed by an active terror cell.
This is how it happened, sir.
I was contacted by Chanel Dyson.
She set a trap. I was ambushed by
Luke Aikens and put into this vest,
to frame me, to point the finger
away from Organised Crime.
You keep asking us to believe you,
David, and now you're telling us
you're arranging a secret meeting
with one of the suspects.
I was trying to trace
Andy Apsted's PSL rifle!
It was supplied by Luke Aikens.
It was his men
that broke into my flat.
Why do you think that, David?
I used a pistol I brought back
from Afghanistan as bait.
Luke knew all about it.
Knew it had been tampered with.
Look, ask Vic. She knows.
She knows! She'll prove
that I'm telling the truth.
Vicky, will you tell him?
He's telling the truth.
The pistol,
someone tampered with the bullets,
they replaced them with blanks.
How do you know this?
After the Home Secretary died,
David tried to shoot himself.
But, look, why would Dave
try and shoot himself with a blank,
unless he didn't realise the gun
had been tampered with?
Thank you.
David, clearly we need
to look into this further.
But we're being told
that you're suicidal,
and now here you are
in a suicide vest.
No, no, no! That's not it,
that's not the point here!
Where's this pistol now, mate?
You got it with you?
No, Luke's men seized it
before they fitted the vest.
Look, forget the pistol, it's
the blank rounds that are proof.
I've still got them.
They're hidden in my flat.
Maybe you can pull DNA,
prints from them that are going
to link it back to Luke's men.
All this evidence
you've kept hidden.
We know you broke into
Julia Montague's flat.
Led me up the garden path
on that one, too.
I am sorry about that, Louise.
I had to.
I couldn't risk what I found
being common knowledge.
Why, David? Why couldn't you
trust your colleagues?
Because of the conspiracy.
Because of the Security Service.
I found where Julia
hid the kompromat.
Phone. The tablet.
Where is it, David?
My flat, downstairs,
in the bathroom, above a spotlight.
Budd's flat. Downstairs bathroom.
Above a spotlight.
Seconds away.
Budd's flat. Turn right.
Do you give consent to search?
Yes, sir.
Control, Silver,
I need a search team
to David Budd's address immediately.
Look at me.
They're changing radio channels.
Security Service
may be monitoring this,
so do not share via
any regular channels.
Advise search team not to tamper
with the spotlight,
to hold back from entering
the property.
Received.
What's the message? What's Budd say?
Sorry, sir,
they're too quick for us.
Aaah! Aah!
Armed police!
Get down on the ground!
Hands where I can see them.
Down on the ground! Search him!
Don't move!
One in custody.
Matching e-fit of Richard Longcross.
Fuck.
Hold Expo.
They need to get this thing off me!
I would if I could, mate,
but you know the drill.
There's a risk you'll trigger
the device to take them with you.
I don't want anyone here
getting hurt.
My hand's aching on this DMS!
I want to talk to my wife.
It might be the last chance I get.
Please.
Go set to set on 3.
Press here when you want to talk.
I've let you down, Vic, I know that.
But on our children's lives,
I'm not a traitor
and I had nothing to do
with Julia's murder.
I'm sorry for
what I've put you through.
I'm sorry I've stopped being
the man you married.
I've tried to explain,
but part of me never wants to
explain what the war did to me.
I never wanted it to touch you,
or us,
but it has.
I tried to stop it, but I couldn't.
I've failed as a husband,
and as a father,
and that's the worst thing.
I'm sorry.
Help him! Why won't you help him?
Please.
Let me examine the device, sir.
OK.
Thank you, thank you!
Ballistic shields.
With me.
Any sudden moves,
any shout from me, take him out.
Hold.
My name's Daniel Chung.
I'm going to begin by
examining this device. Thank you.
I'm David.
David...
..remain perfectly still
with your hands facing me.
Apart from the dead man's switch,
are there any other
initiation devices?
To the best of my knowledge, no.
David, keep pressure on the DMS.
I need you to turn very slowly
through 360 degrees
so I can inspect the whole device.
Thank you.
I don't see any
hidden initiation devices.
Now I'm going to carry out
a closer examination.
Please remain completely still,
maintaining pressure on the DMS.
I will.
The co-ax wires across the clasps
are wired into the control unit.
I'm going to examine
the control unit now.
Please remain perfectly still
for me, David,
maintaining pressure on the DMS.
David, I've completed
my examination,
and now I need to confer with
my colleagues.
Stay here,
remaining perfectly still,
and keep maintaining pressure
on the DMS.
No. Come back.
Come back!
Ma'am. Ma'am.
Great work on getting Longcross
into custody. Ma'am. Well done.
Budd's device appears to be the work
of the original bomb-maker.
It's impossible to tell if he put it
on himself or someone did it to him.
I read the report on
the 1/10 device.
This is equally sophisticated.
Can it be defused?
I can try, but there's an extremely
high risk of detonation.
What's happening?
This is Anne Sampson, David.
Tell us, are there other bombers
at large?
Not that I know of.
Are further attacks planned?
I don't know.
Who built the device you're wearing?
Ma'am, this wasn't my doing.
I don't know who built it.
We've got no idea of the power
of the device
or how long he can hold the DMS.
Added to which, Budd's got a history
of deception
and is highly likely to be
the inside man
who's enabled this conspiracy.
Get everyone to pull back
outside the cordons
and then we'll re-spin the wheel.
Deepak.
Ma'am.
Everyone pull back!
Pull back.
David.
Please!
Mrs Budd.
I'm innocent! Please!
You're killing me!
Pull back to a safe distance,
please.
I love you.
See what she's up to?
All the easier to pin everything
on David when he's dead.
She's the one with links
to Luke Aikens.
Quick as you can.
If I stay put,
she'll order the shot.
If I run, she'll do the same.
No! Stop! Stop her!
Vicky, no! Hold fire! Hold fire!
Vic, it's too dangerous.
That's Charlie and Ella
losing the both of us.
I believe you, Dave,
I believe that you're innocent.
This gives you a chance to prove it.
Trojan to TFC, subject's wife now
in close proximity to device.
Trojan, TFC.
SFC rescinds critical shot.
Off aim!
Budd to Sampson.
Sampson.
I'll lead you to the evidence
that proves I'm telling the truth.
Stay where you are.
What now?
Stay close.
We walk.
David!
DAVID!
Mobile containment -
100 metres rolling cordon.
Red team with me.
Get traffic control in place
to create a safety corridor.
Ma'am.
Help us out here, mate.
Where are you going?
My flat.
Long walk ahead.
The incident began
earlier this morning
with reports of a man wearing
a suicide vest
causing a disturbance
in Saltmarsh Street.
Specialist Firearms Officers
of the Metropolitan Police's
counter-terrorism unit, SCO19,
attended the incident
within a few minutes
and the area was closed
to the public.
The incident moved to Pope Square...
You had the whole situation
locked down.
We've got an innocent civilian
in harm's way
and Budd claims to be leading us
to crucial evidence.
He's making for his home address.
Armed units are in situ
and residents are being evacuated.
Air Ops are also conducting
neighbourhood surveillance
for possible associates.
So far, none detected.
Then who's he working with?
We've established a link to Andrew
Apsted, the Thornton Circus sniper.
I see.
Ah.
You never said you were including
the Security Service.
Anne, Anne,
we're all in this together.
Stephen?
You may be interested to hear my
officers have taken into custody
a male suspect matching
the e-fit of Richard Longcross.
And we're currently exploring
a number of lines of inquiry
in association with the suspect,
such as places of work and seizure
of communications devices.
I can neither confirm nor deny
the suspect's identity,
but what I can confirm is that
the requisite authorities apply
which render his actions lawful.
He should be released immediately.
There are certain actions for which
there are no lawful authorities,
one being the assassination of
a democratically elected
secretary of state.
Anne, please.
Cool heads and cooperation.
This "cooperation" - is it due
to Budd's compromising material
giving you both so much to lose
that you never want its existence
revealed?
Because it would show the hand
of the Security Service
in a failed coup, and despite
your convincing assurances
that the Home Office's role
in Julia Montague's death
was purely accidental,
I wonder if the public
will be equally convinced?
OK, Anne, I think it's best if
Stephen and I continue without you.
A woman was murdered.
A crime was committed.
My officers will investigate.
Thanks.
I've sought a court order
for my officer's release.
Good.
Budd claims to hold
crucial evidence.
He was working with
the Thornton Circus sniper.
Andrew Apsted was a disturbed,
embittered war veteran.
Not only does Budd
fit the same profile,
he possessed all the inside know-how
to overcome Julia's security.
No wider conspiracy involved.
Look no further
for Julia's assassin.
..an evacuation is taking place.
How are you doing?
My hand's in spasm.
You need to go inside.
It's OK. It's completely safe.
Cupboard in the kitchen.
There's some rope.
Rope? What for?
And a spade.
There's something down here -
like a black plastic bag.
That's it, Vic.
This is the evidence.
The original tablet
containing the kompromat.
It'll prove the Security Service
was involved.
The blank rounds that were
smuggled into my pistol,
they'll prove Organised Crime were,
too.
Send Vicky to us with the evidence.
If I go, they can shoot you.
I don't know how much longer
I can hold the DMS.
This vest is crucial evidence.
The others all got blown up.
If forensics got a chance
to examine this,
it might lead us back to
the bomb-maker.
Prevent further attacks.
He's bargaining, boss,
he's playing you.
Or he's giving us the chance
to crack this case.
I'll send Vicky to you
with the evidence.
No, Dave, don't fall for it.
If you give me a chance
to defuse this.
How do you know I'll keep my side?
I've been a soldier,
I've been a copper.
You get to spot a bloke
whose word's his bond.
You happy to let him try?
I wouldn't say "happy".
Robot.
Vicky.
How are things with your boyfriend?
All right.
You deserve to be happy.
I've laid out what you'll need.
The robot's coming up to you,
so I can talk you through it.
Thank you.
Go.
RADIO: Question for DCI Sharma.
Go ahead.
Is Longcross talking yet?
I don't know.
It'd help, sir, if I knew
this hadn't all been in vain.
We'll get back to you on that.
To me, Vicky.
Thanks.
I'll get an update on Longcross.
We've got picture.
Can you hear me?
Receiving.
Get Vicky away.
She shouldn't have to watch.
Mrs Budd...
I'm not going to manage
with one hand.
We'll start by freeing
your left hand.
You'll see a set of scissors.
Use it to divide the tape over your
thumb, creating two loose ends.
Next you'll see
a non-ferrous spacer.
It looks like one of the pieces
in a game of draughts.
Slip the spacer under your thumb,
being sure to maintain pressure
on the DMS trigger.
Being sure to maintain pressure,
roll your thumb through 90 degrees
so you can fold one of the free ends
of tape down onto the spacer.
The next stage is to roll your thumb
in the opposite direction,
over the piece of tape you've just
secured, maintaining pressure...
..so that you can fold the other
free end of tape to the spacer.
If you're sure the tape is secure,
you'll be able to remove your thumb.
Well done, David.
I'd suggest applying another
couple of loops of tape to get
the spacer 100% secure.
David, normally the best approach
is to neutralise the power source.
But remember, with the 1/10 device,
Fort Halstead found it was rigged
with multiple booby traps.
When the power was cut, the control
unit triggered the detonators.
I'm convinced this is
the same kind of device.
Then you're going to have to
neutralise the control unit itself.
I've already removed
the cover successfully,
but there may be hidden trip wires.
Thanks, mate,
that's giving us a good view.
Now, what do you suggest?
I doubt a device like this will be
neutralised by cutting a wire.
A shunt might work.
Hence the croc clips and cable?
Yeah.
I can see a pair of relay blocks
serving the detonators.
I'm going to shunt between the two.
Right, I'm going to disconnect
the power supply.
I'm cutting the first wire.
Oh...
Put some tape over the ends.
Question for DCI Sharma.
Go ahead.
Any news on Longcross?
Sir?
I'm very sorry, David.
He had to be released.
Is that it?
They just get away with it
scot-free?
I'm going to cut the second wire.
Everyone should get
as far back as possible.
Everyone back.
Take cover. Fall back.
Get everyone right back!
Move back! Move back!
Get right back!
All of you, move.
OK.
After him!
Go! Go! Go!!
No obs on Budd in the graveyard.
Widen the search.
Lock off all surrounding roads.
Negative, no obs.
Negative. We lost him.
Minister.
Where's Budd?
I'm afraid I don't have that
information at this time.
What's he up to?
In all probability,
he's fleeing from justice.
And what if he's not?
That'll kill you.
Oh, my God!
So would a suicide vest.
Oh, my God. You're OK.
Like you give a shit.
I don't... I don't even know what
to say to you. I'm so sorry.
Co-operate, you'll get immunity,
witness protection.
You'll be out. I can't do that.
You're going to phone Luke.
You're going to tell him the Inside
Man's going to talk.
He's going to want to silence him.
He's going to lead me straight
to him.
Isn't Luke going to find that
a bit suspicious?
It's what you did to me.
It's the only way to prove
I'm innocent.
I'll drive.
Stay put.
Are you off somewhere?
None of your business.
Talking of which...
I pay for results.
Budd is still out there.
It's a basic rule, Lorraine -
if you're going to frame someone,
you make it the dead bloke.
That's hardly my fault.
No, but it's made you nervous.
On your knees, hands on your head.
Are you fucking joking?
Stand down, Sarge, that's an order.
I know about you, too.
On your knees!
Hands.
Did you kill her?
Did you kill Julia?
David, don't do this.
Tell me.
It was business.
David, don't!
Why?
Just good for business.
It's nothing personal.
Nothing personal.
David, don't.
Argh!
Don't look at me.
Call this in
before I change my mind.
It's over.
Chief Superintendent Craddock.
I need a firearms unit to my home
address right away, please.
We've got prints back on
your blank rounds.
They match known associates
of Luke Aikens.
Why didn't they just steal your gun?
Straightaway I'd have known
they'd been in my flat.
They were trying to frame me.
Suppose they couldn't take the
chance
of leaving me with live rounds.
Cheers.
Great work, mate.
SO15 recorded interview with Chief
Superintendent Lorraine Craddock
by DCI Sharma.
Describe the nature of your
relationship with Luke Aikens.
For some years I've...
..disclosed sensitive
information on...
..on police operations that might
threaten his criminal activities.
What information did you disclose
regarding the Home Secretary?
Her itinerary the day of the
Thornton Circus attempt on her life.
Which Aikens passed
to Andrew Apsted?
Luke recruited Apsted.
He armed him and...
..used one of his
captive businesses to...
..enable Apsted to access
Pascoe House as a tradesman.
And the St Matthew's attack that
resulted in the Home Secretary's
death?
Erm...
Her itinerary.
Her security plans and procedures.
Luke was able to...
..plan steps to overcome
all of them.
What motivated Aikens to induce you
to disclose this information?
Luke found out Julia Montague was
planning to transfer powers
to the Security Service
which would give them...
..an upper hand,
more of an upper hand
against organised crime.
They're harder to contact,
more shadowy, therefore...
..harder to bribe and blackmail.
Unlike corrupt officers
such as yourself.
Aikens needed policing to stay with
an organisation he could manipulate.
Is there any connection with you
appointing David Budd as the
Home Secretary's PPO?
Yes.
So he'd make the perfect fall guy.
And the Heath Bank attack.
Did you provide the confidential
information on PS Budd's family?
No, never, I'd never do anything
like that to one of my team.
If she didn't do it, who did?
Lorraine Craddock, I will now be
seeking the authority of the
Crown Prosecutor to charge you...
There's one other person in this
whole conspiracy
that knew about my kids.
..malfeasance in a public office
and conspiracy to murder.
Interview terminated.
NEWS: Ten days since the
assassination of Julia Montague,
the Metropolitan Police
have announced...
The Metropolitan Police
Counter Terrorism Branch, SO15,
have made a number of arrests...
Arrests include a man in his 30s
who is said to be known to police,
and a woman in her 50s also...
Downing Street and the Home Office
have welcomed the police
breakthrough in investigating the
Home Secretary's assassination.
A Home Office spokesman said it was
too early to make any further
comment.
David.
Good to go.
The DIR is recording.
Nadia.
I'd like to start by asking
you about David Budd.
Did you have any information
regarding his children?
No.
Why are you asking me this?
Nadia, we've had significant
breakthroughs in our inquiry.
There's only one piece of
the puzzle left.
And that's you.
And maybe you're just an innocent
victim in all of this.
The pawn controlled
by the real masterminds.
You can say, "No comment."
Is that true? Are you just a victim?
David Budd made the same mistake.
He thought so little of me,
he showed me pictures.
What do you mean,
"Thought so little of you"?
To him, I was a weak woman.
I remembered everything he told me
about his children.
Their names.
Their ages.
From prison, I was able to
inform my organisation.
So they could launch an attack on
his children's school?
Yes.
There's another finding
I'd like to put to you.
We've been able to examine the
Person-Borne Improvised
Explosive Device David Budd
was forced to wear.
Forensic examination of the control
unit circuitry detected
deposits of your DNA
and your fingerprints.
Why would that be?
Because I built the device.
I built all the bombs.
You all saw me as a poor,
oppressed Muslim woman.
I am an engineer.
I am a Jihadi.
Which bombs?
The one used to kill
the Home Secretary,
the one used to kill police officers
at Heath Bank School,
the one I wore on
the 1st of October.
So you're telling us this man didn't
supply the bomb to your husband?
I invented that story because
Police Sergeant Budd was so eager to
believe it.
And so stupidly eager to believe me.
You made that up to
mislead our inquiry?
How easy that was.
You are all so easy...
It wasn't just you, mate,
we all fell for it.
Who planted the device
at St Matthew's College?
The one that killed
the Home Secretary.
Non-believers.
Criminals.
Luke Aikens?
Yes.
Why did you conspire
with non-believers?
For money.
Money to build more bombs and buy
more guns and spread the
truth to our brothers and sisters
throughout the world.
So that the world could be convinced
that we had put a sword
through the heart of the
British Government.
You failed to detonate your own
PBIED on the October 1st rail
attack.
You couldn't go through with it.
But look how I have atoned.
I have helped the cause
a thousand times more.
Sophie, we are being told
that a statement by the
Prime Minister is imminent.
Meanwhile, all day, ministers have
been giving their reactions
to this morning's news that the
Prime Minister cancelled
today's engagements.
Home Secretary,
any reaction on the breaking news?
Really, please, we should avoid
speculation until the
Prime Minister's had the opportunity
to address the allegations himself.
Yes. Come in.
Just to remind you, today's events
follow unconfirmed reports of a leak
of compromising material relating to
the Prime Minister's past.
Is the Prime Minister going
to resign?
I'm just getting on with the job
of protecting our country.
Thank you.
Home Secretary? Home Secretary?
It's also being reported that the
leak implicates the
Director General of the Security
Service, Stephen Hunter-Dunn...
The Prime Minister will resign
before the day is out.
Hunter-Dunn the same.
Mike Travis, he stays on to make
sure RIPA-18 gets kicked into
the long grass.
Leaking the kompromat.
Whose decision was that?
I couldn't possibly say.
Thanks to you, David, the CPS have
charged Nadia Ali, Luke Aikens
and Lorraine Craddock in the
Conspiracy to Murder Julia Montague.
Some say you should get a medal.
Others reckon you should be
kicked off the Force.
We'll see.
There'll need to be a thorough
investigation into your conduct.
But first, David, there's something
you need more than all of that.
Come in.
Hello. Hello.
I am David.
And I...
I need some help.
Hi. Hey.
Come in.
How are you doing?
I'm good.
How are you?
I'm getting there.
Well, you've taken the first step.
I'm really proud of you.
Yeah. The kids are looking forward
to sleeping in their own beds again.
I bet.
I was thinking,
it's actually my turn for them again
but only if that's OK with you.
Yeah.
Kids, your dad's here.
Dad.
No train journeys this time.
Hello, princess.
There's a monster on my back.
Get him off, get him off!
OK. You behave.
You have fun.
D'you...
What?
Nothing.
There's...
There's room for one more.
Yeah?
Yeah.
OK.
I'll get my bag.
Mummy's going to come, too.
Yeah!
Ease up.
OK.
Everyone in? Good, let's go.