Merry Christmas!
- What's your name, little boy?
- Eric.
What do you want for Christmas, Eric? Hm?
A Johnny Lightning 500.
- You been good, little boy?
- Yeah.
Good. You like Santa Claus? Huh?
Now, you like Santa Claus, right?
Let's sing a little song. "Jingle Bells."
Get up.
Get up! And hold 'em up.
- Hold it!
- Freeze!
Jimmy, watch it. He's got a knife.
- Hold it, you son of a bitch!
- No, no!
That's enough. Don't kill him. That's enough!
- Get up!
- Come on, give me a break!
- I ain't done nothin', man.
- Break, your ass.
- Come on.
- Get up!
Will you stop it? Stop it!
- Jimmy.
- Let me bust him. I wanna bust him.
- I wanna bust him.
- Let me talk to him. Let me talk to him!
- You got a friend here. You got a friend.
- You gonna tell us who your man is?
When's the last time you picked your feet?
Who's your connection, Willie?
- Answer him!
- No, no, man!
Is it Joe the barber?
That's who it is, isn't it?
Don't give us any shit.
What's Joe's last name?
- I don't know, man!
- Give him a chance. Just give him a chance.
All I know is he lives on 125th Street, man.
Above the barber shop.
What side of the street does he live on?
North or south?
- I don't know what you're talking about.
- What side of the street does he live on?
- When's the last time you picked your feet?
- What's he talkin' about?
I got a man in Poughkeepsie wants to talk
to you. You ever been in Poughkeepsie?
- Hey, man, give me a break.
- Come on, say it. Let me hear you say it.
Have you ever been to Poughkeepsie? You've
been to Poughkeepsie? I wanna hear it!
- Yes, I've been to Poughkeepsie.
- You sat on the edge of the bed.
You took off your shoes
and picked your feet, didn't you?
- Now say it!
- Yes.
All right. You put a shiv in my partner.
You know what that means, goddamnit?
All winter I gotta listen to him
gripe about his bowling scores.
I'm gonna bust your ass for those three bags,
then I'm gonna nail you for picking your feet.
Merci.
Bonjour.
C'est merveilleux, chéri.
Tu me gâtes. Je t'aime.
C'est pour toi, chéri.
Merci, chérie.
Need a little help there?
- You dumb guinea.
- How the hell did I know he had a knife?
- Never trust a nigger.
- He could've been white.
- Never trust anyone. Goin' sick?
- No.
- Are you goin' sick?
- No!
- What d'you say we go to Chez for a drink?
- Jimmy, I'm beat. I'm gonna go home.
All right, all right. One drink.
- Drink this.
- Whip it out.
I make at least two junk connections
at that far table over in the corner.
The guy in the striped shirt and tie combo,
I know him too.
I thought we came here to buy me a drink.
Who is that clown?
It's a policy guy from Queens.
- Dig the creep that's comin' to the table now.
- It's Jewish Lucky.
He don't look the same
without numbers across his chest.
That table is definitely wrong.
More!
What about the last of the big-time spenders?
Do you make him?
No. You?
He's spreadin' it around like
the Russians are in Jersey.
Oh, yes.
What do you say we stick around
and give him a tail?
Come on. Just for fun.
Give who a tail?
The greaser with the blonde.
What for? You wanna play
hide the salami with his old lady?
Yeah.
Miss, can I ask you
about those boots? They're...
Monica.
- Who in the hell's that?
- Who keeps score?
- Kissy devil, isn't he? Look at him.
- Well, they're all cousins. You know that.
Yeah, say good-bye. Come on.
What's he got now?
- Hudson Terraplane, that's what he got.
- No, no.
- Easy.
- OK.
Go to work.
Cloudy, I'll lay odds
he takes us to dago town.
We'll take him, Popeye. He's nothin'.
Seven o'clock in the morning.
I don't believe it.
Relax. You're havin' fun, ain't you?
If that's not a drop, I'll open
a charge for you at Bloomingdale's.
Make it Alexander's. I like the toy department.
He's comin' back.
Pass him. Make a left.
Alain.
Our friend's name is Boca.
Salvatore Boca. B-O-C-A.
They call him Sal. He's a sweetheart.
He was picked up on suspicion
of armed robbery. Now get this.
Three years ago he tries to hold up Tiffany's
on Fifth Avenue in broad daylight.
He could've got two and a half to five,
but Tiffany's wouldn't prosecute.
Also, downtown they're pretty sure he pulled
off a contract on a guy named DeMarco.
- "How about his old lady?"
- "Her name's Angie. She's a fast filly."
She drew a suspended
for shoplifting a year ago.
She's only a kid.
19, according to the marriage license.
19 goin' on 50.
- "What else?"
- "He's had the store a year and a half."
Takes in a fast seven grand a year.
So what's he doin' with two cars
and a tab at the Chez?
The LTD's in his wife's name.
The Comet belongs to his brother Lou.
He's a trainee at the garbageman's
school on Ward's Island.
"He did time a couple of years ago" -
assault and robbery.
Black Cadillac.
New Jersey plates.
RWN-264. I know that one cat. We saw him
outside the Pike Slip Inn the other day.
I want a blouse like that for my girlfriend,
but you could model it.
Better not let my husband hear that.
I don't care if he hears it.
Will you do it for me?
OK. How much are you gonna pay?
- $50 an hour.
- 50 an hour?!
- I'll do it. $200.
- No, can't afford it.
I'll call you later. Bye-bye.
Hey, it's 1:30. I didn't expect you till two.
- You work around here?
- Across the street.
That's the third time
he's come here this week.
- "You got anything on this building?"
- "Clean. I checked the tenant list."
Remember Don Ameche, the actor?
He lives here.
Oh, yeah, and somebody else.
- "Does the name Joel Weinstock ring a bell?"
- "You're kidding."
No, sir. He lives right here.
He was the bank on the shipment
out of Mexico three years ago.
Yeah, so I hear.
He's goin' to Ward's Island.
We'll be spotted. Why's he doin' that?
Maybe he's gonna go down
and see his brother.
Well, maybe it's another drop.
Well, he gets a free ride.
All right, Popeye's here!
Get your hands on your heads, get off the bar
and get on the wall! Come on, move, move!
Come on, move out! Face the wall.
Turn around there. Move!
- Hands outta your pockets.
- Turn around.
Turn around. Get on the wall.
Hey, did you drop that? Pick it up.
- Pick it up! Come on, move!
- What are you lookin' at?
All right, bring it here.
Get your hands outta your pockets.
- What's my name?
- Doyle.
- What?
- Mr Doyle.
Come here. D'you pick your feet?
Do you...? Get over there.
Get your hands on your head.
- Hold 'em up.
- We told you people we were comin' back.
We're gonna keep comin' back
until you clean this bar up.
Keep your eye on your neighbor.
If he drops somethin', it belongs to you.
What is this, a fuckin' hospital here? Huh?
Turn around there, fella.
What have we got here?
This belong to you? Huh?
Stand up there, noddy.
Get your hands on your fuckin' head.
- You wanna take a ride there, fat man?
- Oh, bullshit.
Pay attention.
We're gonna ask questions later.
Turn around.
All right, shut up there. Shut up!
Anybody want a milkshake?
All right, come over here. You and you.
Hey, whiskers! Come over here.
Move ass when I call you! You!
Come on, you, baldie. Come on, move.
All right, put it on the bar.
- Get it on the bar!
- Get the hell in there.
- Put your hands on your head.
- All of it.
Smart ass, you dropped somethin'. Pick it up.
You want that hand broken? Get it up there.
What else you got here, huh?
Turn around.
You're under arrest. That goes for you too.
Get in that phone booth. Move!
Get in there. Face the wall, put your hands
against the wall and lock yourself in.
Hey, you!
Haircut! Where are you going?
- You talkin' to me, baby?
- Yeah, I'm talkin' to you! Come here!
- What's happening?
- Where you been?
- In there.
- Can you stand a toss?
- Sure, I'm clean.
- You use shit?
No, man. Who are you, Dick Tracy
or somebody? I said I was clean.
- I'm not gonna get stuck, am I?
- I'm clean!
- If I do, you know what happens.
- Yeah. I said I'm clean.
Get off! I'll break your motherfuckin' ass!
Give me a nickel.
Give me a nickel. Come on!
I told you I'm clean. What the fuck
you wanna come down on me like that for?
This is goddamn full of shit.
- How's everything?
- Everything's everything, baby.
There's nothin' out there. It's all milk.
- There ain't nothin' around. Nobody's holdin'.
- I got a name for you. Sal Boca. Brooklyn.
- Boca?
- Yeah. B-O-C-A.
- Never heard of him.
- What about his wife Angie?
Doesn't register.
There's been some talk, though.
- About what?
- A shipment.
Comin' in this week, the week after.
Everybody's gonna get well.
- Well, who's bringin' it?
- Who knows?
- Where do you want it?
- Huh?
- Oh, shit. This side.
Beat it!
I'm gonna check on this address.
If they don't know you, it's your ass.
- I thought I told you to stand there!
- Get that hair down before Saturday.
We're goin' now. Good-bye!
Move ass. Tell everybody
we'll be back in an hour.
Great, but you belong in
Bedford-Stuyvesant, not Ridgewood.
Why don't you detach us? Give us a shot, at
least till we find out if there's anything here.
Everybody wants Weinstock. Maybe here's
the lead we're looking for. We deserve this.
You couldn't burn a three-time loser
with this garbage.
The man has done absolutely nothin'.
You'll wind up in an entrapment rap.
Brooklyn is loaded with guys that own
candy stores, two cars and go to nightclubs.
You put this hustler together with Weinstock
and maybe we got a big score.
Big score, my ass! At best
he's sellin' nickel-and-dime bags.
I wouldn't be infringin' on your coffee break
if I thought it was a nickel-and-dimer.
Your hunches have backfired before, Doyle,
or have you forgotten about that already?
Jesus Christ, Jimmy,
what's happened to you guys?
Every year you lead the narcotic bureau in
arrests. What was it, over 100 again last year?
Terrific. But who? What did you bring in?
A high-school kid in short pants
that had a twitch?
You grab a bellhop because
he's got three joints in his sock?
Walter, we got the information
there's no shit on the street, right?
It's like a desert full ofjunkies
waiting to get well.
Goddamnit, this could be it. This little
candy-store guy, he's put on a big show
in a club with no narcotics connections.
They were all over him.
And after working a day and night,
we tail him to Brooklyn.
And we sat on him for practically a week, and
who do we come up with? Joel Weinstock.
Now you gotta let us have it.
Do you believe all this crap?
I go with my partner.
- What'll it take?
- A wire.
No, two wires.
One on the store, one on the house.
You know I have to get a court order
for a wire tap, don't you?
- But you'll try.
- We know you can do it, Walt.
Popeye, you still picking your feet
in Poughkeepsie?
J'entends parler de ça.
Je n'arrive pas ŕ y croire.
Alors je vais un peu parler pour moi.
J'ai tendance ŕ penser
ŕ mes propres problčmes, enfin...
Monsieur Devereaux, is this
your first trip to New York?
- Yes, it's my first.
- Why did you choose to come by ship?
The next several weeks
will be very difficult for me,
and the ocean is the only place where
the telephone isn't ringing all the time.
Do you agree with the recent survey finding
that showed that Mayor Lindsay
was the sexiest man in the world?
Tout ŕ fait, oui.
Here's the warrants and the court order
for the wire tap. Judge gave you 60 days.
Mulderig and Klein'll sit in for the feds.
They'll make all the buys.
Make sure you keep 'em informed
of everything that goes down.
You know Doyle there, don't you?
Yeah, I know Popeye. His brilliant hunches
cost the life of a good cop.
If this is the way you're comin' in on this,
why not stay home and save us a lot of grief?
- Because that's my opinion.
- Shove it up your ass.
Whatever.
Bill, do me a favor, give them a chance.
He came in with a little basic information.
You worked with him, had some trouble,
but don't get off on the wrong foot.
- You have any problems, come to me.
- Simonson, just keep off my back.
Just try and cool it with him. If you have
any problems, come to me. I'll handle him.
- I'll be happy to work with him.
- He's a good cop.
- He's got good hunches once in a while.
- Fine. Just keep him off my back.
Florida's Mackel Brothers
invite you to join the great escape.
You can say good-bye to air pollution,
commuting, high prices, rising taxes
and cold, depressing winters.
Mackel Brothers will show you the way
to Florida and fresh, clean air.
Warm and sunny year-round weather
in a home that you'll be proud to own.
Call Mackel Brothers right now...
Popeye.
- What?
- It's me, Cloudy. Open the door.
I can't.
- What do you mean, you can't? You all right?
- Yeah, I'm all right.
Let yourself in, will you?
What happened?
That crazy kid.
She locked me up with my own cuffs.
- Where's the keys?
- Over there.
Hi there.
Anybody hurt in this wreck?
I thought I told you to get
plastic folders for this stuff.
Your scrapbook is like you.
- A mess.
- Give me my pants, will you?
Come on.
- Did you get the warrants?
- Yeah.
I also got two feds. Mulderig and Klein.
What do we need those pricks for?
Because our department's got
about 908 bucks to make buys,
and they can get all they want
from Uncle Sap. Hello.
These yours, darling?
30 over here for this gentleman. Can I get 35?
- 35 here.
- 35 over here. Can I get 38?
- Yeah, right here.
- 38 over here. How about 40?
- 40.
- 40 over here. I got 40. Can I get 41? 41?
40 once, 40 twice.
Sold to the gentleman for $40.
We come now to the next number: 42399.
- 10 bucks.
- I got $10 over here. Do I hear 12?
- 12.
- 12 over here, 12. Can I get 14?
- 14.
- 14 over here. How about 16? Can I get 16?
- 16.
- 18.
18 over there. How about 20?
- 20.
- $20 over here. How about 22?
- 22.
- I got 22 over here. Can I get 24?
- 24.
- 24 over here. How about 25? 25, anybody?
- 25.
- I got 25. Can I get 26? Can I get 26?
25 once, 25 twice.
Sold to the gentleman for 25.
Every car sold here...
- "Where are you?"
- "Taking care of business."
What do you mean, taking care of business?
It's after midnight.
You know, I had to meet some people tonight.
Well, finish all your meetin'people and get
back here now. And bring a pizza with you.
Where am I gonna get
a pizza this time of night?
Well, try, OK?
I don't know where I'm gonna
find a pizza joint open.
- "Sal?"
- "Yeah."
"Don't forget"- "anchovies."
- "Salvatore?"
- "Yes. Yeah, yeah. Hello."
- Who is it?
- "Yeah, this is Sal. How are you?"
- Sounds like a foreigner.
- "You meet me Wednesday at the hotel, OK?"
- Sounds French.
- "Will I expect you?"
- "Yeah. What time?"
- "12 o'clock. Yes?"
Yeah. Yes.
Strictly small potatoes.
You sure can pick 'em, Doyle.
Still wearing your gun on your ankle?
Someone told me the reason
why you do that is
when you meet a chick
and you rub up against her,
she can't tell you're a cop.
I said it's bullshit. It's gotta be
a fast-draw gimmick or somethin'.
Bill, why don't you knock it off, huh?
He's gettin' too far ahead.
You're gonna lose him.
For Christ's sake, move the car!
What the hell is goin' on here?
Klein, this is Cloudy. Do you read me?
Come in, for Christ's sakes!
This is Cloudy. Do you read me?
Listen, we lost him on the bridge.
Right. I got him.
He's headin' north on East River Drive.
Excuse me.
You take Sal. I'll take the beard.
There goes Sal.
- You want the red or the white?
- Pour it in your ear.
- Yes, sir?
- Yeah, guy just walked in, what's his name?
I'm pretty sure that one's a Frog.
He made me, too.
He lives on four, he went up to six.
He's cute, real cute.
The other guy's a Frog. He checked
into the Edison. Had a hooker sent up.
You should have collared him right there.
- Who's on him?
- Klein.
- How about Sal?
- We put him to bed for the night.
Why don't you do the same, Doyle?
You look like shit.
Come on.
Look, my partner and I made
this case, you know, originally.
- We don't want any feds screwing it up.
- Case? So far you haven't shown me a thing.
You keep shootin' your mouth off,
I'm gonna knock you right into next week.
- Knock it off.
- Don't tell me to knock it off.
Cut it out, will ya, for Christ's sakes!
There's nothin' goin' down. Get some sleep.
Blastoff. 180.
200. Good Housekeeping seal of approval.
210. US government certified.
220. Lunar trajectory.
Junk-of-the-month club. Sirloin steak.
230. Grade-A poison.
Absolute dynamite.
89 per cent pure junk. Best I've ever seen.
If the rest is like this,
you'll be dealin' on this load for two years.
- It's worth the half million?
- How many kilos?
- 60.
- 60 kilos...
Eight big ones a kilo, right? This stuff'll
take a seven-to-one hit on the street.
By the time it gets down to
nickel bags, it'll be 32 million.
Thank you, Howard. Take what's left
there with you and good night.
Uh-uh. Not that one. The little one.
- I guess we got a deal, huh?
- What we got here, Sal, is a test.
A deal for half a million dollars? Maybe.
Maybe?
Come on, the guy's in a hurry. He wants
the bread. He wants to go back to France.
This guy's not gonna play games. Look, he's
one of the shrewdest cats I ever come across.
What am I, a schmuck? What's the hurry?
He could see a couple of shows,
visit the top of the Empire State Building.
Don't jerk me, Weinstock.
I spent a lot of time settin' this one up.
So what do you want, a badge?
This is your first major-league game, Sal.
One thing I learned: Move calmly,
move cautiously, you'll never be sorry.
Look, I've been damn careful up to now.
This is why your phone lines are tapped and
the feds are crawlin' all over you like fleas.
- He'll take the deal somewhere else.
- Let him take it and find out how easy it is
to put together a half a million in cash.
There's no hurry to do this kind of business.
The stuff is here!
We can make the switch in an hour!
Look, I'm tellin' you,
he'll split if we don't move.
This guy's got 'em like that.
He's everything they say he is.
What about you, Sal?
Are you everything they say you are?
That son of a bitch.
Thank you.
- Hello?
- This is Doyle. I'm sittin' on Frog One.
Yeah, I know that. We got
the Westbury covered like a tent.
The Westbury, my ass! I got him
on the shuttle at Grand Central.
Now what the hell's goin' on up there?
I make him comin' out of the hotel.
He was free as a bird.
What the hell are you talkin' about?
Yeah, well, uh...
Listen, I don't care how many
bartenders you got that are sick.
No, I'm not workin' that joint.
That's right. Same to ya, buddy.
Can I get a grape drink?
Watch the closing doors.
Son of a bitch!
Hi. Can I have a round-trip
ticket to Washington?
- Cash or charge?
- Cash.
Cash is $54. Please print your name
on both tickets before you board the plane.
- Bye-bye.
- Bye-bye. Have a nice flight.
- Yes, sir?
- Round trip to Washington.
- So?
- So everything's goin' great.
Terrific. Beautiful.
I'll need a few more days, though.
The boys think we oughta cool it for a while,
just to make sure there's no heat.
You must take me for an imbecile.
Why do you think I asked you
to meet me in Washington?
I haven't spent five minutes in New York City
without the company of a policeman.
Look, I'm levelin' with you.
I need a little more time.
My people think we oughta find a better time
to make the switch, that's all.
It has to be by the end of this week.
Look, Charnier, you gotta be reasonable.
It's your problem.
Well, it's your problem, too.
So nice to have seen you again.
We found a set of works
on the kid driving the sports car.
- His girlfriend's in the back. She's dead.
- Give the car a toss.
- I say we keep sittin' on Boca.
- Jimmy, give it up. It's all over with.
If there was a deal, it's gone down by now.
We blew our warrants and we blew our cover.
Listen, I know the deal hasn't gone down.
I know it. I can feel it. I'm dead certain.
Last time you were dead certain,
we ended up with a dead cop.
Break it up! Will you two break it up?
Stop it! Hold on to yourself.
What's the matter with you?
Jimmy, you wasted two months on this.
No collars are comin' in
while you're runnin' around town
jerkin' off! Now go back to work!
You're off special assignment!
Get down! Get out! Get outta the area!
Leave her alone! Stay away!
Leave her alone. There's a sniper up there!
Stop that man! He's wanted by the police!
- What's the next stop into the city?
- 25th Avenue.
Hold it!
Police emergency. I need your car.
When am I gonna get it back?
For Christ's sake!
Hold it! Stop! Halt!
- Don't stop.
- But...
- Don't stop or I'll kill you.
- I gotta stop in the next station.
Touch the brakes and I'll blow you in half.
- What's goin' on?
- I don't know. Sit down, buddy. Relax.
Coke! Coke, you all right?
Hey, Coke, you all right?
Don't answer.
- Get back.
- Relax.
Keep going.
You're not gonna get away with this.
Put the gun down.
Get back!
- Come on, now.
- I said get back!
Stop!
Hold it!
Let's get outta here!
Come on, come on. Shake your ass.
Can't seem to find the damn ticket.
- Where's the guy?
- He's gettin' my car. He's in the back.
Thank you.
- Can I help you, sir?
- Yeah.
- You got your ticket?
- I must have dropped mine.
What kinda ticket did you have?
He's in the brown Lincoln. Foreign plates.
He's walking towards Front Street.
Got him. Angie's parked over here in the LTD.
Cute. You stay with her.
We're gonna sit on the Lincoln.
The car's dirty, Cloudy.
We're gonna sit here all night if we have to.
What time is it?
Ten after four.
- Huh?
- Ten after four.
That's the third time
those guys have been around.
All right, let's hit 'em. Hit 'em!
Freeze!
Nobody move! Put your hands in the air!
Stay right there. If you move,
I'll blow your fuckin' head off.
- What the hell's that?
- What are you doin'? Turn around.
Who's the boss here? Who's runnin' this
outfit? You are? What are you doin' here?
- Just runnin' around.
- Who sent you down here? Don't talk back.
- What are you doin' here?
- We saw the car.
We was breaking down the tires.
That's all it was.
Lock 'em up.
Come on, come on!
Nothin' but a bunch of lousy spic car thieves!
- Nothin' there except a New York City map.
- Are you bullshittin' me?
That car's dirty.
Take it in and tear it apart.
Tear it out.
Nothin' here, Jimmy.
This is all solid.
There's nobody been under that car
since it came from the factory.
That thing is clean.
I don't buy that, Irv.
The stuff is in that car.
Well, you find it. I can't.
Enfin on ne va pas passer la journée ici.
Ça fait deux heures qu'on est lŕ.
Soyez patient.
Look, the car was lost sometime last night.
First they send us to Pier One,
then here. Then what?
Why did you park the car
down by the waterfront?
You're staying in midtown Manhattan
and you lose the car by the Brooklyn Bridge?
Monsieur Devereaux is scouting locations
for a film for French television.
He probably left the car to look at something.
We were told by the police commissioner
that the car was brought to this garage.
- I demand its immediate return.
- You have to be patient.
We get four or five hundred cars here a day.
Monsieur Devereaux is
an important guest of this country.
He is working with the absolute cooperation
and participation of your government.
Here are his credentials
from the French consulate.
Unless you wish to see this in his film,
I suggest you locate the car immediately.
You're in a no-smoking area, sir. Would
you please extinguish your cigarettes?
What was the weight of
the car when you got it, Irv?
4795 pounds.
You sure?
That's what it was. 4795 pounds
when it came into the shop.
Owner's manual says 4675.
That's 120 pounds overweight.
And when it was booked
into Marseilles it was 4795.
That's still 120 pounds overweight.
Jimmy's gotta be right.
Listen, I ripped everything outta there
except the rocker panels.
Come on, Irv. What the hell is that?
Shit.
Son of a bitch.
All right.
I got it for you, Randy.
It just came in from downtown.
- Who's Devereaux?
- I am Mr Devereaux. Why?
I'm sorry, Mr Devereaux, but we get a lot
of cars here and it's hard to keep track...
- You mean the car is here now?
- Oh, yeah. It's right outside.
They stole it right off
the street from you, huh?
Goddamn. You're gonna have to pay
the towing charge, you know.
I was told these things happen in
New York, but one never expects it.
Yeah, well, that's New York.
Is this your first trip over here?
Yes. Where's my car, please?
It's right over here.
You're lucky this time. It's in perfect shape.
Not a scratch. You must lead a charming life.
Henri.
Je vous attendais.
Let's go!
I wouldn't be surprised if I'd been followed.
- Listen, I'll see you at Pop's tonight.
- OK, babe. Take care.
They got the bridge blocked off!
This is the police. You're surrounded.
Come out with your hands up!
Give 'em the gas!
Hold your fire!
Stop!
They're comin' out! Hold your fire!
Popeye. It's me, it's me.
Frog One is in that room.
Drop it!
Mulderig.
You shot Mulderig.
The son of a bitch is here.
I saw him. I'm gonna get him.
Visiontext Subtitles: Sally Lewis
US ENGLISH