We will let Chester
know what happened.
He'll want to know
where to find you.
I left him a letter.
Huh!
[Flesh ripping]
[Squish!]
[Gunfire]
Yurei be anywhere you go.
It follow you.
[phonograph plays,
a woman singing in Japanese]
[♪♪♪]
[man singing along]
Watch Movies, TV Series & Live Sports
www.admitme.app
[speaking in Japanese]
[inhaling sharply]
[glass smashing]
[humming and playing rattle]
[baby cooing]
[door opening]
[baby cooing and fussing]
[baby fussing]
[baby crying]
[gasping]
You did the right thing, dear.
Children can't be raised
on the streets.
[baby crying]
[stones rattling]
[wooden percussion blocks
knocking]
[wood block knocking]
[♪♪♪]
[stones rattling]
[drum beating]
[♪♪♪]
Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org
[♪♪♪]
[fly buzzing]
[birds chirping]
[♪♪♪]
[tray rattling]
[speaking in Japanese]
[pouring tea]
[whisking]
[flies buzzing]
[♪♪♪]
[tray rattling]
[door sliding open]
[fly buzzing]
[swatting]
[water running]
[putting feet into slippers]
[birds chirping]
[faint snip of pruning shears]
[♪♪♪]
[gasping]
[bones cracking]
[♪♪♪]
[rumbling]
[sand shifting]
[gasping]
[muffled cries]
[flies buzzing]
[tray rattling]
[gasping]
[structure rumbling]
[sobs, breath ragged]
[shouting]
[panting in fear]
[flies buzzing]
[gasping]
[screaming]
[thunder rumbling]
[grunting with effort]
[wheezing gasp]
[bones cracking]
[car engine passing]
Wake up, buddy.
You're home.
Chester?
Nakayama, Chester.
Medical discharge.
Chester.
Where's Luz?
She's okay.
But her father
came, and...
She left?
I'm sorry.
She asked me to send it.
You needed happy thoughts,
not this.
[♪♪♪]
The spirit follows you.
It killed your sons.
It drove Luz mad.
It's your fault
my husband died.
Now you put everyone
in danger!
[gasping]
You should rest.
Let's go home.
She's right.
A spirit does follow me.
It followed me
across the Pacific.
That jeep crash,
it was no accident.
It tried to kill me.
Did it do this too?
Chester, please.
Don't listen to this nonsense.
What was she talking about?
What did she mean,
you brought this on?
Son...
[♪♪♪]
Ma?
Ma, let me go.
Let me go!
Yurei...
[choking]
[gasping]
Taizo...
[gasping for breath]
[coughing]
Ma!
- Asako!
- Ma!
What happened?
Asako!
Ma!
Chester?
[Asako]: She was inside me.
But I was there too.
I had to watch my hands...
my own hands...
I tried...
I tried to control my body.
I fought so hard, but I...
I couldn't do it.
I felt the spirit.
So much pain.
So much desire.
Like a tremendous hunger.
Onnen.
What is it?
What does it want?
[wood block knocking]
You.
Then it was her.
Who?
I had a sister,
died many years ago.
Her name was Yuko.
Your sister...
is the yurei?
She was...
Hideo's picture bride.
But he shunned her.
Sent her away.
[Asako]: She went to
the Badger Avenue bridge.
She jumped.
Jesus.
But then what does
she want with me?
When she came to Hideo,
she was...
with child already.
It called me her child.
Taizo.
Is that...
Taizo is the name
she gave you.
I'm sorry.
[fireworks explode,
onlookers cheer]
["The Star-Spangled Banner"
playing on radio]
[baby crying]
[baby crying and fussing]
Taizo...
[crowd laughs and celebrates]
[Asako]: I was still in Japan
when I found out my sister
had taken her life.
I vowed
that I would never
let my sister's child
be an orphan.
I made
the crossing.
We took you.
And my father?
A soldier.
He died at war.
All these years...
All my life...
Those meals at the table
when you looked me in the eye
and never said a word...
How?
We feared
the truth would hurt.
You mean it would hurt you.
Son...
Don't you call me that.
She's my blood.
You are nothing.
[humming lullaby]
[humming gently]
[wind gusting]
Taizo...
[fireworks crackling overhead]
[baby fussing and crying nearby]
[baby crying]
[♪♪♪]
Yuko...
[baby screaming]
Yurei..
How can this be?
I don't know.
You know the traditions.
You need to help us.
I am not onmyoji.
I only know
pieces of old kaidan.
That's more than most.
[♪♪♪]
Her spirit...
somewhere else.
Kaidan tell us
unfulfilled soul
need body to occupy.
If we destroy body,
soul cannot exist.
Destroy the body?
Destroy her body.
No...
It is not her.
Not anymore.
Her spirit
must be set free.
Please.
This must be done.
[♪♪♪]
She looks just like
I remember.
A girl...
...preparing to meet
her husband.
Yes.
It must be done.
[Yamato-san chanting]:
Namu Amida Butsu...
Namu Amida Butsu,
Namu Amida Butsu.
[muttered chanting]
Namu Amida Butsu,
Namu Amida Butsu...
[continues chanting]
[chanting phrase]
[♪♪♪]
[Asako]:
Chester...
Leave me.
Please.
[♪♪♪]
[gasping]
[crying out]
[screaming]
[♪♪♪]
[fireworks crackling]
[wind whistling]
[echo of Yuko's voice
singing lullaby]
Taizo...
[Yuko's voice singing lullaby]
Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org
Watch Movies, TV Series & Live Sports
www.admitme.app