Gregorio. Gregorio!
They're all dead!
Oh, God, they're all dead!
Massacred!
The Alamo has fallen!
They're dead, all of them!
They're all dead at the Alamo!
Did you hear what he said?
The Alamo!
Take the oath for militia duty,
and you will receive 640 acres...
640 acres of your own...
of your own choosing.
640 acres of your own choosing.
That's better.
Smooth.
If it doesn't burn going down,
how can you be sure it's bad for you?
I'll be interested to see you gentlemen
when you arrive in Texas
and have your first taste of mescal.
Is it true that men and women
imbathe together out in the open?
Cleanliness is next to godliness.
Yes, well... excuse us.
Invest now, gentlemen,
or lament later.
I'm a screamer.
I got the roughest racehorse,
the prettiest sister,
the surest rifle and the ugliest dog
in the district.
My old man could lick
anybody in Tennessee,
and I could lick my old man.
I can outgrin a panther
and ride on a lightnin' bolt,
tote a steamboat on my back
and whip my weight in wildcats.
Whip my weight in wildcats.
Whip my weight in wildcats. Whip...
- What is it?
- He's here.
- Who's here?
- He is here!
Five minutes!
I'll tell you, these old bones
could sure use a respite.
'Course, the good citizens of Tennessee
may grant me that wish come next election.
- No!
- Excuse me one moment.
- Yes. Yes, of course.
Sam Houston.
Makin' friends wherever you go.
- To Tennessee.
- Oh, to hell with Tennessee.
To Texas.
It's sad, isn't it?
A year ago, we'd be looking at two men
with their caps set for the White House.
Now...
What you peddlin', Sam?
Somethin' a certain Congressman
might need before long.
Are you sellin' rockin' chairs?
I'm sellin' Texas.
And what would I want with Norte Mexico?
David, you remember
what Tennessee was?
You come to Texas.
Timber, water, game, cattle,
more land than you can possibly imagine.
You take the oath for militia duty, you will
receive 640 acres of your own choosing.
- My own choosing?
- Mm-hmm.
Sam! You figure this new republic's
gonna need a president?
Before we begin tonight's performance,
I should like to acknowledge
the presence of the man
whose life inspired our humble play.
Good evening, Mr. Crockett.
You want to call me an opportunist?
Hell, yes, call me an opportunist.
But taking the Alamo
changed everything.
- We're in control now.
- Yes!
We swore allegiance to Mexico
under the Federalist Constitution of 1824.
Santa Anna tore that document up
personally, did he not?
Named himself supreme dictator?
Well, I, for one, ain't swearin' allegiance
to no son-of-a-bitch dictator.
Yeah!
Neither am I.
Time to go, General.
They are talking crazy.
Drunk back sober.
It's a miracle of the first order.
Seguin, why'd they put me in charge
of the army if they won't listen to me?
We need to muster and train troops here,
not send soldiers all over Texas.
Idiots. They think Santa Anna's just gonna
hand over part of Mexico without a fight?
They are gonna want you humble,
General.
I humble myself before God,
and there the list ends.
To march an expedition
between here and Matamoros
- is lunacy!
You do not split an army
into vagabond militias
that march off on the slightest pretext
like bloodthirsty rabble.
Do you really believe this war is over?
You opposed Bexar, but victory was ours!
Yeah!
And now you oppose Matamoros,
where victory will be as sweet.
No.
Perhaps, sir, you simply
oppose fighting.
Fighters shall lead the new country
of Texas, sir.
The council will now consider
the removal of General Houston
from command of the regular army.
- All in favor, show of hands.
- Aye!
The late, great Sam Houston,
former governor of Tennessee
and now former general
of the Texian army.
- Scottish catamite.
- What did you say?
I called you a Scottish catamite, Grant.
One step down from associate pederast.
- All right.
- Remain clothed!
Come for me! Come! Come!
Any excuse to start removin' your clothes,
is that right, Houston?
This is not your concern, Mr. Bowie.
Indeed. This is between me
and the Scottish catamite.
Wanna borrow mine, Grant?
'Cause I'll surely give it to ya.
Buy you a drink?
I didn't know you drank.
You marked the coat as single-breasted,
with a four-inch stand collar?
- As you desired, Mr. Travis.
- Lieutenant Colonel.
And the epaulets are gold bullion?
Should be quite a sight.
Where would you like the uniform sent?
San Antonio de Bexar.
I'll be there defending the Alamo.
Defend against what? The Mexican army
left there with their tail between their legs.
Mr. William... she here.
In your office, waitin'.
Your wife.
Mr. Bowie!
- Colonel.
- Buck.
Drunken Hottentot.
Two-bit dandy.
Well, the choices are
abandonment, adultery,
or cruel and barbarous treatment.
I think abandonment's most accurate.
Any of the choices would be appropriate.
You sure you want to do this?
Well, we-we signed the papers.
I meant Charlie.
I don't intend this harshly, but
he should have a male example in his life.
I've already made arrangements for him
to stay with a fine family while I'm away.
Well, we have a long way to travel.
Your father's becoming a rich man,
and he'll be able to see to your education.
You're makin' a jackass
outta yourself, Sam.
Vindictive sons of bitches.
Texas... wasted on the Texians.
They'll come back.
The Mexicans.
A well-trained army,
against all this handful of amateurs.
Only chance we have
is to fight 'em out in the open.
Forts, they're useless,
useless to us.
What is it about
that damn place, anyway?
What place?
The Alamo.
Every time a sour wind blows through,
everybody runs there and hides inside.
Ain't nothin' but mud.
A caved-in church.
And cannon.
Cannon.
Protects my home, Sam.
You don't have no home,
any more than I have.
It's a damn shame about your wife, Jim.
Am I still your general?
You know you are.
I want you to return to the Alamo,
fetch the cannon back.
Will you do that for me?
Will you promise that you'll do that for me?
Yeah.
Now, you mind Mr. and Mrs. Ayers.
Don't go causing any fuss.
When I return,
we'll get a home of our own.
I promise.
"One crowded hour of glorious life
is worth an age without a name."
Jim Bowie's here!
- Know which one he is?
- Right there.
Welcome to San Antonio, Bowie!
- Welcome home, Jim.
- Welcome home, Mr. Bowie.
Welcome home, Jim.
You all right, Mr. James?
I have a home.
Sir?
We know you guys
from somewhere?
Whoo, that one's
pretty dandy, that one.
Halt!
- Have the quartermaster secure billeting.
- Yes, sir.
- Where you going, sir?
- I'd like to see what I'm fightin' for.
Dismount!
It was founded as a mission 100 years ago.
The Bexarenos called it the Alamo,
after Alamo de Parras,
a Spanish cavalry unit
that moved in 30 years ago.
As you can see, it is not designed
with military intentions.
She's well armed.
Most cannon of any fort
west of the Mississippi.
I placed our largest, the 18-pounder, on
the southwest corner, so it fronts the town.
The north wall is in ruins, so I have
two batteries with five cannon to defend it.
What was the original convento
is now barracks and a makeshift infirmary.
Major Jameson, our engineer,
is emplacing a palisade
between the main gate and the church.
- What was here before?
- Nothing. An indefensible flank.
It still appears indefensible.
Good riflemen and a 12-pounder
should hold it.
The church itself wasn't built till 1756.
It has no roof.
Was it destroyed in battle?
The Catholics never quite finished it.
Saints Dominic and Francis.
Francis had two gifts:
prophecy,
and the ability to inspire
passionate devotion.
This fort is the only thing
that stands between Santa Anna's army
and our settlements.
As goes the Alamo...
so goes Texas.
If the need arises, I recommend you take
my personal quarters on the west wall.
They're isolated,
yet near the primary defenses.
I'm afraid I don't understand, sir.
I have personal matters
to attend to in Mina.
I'm leaving you in command.
I know you fought this posting, Travis.
Forting up is not exactly
a cavalryman's dream.
I'll defend it with my life, sir.
Your biggest task will be keeping
the volunteers and the regulars
from killin' one another out of boredom.
The Mexican army would have to cover
300 miles in the dead of winter
to get here before I return.
I got one guy around my neck,
I got another guy takin' off half my ear
- with his one good tooth.
The two that I knocked out are now
wakin' up, realizin' who knocked 'em out.
But I'm fine. I'm fine.
'Cause I know I got my trusty, loyal Ward
right next to me.
So I turn over my shoulder,
and who do I find?
Tortilla lady
and her 13-year-old hound dog.
Where were ya?
I hate to tell you this, Jim,
but you were in the wrong.
Exactly. That's when I need you the most.
Oh, God. I love this place.
I love it, too.
Colonel?
You look terrible,
almost yellow right around
the cheeks and forehead.
You a doctor now,
along with everything else?
I've heard rumor that you plan to destroy
the mission and remove the cannon.
- Where'd you hear that?
- Men tend to prattle on when they drink.
Your men tend to drink.
It would be a great mistake.
I agree.
And any further discussion on this
will be between myself and Colonel Neill.
Colonel Neill left Bexar this morning
on personal business.
It's my command now.
Well, my, my, my.
That is a swift rise, Billy.
Might as well break out
those long britches.
Your men exhibit no discipline.
If matters don't change, it will become
my duty, as colonel of this post...
Lieutenant colonel.
Restrain your men... or I will.
Habla ingles. muchachos?
We got 'em, David.
It appears to me
that we're all on the same side here.
What you doin' out here?
My name is David Crockett.
Crockett of Tennessee?
Davy Crockett?
He prefers "David."
Now, there was this little detail
of a re-election back home.
Aww!
It's all right. It's all right.
- 'Cause you know what I told them folks?
- What'd you tell 'em?
- I said,"You all can go to hell."
- "I'm goin' to Texas!"
- Yeah!
- Welcome to Texas, Davy.
- Thank you, sir.
- Put your mark on it, Mr. Crockett?
- Look out. Let me through here.
Absolutely.
"I'm half alligator, half snappin' turtle."
"I can slide off a rainbow and
jump the Mississippi in a single leap."
Tell 'em, Davy,
how you can whup your weight in wildcats.
I seen you onstage.
Well, that wasn't me.
Why... Why, sure it was.
No, sir, that was just an actor in a play.
He was performin' a character.
Aw, come on, Davy.
Say the lines.
Davy Crockett, the Lion of the West.
I dare San-tanna to show his face
now you're here.
Well, I understood the fightin' was over.
Ain't it?
iAlto!
iFuego!
Well done.
You don't have the sand to even talk
to two of my men, much less arrest them.
I told you I intended
to restore order.
You've got no command
over my volunteers. None.
I have absolute command.
Break 'em out, boys.
Yeah.
'Cause it's gonna be a cold day in hell
anybody takes orders from a debtor
who leaves his pregnant wife
in the middle of the night.
How about a land swindler
who marries a girl, God rest her soul,
for her father's money?
Whoa, whoa, fellers!
Hey, hey, hey, fellers, now, listen.
Just 'cause we ain't got nobody to fight
don't mean we need to fight one another.
Congressman Crockett has a point.
We should do this democratically.
A vote.
- What about Colonel Crockett leadin' us?
- No, I'm with you fellers, not above you.
All for the lieutenant colonel,
raise your hand.
Now, come on, men. No repercussions.
All in favor of me commanding.
And all for me?
All right.
You can command the militia only.
Regulars can't be led by a volunteer.
It's illegal.
You don't like the outcome,
you change the rule?
Is that it, Buck?
Aw, don't fret about it, Jim.
We all know who's in charge.
You know, I don't know why
we had to tent up outside of town
when there are so many fine houses
with big corn-husk beds just sittin' empty.
Why are they empty?
Apparently some of the folks hereabouts
seem to think the Mexicans is comin' back.
Most of the boys think they wouldn't be
here till late spring if they come at all.
- Figure they know something we don't?
- Mijito. cierre la puerta y ven para aca.
Tell me what is going on!
We'll never be able to defend the town.
Orderly withdrawal
into the Alamo.
- Greys fall in!
- Close up!
Shoulder arms! Forward! Forward!
Orderly withdrawal!
Please proceed to the Alamo in an orderly
manner. Don't run. You're fine.
- Almeron!
- One, two, one, two.
Almeron!
Susanna!
Let's go, men!
Come on! Follow me!
Come on!
Colonel? I'm sorry to disturb you,
but we got quite a mare's nest out here.
I have to get couriers out
while there's still time.
You and your men
will defend the palisade.
The palisade? You talkin' about
that little old bunch of sticks over there?
You prefer a different assignment?
No, that's the one
I was gonna put in for.
If you could oversee manning the walls,
it would be a help.
We should have six men to a cannon,
18 tubes,
- which works out to...
- 108 men.
And we should have a man with a musket
every four feet of wall.
We're gonna need more men.
iViva Santa Anna! iViva Mexico!
To Gonzales, and
to Colonel Fannin at Goliad. Godspeed.
Sir.
Colonel, you should see this.
We're gonna need a lotmore men.
What is Colonel Bowie doing
on the bridge?
Tryin' to talk us out of the spot we're in.
Fire the 18-pounder.
- Sir?
- You heard me.
Fire the cannon.
Prime the gun.
Fire!
Lo siento. Manuel.
I had nothing to do with this.
You out of your mind?
- I'm trying to get us a truce!
- A truce?
If we broker a cessation, we will do so
from a position of strength, not weakness.
- Goddamn!
- We don't turn belly up and beg.
Otherwise, we have said nothing,
and this conflict means nothing.
Dyin'for nothin' means shit to me.
- Their response?
- Shit!
David.
Surrender at discretion... Buck.
Perhaps, Colonel,
they'll only execute the officers.
I think we all just got promoted.
Looky here.
Within a few days
all of Texas will know our situation.
Tell me, Buck,
in Alabama,
precisely how many is "a few"?
No. Excelencia.
Ah.
Crockett?
Si. Alteza.
iExcelente!
You know, personally, David,
I'd just as soon take my chances
fightin' out in the open.
Hell, I don't like being hemmed in
any more than you do, but here we sit.
Avoid cluster at all times.
Keep your eyes set for crossfire.
Pack plenty of grease wrap balls,
put 'em in your blocks.
You may be a-firin' fast, but not yet.
Load all your muskets and stack 'em,
but don't powder 'em.
Ten minutes in this, they'll be
nothin' but sticks, understand? Oh...
And no more of this, by anybody.
Go to it, boys.
- Here we go, sir.
Come on, let me help you.
That's right.
- Take it in.
It burns.
- But, sir...
- That's it.
I smell like a skunk's ass.
Jim, what ails you, exactly?
Consumption.
Typhoid. Pneumonia.
One or all.
Exactly.
She's a dandy, all right.
That knife fight you got into,
sand bar over in Natchez...
It was the one that got you written up.
That all true?
You believe everything you read now?
I didn't read it, I heard it.
And the way I heard it,
he put a sword cane and two shots in you.
I don't remember.
Figure ol' Sam will be
down here pretty soon.
When he gets here,
we'll have a good ol' time.
It was three shots.
Sword came through my lung
and went through my hand,
and then I cut his heart out.
Those ain't bears out there.
Do you understand that... Davy?
Why in the hell do you suppose
they don't just attack us?
I seen vaqueros spend all day long
just killin' one bull.
You bring a band, you're countin' on
havin' something to celebrate.
Mighty nice of'em to serenade us like this.
It's a cavalry march, but I'm told
Santa Anna fancies it for other uses.
He borrowed it from the Spaniards,
the Spaniards from the Moors.
- It's called "Deguello."
- Kinda pretty.
Deguello means "slit throat."
Now, ain't that pretty.
Get down! Get down!
iFuego!
iFuego! iFuego!
Fire!
Watch the north wall!
iFuego! iFuego!
Keep your heads down, boys!
iFuego!
Mornin'.
Yes, sir.
Lieutenant, check the main gate for me.
I need a head count for Jim Bowie.
Yes, sir.
Notice how you can't really hear it
until it stops?
Until they decide to attack, I suspect
we'll be bombarded on a nightly basis.
Deprive us of sleep.
They want you to
start seeing ghosts everywhere.
Colonel, I became a little heated with you
in front of your men.
It was ill-advised
and not terribly professional.
Don't worry about it.
Most of my men didn't even understand
the words you were usin'.
It's important that you and I agree.
For me, though we are poorly supplied,
surrender is not an option.
I submit that we engage and delay
until reinforcements arrive.
Sometimes, it's just the way
you say things, Travis, that's all.
I swear to God.
Bring it down! Down! Down! Down!
Down!
Down! Down!
To the left. To the left.
In.
Do you notice anything different
about them cannon?
They moved 'em closer last night.
This will be the spot.
As our well is dryin',
anytime you find yourselves
not busy with other matters,
I need you to be diggin' a new one here.
Ain't bad enough we got to fetch 'em
the water. Now we got to find it for 'em, too.
David, you said you wanted to see him.
There he is,
the Napoleon of the West.
Which one?
- That's Santa Anna?
- Yeah.
He's quite the peacock, isn't he?
Wind kicked up.
ilnfanteria! Saquen sus canones.
iFuego!
Go back! Take cover!
Take that ball to Captain Dickinson.
We can reuse it.
You'll be pickin' that up yourself.
Well, I'll be.
- Cut it to shot and send it back to 'em.
- Yes, sir.
Fire the cannon.
Fire!
Fire once from each cannon!
You heard the colonel.
Lieutenant colonel, Colonel.
- You heard the man. Let's give 'em a taste!
- Let's give 'em hell!
Come on, get up here!
And fire!
Fire!
- Fire!
At this very moment our soldiers are held
in the Alamo against a force of thousands.
They put their hopes in Colonel Fannin.
who. despite his pedigree.
has proven himself ill-equipped to lead.
much less march. an army.
This is from Colonel Travis.
"I call on you in the name of liberty
to come to our aid with all dispatch."
"If this call is neglected,
I am determined to sustain myself
as long as possible
and die like a soldier,
who never forgets what is due
to his own honor and that of his country:
victory or death."
Gentlemen...
I will raise an army.
We will relieve the Alamo.
But only after
we have declared independence
and created a government
that can be legally recognized
by all the nations of the world.
That... is what every besieged man
in the Alamo is fighting for.
We have no idea
if any of our couriers made it out.
- You know the land and the language.
- You are asking me to leave my men.
I'm asking you to deliver a message
to Houston and return with a response.
I'm ordering it.
Don't give him too much water.
He's just like me.
He drinks too much, he ain't worth a damn.
I'll bring him back to you, Santiago.
You bring yourself back.
Captain... go with God.
Makes a man ponder
the possibilities, don't it?
What happened to your cap?
Crawl away?
No. I only wear it when it's extra cold.
The truth is,
I only started wearing that thing...
because of that feller
in that play they did about me.
People expect things.
Ain't it so.
- Can I ask you something?
- All right.
Now, which was tougher,
jumping the Mississippi
or riding that lightning bolt?
Can you catch a cannonball?
If it was just me,
simple old David from Tennessee,
I might drop over that wall
some night and take my chances.
But that Davy Crockett feller,
they're all watchin' him.
He's been on these walls
every day of his life.
He's burning with fever.
Try to get him to drink
something not whiskey.
Sam, get me some sheets
and cold mud.
I have issued orders for Colonel Fannin
to retreat from Goliad.
John Forbes is mustering more men
throughout South Texas
and bringing them to Gonzales.
I expect 1500 men
to be there when I arrive.
We will march out,
circumventing Santa Anna's army,
and relieve the Alamo from the west,
withdrawing back to the Colorado
and establishing on a line southeast
from Beason's Crossing to Brazoria.
You will have command
of the regular army.
The militias will have their own command.
No. I will command all or none.
You do your calling, and I shall do mine.
I will lead an army.
You will birth a nation.
Gentlemen, to Texas!
To Texas!
Here they come! Here they come!
Position the cannon!
Muster!
Move back! Move back!
They're measuring our strength.
Prepare yourselves.
Fire at will, gentlemen!
Captain Dickinson!
Aim! Fire!
Run, you rabbits, run!
Them jacales out there
offer pretty good cover.
I wouldn't mind stretching my legs.
- Burn 'em down.
- Yes, sir. Yes, sir.
Get that first one, right there.
Agh!
Arrgh!
What's your name, boy?
Oh, yeah, Davy. Thatta boy!
Fine shootin', boy.
Muy bien. Muy bien. Muy bien.
Watch the north wall!
Over there.
What are they working at?
When they come over those walls,
I want you to throw up your hands
and holler,
"Soy negro. No disparo."
What's that?
Mexican law said
there ain't no slaves, right?
- Yeah.
- And contract or no, that's what you is.
Now, the Mexicans see your color, you
tell 'em,"Don't shoot." They pass you by.
But Mr. William,
he gonna give me a gun, and I'll...
You clean up their shit, you take care of
their horses, you wash 'em, you feed 'em.
Damn if you ain't gonna die for 'em, too.
Where is everybody?
30 men from here in Gonzales
have already left for the Alamo.
Assemble the men that we have.
We need more men.
If they arrive every day,
soon we will have enough.
But for now, we wait.
If we can't run, we walk.
If we can't walk, we crawl.
But we gotta go to the aid of those boys.
It's only right.
General, I'm the man who left Travis there.
I do not enjoy waiting
any more than the next man,
but I will not sacrifice Texas.
These 124 men cannot pierce
an army of thousands.
Colonel Fannin is en route from Goliad
with 400 men.
These troops need training.