(ALL CHANTING IN LATIN)
(CHANTING CONTINUES)
(DRILL WHIRRING)
MAN 1: What the hell is this?
MAN 2: I don't know.
MAN 1: Whoa.
Bloody hell.
The Crossrail is the biggest
construction project in Europe,
carving 26 miles of new
commuter train tunnels
beneath the surface
of London.
But today, an ancient tomb filled with
the coffins of Crusader knights...
ARCHAEOLOGIST:
People don't realize
that London is
a giant graveyard.
A modern city built
on centuries of death.
FEMALE REPORTER: Because of the
tomb's proximity to the Thames,
half the space is flooded,
is that right?
ARCHAEOLOGIST: There are even more
coffins submerged underwater.
The tomb appears to have been
built during the Second Crusade,
which means it's filled
with the bodies
of Crusader knights
who invaded Egypt
before returning to England.
MALE REPORTER: It has also
revealed a treasure trove
of secrets about
London's history.
(IN DISTINCT RADIO CHATTER)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
HENRY: Clear them out, please.
MALIK: Ladies and gentlemen,
please stop what you're doing.
The train tunnel has been
rerouted north of here.
We are now taking
control of this site.
Please collect your tools and
gear and exit immediately.
CONSTRUCTION MANAGER: Oi!
Excuse me.
Excuse me!
This is my site.
What do you think you're doing?
Evacuate your men.
We'll take it
from here.
CONSTRUCTION MANAGER:
Who the hell are you people?
MALIK: This way, sir.
Thank you very much.
HENRY: The past cannot
remain buried forever.
In my lifetime, I have unearthed
many ancient mysteries.
At last, this tomb reveals
antiquity's darkest secret.
A secret erased from history
and forgotten to time.
Princess Ahmanet.
Beautiful,
cunning,
and ruthless.
Sole heir to
the throne of Egypt.
The pharaoh's kingdom
would one day be hers to rule
without mercy or fear.
And Ahmanet would be
worshipped as a living god.
(SCREAMING)
(BABY CRYING)
But Pharaoh had a son.
The boy, now,
would inherit her destiny.
And Ahmanet understood
power was not given.
It had to be taken.
Vowing revenge,
she made a choice to embrace evil.
Set. The god of death.
(AHMANET CHANTING
IN ANCIENT LANGUAGE)
HENRY: They made a pact.
(CONTINUES CHANTING)
A pact that would
unleash darkness itself.
(RAVENS SQUAWKING)
(MUMMY GROWLING)
(SIZZLING)
(SEARING)
Ahmanet was reborn
a monster.
(GASPS)
(BLADE SWISHING)
(BABY CRYING)
Yet the pact was not complete.
She vowed to bring the demon into our
world in the body of a mortal man.
Together, they would take
their vengeance upon humanity.
(GROANING)
(SCREAMING)
(STRAINING)
For her sins,
Ahmanet was mummified alive,
(SCREAMING)
her body carried
far from Egypt.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
There she would remain,
condemned to eternal darkness.
But death is a doorway, and the
past cannot remain buried forever.
(GUNFIRE)
(MEN SHOUTING IN ARABIC)
VAIL: Out of luck,
huh, Sarge?
The civilians are gone.
It's filled with
insurgents down there.
I guess we're too late.
We can do this.
VAIL: Oh, no, no, no!
We are too late!
Command thinks we're
doing advanced recon
100 miles from here.
Sarge, you're not
going down there.
You're right, I'm not.
We are.
At least call in
an airstrike.
"Airstrike"?
Bad idea.
A little one. Just...
Maybe they'll run off.
And then command will
know where we are...
And we'll do 20 years in
Leavenworth for looting.
Hey. What'd I tell you?
We are not looters.
We are liberators of
precious antiquities.
Liberators of
Right.
But we don't even
know what's down there.
Haram. Haram is what's
down there. Treasure.
No, the translator said
"haram" means "forbidden knowledge."
Like a curse.
Around here, that's just
another word for "treasure,"
and this guy, this Henry guy,
he seems to want it pretty bad.
Well, now he's gonna
have to pay double.
Mount up. No, sir, I
ain't going on this one.
What?
I'm not going.
Vail.
What are you gonna do,
stab me with that?
Oh, no, no, no!
You crazy bastard.
It's a full day's ride
to the nearest water!
The nearest water
is right down in that village.
Come on, Vail.
Where's your
sense of adventure?
Well, that's just great, Nick.
That's just great!
Come on, slip in, slip out,
just like we always do.
(GUNFIRE)
VAIL: You son of a bitch!
NICK: Oh, my God!
VAIL: We're gonna die!
We're gonna die!
(BOTH GASPING)
NICK: Move! Move!
Just run! Run, run!
(VAIL YELLING)
(MEN SHOUTING)
(GUNFIRE)
NICK: Go, go, go!
VAIL: You kidding me?
(BOTH GRUNT)
"Slip in, slip out"?
(NICK YELPS)
VAIL: This is not like
we always do!
NICK: Stairs! Just run! Run!
Run, run, run!
(MEN SHOUTING IN ARABIC)
(MAN SHOUTING IN ARABIC)
Grenade!
VAIL: I hate you!
I hate you so much!
I never even wanted to
come to this country!
NICK: Let me think.
Just let me think.
If anyone is listening,
this is L-26, urgent, hot!
Request dynamic precision
strike at our mark!
You did not just
call in an airstrike!
Oh, yes, I did!
(EXPLOSION)
Where are you going?
Don't leave me!
Where do they
keep coming from?
(VAIL YELLING)
There's nowhere to go!
Oh, man!
We're gonna die!
Just, please, Vail!
Let me think!
We're gonna die because of you!
Just let me think!
VAIL: Think about what?
Think about what?
I'm thinking...
(GROANS)
What?
I'm thinking...
What are you thinking?
I'm thinking we're
probably gonna die here.
I knew it!
(MEN SHOUTING IN ARABIC)
(TRUCKS RETREATING)
(LAUGHING)
Huh?
I am still alive!
(VAIL WHOOPS)
(RUMBLING)
(VAIL SCREAMING)
VAIL: No!
(BOTH GROANING)
(GRUNTING)
Nick! Nick!
(PANTING)
(VAIL GROANING)
Haram.
Sir!
(INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER)
I was told you boys were supposed
to be 100 klicks from here!
Yes, sir!
But based
on intelligence,
we had reason to
believe the insurgents
were holding civilian hostages.
We had to make a call, wait for
Delta to respond or go in alone!
It was Sergeant Morton's
idea to go in, actually!
Uh-huh.
Only to find out that the villagers
had long since evacuated.
Yeah, lucky for them,
not for us.
Delta, south-side
perimeter.
Sir,
when we realized
we were in the center of
the insurgent stronghold,
it was too late.
We were discovered,
we started taking on heavy fire.
Well, sir,
Corporal Vail, here,
is too humble
to admit it,
but he risked his
life to save mine.
He's a hero. In fact, I'd
like to recommend him
for a citation.
Let me run another
scenario by you.
Sir?
One in which two assholes from
long-range reconnaissance,
that would be you,
run all over northern Iraq just
one step ahead of the enemy.
Except, instead of hunting for the enemy,
you hunt for antiquities,
stealing whatever
isn't nailed down
and selling it on
the black market.
Meanwhile,
these fanatical insurgents
trying to erase
5,000 years of history
unwittingly cover your tracks.
It's a pretty good scam.
Sergeant Morton!
Where is it?
What? Where's what?
The letter, the map
you stole from me.
(SIGHS)
NICK: Map?
I don't know what
you're talking about.
How would I have
even had an opportunity
to steal anything
from you, Miss...
Miss...
(CHUCKLES) Okay.
Sergeant Morton,
here, thinks that I'll
be too embarrassed
to tell you that I had
him in my hotel room
three nights ago
in Baghdad.
And whilst I was sleeping,
he went through my things.
I'm not embarrassed, Nick.
Disgusted, yes.
Regretful? Certainly.
But mainly,
just amazed at your ability
to mimic all the qualities
of genuine human intimacy
if only for 15 seconds.
(LAUGHS)
Where's the map, Morton?
(SIGHS)
Okay. Sir, I admit
that Miss Halsey
and I did spend
a delightful
evening in Baghdad.
A very long and
satisfying evening,
if her reactions are to
be considered sincere.
But, sir, I left with nothing
more than fond memories.
Now, perhaps I may
have neglected
to say goodbye to
her the next morning,
only because
she was exhausted
and I didn't wanna wake her.
Okay.
And the reward for my
gracious consideration?
Well, sir, as you can see,
hell hath no fury. Hmm.
NICK: Sir.
JENNY: Oh, my God!
It's Egyptian.
VAIL: Oh, is that
unusual?
We're in the Persian
Gulf, Vail.
Right, Egypt's 1,000 miles away,
so it's unusual.
Put those down, hurry.
Go get the rest.
MAN: Got it.
Colonel,
this is a significant find.
I need your men to
secure this village.
We're not even
supposed to be here.
It is my job to make sure
that anything of value
stays out of enemy hands.
We have no idea what
could be down there.
The contents of
Tutankhamun's tomb alone
were valued at 650
million pounds sterling.
Understand?
Oh. Um...
Colonel? If I may.
With a couple of shaped charges, we
could just close this hole right up
and Miss Halsey can
come back another day.
Shut up.
Okay.
You got two hours,
then we're moving out.
You're getting in the
hole with her. Him?
Me?
Yep.
Sir...
You gear up.
That's an order.
I'll be right here
holding the rope, Sarge.
Get in the damn
hole, Vail!
Oh, man!
(EXHALES)
(GASPS)
(TAPE RECORDER BEEPS)
I'm in a large
antechamber of some kind.
There is an inscription
on the northern wall,
the Litany of Ra.
(RUMBLING)
VAIL: Are you kidding me?
Your fault, Nick.
Your fault.
(WHISPERS) Do you see any treasure
in here, Nick? 'Cause I don't.
You know what I see? I see
statues that I can't carry out.
Just keep it down.
You keep it down.
What are you doing?
It is definitely a tomb.
(LIQUID DRIPPING)
VAIL: What is that? Mercury?
Yeah.
The ancient Egyptians believed
it weakened evil spirits.
Well, now we know better.
Stuff will kill you.
Yeah, after it makes
you crazy.
JENNY: There is mercury dripping from
the ceiling into holes in the ground.
Possibly interconnected.
It's a canal system
leading all the way to...
Get the lights!
Oh, my God.
Get everything
out of the bags.
(WHISPERS)
What did I tell you?
(WHISPERS) That's a
lot of gold, Nick.
I'm in a large, man-made cavern
adjoining the antechamber.
There are chiseled stairs
descending from the ledge.
There is a canal at
the center of them
that feeds a ritual well at the
base, filled with mercury.
Pleated skirts,
scarab signet rings.
This is a High Priest of Amun
from the temple in Thebes.
There is a ritual barrier
chain that surrounds the well
as a warning to intruders.
To keep people out.
There isn't
a single provision
made for someone's journey
into the underworld.
No canopic jars, no shabtis.
To be buried in
a place like this
would have been
a fate worse than death.
Nick!
Don't even think about it.
There are six
watchers around the well
facing inward
instead of out.
Whatever's in there, those chains
aren't for bringing it up.
They're for holding
it down.
(CLINKING)
(GASPS)
This is not a tomb.
It's a prison.
COLONEL GREENWAY: (ON RADIO)
Lima 2-6, come in.
Copy, sir.
Get out now. We got reports
of bogeys inbound.
We gotta take off.
Tell Greenway we
have to notify DTRA.
For what?
I need specialists
from Cairo...
VAIL: Cairo?
...CBRN suits,
and shielding casks.
VAIL: Jenny,
we are out of time.
You better grab
what you can now!
JENNY: I am not leaving until
I see what's in that pool.
VAIL: You're leaving.
We're leaving right now.
JENNY: I did not come this
far just to leave with...
(YELPS)
(GASPS)
(CREAKING)
(CAMEL SPIDERS CHITTERING)
Oh! (WHIMPERING)
Ahh! Ow! (GROANING)
Hey! Hey!
(VAIL YELLING)
(NICK SHOUTING)
Cease fire! Vail!
Vail, cease fire!
Cease fire!
They're just camel spiders!
They're not even poisonous!
Can we please leave?
Are you out of your mind, Vail?
Please!
What is wrong with you?
The thing bit me, Nick!
Okay, okay.
It bit me!
Enough of this! I don't care!
I'm leaving! With or
without you, I'm leaving!
It bit me! Please, Nick!
(CREAKING)
(WIND WHOOSHING)
(AHMANET SPEAKING
ANCIENT LANGUAGE)
JENNY: Nick!
Nick!
Tell Greenway he's
gonna send a team
to get this thing
out of here,
or he's gonna have to explain
why he left me behind.
Do it!
Okay.
JENNY: Guidelines are manned!
PILOT: (ON RADIO)
Guideline is steady.
Move more to
your 9 o'clock!
Holding at 30 feet.
JENNY: A little more.
(BOTH CAWING)
(RAVENS SQUAWKING)
(SQUAWKING CONTINUES)
PILOT 1: Three-eight-Sierra-
four-two-seven-niner-point-six-six-nine.
(SHUDDERING)
Go to the MSR, grid two-five-seven-
seven-eight-eight-four.
PILOT 2: Bishop to Echo,
we have visual on a severe sandstorm
heading west at angels 12.
(SOLDIERS SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
Hey!
Wait, wait,
please be careful.
This is 5,000
years old.
Sixty seconds!
In the air! Let's go!
Carefully.
Very, very carefully.
COLONEL GREENWAY:
Get us off the ground now!
Halsey, take a seat!
(INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER)
(GROANS)
(EXHALES)
Need some help?
No.
You're welcome, by the way.
How's that?
Because I saved
your whatever-it-is.
That was safely
hidden for 5,000 years
before you dropped a
Hellfire missile on it.
And you might never have
found it otherwise.
Again, you're welcome.
(SCOFFS)
Do you have any
idea what this is?
The significance of it?
An Egyptian sarcophagus
in a tomb in Mesopotamia.
Why'd you say
15 seconds?
Why'd I what?
You told Greenway
that I could mimic
all the qualities
of human intimacy
for 15 seconds.
I mean, let me tell you,
it was not 15 seconds.
Well, however long it lasted,
it wasn't real.
I never lied to you
about my feelings.
You stole from me.
But I didn't lie.
Do you ever think of
anyone but yourself?
This means something.
Something bigger
than you can imagine.
My life's work.
And you were
going to steal it.
How much do you figure that's
worth on the black market?
(WHEEZING)
This is Dr. Jennifer Halsey
conducting a preliminary analysis
of an Egyptian sarcophagus
discovered in the Nineveh
province, northern Iraq.
The hieroglyphs are
definitely New Kingdom.
It appears that
the wife of King Menehptre
died in childbirth,
leaving a sole
heir to the throne,
a girl
called Ahmanet.
(AHMANET GRUNTS)
(AHMANET EXHALING DEEPLY)
(SPEAKING ANCIENT LANGUAGE)
(GASPS)
COLONEL GREENWAY: Corporal, what in
the living hell are you doing, son?
Vail?
COLONEL GREENWAY:
Corporal Vail?
Damn it.
Corporal Vail, do you hear me
talking to you? I said what...
(GROANS)
(GASPS)
(VAIL HISSING)
Vail, just...
Vail! Whoa, whoa!
Vail!
Oh, my God. Vail!
SOLDIER 1: Drop your weapon!
SOLDIER 2: Put it down!
Drop it now!
Please! No, don't!
Drop it, now!
Put the gun down!
SOLDIER 1: Drop it!
Put down the weapon! Put it down! Back off!
JENNY: Wait, wait.
Stop! Do not shoot!
This is a pressurized
aircraft! Nick.
What...
JENNY: Vail.
(HISSING)
Vail, put the knife down.
Vail. Vail. Vail.
Vail, no. No, no!
NICK: Vail! Vail! Vail!
Vail! Vail!
(HISSING)
Okay, Vail, stop.
Stop! Vail, Vail, Vail!
(PANTING)
I'm sorry.
(RUMBLING)
(ALL GASP)
(ENGINE SPUTTERING)
CO-PILOT: Pan, Pan, Pan!
This is November
four-zero-niner-niner,
United States C-130 Hercules
inbound 6 miles off the coast...
What's happening?
Take your seat and strap in.
...of Dover, England.
England?
Ma'am, I don't
know what's happening.
Take a seat!
(JENNY GASPS)
CO-PILOT: We lost thrust
in both engines.
No radar contact.
Dropping to 12,000,
280 on the heading.
What the hell is that?
Go, go, go!
(PILOTS SCREAMING)
(JENNY GRUNTS)
(SOLDIERS YELPING)
Parachute!
I don't know
how to do this!
Jenny, Jenny, you can do this.
You can do this.
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(JENNY SCREAMING)
(BOTH STRAINING)
(JENNY YELPING)
Give me your hand!
(SOLDIER SCREAMING)
(BOTH SCREAMING)
(JENNY SCREAMING)
(SCREAMING)
(SCREAM ECHOING)
HELEN: It's an awful thing
to have to ask, I know.
DR. WHEMPLE:
It's most irregular.
Noted, Doctor.
Thank you.
We'll let Miss
Halsey decide.
Miss Halsey?
Miss Halsey, do you
think you're up to it?
I'm sorry, what?
We need your help
identifying the bodies.
(PANTING)
Whoa!
Vail!
VAIL: Hey, buddy.
You scared
the shit out of me.
We need to talk, Nick.
What's...
What's happening?
You know
what's happening.
Am I dead?
Dead?
No, but you're
gonna wish you were.
Right this way,
please.
Oh, my God! Nick.
HELEN: Oh!
Jen... Oh!
What's happening?
Where am I?
Who's in charge here?
DR. WHEMPLE: Uh...
MR. BROOKE: (ON RADIO)
Base, this is Search Team One.
Looks like
the trail of wreckage
spread across two, two and a
half miles through the forest.
Coming up on
Aylesford Pier now.
Stand by.
Pier's a wreck.
Looks like part of the wing.
A turbine.
Miles away from
the primary crash site. Over.
FEMALE DISPATCHER:
Copy, Search Team One.
Message received.
One body found, no obvious
signs of life. Stand by.
Casualty confirmed,
deceased.
Request attendance
of ambulance personnel. Over.
FEMALE DISPATCHER:
Copy, Search Team One.
Ambulance personnel en route.
Over.
MR. BROOKE: We got aircraft debris scattered
across the north side of the banks,
still alight, but no immediate
danger or threat. Over.
(WATER TRICKLING)
(RAVENS SCREECHING)
(GASPING)
(RAVENS SQUAWKING)
What?
What the hell?
Hey! You better come and look at...
(GROANS)
Allen?
You all right?
Allen!
(HISSING)
Jesus! (GROANING)
(RAVENS SQUAWKING)
(MUFFLED SCREAMING)
(HISSES)
(GROANING)
(AHMANET SPEAKING
ANCIENT LANGUAGE)
(BOTH SNARLING)
FEMALE REPORTER: (ON TV)
A United States military plane
crash-landed in Surrey
this evening,
just missing Waverley Abbey.
How did you get
out of that plane?
There's not a single
scratch on your body.
Yeah.
(CHUCKLES)
Thank you.
For what?
You saved my life.
You'd have done
the same for me.
VAIL: Nick.
Nick.
JENNY: Listen, Nick.
I... (SIGHS)
I think you
should know something.
You know I work with
a group of archeologists.
Yeah.
Well,
we've developed
this theory
that an Egyptian princess had been
erased from the history books
deliberately.
We've been searching for something
called the Dagger of Set.
A ceremonial knife with a
large jewel at the hilt.
Set is the Egyptian
god of death.
And legend has it that the
dagger and the stone, together,
had the power to
give Set physical form.
I'm convinced it was
hidden here in Europe.
Stolen by Crusaders
centuries ago.
I found reference to it in a manuscript
written by a Crusader knight
that suggested the dagger was broken apart.
(AHMANET SCREAMING)
That the stone was buried with this
knight somewhere here in England.
A massive Crusader tomb was
recently discovered under London.
We believe that the stone
is in there somewhere.
That tomb is what
led us to Ahmanet.
I think she's the
princess in the legend.
The hieroglyphs said
she murdered her father.
Murdered?
Along with his child.
She made some sort of pact
with the god of death.
And then, when I
saw those birds,
and that sandstorm... You know, I mean...
Something is happening.
You're alive and
I don't know how.
(MOUTHING)
You. Me. Go.
I'm sorry, Nick. I think
we've angered the gods.
Would you excuse me?
I'll be right back.
MAN: (ON PHONE)
Identify, please.
This is Jenny. Get me Henry.
Jennifer.
This is a far more significant
problem than we had ever imagined.
Something is happening, Henry.
I'm worried about him.
Bring your soldier to London.
Do not discuss
anything further with him.
Understand?
(SIGHS)
What are you doing here?
Jenny looks good.
Okay, this isn't happening.
I mean, really great.
Okay, really. Stop.
You know, I always thought
I had a chance with her.
What?
How do you squander that?
There was mercury in that tomb.
The vapors were toxic.
I mean,
how do you mess that up?
It's just in my head,
it's in my head.
No, it's not.
You shot me.
Wait, wait. Wait,
wait, wait. You... You...
You
stabbed Greenway.
I saved you...
You murdered him.
...and you shot me.
You tried to kill me.
You even went after Jenny.
You shot me. Three times.
Yes.
Three times, Nick.
Okay, the third
one was unnecessary.
You freaked me out,
I panicked.
I'm sorry. Okay?
Not okay.
Look at me. Look at my face.
I'm cursed, Nick.
And you're cursed.
And there's only
one way to break it.
You are going to do
exactly what she wants,
or this is gonna get a lot
worse for both of us.
What do you mean, I'm cursed?
(WOMEN CHATTERING INDISTINCTLY)
I'm sorry.
Just give me a minute.
Thank you.
You walked into the chicks'
bathroom, by the way.
WOMAN: Go to your
own sodding loo!
VAIL: Yeah, it's a ladies' room.
WOMAN: We just want to pee!
What do you mean,
I'm cursed? (KNOCK ON DOOR)
How do you think you
survived the crash?
Setepa-i.
WOMAN: Bloody Yanks. Unbelievable.
WOMAN 2: Yeah!
VAIL: You know
what it means.
She's got plans
for you, Nick.
Plans?
You can't run.
You can't escape.
(SHUDDERS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(SQUEAKING)
(RATS SQUEAKING)
(GRUNTS)
(SNARLING)
(SQUEAKING)
(YELPING)
Help me!
Setepa-i!
(SCREAMING)
(HORN HONKING)
(BRAKES SCREECHING)
(SCREAMS)
DRIVER: Out of the road, wanker!
Nick! What the hell
are you doing?
Okay, you were right.
We've angered the gods.
Wait, what?
I saw her.
The chick in the box.
Ahmanet?
That one.
Nick...
He said I'm cursed.
Who said?
Vail.
Vail?
The coffin we found.
Sarcophagus.
Whatever.
There was writing on it.
Hieroglyphics.
Jenny, respectfully,
I'm not interested
in archeological
jargon right now.
The writing on the box that
we took out of the hole.
Yes, sorry.
There was something about a
curse on there, wasn't there?
Nick, you've had
a concussion.
Yes.
Toxic exposure.
How does that
explain that I know
that Setepa-i
means "my chosen"?
That's ancient Egyptian.
Ancient Egyptian.
How do I know that?
You've been in the
Middle East for years.
What? No! You heard
it, you forgot it.
Why are you backing off from this?
I'm telling you.
She is real.
JENNY: Nick.
Nick, what is it?
I think you're right.
I... (LAUGHS)
I think this is
all in my head.
We should find the box,
look inside,
and when I see a 3,000-year-old
prune in there...
Nick.
...no more curse.
You don't need a sarcophagus,
you need a doctor.
I know someone.
A specialist in London.
Don't tell me that you
don't wanna see it, too.
Your life's work.
Come on, Jenny.
I think I know
where it is.
PILOT: (ON RADIO) Charlie 8-1.
Charlie 8-1 to Base.
We are at the main crash site,
400 meters north of Waverley Abbey.
Firefighters are containing the
wreckage, but the site is still hot.
(MUMMIES GROANING)
(CHOKING)
(GASPING)
(COWS MOOING)
(HELICOPTER HOVERING)
JENNY: Nick.
Nick! Where are
you going?
The crash site is up that way.
Where are you going?
No. We're in
the right place.
Nick.
Nick!
I don't know what
we're doing here.
This isn't
the right place.
Yes, it is.
No, it isn't.
The main crash site is up that
way, and so is my artifact.
And that's where
we're going.
(WHISPERING VOICES)
(CREAKING)
Setepa-i.
What the hell?
How did I...
Jenny?
Okay.
(YELPS)
Nick?
(GRUNTS)
(SNARLING)
(GASPS)
(SCREECHING)
(EXHALES)
Ah...
(GASPS) Okay.
Okay.
(NICK LAUGHING)
(MOANING)
No, seriously...
(SPEAKING ANCIENT LANGUAGE)
What?
NICK: I'm sorry, what?
(CONTINUES SPEAKING
ANCIENT LANGUAGE)
Oh, God.
No, no, no.
(SPEAKING ANCIENT LANGUAGE)
No, please.
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
(WHIMPERS)
Jenny!
(SOFTLY) Yeah?
Run! Run!
(MUMMY SNARLING)
(GROANING)
(GRUNTS)
(GRUNTING)
(GROANING)
Ugh! (GRUNTING)
(CHOKING)
(GROANING)
JENNY: Come on!
Come on!
Nick! Nick!
Nick!
Hey! Hey!
No, no, no! Hey!
(ENGINE STARTS)
Hey! Nick! Stop!
Nick!
Were you just gonna
leave me?
You saw that, right?
You were gonna leave me!
You saw it, right?
I can't unsee it!
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Where are we going?
Away from here. There's
a highway up ahead.
How do you know?
I know.
Oh, my God. Do you
realize what this is?
NICK: It's the Dagger of Set.
She was gonna drive that
thing right through me.
The stone,
it is missing.
Yeah, that seemed to
really piss her off.
It's real.
NICK: How was it in a statue?
That statue was
a reliquary.
Crusaders would use them
to hide holy relics.
But she knew
it was there.
What... You're saying that she
brought the plane down there?
On purpose?
That's why she wanted you
to come to the church.
She wanted me to
go to the church?
I told you that I wanted
to go to the church.
I told you,
I said I wanted to see...
I wanted to see her corpse.
See her corpse.
Nick, she's in
your head.
What are you talking about?
That is ridiculous. Because I...
(BRAKES SCREECHING)
(JENNY GASPING)
NICK: I drove
right back to her.
Oh, my God,
she's in my head.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Go, go, go!
(MUMMY SNARLING)
(GRUNTING)
Get it off me!
Son of a bitch!
(GRUNTING)
(SNARLING)
(JENNY SCREAMS)
(NICK YELPING)
That's my face! That's my face!
That's my face!
Sorry!
(GRUNTS)
(JENNY YELPING)
Nick!
(SNARLING)
(SCREAMS)
(BOTH SCREAMING)
Nick!
(AMBULANCE CRASHING)
(PANTING)
Jenny?
(JENNY GRUNTING)
(SEAT BELT CLICKS)
Jenny. Jenny.
Nick! Nick!
NICK: Okay.
All right.
Get her, Nick!
Get her! Get her!
Kick her ass!
(NICK YELPS)
(BRANCHES SNAPPING)
(GROANS)
(GASPS)
AGENT 1:
Route is clear. Come on!
(GROANS)
(AHMANET SCREAMING)
AGENT 2: That's it, pull her back tight!
(AHMANET CONTINUES SCREAMING)
AGENT 3: Delta Team, move!
AGENT 1: Bring target down!
Clear!
Who are you...
Where are you taking me?
What's happening?
(DOOR BUZZING)
(BEEPING)
(DOOR LOCKING)
Stay.
HENRY:
Make yourself comfortable.
Who the hell are you?
Who am I?
(CHUCKLING)
The more relevant question,
Mr. Morton,
is who exactly are you?
In theory,
I know all about you.
Army reconnaissance,
decorated soldier,
and page after page indicating a
deep and troubling moral turpitude.
But, you see,
this file contains
nothing of any
real value to me.
That's why I wanted to
see you face-to-face.
Who are you?
I'm a doctor.
A doctor.
Chemical pathology,
neurosurgery.
Fellow of the Royal Society.
I'm also a lawyer.
My name is Jekyll.
Dr. Henry Jekyll.
(SIGHS)
There you are.
These days,
I specialize in immunology, perhaps.
(CHUCKLES)
Infectious disease, perhaps.
I would like, if I may,
Mr. Morton,
to tell you a story.
A story about
a patient of mine.
A man of promise.
A man who believed
he was beyond reproach
until he got ill.
The disease manifested itself
in subtle ways, at first.
And then it grew
into an overwhelming desire,
an unquenchable thirst...
(GRUNTS)
(IN COCKNEY ACCENT)
...for chaos.
For the suffering of others.
(GROANING SOFTLY)
He was quite fortunate.
He himself
was a physician.
And if evil were a pathogen,
he reasoned,
then there must
surely be a cure.
I would like, if I may,
Mr. Morton,
to show you something.
(AHMANET SHIVERING)
Welcome to Prodigium,
Mr. Morton.
From the Latin,
monstrum vel prodigium.
"A warning of monsters."
Forgive the state of things.
We had very little time
to prepare for our guest
and only the information
Jennifer provided to go on.
In truth,
she works for us.
It's not an exact science,
this business.
What?
And the business being?
Evil, Mr. Morton.
Recognize, contain,
examine, destroy.
She is by far the most ancient
we've ever encountered.
What are you doing to her?
HENRY: Embalming her
with mercury.
At minus 38 degrees
the mercury in her veins
will solidify,
and she should be
safe for dissection then.
Dissection?
You said that we'd study her.
Yes, by dissection.
But she's a living witness to a
history that we barely know.
HENRY:
She's a threat, Jennifer.
Hold on, hold on.
So, where does that leave me?
Cursed, Mr. Morton.
This is not some
common cold you have.
Some chicken soup and a good night's
sleep will not make it go away.
You have been selected as the
vessel for the ultimate evil.
And we are the only ones
who can rectify that.
(AHMANET SPEAKING
ANCIENT LANGUAGE)
(SPEAKING ANCIENT LANGUAGE)
No.
AHMANET: (IN ENGLISH)
I was going to give him
eternal life.
Make him a living god.
You murdered your father.
AHMANET:
I loved my father
with all my heart.
I only wanted
his love in return.
You killed his wife.
Their child.
(BABY CRYING)
(BLADE SWISHING)
They were different times.
The Day of Awakening
will soon be upon us.
You will become Set.
The world will
fall to your desire.
You will have power
of life over death.
And you will have me.
I will be your queen.
Just give in.
JENNY: Nick.
Nick. Wake up.
Wake up.
They will kill you, just as they
killed my chosen before you.
It burns.
What?
It burns! (SCREAMING)
Stop it!
Stop it! Stop!
Stop!
(GROANING)
Stop it!
Stop!
Fascinating.
What was I
supposed to tell you?
Would you even
have believed me
if I'd said this
place was real?
When Henry came to me,
I took the job because
we had a common interest.
So, you're using
each other.
Now she's using you.
(AHMANET SHIVERING)
Look.
Despite what
you might think,
despite my...
My better judgment,
I care about you.
Somewhere in there,
fighting to get out,
is a good man.
You don't know that.
I do.
How?
You saved my life
on that plane.
You gave me the only parachute
without hesitation.
I thought
there was another one.
HENRY: Mr. Morton.
Drink?
(CAMERA CLICKING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
I think
I've found something.
(GRUNTS)
(GASPS)
(CAMERA CLICKING)
(JENNY SPEAKING
ANCIENT LANGUAGE)
(IN ENGLISH) The "old" gods?
Your language is simple.
What you truly wish
to know is
what lies beyond
the veil of death.
To know what I have seen?
Yes.
And you will,
when I
kill you.
They have found the stone.
You brought my chosen here.
What do you think
they will do with him now?
Huh.
Welcome to a new world
of gods and monsters.
Evil has many names,
Mr. Morton. Mmm.
Take Set, for example.
Known to Egyptians
as the god of death.
Mmm. In the Old Testament,
Satan, Lucifer.
The devil.
Quite so.
Yeah. Bad... Badness.
Got it.
So, you see,
evil is the shadow
that exists just outside our world...
Uh-huh.
...continuously searching
for a way to come in.
For a way to
become flesh and blood.
(CHANTING IN ANCIENT LANGUAGE)
(CLEARS THROAT)
Either we wait
for that day to arrive,
or we can fight it
on our own terms.
Which brings me to you.
Me? Yeah, great.
Yes, Doc.
You said you could cure me of this curse.
Get rid of it.
So, let's do it, Doc.
What's your plan?
Mr. Morton,
these things are complex.
Yeah. I bet, I bet.
When one is dealing with
the salvation of humanity,
certain sacrifices
must be made.
MALIK: Excuse me, sir.
They found it.
Found what?
JENNY: Henry.
Are you planning
on killing him?
NICK: Kill?
Jennifer...
Kill who?
Mr. Morton, here,
essentially killed himself
when he severed
the barrier chain
that had kept Ahmanet's power
imprisoned for 5,000 years.
(CONTINUES CHANTING)
He was chosen
as her ideal candidate.
A thief, physically capable,
compulsively devious,
and utterly devoid of soul.
What?
That's insane.
You want to put the stone in the
dagger and stab him with it?
Well, the dagger will allow
Set to enter his body,
and then, we obliterate it.
Wait, wait, wait.
You wanna stab me
with that thing?
Intentionally?
Precisely what the Egyptians
should have done.
(CONTINUES CHANTING)
HENRY: You see, they interrupted
a ritual in process,
and that is a mistake
we cannot...
(HENRY CLEARS THROAT)
...afford to repeat.
What?
That's the plan?
Henry,
you can't possibly do this.
(HENRY GRUNTS)
That's your plan?
HENRY: The dominoes
are already falling.
We haven't much time.
Unfortunately,
it is a risk we must take.
That's really your plan?
You heard Ahmanet.
Your curse cannot be broken.
I am truly sorry, Mr. Morton.
No matter what I do,
you are going to die.
Yes, evil is a disease.
A pestilent,
pustulant infection
burrowing its way
into our souls.
The world needs a cure.
You can be that cure.
Stop.
A sacrifice for the greater good!
Just stop.
I'm not interested
in that at all.
(GROANING)
Okay.
Don't!
Give me the injector.
Okay, we're just
gonna take a minute,
and we're all gonna
come up with a new plan.
We have to go. You don't
know what you're doing.
Really? I know
exactly what I'm doing.
(GROWLING)
(IN COCKNEY ACCENT)
Oh, my dear Henry Jekyll,
if ever I've seen Satan's
signature upon a face,
it is on that of
your new friend.
(GROANING)
Okay, hey, hey, hey!
Take it!
MALIK: Now!
Run, Mr. Morton.
What?
Run! (GROANING)
Nick! Open the door!
You don't want that.
Stop! Jenny!
Stop!
(GROWLING)
(CHUCKLES)
(SCANNER ALARM BEEPING)
They won't
let me out, Nicholas.
They never do.
(GROANS)
(CHUCKLING)
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
What's happening?
Did you just shut
down the mercury?
Pete?
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
You are a younger man,
but you'd best learn to be
wary of a man like me.
(YELLS)
(CART CLATTERING)
(SNARLS)
(CHUCKLING EVILLY)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
It's not me that wants
to kill you, it's Henry.
I have something more
collaborative in mind. (GROANS)
Oh, nice.
(SNARLS)
(YELPING)
(TECHNICIANS CLAMORING)
(GROWLING)
(NICK GRUNTS)
I'm offering
you a partnership.
You, Evil Incarnate.
Me, your good friend,
Eddie Hyde.
Think about it.
MALIK: Jenny!
HYDE: Oh, come on.
(HYDE LAUGHS)
(COUGHING)
(GROANS)
Jenny, stop!
(HYDE YELLING)
Come on, son.
Think about it.
Mayhem, chaos, destruction.
The ladies will love us.
Come here.
(BONE CRACKING)
(SCREAMING)
I do enjoy
the countenance of pain.
(HYDE LAUGHING EVILLY)
(GROANING)
(IN NORMAL ACCENT)
Well done, Mr. Morton. Well done.
(BOTH PANTING)
(HENRY GROANS)
(CONTINUES PANTING)
Come on. We have to
destroy the stone.
What?
No stone, no ritual.
No ritual...
No curse.
Yes.
I know where it is.
(PANICKED SCREAMING)
(GASPS)
Nick! Nick!
(SCREAMING)
(GRUNTING)
(MUFFLED SCREAMING)
(INHALES DEEPLY)
Just wait, wait.
Which way out?
I don't know.
(AHMANET CHANTING
IN ANCIENT LANGUAGE)
(CHANTING ECHOING)
(YELLING)
(PANICKED SCREAMING)
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Hello?
She's out! She has the dagger.
We think she's coming to you.
So are we.
Lock your doors
and secure that stone.
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
(JENNY SCREAMING)
(SCREECHING)
(ROARING)
VAIL: Nick! Nick!
Let's go!
I know where the stone is!
(JENNY YELPING)
(GRUNTING)
(GASPS)
(CHUCKLING)
Wow, that was intense!
Okay, follow me.
AGENT: (ON RADIO) We're heading
to the Crusader burial chamber.
We'll make our entry through the
northwest train tunnels. Over.
This is the moment, Nick.
This is the moment!
Yeah, you're damn right.
I'm gonna take you to that stone,
deliver you to Ahmanet,
then my work here is done.
What?
Nick?
Jenny?
VAIL: Hey, buddy.
Ahmanet is never
going to let her live.
You can't save her.
(AHMANET SPEAKING
ANCIENT LANGUAGE)
(RUMBLING)
TECHNICIAN: Oh, no! Move!
(ALL GASP)
(MUMMIES SNARLING)
(PANICKED SCREAMING)
(SCREECHING)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING ON RADIO)
(BOTH SCREAMING)
Nick?
(NICK GRUNTING)
(JENNY GRUNTING)
(BOTH PANTING)
(SCREECHING)
(ROARS)
(SCREAMS)
(GRUNTING)
You shouldn't be here.
I followed you!
(MUMMIES SNARLING)
NICK: Go, go, go!
(BOTH GASP)
(ALL SNARLING)
(EXHALES)
(SNARLING)
(NICK GRUNTS)
(BOTH GASPING)
Are you okay? Are you okay?
Where are we?
I don't know.
Are you okay?
I'm scared.
Just look at me.
We're gonna figure this out.
Just...
You just stay with me, please.
We're gonna figure this out.
Okay? You just stay with me.
Just stay with me.
We'll figure this out.
Okay, it's gonna be okay...
(NICK GASPS)
Ah! No! Jenny!
(MUFFLED SCREAMING)
(COUGHING)
(GASPS)
(GRUNTS)
Jenny! No! No!
Don't!
Let go! (YELLING)
Jenny!
(GRUNTING)
Jenny! Jenny!
No! (COUGHING)
(PANTING)
AHMANET:
Don't blame yourself.
She was always doomed.
There are worse fates
than death.
Come to me.
(GROANS)
It hurts.
I know.
Let me take the pain away.
(GROANING)
Give in to me.
Oh. Uh...
(SCREAMS)
(GROANING)
(CHOKING)
Give in.
When it's over,
you will thank me.
I promise.
I'm sorry.
We're just
never gonna happen.
And it's not me.
It's you.
(GROANS)
Thief.
(GRUNTS)
(GASPS)
Wait!
Destroy the stone
and all is lost.
You will be a living god.
You will have power
of life over death.
Give it to me,
my chosen.
my love.
(GRUNTS)
(GASPS)
(GROANING)
(EXHALES)
(BREATHING SHAKILY)
(SPEAKING ANCIENT LANGUAGE)
Setepa-i.
(AHMANET SIGHS LONGINGLY)
Somewhere in there,
I know you're a good man.
HENRY: The world needs a cure.
You can be that cure.
A sacrifice for
the greater good!
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(YELLS)
(YELLS DEFIANTLY)
(MUFFLED SCREAMING)
(GASPS)
(PANTING)
(GROANS)
Jenny.
Wake up, wake up.
Wake up. Wake up.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, Jenny.
Jenny.
Jenny, please, wake up.
I'm sorry.
I don't know what I'm doing.
Just, please, wake up.
(GROANING)
Jenny.
Wake up, please.
(CONTINUES GROANING)
Just...
(GROANING DEMONICALLY)
Jenny, please, just wake up!
(SCREAMING)
(COUGHING)
(SHIVERING) Nick? Nick.
Nick. Nick.
Nick...
(RUSTLING)
(GASPS)
Nick.
Nick. Nick?
NICK: Stop!
(GASPS)
Stop. Please.
I don't know what I am.
I don't want to
hurt you, Jenny.
You're alive.
I'm so glad you're alive.
Oh, Nick.
You did this for me?
Yes.
I have made so many,
many mistakes.
But not this time.
Not you.
I don't want to hurt you.
I never wanted to hurt you.
You won't.
Didn't see this coming,
did we?
(SNARLS)
(GASPS)
They're coming for me.
I wish we had more time.
I'll find you.
Goodbye, Jenny.
(MEN SHOUTING)
JENNY: You were wrong
about Nick.
He gave his life to save me.
To bring me back.
Yes, Jennifer.
He found his redemption,
but at great cost.
He is a monster now.
JENNY:
He is also still a man.
A good man.
HENRY: Perhaps.
Yet he has only begun
to discover his power.
And we cannot know
which side will win out.
Between darkness and light,
good or evil.
VAIL: Hey, Nick? Nick.
I'm really glad to be here.
I mean,
thank you for bringing me
back to life
and everything, Nick.
But what are we
even doing here?
Where are we going?
NICK: Come on, my friend.
Where's your
sense of adventure?
Oh, no.
HENRY: Whatever human
part of him remains
will search the world over
for a way to break the curse.
To find a cure.
Yet evil never rests.
And it will call to him
always.
JENNY: Henry, he used
his power to stop Ahmanet.
You know more than anyone
he could be our greatest ally.
HENRY: Perhaps.
Sometimes, it does take a
monster to fight a monster.