Merry.
No!
With a sigh
You turn away
With a deepening heart
No more words to say
You will find
That the world has changed
Forever
And the trees are now
Turning from green to gold
And the sun is now fading
I wish I could hold you
Closer
Merry!
Merry.
Merry, it's me.
It's Pippin.
I knew you'd find me.
Yes.
Are you going to leave me?
No, Merry.
I'm going to look after you.
Hands off!
That shiny shirt, that's mine.
It's going to the Great Eye,
along with everything else.
I don't take orders from
stinking Morgul-rats!
You touch it, and I'll stick
this blade in your gut.
The scum tried to knife me.
Kill him!
That's for Frodo!
And for the Shire!
And that's for my old Gaffer!
Stop your squealing, you dunghill rat.
I'm gonna bleed you like a stuck pig.
Not if I stick you first.
Sam!
Oh, Sam, I'm so sorry.
Sorry for everything.
-Let's get you out of here.
-It's too late. It's over.
They've taken it. Sam...
...they took the Ring.
Begging your pardon, but they haven't.
I thought I'd lost you.
So I took it.
Only for safekeeping.
Give it to me.
Give me the Ring, Sam.
Sam.
Give me the Ring.
You must understand.
The Ring is my burden.
It will destroy you, Sam.
Come on, Mr. Frodo.
We best find you some clothes.
You can't go walking through Mordor
in naught but your skin.
We did it, Mr. Frodo.
We made it to Mordor.
There are so many of them.
We'll never get through unseen.
It's him, the Eye.
We have to go in there, Mr. Frodo.
There's nothing for it.
Come on. Let's just make it
down the hill for starters.
Frodo has passed beyond my sight.
The darkness is deepening.
If Sauron had the Ring,
we would know it.
It's only a matter of time.
He has suffered a defeat, yes...
...but behind the walls of Mordor,
our enemy is regrouping.
Let him stay there.
Let him rot! Why should we care?
Because 10,000 Orcs now stand
between Frodo and Mount Doom.
I've sent him to his death.
No.
There is still hope for Frodo.
He needs time and safe passage
across the plains of Gorgoroth.
-We can give him that.
-How?
Draw out Sauron's armies.
Empty his lands.
Then we gather our full strength
and march on the Black Gate.
We cannot achieve victory
through strength of arms.
Not for ourselves.
But we can give Frodo his chance
if we keep Sauron's Eye fixed upon us.
Keep him blind to all else that moves.
A diversion.
Certainty of death...
...small chance of success...
...what are we waiting for?
Sauron will suspect a trap.
He will not take the bait.
Oh, I think he will.
Long have you hunted me.
Long have I eluded you.
No more.
Behold the Sword of Elendil.
The city has fallen silent.
There is no warmth left in the sun.
It grows so cold.
It's just the damp
of the first spring rain.
I do not believe this darkness
will endure.
Look, the Orcs...
...they're moving off.
You see, Mr. Frodo...
...some luck at last.
Move it, you slugs!
Come on! Faster!
Come along, you scum....
I'll whip you down to the bone, you....
Come on!
What have I told you?!
Get up!
Come on, you slugs!
You two are going straight
to the front line!
Now, move it! Go on!
Fall in! Move it!
To the Gate, you slugs!
Now, move it!
Don't you know we're at war?
Company, halt!
Inspection!
Sam, help me.
Mr. Frodo!
Stand up, Mr. Frodo.
Stand up!
It's so heavy.
Oh, no.
What do I do?
What do we do?
-Hit me.
-What?
Hit me, Sam. Start fighting.
Get off of me!
Nobody pushes me, you filthy maggot.
Break it up! Break it up!
Oi! I'll have your guts if you don't
shut this rabble down!
Go, Sam. Now!
Move along, scum!
Back in the line!
You maggots!
Get back into the line,
you slugs!
Dig it, you slugs. Move it.
Move it!
I can't....
I can't manage the Ring, Sam.
It's.... It's....
It's such a weight to carry.
It....
Such a weight.
We're going that way.
Straight as we can.
There's no point carrying anything
we're not sure to need.
Mr. Frodo.
Look.
There is light...
...and beauty up there...
...that no shadow can touch.
Take mine.
There's a few drops left.
There will be none left
for the return journey.
I don't think there will be
a return journey, Mr. Frodo.
Frodo, get down!
Hide!
Frodo!
Where are they?
Let the Lord of the Black Land come forth!
Let justice be done upon him!
My master, Sauron the Great,
bids thee welcome.
Is there any in this rout
with authority to treat with me?
We do not come to treat with Sauron...
...faithless and accursed.
Tell your master this:
The armies of Mordor must disband.
He is to depart these lands,
never to return.
Old Greybeard.
I have a token I was bidden
to show thee.
Frodo.
-Silence.
-No!
Silence!
The Halfling was dear to thee, I see.
Know that he suffered greatly
at the hands of his host.
Who would've thought one so small
could endure so much pain?
And he did, Gandalf.
He did.
And who is this?
Isildur's heir?
It takes more to make a king
than a broken Elvish blade.
I guess that concludes negotiations.
I do not believe it.
I will not.
Pull back.
Pull back!
It's gone, Mr. Frodo.
The light's passed on,
away towards the north.
Something's drawn its gaze.
Hold your ground! Hold your ground.
Sons of Gondor, of Rohan, my brothers!
I see in your eyes...
...the same fear that would take
the heart of me.
A day may come
when the courage of Men fails...
...when we forsake our friends
and break all bonds of fellowship.
But it is not this day.
An hour of wolves
and shattered shields...
...when the age of Men
comes crashing down.
But it is not this day.
This day we fight!
By all that you hold dear
on this good earth...
... I bid you stand, Men of the West!
Never thought I'd die fighting
side by side with an Elf.
What about side by side with a friend?
Aye.
I could do that.
Do you remember the Shire,
Mr. Frodo?
It'll be spring soon.
And the orchards will be in blossom.
And the birds will be nesting
in the hazel thicket.
And they'll be sowing
the summer barley in the lower fields...
...and eating the first
of the strawberries with cream.
Do you remember
the taste of strawberries?
No, Sam.
I can't recall the taste of food...
...nor the sound of water...
...nor the touch of grass.
I'm...
...naked in the dark.
There's-- There's nothing.
No veil between me
and the wheel of fire.
I can see him...
...with my waking eyes.
Then let us be rid of it...
...once and for all.
Come on, Mr. Frodo.
I can't carry it for you...
...but I can carry you.
Come on!
Aragorn.
Elessar.
For Frodo.
Look, Mr. Frodo.
A doorway.
We're almost there.
Clever Hobbits to climb so high!
Mustn't go that way.
Mustn't hurt the precious.
You swore!
You swore on the precious!
Sméagol promised!
Sméagol lied.
Frodo!
Eagles.
The eagles are coming!
Frodo!
I'm here, Sam.
Destroy it!
Go on! Now!
Throw it in the fire!
What are you waiting for?
Just let it go!
The Ring is mine.
No.
No!
Yes!
Precious! Precious!
Give me your hand!
Take my hand!
No!
Don't you let go.
Don't let go.
Reach!
Frodo!
It's gone.
It's done.
Yes, Mr. Frodo.
It's over now.
I can see the Shire.
The Brandywine River.
Bag End.
Gandalf's fireworks.
The lights in the Party Tree.
Rosie Cotton dancing.
She had ribbons in her hair.
If ever I was to marry someone...
...it would've been her.
It would've been her.
I'm glad to be with you,
Samwise Gamgee...
...here at the end of all things.
Gandalf?
Frodo!
Gimli!
Now come the days of the king.
May they be blessed.
This day does not belong to one man...
...but to all.
Let us together rebuild this world...
...that we may share
in the days of peace.
My friends...
...you bow to no one.
And thus it was.
A Fourth Age of Middle-earth began.
And the Fellowship of the Ring...
...though eternally bound
by friendship and love...
...was ended.
Thirteen months to the day since Gandalf
sent us on our long journey...
...we found ourselves
looklng upon a familiar sight.
We were home.
Hi.
Hey, watch the pumpkin.
More of the same, Rosie.
Good night, lads.
How do you pick up the threads
of an old life?
How do you go on...
...when in your heart
you begin to understand...
...there is no going back?
There are some things
that time cannot mend...
...some hurts that go too deep...
...that have taken hold.
There and back again...
a hobbit's tale, by Bilbo Baggins
Mr. Frodo?
What is it?
It's been four years to the day
since Weathertop, Sam.
It's never really healed.
"There and Back Again. A Hobbit's Tale
by Bilbo Baggins.
And The Lord of the Rings
by Frodo Baggins."
You finished it.
Not quite.
There's room for a little more.
Bilbo once told me his part
In this tale would end...
...that each of us must come and go
In the telling.
Bilbo's story was now over.
There would be no more journeys
for him...
...save one.
Tell me again, lad,
where are we going?
To the harbour, Bilbo.
The Elves have accorded you
a special honour...
...a place on the last ship
to leave Middle-earth.
Frodo...
...any chance of seeing
that old Ring of mine again?
The one I gave you.
I'm sorry, Uncle.
I'm afraid I lost it.
Oh.
Pity.
I should like to have held it
one last time.
Well, here's a sight
I have never seen before.
The power of the Three Rings is ended.
The time has come...
...for the dominion of Men.
The sea calls us home.
I think I'm...
...quite ready
for another adventure.
Farewell...
...my brave Hobbits.
My work is now finished.
Here at last,
on the shores of the sea...
...comes the end of our Fellowship.
I will not say, "Do not weep"...
...for not all tears are an evil.
It is time, Frodo.
What does he mean?
We set out to save the Shire, Sam.
And it has been saved.
But not for me.
You don't mean that.
You can't leave.
The last pages are for you, Sam.
My dear Sam.
You cannot always be torn in two.
You will have to be one and whole
for many years.
You have so much to enjoy
and to be and to do.
Your part In the story will go on.
Well...
... I'm back.
Lay down
Your sweet and weary head
Night is falling
You have come
To journey's end
Sleep now
And dream
Of the ones who came before
They are calling
From across
The distant shore
Why do you weep?
What are these tears
Upon your face?
Soon you will see
All of your fears
Will pass away
Safe In my arms
You're only sleeping
What can you see
On the horizon?
Why do the white gulls
Call?
Across the sea
A pale moon rises
The ships have come
To carry you home
And all will turn
To silver glass
A light on the water
All souls pass
Hope fades
Into the world of night
Through shadows falling
Out of memory and time
Don't say
We have come now to the end
White shores are calling
You and I will meet again
And you'll be here
In my arms
Just sleeping
What can you see
On the horizon?
Why do the white gulls
Call?
Across the sea
A pale moon rlses
The ships have come
To carry you home
And all will turn
To silver glass
A light on the water
Grey ships pass
Into the West