Here's your coffee, Bernie.
Coffee, Mr. Cook?
If we're going to discuss this,
let's discuss it,
but don't sit there and pout
as if I'd just taken away your tricycle.
I'm not pouting.
I just happen to disagree with you.
But Frank Elgin...
Why not let the doorman read
for the part?
Phil, look at some facts.
We've been in rehearsal for five days.
Our leading man, to put it mildly,
was dreadful.
Now, maybe that was my fault.
Maybe I was the wrong director for him.
At any rate, we let him go yesterday.
As of this morning,
we do not have a replacement.
We open in Boston on the 28th.
We are in trouble.
And I can do without the sarcasm, too.
Cookie, look, all I'm saying is
let me audition him for you.
Phil, after all, there's no harm done
in giving the man a reading.
No. I agree with you.
But when I wanted to read Ray Watson,
that was just a big waste of time.
And he's a much better actor than Elgin.
I know a lot of guys
who can act better than Elgin.
And I know a lot of guys
who can sing better.
But I can't think of anybody
who can do both as well.
- What about Billy Hertz?
- He's stiff, pompous.
Look, Cookie, this isn't
Student Prince or Blossom Time.
The guy who plays this part
has to act while he's singing
and sing while he's acting.
You never saw Lonesome Town.
Elgin played a part exactly like this,
and he was just magnificent in it.
All right, don't take my word for it.
Ask Henry.
He played the piano in the pit
for that show.
- When was that?
- Seven or eight years ago.
He wasn't falling off bar stools then.
I hear he hasn't had a drink
in a long time.
- To a drunk, 10 minutes is a long time.
- I'm not asking you to live with him!
I just want you to listen to him!
All right! Go ahead! Go ahead!
- Go ahead!
- Larry!
Larry?
- As soon as Elgin comes in, I want...
- He's here waiting.
I didn't want to interrupt you
while you were...
Send him in.
Now, Cookie, no cracks, please.
What are you fellows
auditioning out there, owls?
Hello, Frank.
- Bernie Dodd.
- How do you do?
- This is our producer, Mr. Cook.
- How do you do, Mr. Cook?
Hello. How are you?
Paul Ungen
and you know Henry Johnson.
- Hey, Henry.
- Hello, Frank. It's been a long time.
Gee, I told this guy years ago
to stop playing other people's music
and write some of his own.
So, you took my advice?
- How's the family?
- Fine.
Guess that big boy of yours
is in high school by now.
- He's in the Air Force.
- No.
Yes, he is.
Now let's get started.
I've got a luncheon date.
Frank, this is an offbeat kind of show.
It's a dramatization
of The Land Around Us.
- You remember the book?
- Yeah, sure.
Well, the boys have done what I consider
a kind of an exciting musical adaptation.
No numbers exactly.
The music is part of the fabric,
woven in and out.
That's the way to keep the seats
from getting dusty.
Give 'em something different.
Yeah.
Would you mind reading
a couple of scenes for Mr. Cook?
- There's one in the first act.
- Excuse me, Bernie, for interrupting,
but you were speaking
of Lonesome Town a minute ago.
Maybe Frank could do
the pitchman number.
That'd show Phil
everything you want him to see.
- It's all right with me if...
- I don't know if I remember it.
- You sure you do?
- I certainly should.
Eight performances a week
for a year and a half.
Maybe you ought to describe
the number to Mr. Cook.
- Give him a kind of a lead-in.
- Okay.
Well, it wasn't much, really.
It was just a thing where I played
one of those pitchmen.
Sort of a fanciful character,
only instead of selling a patent
medicine or something like that,
I was selling a philosophy.
You know, sort of a sunshine salesman.
And the scene was
a New York street corner,
and I worked under
a lamppost like this, and I had a...
Is it okay if I use this for a minute?
- Use anything you like.
- Thanks.
And now, when I made my entrance,
I was carrying...
Okay, okay, I get it.
Now, let's get on with it.
Right.
I just wanted to say
I was carrying an imaginary valise,
you know,
one of those pitchmen's outfits?
Okay, Henry.
And then a crowd of sourpusses
begin to gather around, you see?
Hurry, hurry, hurry, hurry, hurry
And... That's a little high for me, Henry
Can you get it down a tone?
Hurry, hurry, hurry, hurry, hurry
And do away with
worry, worry, worry, worry
Sometime or other, brother
Everybody gets his back to the wall
History discloses life's no bed of roses
And that's for darn sure
Kings topple and nations fall
Rich man, poor man, Indian chief
How, Chief!
He's a left-handed Indian, this kid
I include you all
Simpletons, noodle-heads
You're off
If you don't take advantage of my cure-all
Now, friends,
I tell you what I'm going to do.
I have here in this little valise here
nostrums, cure-alls, panaceas,
unguents, oils, and the healing waters.
What did you say, son?
You say the valise is empty?
Son, this valise is loaded.
You're just looking at it with your eyes,
and your windows are foggy.
What did you say, friend?
You say you can't see nothing, either?
Well, friend, let me tell you something.
There's no trick in believing
in just what you see.
The trick is in
believing in what you can't see.
You've got to visualize the indiscernible.
For instance...
Here's a moonbeam
that wants to go peeping in
Here's the lilt that the bluebird shares
Here's a tropical night to go sleeping in
Step up and sample my wares
Every item in this valise,
ladies and gentlemen,
belongs to you as well
as it does to me.
Here's the silver moon
from the sky up there
And the emerald meadow outdoors
Oh, yes
For the wealth of treasure
there is to share
It's mine
It's yours
Now, if you live a dream
oh, how precious is
An imagination that soars
It can make this world we're in
Hers and his and mine
And yours
Now, if you want blue skies about
Year in
Year out
All you ever need in the last analysis
Is this
Try a cheerful song and a valentine
And a sense of humor that scores
You're no longer in a spin
It's a great world we're in
And it's mine
It's yours
What's that you say, Officer?
Have I got a license?
Just got the greatest license
in the world, poetic license.
What did you say?
You've been listening to my pitch?
We're going to the station house?
You got a desk sergeant down there
who's a little on the prod,
a little on the muscle,
a little on the cantankerous side?
Here's how we'll handle his case.
With a cheerful song and a valentine
And a sense of humor that scores
You're no longer in a spin
It's a great world you're in
And it's mine
It's yours
And it's hers
And it's his
Share it among your friends.
If you got some of it on you,
tell 'em where you got it.
Thanks, Henry. You always did have
a good beat for a writer, you know that?
Fine, Frank, fine.
You ought to hear it with an orchestra.
It's much... It's good and lousy.
Would you wait outside for a second?
Say, I'm a little in the dark about this.
What's it for, a musical spot?
A small part or what?
It's the lead, Frank.
The whole show is built
around this character.
Well, what do you think?
Didn't it speak for itself?
Bernie, he's probably
been doing that material
at dinner parties for the last 10 years.
Did it prove he's worth risking
over $200,000 on?
Did it prove he can carry a whole show?
Bernie, be sensible.
That guy has been laying in the pickle,
ever since you were a kid.
Someone once took a chance
with an actress named Laurette Taylor
in The Glass Menagerie,
and look what she did.
Bernie, tell me something.
What are you trying to prove?
You've got a good book, good music.
Why can't you be satisfied
with a good, reliable,
adequate, normal, sober actor?
Because he'll give you a good, reliable,
adequate, normal, sober performance.
And that's not what people
pay $6.60 to see.
On the last show, you fought me
every step of the way with Danelli.
And I still think you were wrong.
Instead of taking an actor
and teaching him how to box,
you have to go to Stillman's Gym
and get a punch-drunk fighter
and teach him how to act.
He gave you a great performance,
didn't he?
Yes. He gave us a lot of trouble, too.
He was cracked.
If there was a good fight at the Garden,
he just wouldn't show up
for the performance.
Cookie, I promise you,
with Elgin, you're apt to get something
that happens once in 20 years.
I know it'll be a lot of hard work,
but I'll get it out of him.
You're good, Bernie,
but you're not that good.
That's what people have been saying
to me since I was this high.
So, now you're going to show them.
Every one of them.
Just directing
doesn't satisfy you any longer.
Now, you want to take a corpse
and breathe life into it.
Maybe I'm crazy, but...
Doesn't this worry you guys?
Not if it doesn't worry Bernie.
He's too old for the part.
We'll get a couple of hairpieces.
We'll make him look 10 years younger.
All right, all right, Bernie.
But could we at least look around for
someone else while he's rehearsing?
No. No, once we start with him,
we don't let him go without real cause.
A binge is a real cause,
or if he can't retain lines.
And I want to give him a run-of-the-play
contract, no two-week deal.
Now wait a minute...
Because I need his complete confidence.
We give him a two-weeks clause,
he knows we can let him go at any time.
No, sir.
I'm in for a $40,000 bite already.
But I'll take that loss before
I'll give him a run-of-the-play contract!
Okay, Phil, two weeks.
Agreed with you, Paul?
- Henry?
- Okay with me.
Frank?
Frank Elgin!
Elgin?
He's gone. He left.
- What do you mean he left?
- He left.
Where? Coffee, what?
He just walked out, Bernie. He didn't say.
Try the nearest bar.
Mr. Elgin in?
No, he's not.
You Mrs. Elgin?
I'd like to talk to Frank.
I'm Bernie Dodd.
How do you do?
I don't know when Frank will be back.
- Mind if I wait?
- Well...
I was just going to have some coffee.
Would you like some?
No, thanks.
Frank say when he'd be back?
He didn't say where he was going.
Didn't he tell you he had
an audition with me this morning?
No.
I looked around after it was over,
but he'd gone.
Will he do?
That all depends.
If you're wondering if you can get Frank
for very little money, you can.
Doesn't depend on that.
Does he still drink?
Now, just what did you think
I would answer to that, Mr. Dodd?
- Touché.
- What?
"Touché." In French that means...
Come on, everybody knows
what "touché" means.
You're even younger than I thought.
And you try to look like an old lady,
and you're not.
Shouldn't wear your hair like that.
There are two kinds of women,
those who pay too much attention
to themselves
and those who don't pay enough.
Say, that's quite a pearl of wisdom.
May I quote you?
How long you and Frank been married?
- Ten years.
- Where'd you meet, in a show?
Now, look, Mr. Dodd, don't you think...
I'm just trying to find out
if you were ever an actress.
No, not me, thank you.
I'm just a girl from the country.
The theater and the people in it have
always been a complete mystery to me.
They still are.
Dreiser, Balzac, Montaigne...
- Who reads these books?
- I do.
I'm afraid to ask you if you enjoy them.
You'd bite my head off.
Montaigne's too polite for me.
That doesn't surprise me.
Frank's old recordings?
Some new.
The one on the machine
he did last week.
A man with his talent.
It's degrading.
So is not eating.
Why didn't you wait?
I figured the boat had sailed.
I had a feeling
the producer didn't like me.
Since when does it have to be
in an actor's contract
the producer has to love him?
Well, I can't go to bat
unless I feel everybody's rooting for me.
- Cook thinks you're a drinker.
- No, I don't booze it up on a show.
Not according to Maxwell. I checked.
You worked for him in '46.
After a couple of months,
he had to replace you.
While I was playing in that show, our...
Our son died.
All right, that takes care of that show.
What about this one?
I need an actor who can stay sober
and learn lines.
- Are you that actor or not?
- I don't...
Make up your mind.
Give me a little time.
Cook wasn't the only reason
I left the theater just now.
I wanted to talk it over with my wife.
Gee, I wouldn't think of taking
a part like this
without talking it over
with Georgie first.
All right, talk it over.
I'll be back in 10 minutes.
Mr. Dodd, don't you see?
He's afraid of the responsibility.
But I'm the one that's taking the chance.
The gamble's all on my side.
It's not a question
of being afraid of the responsibility.
It's just that...
Well, the part's the whole show.
You said so yourself.
Gee, you've been rehearsing five days,
and you're opening in Boston the 28th.
I don't think I could
learn the lines in that time.
You need a Walter Huston
or somebody like that.
It's bad enough to go
to Hollywood to cast.
Now, you suggest I go to heaven.
You can do it, Frank. I know you can.
Why are you so sure?
Because when I first saw him, I was
a hatcheck boy at the Shubert Theatre.
You, Lunt and Jolson,
you were my heroes.
I know everything you've done.
Naturally, Mr. Dodd, you exaggerate
the sentiment to make your point.
Are you for him or against him?
I'm his wife.
All I want is complete honesty
from both of you.
Flattery is cheap, Mr. Dodd.
How about a little costly truth?
All right.
I'm not blind to Frank's condition.
One look at this room tells me
what he is.
And I'm not one of
those nice, friendly people
who slaps you on the back, buys you
a drink and that's as far as it goes.
If you take this job, Frank,
I won't leave you on a limb.
We'll work together and worry together.
But if you do me dirt, just once, no pity.
Not a drop of pity.
No pity, I like that.
Now, at least he knows what to expect.
What kind of a contract do you offer?
- Honey...
- Standard two-week contract.
- Not run-of-the-play?
- No.
Doesn't that mean you could let Frank
out anytime with two weeks' notice?
- That's exactly what it means.
- You just said he needed confidence.
He won't have it with a two-week clause
over his head. Would you?
I have nothing in my mind
except for Frank to play this part.
That sentiment again.
- Dear Lord.
- What is this?
I come up here
with the best intentions in the world,
and suddenly, I find I'm victimizing you.
Can I get a word in?
What'd I bring you, a basket of snakes?
It's not the two-weeks clause.
It's just that I don't want to bite off
more than I can chew, that's all.
You got the offer. Make up your mind.
We're booked into Boston for two weeks.
The season's still young.
We could stay out
until you were letter-perfect.
- Would you do that?
- Do it? I'd insist on it.
Talk it over with your agent here
and call the office by 3:00.
And that means not later.
Need a $20 bill?
You need it.
Why did you have to make
that crack about responsibility for?
Why didn't you tell me
about that audition this morning, Frank?
Because I wasn't sure
whether I could make it or not.
I must've walked up and down
47th Street a dozen times
before I could make myself
go through with it.
Don't keep things from me.
- I can't do it, can I?
- Of course you can.
You've got to try again,
and this seems a perfect opportunity.
Well, if I do take it, Georgie,
I'll need you,
every second, every step of the way.
I don't have any appointments, Frank,
all winter.
I wish it were a run-of-the-play contract.
Well, then why didn't you tell him that
when I brought it up?
Because I didn't want to antagonize him.
After all, if I do take the part,
I'm the one
that's going to have
to work with him, you know, not you.
Well, you'll never get a better deal.
They won't give you perfect terms.
So, take it and do your level best.
Wait a minute. Wait a minute here.
Two-weeks clause.
They can give me notice anytime,
but I can give them notice, too.
I can walk out anytime I want.
If I feel it isn't working out, I...
You mean you can quit, Frank?
No, not the way you mean it.
But if the show doesn't pan out,
I certainly don't want
to come into New York in a turkey.
But maybe this time,
it will work out, though.
Bernie likes me,
and Henry Johnson's pulling for me.
That guy, Cook, I got to worry about.
Ever since we've settled here,
we've been having trouble, Joe.
And now, instead of fields of wheat,
we got nothing but stubble
rotting in the brown dust.
I've talked it over with Stella.
We've had enough. We're leaving.
Well, what are we waiting for?
Let's push on.
There's nothing to stay around here for.
- How about you, Joe?
- I'm staying.
You know, they say sometimes
when a man falls from a great height,
before he hits bottom,
his whole life flashes by.
In one split second, he sees himself
for what he was and what he is.
But you don't always
have to plummet like a hailstone
to face that split second.
Mean it, Frank, mean it!
To plummet like a hailstone
to face that split second.
It can come to you as it did to me today,
as you stand...
It can, if...
What is it, Larry?
"In the middle of a smoldering field."
As you stand in the middle
of a smoldering field,
and you see your prayers and hopes
go up in wisps of smoke.
It's nothing, Frank, just nothing.
This is the most important decision
in the man's life.
The way you're playing him,
it sounds like he's trying to decide
what kind of eggs to have for breakfast.
And that goes for the rest of you, too.
I'm sorry, Bernie, it's just that
I'm still fighting these words.
You should've had 'em licked by now.
We've been in rehearsal 10 days.
- All right, let's take it from...
- Bernie.
It can't be that late.
Where does it go?
All right, knock off. Same time tomorrow.
We'll start with this scene.
Good night, Bernie. See you tomorrow.
- Good night, Bernie.
- Good night.
- You need me for anything, Bernie?
- No.
Want me to turn off the border?
- Yeah. Good night.
- Good night.
I'm sorry, Bernie, about the words.
It's just that,
well, I've had a lot
of other things on my mind.
I know you have.
Every time I give you a direction,
I have the feeling you're
off in space somewhere.
Frank, you can be great in this part,
but it demands your
undivided concentration
and every ounce of energy you've got.
I know.
I know,
I keep telling myself that, Bernie.
And then after rehearsal,
I go home to study, and there's...
Well, you've got headaches enough
of your own.
- Good night.
- Frank?
Having trouble at home?
No, nothing like that.
What's the matter?
Don't you believe me?
Everyone has trouble at home.
The only ones who deny it
are those that have too much of it.
I denied it for five years
with the former Mrs. Dodd.
Funny, I never had the impression
that you were married.
Neither did my wife.
That was my trouble.
What's yours?
It's nothing important. It'll work out.
I'll see you in the morning.
Does your wife
really want you to play this part?
Yeah, she's all for it.
I was just wondering.
The day I met her, she seemed
a little difficult about terms.
- Rather domineering, I thought.
- She wasn't always like that.
I know, I know.
They all start out as Juliets
and wind up as Lady Macbeths.
When I first met her, she was
as fine a person as you've ever seen.
She had background and breeding.
She had a kind of a nobility about her
that just made me feel proud
to be with her.
Of course, I was a good deal older
than she was,
but it didn't seem to make any difference,
because she wasn't a flighty kid
or anything like that.
She had a poise
and a dignity that was ageless.
Those first few years, I...
I just never knew a better life.
A wife who was everything
I'd always been looking for
and a son who was smart and healthy.
Then our son died.
I came home from the theater one night
a couple of months later, and...
And there's this kid who...
Well, I don't think she ever
had a real drink in her life before.
There she is stretched out
across the bed dead drunk
with her wrists cut and bleeding like a...
She was jealous of the fact that
I had my work and something to live for.
She felt she had nothing, you see?
Inside of a year,
she was a hopeless drunkard.
So, in an effort to give her
some purpose in life,
I made her feel
that I needed her in my work.
I let her pick
all the songs I should record
and the shows I ought to do.
She started taking over everything,
then she became very possessive.
And wanted to make all the decisions,
had to be with me all the time.
Whenever I was away from her, why,
she acted as if I'd run off
with another woman or something.
She had fits of depression.
One time, she set fire to a hotel suite.
That's when I began
hitting the bottle pretty hard.
Does she still drink?
No.
She stopped when I began.
That figures.
You were the weak one now.
That's what she wanted.
I suppose you have
to bring her up to Boston, huh?
I couldn't leave her alone, Bernie.
I guess you thought it was kind of funny
I didn't hang around the theater
after the audition the other day.
But, gee, if I'd have taken
this part without talking to her first,
I don't know what would have happened.
I had to make believe
that I didn't want it,
that I was afraid of it, you see?
And then that left it open
for her to convince me,
like it was her idea and not mine.
They can get awful bent
out of shape sometimes, can't they?
You know, my wife was so twisted,
she once said to me,
"I hope your next play's a flop,
so the whole world can see
how much I love you,
even though you're a failure."
Georgie?
Just coming from a movie.
Passing by, I thought
you might be through.
Your timing was perfect, Mrs. Elgin.
I have a knack that way.
Good evening, Mr. Dodd.
How is my husband doing?
Well, in my less-than-humble opinion,
he's what you call a natural.
Don't let him kid you, honey.
I was floundering all over the place.
We're going to have to
rehearse those cues a lot.
You can thank her, you know, for the
six or seven words that I did know.
Thanks.
- Did I intrude?
- No, no. We were just breaking up.
I don't like to make myself obtrusive
when Frank's working,
unless, of course, he needs my help.
- You're sure I'm not in the way?
- No, no. We were just closing up shop
and giving it back to the theater ghosts.
There's nothing quite so mysterious
and silent as a dark theater.
A night without a star.
- Why don't we go and get some coffee?
- Georgie?
She's the one that makes
all the decisions in our family.
Is that true, Mrs. Elgin?
To the extent that Frank's
brought out the mother in me, yes.
I'd like some coffee.
And I'd like to get to know
Mr. Dodd better.
I'd like to get to know you better.
Shall we go along?
Yes.
The theater's mysterious.
It sure is.
This way, please.
Hi, Charlie.
Excuse me a minute, will you, honey?
No, thanks, never use them.
Are you really satisfied
with Frank's work, Mr. Dodd?
I'll be happy
when he gets the part out of his hands.
He has his worries with those lines.
And I'd appreciate it if you didn't
add to those worries, Mrs. Elgin.
He seems to be more concerned about
how you're going to take
his performance than the audience.
You mean he's too focused
on my reaction?
That's one way of putting it.
You could help a lot
by being careful of what you do and say.
I try to be careful, Mr. Dodd,
but being an actor's wife
is not the easiest of jobs.
If I tell him he's magnificent,
he says I'm not being honest.
If I tell him he's not magnificent,
he says I don't love him.
Why don't you tell him he's good
but can be better?
- Is that what the critics will tell him?
- Are you a critic or a wife?
Let's say I try in my small way to help.
That's what my ex-wife
used to keep reminding me of.
Tearfully.
She had a theory that behind every
great man there was a great woman.
She also was thoroughly convinced
that she was great
and that all I needed to qualify
was guidance on her part.
She worked hard at it.
Too hard.
That still doesn't prove
her theory was completely wrong.
I imagine one could go through history
and find a few good examples.
It's a pity that Leonardo da Vinci
never had a wife to guide him.
He might've really gotten somewhere.
I'm sorry, dear,
but do you know who that was?
Old Charlie Blair.
You remember him, he was...
Here's another oldie coming up.
It's climbing right back up
onto the hit parade again.
But let's turn back the calendar
and listen to the original recording
made by Frank Elgin.
It's on a Vogue label, and he's backed up
by Jimmie Bolton's orchestra.
Here it is. See if you remember it.
The flaxen hair
The tender voice
The laughing eyes gave me no choice
No more the doubt
I used to face
No more the chase
The search is through
You've got what it takes
There was no passing you by
In my who's who
You've got what it takes
The who, the where, the when, the why
One look and, oh
No painting I know
Can equal your loveliness
Head to toe
At last the breaks
You've got what it takes
So easy to see
For all time to be
You've got what it takes
To take me
- Was that okay for you, Jimmie?
- Good here.
How about you, Harry?
You want to buy that one?
Sure will.
This one was it for my money.
Give you the playback in just a second.
Take five, boys.
There's my master.
You pretty near broke me up there,
you and your bad beat.
- How did it sound, honey?
- It's a lovely tune.
- Well, what about the singer?
- He has a pleasant voice.
Pleasant voice?
Good thing you're not my press agent,
or we'd all starve to death.
Come on, Johnnie.
I've got a hair appointment.
Well, you're not going to take him
to the beauty parlor?
- Well, it's Sally's day off.
- No, you don't.
He'll grow up to be
a hairdresser or something.
- I'm not doing anything. I'll take him.
- Where to? The Lambs Club?
And watch you play pool all afternoon?
Well, that's better
than teaching him how to set a wave.
All right, all right,
I'll take him to the zoo.
And bring him home
full of peanuts and ice cream
and chocolate bars. No, thanks.
Hey, Johnnie,
tell this lady to run along, will you?
- Okay.
- Tell her this is strictly stag.
- Strictly stag.
- All right.
All right. He's your responsibility.
And if he gets a stomachache
in the middle of the night,
that's going to be strictly stag, too.
Goodbye.
Isn't Mommy a doll?
Goodbye, hon.
- Peanuts.
- Yeah, well, you're a cinch.
First, we got to hear this playback,
then Charlie wants a couple of pictures.
Here it comes.
Take two of the chorus, Frank.
The search is through
You've got what it takes
There was no passing you by
Mr. Elgin! Mr. Elgin!
Can I get just one more shot?
Dave wants one of you
looking at the trademark.
It's for the album cover.
Well, make it fast.
I got a date with my friend here.
Right.
I think it would be better
without the hat, Mr. Elgin.
Right.
Now, put your hands up on the record.
Put the right one down at the bottom, too.
That's perfect. Just be a second.
Just hold it.
Hold it. Hold it!
Come on, quick, hurry up!
Johnnie! Johnnie!
At last the breaks
You've got what it takes
So easy...
The men for the trunk
are downstairs, so I...
For all...
When did you get these, Frank?
Last night, after you fell asleep.
I went out and got a paper and...
What's the difference?
I got a good night's sleep.
No more, Frank.
When we get to Boston,
I'll get you some sleeping pills.
One a night can't hurt.
I'm not sure I'm going to Boston.
What's the use of me trying
to kid myself?
I'll never be able to go
through with this show.
I'll mess it up just like I've messed up
everything else in my life.
- That day was an accident.
- Yeah, that's what the papers said.
It wasn't any accident, and I know it.
He was my responsibility that day.
- All I had to do was hold on to his hand.
- Frank, stop it! Stop!
Have you told Dodd about this?
Of course I haven't.
And don't you tell him, either.
I won't.
I think maybe you should. It might help.
Nobody's going to have any respect
for a guy who...
He'd tell Cook.
He'd fire me in five minutes.
Who's going to risk $200,000
on a guy who's that irresponsible?
All right, let's say you were responsible.
That's exactly
why you've got to go through with it.
- You've got to prove to yourself...
- You don't got what that...
You don't know what it's like
to stand out there on that stage all alone
with the whole show on your shoulders.
If I'm no good, the show's no good.
I got the future of 100 people
in my hand.
This hand. This hand!
- Elgin? Trunk for Boston?
- Come in.
- Theater or the hotel?
- Theater.
- No, no, wait a...
- Everything's packed. It's ready.
Maggie, I tell you,
Joe's nothing but a dreamer.
Then the least you can do
is go out to the valley
and let him show you
what he's been dreaming about.
That's fair enough, Maggie.
Come on, Phil.
The land around us
Will be in bloom
With song and laughter
And elbow room
A town will blossom here
With all serene
With houses white
And with gardens green
The lanes are shady
The streets are wide
You and your lady are full of pride
I can hear children's voices
I can hear Sunday chimes
All across the valley better times
On land we found us
One thing I know
The land around us
Will grow and grow
We'll put the post office here
And the high school there
And if we fail to put up a jail
We hope you don't mind
Round here we'll have no galoot
Who totes a sixer to shoot
For in our plan, each citizen
Will be the respectable kind
Railroad station here
Opry house will be there
We'll do our best, the uncivilized West
To conquer and tame
We'll settle for not less
Than a town that's pure and spotless
Or mud will be our name
How do they expect me
to make these fast changes like this?
What's the matter?
Haven't I been doing it right?
You've been doing it all right,
but I want you out front
watching my performance.
Give me the dickey. Come on.
But I can tell from here, Frank.
You're doing just wonderfully.
I am not, and you know it.
Why don't they get me a dresser?
Why, with the money they're paying me,
they could afford a dozen of them.
Do you want me to talk to Cook about it?
Yes. And while you're at it,
tell him to stop that understudy
from snooping around backstage.
I come off just now,
and he's hovering there like a vulture,
just waiting for me to cave in.
I'm sure if you talked
to Mr. Dodd about it, he'd...
You talk to him.
Tell him to keep that guy out front.
And get me some new tissue.
That stuff is murdered.
I will right after rehearsal.
Frank, I'm sorry
I stepped on that line of yours
in the depot scene.
Well, that's all right.
Think nothing of it.
- It's just that I was so nervous.
- Nervous? What's to be nervous about?
It's just another show.
Where would you ever
find another star as sweet as that?
What a wonderful guy.
I'd like to hold the orchestra
for about a half hour longer, Frank.
I want to go over that new arrangement
on Land Around Us.
Wait a minute, Henry.
They've been on overtime
for three and a half hours already.
Can't you do it in the morning?
Hey, Bernie,
is it okay if I take the doohickeys off?
Yeah, yeah. Go ahead.
There we are. Be here tomorrow.
Bernie, Paul mentioned
something to me during the second act.
Well, I think Eleanor is way overboard
in that town hall scene.
I know she is. I know she is.
I wasn't thinking about Eleanor.
I was thinking about...
Don't you think I know?
- Now, look, Bernie, I have some notes.
- So have I. I've got nine zillion of them,
but we'll go over them tomorrow.
Dismiss the company.
Give them a 1:00 call.
I'm going out for a breath of fresh air,
then we'll sit down quietly
and discuss that spot.
Larry, hold Frank and Helen, will you?
And run that scene in front of the church.
See if you can find out
what caused the mix-up.
Yeah.
You talked about the costumes,
the scenery, the lighting,
but not one word about our real problem.
I thought Elgin was terrible.
That's why you take shows
out of town, Cookie.
Actors can improve. The scenery can't.
If he spoke one word of the author's
script tonight, I never heard it.
He tripped on a rug
he'd never seen before!
He goes to sit down, and there's no chair!
In the big scene, the door wouldn't open!
What do you expect of him?
Besides that, Larry tells me
his wife was backstage
all during the performance tonight.
She's enough to upset anyone.
What are you going to do about it?
Lower the boom on her.
Well, you asked for him.
He's your problem, Bernie.
I got plenty of my own.
The union insists
I take on three more stagehands.
Mr. Cook?
Excuse me. May I ask you something?
- Do you think Frank needs a dresser?
- No, I don't, but I suppose you do.
Well, those two fast changes...
Well, it's a very large part, after all.
Bernie, every time
you nod your head like that,
it costs us a couple hundred dollars.
You're going to nod us
right out of business.
Don't worry. We'll get him a dresser.
Mr. Cook seems to be almost what the
bad fairy promised Frank at his cradle.
He's not too bad.
Gruff, but with a heart of stone.
You smoke too much.
That's obvious.
A whole pack since 10:30.
Careful you don't catch cold.
After every first dress rehearsal,
I always sit in a draft
hoping to catch pneumonia.
It never works.
For the peaceful quiet of an oxygen tent.
Mr. Dodd,
who is that tall, sort of gloomy man
that hangs around backstage?
- Lucas? Is that the name?
- Yes.
General understudy.
Not much personality, but competent.
Well, excuse me for saying this,
but must he stay backstage?
- It seems to bother Frank, and I...
- I'll watch him.
Frank that insecure? He's working well.
Good humor most of the time.
Don't you know what hides
behind that good humor?
Certain men are very strange.
Business couldn't be better.
Wife and kiddies are fine.
Jokes with the boys at the club.
Then the next day you read
he's hung himself from the chandelier.
Is that supposed to be
a picture of Frank?
Yes and no.
Frank doesn't like to make
the slightest remark that might lose him
people's regard or affection.
If anything has to be said
that might cause antagonism,
well, that's my job.
I hate to say this, Mrs. Elgin,
but I hired a performer.
A good performer. I may want him
without his sisters, cousins and aunts.
I never meant to interfere.
I was just sort of offering myself
as sort of liaison officer...
I have no problems with Frank.
Don't make any where they don't exist.
Before this is over, Mr. Dodd,
you may face a couple of beauties.
Is that a threat?
No.
It's just a simple statement
based on experience.
Whether you like it or not, Frank's weak.
He's a leaner.
And I happen to be the one he leans on.
The good, strong helpmate.
Did it ever occur to you
that you and your strength
might be the very reason he is weak?
I don't like strong women, Mrs. Elgin.
I'm not here to audition
for you, Mr. Dodd.
I'm here for the same reason you are,
to do everything in my power
to make him a success in this.
I want to see Frank stand
on his own two feet again
for very personal reasons.
Then don't overplay your hand.
Frank can go anywhere from here,
other shows, right to the top again.
Or he may go back to that smelly room
over that cheap restaurant,
and you right along with him!
Say, I got that line mix-up
all straightened out.
It wasn't my fault at all.
It was Helen's.
She was throwing me the wrong cue.
I'm glad you got it fixed.
Say, Frank, I noticed the understudy
hanging around backstage tonight.
- That bother you?
- Me? No.
Never even noticed. Besides, how else
is he gonna learn his business?
Is that you, Georgie?
Yes.
Are you coming in?
In a minute.
I just want to get a breath of fresh air.
Well, I can't come out.
I'm still a little soggy.
Well, come on, give.
What'd they say about the dresser?
You'll get him.
Well, looks like they got a little respect
for the old man after all.
Yes, they have respect for you, Frank.
Well, I'll be out in a second.
It's a different kind of a show, isn't it?
Yes. It confused me in the beginning,
but I'm enjoying it now.
It's a beautiful production.
Must have cost a fortune.
I'll bet the costumes alone cost $50,000.
I think it's the most exciting thing
I've seen in years.
- Where did you get it?
- George gave it to me for my birthday.
Henry, I'm positive you've
seen him before, years ago,
in that show
that all took place in Central Park.
Is he the same one?
- So easygoing and likable, isn't he?
- Yes.
You catching cold?
That's all I need.
You're probably smoking too much.
Try and go to sleep, Frank.
I want to see the review
in the morning paper first.
You can see it at breakfast.
You need sleep.
I can't sleep until I know
what they thought of me.
What time do they deliver
the morning paper around here anyhow?
In the afternoon?
Don't know why they
picked this place to open in.
Playing to that audience
is like getting locked in a deep freeze.
- Just came in, Mr. Elgin.
- Thank you.
I'll get you another sleeping pill.
Hello.
The bellboy said
he just took you a paper, Frank,
so I didn't think I'd be waking you.
Now just remember the only important
ones are the New York notices.
Yeah, I...
I don't worry none about
these out-of-town critics.
Nah, they don't bother me any.
Georgie was a little upset,
but I reminded her of Lonesome Town.
Yeah, the Philadelphia critics
murdered us,
but we got up to New York,
we were a smash.
Well, we've got five weeks
to rewrite, change and polish.
And believe me, opening night
in New York, it'll be great.
But, Frank, let's not kid ourselves.
It's gonna take an awful lot of work
on everybody's part.
Now, get some sleep.
You've got a big day tomorrow.
Rehearsal in the afternoon,
performance tomorrow night,
and then production stills after that.
So, get all the rest you can, will you?
- Okay.
- Okay, good night.
The dame in this paper
puts her finger on it.
Right on it.
She says, "Elgin lacks authority
in the role that cries for it."
No authority. That's it.
You know why he lacks authority?
Because his wife has too much of it.
She's got to go back to New York,
Cookie.
I think we ought to make it
transportation for two.
If you don't like what I'm doing
or the way I'm doing it,
you can make it transportation for three.
Now, we were discussing that scene
in front of the town hall.
I think we go past the climax.
Let's try cutting this scene
here tomorrow night.
Over a little more.
All right, everybody out front keep quiet!
Okay, now, sit down and keep quiet,
otherwise we're gonna be here all night!
Now, settle down.
- Johnny?
- All right, here we go.
Steady!
- Hold it!
- Pardon me. Okay, go ahead.
Hold it!
Thank you.
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
Hold those positions for a second.
I want to change one thing here.
While Frank is speaking,
instead of you people
looking at each other,
I want you to look directly at him.
And no movement.
I don't want anything
that will distract the audience
from keeping their focus on him.
He's got to be
the dead center of attention.
You...
You really think
it would be better that way?
I thought it'd be kind of nice,
be natural,
if I was just sort of in the crowd here.
No, no. It's all wrong, Frank.
I saw it tonight.
The words lose importance.
After all, this character's asking
these people to put their faith in him,
to trust him.
He's promising to make
their dreams a reality.
He's accepting
the responsibility for their future,
and it's got to be a lot more important.
Believe me, it'll be a lot better.
All right, we'll rehearse it tomorrow.
I just wanted to tell you about it.
Frank. Frank, we got one more shot.
Where you're here looking at the poster.
Okay, yell when you're ready.
Now, this is color.
Turn your head towards the poster.
- Would you look at the poster, Frank?
- Yeah, sure.
There you are. Hold it. Steady.
- Hold it.
- Put your hands up on the record.
Frank, what's the matter?
I got a cough.
I got some stuff in the room.
I'll be right back.
- All finished?
- No.
Frank, I don't like
that cough syrup you bought.
Why not? It's a buck a bottle.
Well, "buck a bottle"
is a jim-dandy slogan,
but you can read labels
as well as the next one.
That's got 22% alcohol in it.
I'll get you some lemon and honey
in the morning.
Cook didn't come back
after the show, did he?
No, he didn't.
Well, I'm glad I got that
two-weeks clause in there.
I can quit anytime I want.
Why should I care? They don't seem to.
Producer doesn't come back
second night after the show.
Frank, leave the bottle here.
I need it for my cough.
Leave it here.
But I need it!
Georgie.
I need it.
- Frank's onstage.
- I know.
I want to talk to you.
The last time we talked, Mr. Dodd,
you reduced me to tears.
I promise you it won't happen again.
As a matter of fact, I'm glad you're here.
At the risk of being
considered a saboteur,
I think you ought to know
he's getting a cold
and he shouldn't be kept up this late.
We need production stills.
- How's his spirit?
- Low.
- Why?
- Ask the Boston critics.
For the last month, I've spent between
10 and 15 hours a day with Frank.
Nothing ever bothers him
except through your mouth.
Why?
We've been through all of that before.
Either he laughs and makes bad jokes
or he sits in silence
and rots away inside.
But either way, for your edification,
he's heading for a bender.
Why is it that women always think they
understand men better than men do?
Maybe because they live with them.
If you're not careful, you're going to
have him full of whiskey before morning.
He's getting a cold and that's
a respectable surface reason
for any drinker to jump down the well.
Why work so hard at this marriage?
You make him tense and uneasy.
You never stop handling him, and now,
you're trying to handle me, too!
And don't think I couldn't after handling
a cunning drunkard for 10 years!
If you had any compassion
or love whatsoever for this man,
you could never call him
a cunning drunkard.
Maybe I have a greater love for the truth.
That's what he is. I'm a drunkard's wife.
That's the truth, too.
And I think it's high time
you stopped looking at everything
as if it were a musical comedy,
and faced a little bit of it yourself!
To be frank,
I find you slightly grotesque, Mrs. Elgin.
You came here to tell me something.
What is it?
I've been fighting with Cook.
He's got
a first-class replacement for Frank
and a lot of money to protect.
I think Frank will improve.
Cook thinks he won't.
Well, he won't
unless you get out of town.
You might be sorry.
That's a risk I can't wait to take.
- He'll be helpless.
- I'll help him.
You?
You wouldn't know where to begin.
I'll begin by not calling him
a cunning drunkard.
I'll give him pride and confidence
by occasionally rejoicing
in his God-given talents,
instead of constantly reminding him
of his weaknesses.
I'll let him face a decision without first
filling him full of doubts and fears,
and I won't stifle him
with my own inadequacy and bitterness.
I might have to
bend the truth here and there,
but I'll get a performance out of him.
And that's the difference
between us, Mr. Dodd.
You want him to become
the actor he once was.
I'm his wife.
I want him just once more
as the man he once was,
able to stand on his own two feet
and face responsibility, and...
And you don't do that
by bending the truth!
And you certainly don't do it by stripping
him of every vestige of self-respect.
I'm warning you, I'm gonna fight you
as hard as I can for this man.
Not too hard.
I may let you have him.
No. No, you want him wholly
and utterly dependent.
You realized long ago with all
your fine background and breeding
you were a failure.
But it gave you a reason for being,
a feeling of power
to control and manipulate
someone else's life.
And worst of all, you do it
in the name of love.
You're as phony to me
as an opera soprano!
Did I forget to tell you I'm proud?
Make up your mind.
Either you go to New York alone
or you both go.
I'll go.
On one condition.
Let me tell Frank in my own way,
in my own time.
As long as you're on that train
by tomorrow night.
Traffic's a little heavy throughout.
They ought to put a light out there.
- Finished?
- Yeah, they're all wrapped up.
- Frank.
- Yeah?
I'd like to run through that new scene
after the matinee tomorrow.
- You tired?
- Tired? Me?
How can you be tired,
when you're back in the harness
playing a part
you've waited for all your life?
Your energy was low again tonight.
Yeah, I know. It's this cold,
but I'll get rid of it in a day or two.
- You sure it's not nerves?
- Nerves? You kidding?
Why don't you tell him
what's bothering you?
Well, what's bothering me?
Cook and the notices, for instance.
That? Well,
I just wondered why he didn't
come around backstage after the show.
Is he mad or something?
Might as well be honest about it.
Those weren't exactly money notices.
Frank, Mr. Dodd believes in you.
I can't help you if you're worried.
He can.
But I'm not worried.
Did you or did you not
tell me 10 minutes ago right in this room
that you wanted to hand in your notice?
Well, I was just ribbing you, honey.
Guy's got to be careful around here.
You can't open your mouth.
Gotta watch your step, I guess.
Your wife says
she's thinking of returning to New York.
I told you nothing of the sort!
What do you mean, New York?
We can talk about it later.
Would you leave us alone
for a few minutes, Mrs. Elgin?
Now, Frank, let's get one thing straight.
What is that?
It's cough syrup
with pine tar and cherries.
A whole bush in a bottle, you know?
This stuff is laced with 22% alcohol.
Alcohol.
Gee, I told Georgie to just get me
a little something
to loosen up my throat.
Don't you know
what these little appetizers can do?
Well, I suppose she didn't even bother
to look at the label, Bernie.
Or maybe she did.
She's jealous of the show
and jealous of me.
This is how far she'd go.
Far enough to kick you off the wagon!
Now, Bernie, I know she's high-strung
and difficult, but...
I want her back in New York.
We've got
a lot of hard work ahead of us,
and I haven't time
to outmaneuver frustrated females!
Go on back to the hotel
and get a good night's sleep.
I want you fresh and clear tomorrow.
Mrs. Elgin?
Frank knows exactly how I feel,
and I think he appreciates
what has to be done.
See you tomorrow, Frank.
Good night.
He can be pretty arrogant and insulting,
can't he?
Well, he had no right
to treat you like that.
Did you tell him that?
I poured it in the sink.
If you don't believe me,
why don't you go smell it?
Where's the other bottle, Frank?
- What other bottle?
- Frank, I'm tired. Don't play peekaboo.
Where's the other bottle of that syrup?
I didn't buy another bottle.
I wish you'd take
my word for something for a change.
Never mind.
Never mind. I give up.
I'm not going to look.
Georgie, I want to apologize.
- He had no right to take that attitude.
- Stop putting on a front.
- Who's putting on a front?
- You're putting on a front!
And you lie! You lie, you lie!
You going back to New York?
I don't know why not.
You want to leave me, don't you?
At the moment,
all I want is for you to get dressed
so we can get out of here.
Who's in New York?
Who's the guy you want to get back to?
Frank, I'm warning you.
I'm going to hit you
with the first thing I pick up.
Now get dressed!
Why don't you go
if you're in such a hurry?
Go on, go ahead!
I'll take a walk, get something to eat.
It's not gonna do your cold any good.
Well, let them worry about it.
And I told you what you could do, too.
Do you want me to go?
Is that what you want?
Yes. Yes, if you're in
such a great big hurry, go on!
You got the key to the room?
Well, keep it.
I'll get another one from the hotel.
And don't wake me up
when you come in.
Who knows,
I may be having a happy dream.
Sixty-five, 75.
- And that's for you.
- Thanks, Doc.
Do you like me?
Doc, I think you're one
of the most likable guys I ever seen.
Come on, Jackie, sing something!
- How about Love and Learn?
- Okay, I'll sing if you be quiet.
Yeah, Love and Learn, Jackie.
All right, all right. Simmer down.
It's my turn to holler.
Love and learn
It's a breeze, let it burn
You retreat, then return
You may have climbed
the tree of knowledge
But when you love you really learn
Love and learn, learn a lot
It's the be and end-all, then it's not
It's a dream, it's a plot
It's something out of seventh heaven
Something misbegot
Each morning when I count
my blessings
They tally up to none
- I've arrived at this...
- Well, this state of bliss
Is somewhat overdone
Well, go, Dad, go.
Love and learn
Weep and sing
Till the final day of reckoning
What about this guy.
But when arms start to cling
With the thrills, kisses bring
What you have learned is
Is you haven't learned a thing
- Take me home, Dad.
- Go on, girl.
It's a dream and it's a plot
Oh, what you thought it was, was not
But when arms begin to cling
And angels start to sing
What you have learned is
Is you haven't learned a thing
Hey, aren't you Frank Elgin?
Yeah, I used to be.
Not a word,
or I'll tell them you're Harpo Marx.
Jackie, The Pump Song.
Do The Pump Song.
Look, I'm tired. Dance a while.
Order up. Buy something already.
- I'm sorry.
- It's all right.
- Have another?
- Yeah.
Give me a double.
Pour, pour. Go ahead. Fill it up.
Sorry about that drink.
It's all right.
Could've happened to anybody.
Just an accident.
Yeah, just an accident.
That's what the papers said.
You're right.
It could've happened to anybody.
Just an accident.
Come in.
- Good morning.
How's it going?
- We got out 23 minutes.
- That's fine.
Now, if we cut that chorus in half
in front of the courthouse,
- what'll that give us?
- Save another seven and a half minutes.
Good. Good.
That's first act, where we need it.
Hello?
Yeah.
What? When?
Oh, no.
So, I think you better come right down.
Yes, I'll wait for you.
Here's his keys, his belt.
I know, I know.
Seventy-five, 85,
90.
Here, here's your fine, Officer.
You promised me the other night
I'd have a couple of big problems
with Frank before this was over.
I see you made good your threat.
I didn't threaten you. I warned you.
When he hadn't come in
by 3:00 or 4:00 this morning,
why didn't you call me?
Suppose he had been
with another woman?
You're being deliberately evasive.
You must've known...
Sit down, Frank.
Get me some water, Georgie.
What happened, Frank?
Sit up! Don't act as though
I'm beating you! Sit up!
I'm sorry, Bernie.
- What happened?
- I don't know. I just...
What happened after
I left you last night?
Georgie and I had a fight,
and I don't know.
I thought so.
She certainly picked a fine time
to start yelling and screaming.
Wasn't her fault at all, it was mine.
Of course it was your fault,
but stop protecting her!
She's weak, Bernie. She's so weak.
She's driven you to drink for 10 years,
and you call her weak?
You could be magnificent in this part,
but not when she's around.
- She goes back to New York.
- Bernie, I can't do that.
- I don't know what she'd do.
- She goes back this morning.
- She's weak, Bernie. She's awful weak.
- I'll talk to her.
If we go on together,
you move in with me.
- Cook doesn't want me.
- I'm not so sure I want you!
Whatever you say, Bernie.
You decide. I...
Frank stays, you go.
The management will take care
of your expenses.
Frank may follow you
in a couple of days.
I'm not sure.
Right now, he's moving in with me.
Crisp as lettuce, aren't you?
Do you want me to go, Frank?
All right, I'll go and pack.
Before you go, tell Frank
he has nothing to worry about.
He thinks you may go drastic.
It's happened before, I understand.
- Bernie, I...
- What's happened before?
Phony suicide attempts.
Bernie, she...
Mr. Dodd.
When I was a child,
we had a town idiot.
He kept insisting that elephant tusks
came from piano keys,
but he had nothing on you.
Suicide attempts are Frank's department.
Show me your wrists, Frank.
Show me your wrists!
Did you once set fire to a hotel suite?
He told you that?
Was I a hopeless drunk?
Did I have fits of depression?
Was I possessive?
Did I have to have a nurse watch me
when he was onstage?
Didn't you recognize any of it?
That was his big speech
in one of the plays you admired him in
when you were a hatcheck boy.
Larry.
Do you think the understudy
can play the matinee?
Yeah, I think so.
Pay the fine and damages.
This is a receipt for his coat
and wallet and the rest.
Take him back to the hotel.
No, wait a minute.
They see him in the lobby,
it'll be all over the papers.
Take him back to the theater
and let him sleep it off there.
Come on, Frank.
Georgie, I...
Go on, Frank.
I won't leave without seeing you.
Tell Cook I'll be along in a few minutes.
May I smoke?
May you smoke?
What is that supposed to be,
homage to a lady?
That'll never make me forgive you,
Mr. Dodd,
for what you've said and done.
I'm not asking for forgiveness.
I want information.
What about Frank?
What made him go to pieces?
The responsibility became
too much for him.
But in the beginning, why the lying,
why the cunning?
He hates himself.
Consequently, he'll do or say anything
to be liked by others.
People like Frank ought
to have two votes.
Then they could mark their ballot
Democrat and Republican.
That way everybody would love them.
Was he always like that?
No.
No, he drank a little.
Wasn't too dependable.
But that was
only a pathetic hint of frailty
in a wonderful glowing man.
That appeals to a lot of us.
It did to me.
I was so young.
His weaknesses,
they seemed touching and sweet.
They made me love him more.
And then one day
he was walking with our son.
He let go of his hand, there was traffic,
looked the other way,
and the boy was killed.
Ever since then,
Frank has acted like a murderer.
Guilt and repentance
and all that goes with it.
But worse than that, he shunned
any responsibility like the plague.
It covered a pretty wide range.
Everything from...
From not wanting any more children to...
I know it must sound ludicrous
to anyone
who hasn't actually lived
through it, but it...
It got to the point that he...
He wouldn't even pick out
a coat or suit by himself.
I don't know where
to begin to apologize, Mrs. Elgin.
You can begin
by not calling me Mrs. Elgin.
And you never left him.
Twice left. Twice returned.
He's a helpless child.
Anyone taking a cab to New York?
But if he's as helpless as you say...
He's not helpless now.
He has you, Mr. Dodd.
He has to be watched and handled.
You're the only one that can do that.
I didn't know it before now.
Well, then maybe
you've learned something!
The man needs you.
He has to be watched.
You take on the job with waving banners
and 10 hours later, hand it back.
You're telling me he has to be watched?
He has to be nursed and guarded
and coddled, but not by me!
I'm going back to New York to
the peace and comfort of a quiet room.
For the first time in years,
I won't have to wonder where he is.
He'll be in the strong,
sober hands of Bernie Dodd.
Can you stand him up on his feet again?
Because that's where
all my prayers have gone.
To see that one holy hour
when he can stand alone again.
- Listen to me.
- And I might forgive even you, Mr. Dodd.
If you can keep him up long enough
for me to get out from under.
All I want is my own name and a
modest job to buy sugar for my coffee.
- Will you...
- You can't believe that, can you?
You can't believe
that a woman is crazy out of her mind
to live alone in one room by herself!
- Listen to me! Listen to me!
- Why are you holding me?
I said you're holding me!
How could you be so angry
at someone you didn't even know?
Maybe, I really wasn't.
Maybe, I screamed at you
to keep myself at an angry distance.
No one has looked at me as a woman
for years and years.
And I never knew
there was such a woman.
Loyal, steadfast.
And when I found her...
Now, I need your answer.
Do you think Frank can make it?
I don't know.
But I do know that if he doesn't
go through with this show,
he'll never work again.
I'm sure of that.
You'll be taking a big chance.
They're the only ones worth taking.
But I can't unless you stay.
Will you?
Yes.
You kissed me.
Don't let it give you any ideas,
Mr. Dodd.
No, Mrs. Elgin.
It's more thoughtful.
You see, he's trying
to figure out an approach.
- Did you see Cook?
- No.
He's in the box office
talking long-distance to Watson.
I haven't got time now.
I've been going over the part
with the understudy
and I think we can get by with him.
- You want to listen to him?
- Not now.
- How do you feel?
- Okay.
Larry got me some coffee.
- I'll be out of here in a minute.
- You don't have to get out.
All you have to do is get some sleep.
But the understudy,
he's gonna want to get in here.
I've just listened to him read, Frank.
He's no good.
- You'll have to play the matinee.
- No, no, Bernie.
Don't stick your neck out.
Listen, Frank, I'm in no mood
to cut my throat in public.
The understudy stinks, and
you're the only thing I've got around.
It's not just the matinee, Bernie.
I've been thinking.
You gotta replace me.
When you took this job
I promised you no pity.
- And no pity it's going to be.
- I don't expect any!
I'm only warning you. Get rid of me.
Let me go back to New York.
So you can tell the boys
at The Lambs Club
that you quit because
the part wasn't big enough?
No.
If you leave this show,
it'll only be for one reason.
Because I fire you!
Because I fire you for being
an unreliable, slobbering drunk!
I know a lot of people who hire actors
and that's what I'll tell
every one of them.
And those I don't talk to, Cook does!
You don't understand.
It's not just this performance.
I can do a show for you.
I can keep on doing shows.
I've gone on
when I could hardly stand up.
It's not when I'm out there that it's bad.
Well, this is just a matinee in Boston!
Suppose I do this to you in New York?
Suppose I don't show up on you
for a week? Then where are you?
Where are you?
You keep talking
as if I do this on purpose!
I can't help it, Bernie!
In between shows,
in the night sometimes
when I start thinking about it, I...
You mean the accident?
Georgie told me about it.
Well, then you know
it hasn't been easy trying to...
Why didn't you tell me
about the accident before we started?
I don't know. I just didn't think...
You knew I wouldn't buy it.
And I don't buy it now.
A crazy wife, yes,
because you knew I had one.
- It was an accident.
- It was just a crutch and you know it!
You were getting older,
beginning to slip.
You didn't want to admit it,
so you started looking for excuses.
The accident was a perfect excuse!
Everybody expects a guy to take
a thing like that pretty hard.
So, you used it.
You played it to the hilt.
- No, no, Bernie.
- I'm right, and you know it!
You're pretty sure of yourself,
aren't you?
You don't know
what it means to be afraid, do you?
You're right up there
on top of the heap now.
Everything's rolling good for you,
but wait till you get a little older.
Wait till you've had a couple of flops
and the people stop writing about you
and they stop talking about you.
Then you'll get afraid.
Then you'll start
looking around for excuses, too.
I'm not blaming you.
I just want you to stop lying to yourself!
All right! All right!
Sure, everybody thought it was
because of the accident.
That's what I wanted them to think.
Because I was afraid.
Even when I was the biggest,
I was afraid.
I've always been afraid.
I don't know why.
It was good to find
a respectable excuse for failure.
Sure, I could drink a little more.
Nobody blamed me.
They blamed it on the accident.
After I'd milked every tear out of it
I cut my wrists, not deep enough to die,
but just enough to bleed myself
back into the center of attention.
So, everybody felt sorry for me again.
They understood.
Everybody was talking about me
and my tragedy.
That's the way I wanted it.
To keep it that way, I lied.
God, how I lied.
I even lied about Georgie.
You were so right, Bernie.
I'll keep thinking about it.
Not about the accident,
but how I used it.
- Get some rest, Frank.
- I'll keep on thinking about it, Bernie.
You better not take
a chance on me, Bernie.
You better get rid of me.
Get rid of me, Bernie.
Bernie, I...
He's got to get some sleep.
If you want to talk...
I don't care if he does hear me.
I just talked to Ray Watson in California.
He's available.
He can catch the sleeper plane
and be here in the morning.
- I said I'd call him right back.
- Don't bother. Frank's going to play it.
Now, wait a minute, Bernie.
I'm not going to let you
protect this guy any longer.
I'm calling Ray Watson.
If you do, tell him
to bring a director along with him!
Maybe not now, Maggie,
but all that valley needs is a few friends
to treat it kindly for a while.
To loan it the sharp edge of a plow,
some seeds, and plenty of care.
It'll pay us back.
I know it, Joe,
but it's the others
that are gonna take a lot of convincing.
- Western Union.
- Yes, come in.
How's it going
on the other side of the stage, Ralph?
Fine, Mr. Dodd.
That Mr. Frank's a big man. Big man!
Positive honor to work for him.
Where have you been, Bernie, out front?
Yeah.
Opening night in New York.
The world's most useless man.
How's Frank?
Okay.
How's it been back here?
He was a little uneasy
with the curtain going up so late.
If only the first few rows
had the balcony's manners,
what a wonderful world this would be.
It was sweet of you
to send all these wires.
- Who told you?
- I guessed.
How many did you send?
Nine or ten. You?
Five or six.
Where did you get all the names?
Lambs Club.
Good. Good.
Why don't you go out front?
Not me. I don't sit out there
with those nabobs and critics.
I hear very well right from here.
That's the advantage
of an onstage dressing room.
Bernie, keep quiet!
That's the disadvantage.
Larry's right, you know?
From now on, it's his show.
I'm just a visitor.
Depressed, aren't you?
Depressed and mean.
It's been a long nine weeks.
A job is home to a homeless man.
Now, the job is finished.
Where do I go from here?
Georgie,
five weeks ago,
I kissed a woman, a married woman.
And now I know I love her.
And I don't know where to turn.
Lady, close to you like this...
Bernie.
I waited.
Are you going to leave him?
Bernie.
In Boston, you told me all you prayed for
was to see him on his feet again
so that you could get out from under.
Let me show you something.
The land around us
Is now in bloom
With song and laughter
And elbow room
A town has blossomed here
With all serene
With houses white
And with gardens green
-The lanes are shady
-The streets are wide
You and your lady are full of pride
I can hear children's voices
I can hear Sunday chimes
All across the valley better times
Looks to me like he's made it.
What about you? Are you leaving him?
- Don't you think that can wait?
- No. It happens to be on my mind.
It has been ever since
that morning in Boston.
Georgie, if I could only
make you understand.
Not now, Bernie. Not now.
First-act curtain.
I've got to make the dressing room tour
and give out with the rah-rah stuff.
I thought you were out front, Bernie.
Just came back.
You really hit it tonight, Frank.
Keep the drive. It's good.
Okay, Ralph, I can handle this.
Go have yourself a smoke.
You know something? That's work.
Sounded wonderful back here.
Were you pleased?
Well, I messed it up in a couple of
spots, but I don't think anybody noticed.
I think you'd better touch up
the gray a little bit.
Yeah? Make me look at least
two weeks younger.
How do you feel?
Good. Good.
How they liking it out front?
I only know what I read in the papers.
They came in late on you.
As long as they don't leave early.
Frank.
Frank, a lot of things are said
in the heat and the toil of the day.
Sure.
I hope you'll accept my apologies.
Yeah, I know how
those things can happen.
Naturally you include my wife
in your apologies, too.
Of course, Mrs. Elgin.
I include you, too, of course.
Well, then you can start
by taking your hat off.
You're not at a smoker, Mr. Cook.
You know something?
This is the first kind word
you've had for either one of us.
I think I know why.
You'd like me to sign
a run-of-the-play contract
before the morning papers come out
so you could get me
for about half of what I'm worth,
is that right?
Now, Frank, Frank,
I'm sorry, but you'll just have to
take my word on a thing like that.
It's true, true, I have been thinking
of different contractual arrangements,
but that's not why I came back. No.
I'm having some people
over for supper after the show
while we're waiting for the notices,
and I just wanted to invite you.
And you, Mrs. Elgin.
Well, thanks. I'll...
I'll drop by if I'm not too tired.
Good. Hope to see you.
Yeah.
Excuse me, Mrs. Elgin.
We'll be looking for you.
Thank you.
- Congratulations, Frank.
- You're very kind.
They've got you trapped.
Don't ever learn to play the piano, pal.
Congratulations, Frank.
Great performance.
Thank you.
Say, Paul,
have you seen Georgie anywhere?
Well, she was here
a minute ago, Frank.
There you are, dear.
Only lost about half of it en route.
Well, now that it's all over,
I guess this is as good a time as any to
say thanks to both of you.
For what?
Well, if it hadn't been for you two,
Ray Watson would be here right now
looking for a spoon for his coffee.
Pardon me, Frank.
There are as many reasons
for drinking as there are drinkers.
But there are only two reasons
why a drinker stops.
He cites or he decides to quit
all by himself.
I'm not sure I have.
I faced a crisis up there in Boston
and I got away with it.
But just about anybody can face a crisis.
It's that everyday living that's rough.
I'm not sure I can lick it,
but I think I got a chance.
The point is, Georgie, what about us?
No, no, don't go, Bernie. You're...
You're involved in this.
You know, there's only
one thing more obvious
than two people looking
longingly at each other,
and that's two people avoiding it.
Frank, I certainly didn't want to bring up
any of this tonight,
but you did,
so let's have the whole truth.
I married you for happiness,
yours and mine.
If necessary,
I'll leave you for the same reason.
And I can't guarantee you
that happiness.
And the rest of the whole truth is that
it was as much my fault as it was yours.
In Boston, Bernie accused me
of wanting you completely dependent,
that I wanted to control
and manipulate your life.
I denied it, of course, but I think
there's an element of truth there.
I don't want
to run that risk again, Frank.
No, you're right.
This is something
I've got to work out for myself.
With you or without you.
Whether the show is a hit or a flop
is beside the point.
I've got to find myself
whether it's in one room or in five.
Well, I don't think there's any point
in us torturing each other
any longer by delaying this.
You two talk it over,
and I'll go along home.
But, Georgie, don't dismiss
what we had together.
I gave you 10 of the roughest years
anybody ever spent outside
of a concentration camp.
It could be more of the same.
That was quite a little speech, wasn't it?
I guess I'm still giving a performance.
This time there's a slight difference.
At least I... I know it's a performance.
I know it's gratifying for a woman
to be wanted and needed.
But not for every minute of every day.
Just remember that for years
he's been a leaner.
You said so yourself.
Pretty tune, isn't it, Frank?
Remember it?
Yes. Yes, I do.
I made a record of it once.
Bernie, I...
I'm always running out of cigarettes.
You smoke too much.
And you're impertinent.
And you're loyal.
And steadfast.
And devoted.
I like that in a woman.
Larry, have you seen Frank anywhere?
He just left, Mrs. Elgin.
Here you are, Mr. Cook.
- About time!
- How are they?
I don't know.
I didn't get a chance to read them.
Here's The Times and Tribune,
Bernie.
Thanks, Larry.