Attention please,
TWA flight 820 from Hong Kong
has arrived 30 minutes early.
Passengers will exit from Gate 3.
Mam.
May I help you?
Eggs.
Tang Lung?
Miss Chen Ching Hua?
Yes.
You weren't waiting at the gate.
The plane arrived early.
I was hungry, so I went and grabbed a bite.
How is my uncle in Hong Kong?
He's a bit unwell, so I came instead.
He wrote me about you but didn't go into details.
How can you help me?
Please don't stand on ceremony
I'll personally help you.
Personally help me?
Do you understand my problem?
That you must tell me later.
But first, can you tell me where the toilet is?
Precious horse (BMW)?
Wild horse (Mustang)?
A flying horse?
Dad died recently,
and left me this restaurant.
Uncle Wang and the others
have helped out a lot.
Business wasn't bad
in the beginning.
Then a huge syndicate stepped in.
They're interested in our land
and wanted me to sell the restaurant.
There's no sale
without mutual agreement.
If you refuse, what can they do?
In theory, you're right
but they won't listen to reason.
They'll do anything for my land.
They hired some young thugs
to watch the place day and night.
If a customer comes in
they simply drive him away.
What am I to do?
Why not report it to the police?
They disappear when the police come.
We can't ask
for round-the-clock protection.
Business has gone down badly
and I still have to pay my workers.
How can I go on meeting the expenses?
The thugs have become worse lately
demanding an immediate answer.
So I wrote to my uncle for help.
I thought he'd send a lawyer, but...
I told you not to worry.
I am here to help.
Don't worry, Miss Chen.
It's nothing. I can take care of them.
Look up there!
That's their headquarters.
Make yourself at home.
I rent this place.
It's more convenient.
All the men live at the restaurant.
There's always a spare room
for my sick workers.
You can stay there for the time being.
You're my uncle's friend,
so please feel at home.
Let me know if you need anything.
May I use your toilet?
It's over there.
Chinese New Year is coming up,
do they celebrate it in Rome?
I haven't been back to HK in 12 years,
it certainly will take some
getting used to.
How's the restaurant business?
I live on a farm in the New Territories.
I practise martial arts every day.
Restaurants haven't changed much.
Take a seat.
Here's the key.
Our telephone numbers are on it.
The restaurant is nearby.
If you lose your way, show that card
and any taxi driver will bring you back.
Taxi? It's too expensive here.
Do they have public light buses?
Do you need some money?
No, I brought some with me.
Better put it in a bank,
it's safer that way.
No, it's safer and easier to carry it.
I won't argue. How much did you bring?
Not much.
Really, not much.
Still, I say it's safer in the bank.
Come!
Miss Chen! How are you? How are you?
This is Mr. Tang
He wants to deposit some money.
My friend.
How much money do you have, let's see it!
This way.
How much you want to change
into our currency?
How much local money will you change?
20 will do.
Lately the exchange rate has been bad.
That was the bank manager,
not a pickpocket.
You must be more polite.
Not everyone you meet is a villain.
Besides, I know that bank manager.
Foreigners are warm and polite.
When people smile, smile back,
that's politeness.
When someone puts an arm on your shoulder,
it's a sign of friendship
You should react the same way.
Remember that well!
Have a seat please!
Make yourself at home!
Ah Lung, you must be Ah Lung!
Welcome to Rome.
I'm Quen, from Miss Chen's restaurant.
Quen!
Miss Chen has returned to the restaurant.
She asked me to take you there.
By the way, where were you just now?
Let's go!
Ah Lung is back.
Ah Lung, this is Uncle Wang.
Uncle Wang.
Have a seat!
Quen, prepare some tea.
Ok...
It must have been
a long and tedious flight.
How do you like it here so far?
I'm certainly not used to things yet.
Doesn't matter, you will,
as time goes on.
It's been a long time since I was back home.
How are things in HK?
HK? I seldom went to town
when I was in the New Territories.
Have some tea.
Come, have some tea.
Thank you!
Why are there no customers?
With those thugs around,
who'd dare come here?
Ah Lung,
there are more workers training out back.
Let's go meet them.
Ok...
There's no business
so they spend their time exercising.
Come on!
Before Mr. Chen passed away,
they learned karate
to handle the villains.
Why didn't you take it up?
I'm not interested
in foreign martial arts.
It doesn't matter what style
if you can use your body well
even in the midst of violent movement,
to honestly express oneself.
I prefer Chinese boxing.
Do you know Chinese boxing?
Yes!
Really?
Let's take a breather.
Come here.
This is Tang Lung.
Introduce yourselves.
My name is Tony!
Jimmy!
Thomas!
Robert!
I've no English name.
Call me Ah Chuan.
Ah Chuan.
He looks like a typical Chinese boxer.
Have you learned any boxing?
Ah Lung came from HK to help us.
He's an expert Chinese boxer.
I'm just a novice.
Chinese boxing?
I understand it's like dancing.
But it sadly lacks power?
You lack power when you haven't
mastered the fundamentals
Right.
How then do you develop power?
By putting the hip into it.
Right.
Will you demonstrate
how to put the hip into it?
I'm afraid I'll hurt someone.
What are you afraid of?
They're wearing protective padding.
They won't get hurt.
We've guests coming.
Change and get to work.
Hurry!
Come on, let's go.
Change and get cracking!
Quen, where's the toilet?
Over there.
It's labelled in English.
Thank you!
Out, get the hell out of here, now!
Come on!
Get out!
Why?
That's why!
What's your decision?
Uncle Wang.
Yes.
Come quick, they're here again!
Stop it!
All right!
If you don't answer by tonight,
don't blame us for getting rough.
Please help us out,
put in a good word for us.
Give us a few more days to think it over.
You've been delaying a long time.
Are you or are you not selling?
Hey, don't you hit anyone.
Don't fight please!
We'll only wreck our own things.
Remember, by tonight you'd better
have an answer for us
Let's go!
Sorry!
Watch where you're going next time.
You don't even know a word of English.
Why did my Uncle send you here?
They're young and headstrong,
Don't blame them,
everything will be all right.
Lucky they weren't armed today.
In broad daylight?
They wouldn't dare use a gun in public.
If Uncle Wang hadn't stopped them...
I'd have used karate on them!
You can talk!
What good is your karate?
It's still better than Chinese boxing
People shove you out of the way
and you even apologised!
Sit down, sit down, please!
May I help you?
Can you help me?
Sure!
I'd like some Chinese spareribs.
Chinese spareribs?
Do you need me to tell you
what Chinese spareribs are?
Well let me show you!
What are you doing?
You know what we are doing,
don't they, fellas?
You all should have left
this restaurant!
Get Uncle Wang out here to help.
Stay calm. Don't wreck our place.
It's no use.
Do you want to step outside!
Sure!
Good!
Go...
Ah Lung, you...?
Let's go!
Jimmy... Jimmy...
Chinese boxing?
Damn!
They think this is Chinese boxing
If I knew Chinese boxing
I'd give them a good taste of it!
I'll go!
Tell him this is Chinese boxing
Hey! Chinese boxer!
The Dragon Set Movement No. Four
"Little Dragon Seeking Its Path"
"Big Dragon whipping its tail"
Ah Lung, bravo!
Magnificent!
Excellent!
Don't be overjoyed.
There'll be more trouble after this.
With Ah Lung's skill
those men will think twice now.
You don't understand.
It's hard to beat local hoodlums.
This is their territory.
We must be careful.
Let's be more patient.
More patience! Man, our Dragon is here!
You'd be wise to heed my advice.
Is that so?
Calm down, everyone.
Ah Lung, it's late, you must be tired.
Let's turn in.
Want some supper?
No, I must get up early for training.
I hear it's easy to buy a gun here?
Yes, any local citizen can get a licence.
What are you doing?
Making darts.
Darts?
What's the matter? Want to eat?
You can if you're as good as Ah Lung.
Better go practise your karate!
Is it for brother Lung?
Why didn't you say so?
Brother Lung!
Good morning, Brother Lung!
I made this especially for you.
Eat it while it's hot.
You're terrific.
Who was your teacher in HK?
Look at this!
Little Dragon seeking its path
"Big Dragon whipping its tail"
With that, all the enemies are down!
You said Chinese boxing lacks power.
I was only kidding.
Ah Lung, you were too fast yesterday.
We couldn't see clearly
Will you show us again?
Please show us.
Go on then!
Everyone says you're fast and powerful.
I didn't see it last night.
You said one must use the hip.
How about a demonstration?
Be quiet and let's watch, okay?
So shut up!
Step back!
Are you all right?
Everything all right?
Fantastic!
Ah Lung, will you be my teacher?
You said physical training is useless.
So why are you doing it now?
I never liked karate.
That's Chinese boxing, you dig?
We'll give up karate.
Let's learn from Ah Lung.
Right!
Customers! Come quick!
Change, on the double!
Ah Lung, no, Master, Master
I have to go take care the customer.
We'll talk later.
Is there anything for me to do?
Watch out for those villains.
My boss wants to see you!
What was that?
He wants us to see his boss.
Shut up! Now move!
See you tomorrow.
All of you are good for nothing!
You! Didn't you have a gun?
What I like, I get
and I want the restaurant.
Yes boss! Yes boss!
You've wasted enough time!
But, I... I always do my best.
Then why did you fail?
They're getting help
from a man called Tang Lung.
A man? Only one man?
But this man knows Chinese kung fu.
Kung fu?
Good morning. Sit down. Eat.
You won't often find this in Rome,
how does it taste?
It's not as good as in HK.
I cooked it, it's all right.
And you?
Want some more?
I'll take you around Rome later.
Wait!
Go on!
Move, move, come on!
Where's the man from HK?
Tell him to come out.
Where is he? Talk!
I don't know.
You'd better talk!
All right. He'll be back soon.
Where is he now?
These are famous relics of the past.
Over there... what is it?
Our slum is full of these wrecks.
Please.
A king built these gardens for his queen.
It took a lot of time and money.
They must have been really in love.
Are you married?
How do you like the palace?
Such a big place is a waste.
In HK I would build a skyscraper
and collect rent.
I'd better return to the restaurant.
Close the door.
You better cool it, baby.
Bring him down!
Chinese kung fu?
The boss means well.
He appreciates talent
and he knows you're strong.
Oh, what rippling muscle!
We don't want to harm you.
Here's a ticket back to HK.
Better to stay out of trouble.
All right! Take him away
but be careful with the gun in public.
Yes boss! Come on, let's go!
Go to see if anybody around?
Put your hands down! Put your hands down!
Listen, listen!
Boss, that bastard got away!
Go! Get him, but no gun!
Get him!
Let's get him!
Miss Chen, quit while you're ahead.
You'd better say yes.
We're offering you a good deal.
Hello!
Tell him.
We don't want any more trouble,
or else I will retaliate.
He told us not to come
and cause any more trouble.
Move them out.
Hurry up and pick up everybody.
Hold it, that's a customer.
Welcome!
Serve our guest properly.
See? I told you to be patient.
You should bear the responsibility for this.
What should we do now?
We'll fight to the end.
This is no joke.
I know, but...
I know how you feel
but we must think of Tang Lung.
They'll do what they say.
You mean...
Keep him under cover for awhile.
Tomorrow is Chinese New Year's
If there's trouble...
I don't know if he'll agree?
I know he's stubborn
You must persuade him.
Without him,
we'll be forced to sell the restaurant.
We'll have to see.
We may have to cooperate.
But we mustn't sell the place.
Let me decide.
All right.
Better go and talk to Lung.
Is your restaurant open tomorrow?
Good, we'll go to the countryside and practise.
Remind Quen to bring
the protective padding.
Firecrackers?
It's banned in HK.
There must be Chinese living nearby.
You must leave Rome for awhile.
Leave Rome?
We don't want you to go,
especially me, but you must.
Do you understand me?
I don't understand.
Ah Lung, why won't you...
Are you afraid of fire crackers?
I'll take you to the airport.
Why?
Those men want you...
My duty is to help you.
I know, but you must leave
They intend to kill you
Kill me? Who?
Time's up. Let's go!
It's too noisy. I'll close the window.
Stay here, don't move about.
Miss Chen!
Hello! May I help you?
Three... five...
Hello, what was that Sir,
can you please repeat that?
Hello... hello... hello...
Don't waste time.
Here's the agreement of sale.
Sign it!
No!
Why be so stubborn?
The boss has been nice to you.
If this knife crosses your face,
you'll look ugly.
So don't make our boss mad.
I won't sign!
It's for your own good.
We'll get the restaurant
sooner or later anyway.
Tang Lung will soon be here.
Tang Lung? You think he will come?
He's reporting to our Lord in Heaven!
Be careful.
The mastermind is over there.
You're crazy!
Let me tell you.
He doesn't understand Chinese.
Let's go.
I've thought of a great way
to handle that Tang Lung.
Do unto other's as you
would have them do unto you!
Well, among my friends
there is one Japanese martial artist
and one European martial artist
They are both strong
but the problem is they are from
different schools.
I'm afraid they might not
cooperate with each other.
Money will buy cooperation.
If money is not a problem.
Then I suggest we call America for Colt.
Is this Colt good?
Is Colt good? He is America's best!
You better pray
that you don't fail this time!
He will beat Tang Lung.
I'll bet my life on it.
Operator!
I'd like to call America.
Yes, A-me-ri-ca!
Happy New Year!
Thank you, Uncle Wang...
I didn't expect
traditional lucky money abroad.
Uncle Wang gives us lucky money yearly.
This is my best New Year ever.
First, we successfully defended
our restaurant,
and second, we have Ah Lung with us,
who's also our teacher.
Third, we finally beat the hoodlums.
Let's enjoy the new year
and skip the violence.
Here comes Ching Hua.
Happy New Year!
Come, this is for you.
Thank you, Uncle Wang
Ah Lung, a cable for you.
It's from my Uncle.
He wants you to go
somewhere to help someone.
Don't be like that. I'll be back.
I won't leave
until the whole thing is settled.
Happy New Year!
Beautiful decorations indeed.
What a warm gathering.
What do you want?
I came to bring greetings.
It was our fault. I must apologize.
We must all be friends.
Our boss would like to see Mr. Tang.
Would he do us the honor?
Wonderful.
Business will be good this year.
Tell your boss we'll be there.
Fine. Empress Restaurant
tomorrow morning, bye.
Just a minute please! Please, please!
We are friends.
Tang Lung is our enemy.
Please wait for our boss
to come back to decide.
Which one of you will take care
of that Chinaman?
Stop!
Sensei!
Bob's my student.
He will personally take care of Tang Lung.
Yes, boss!
Who can do karate better than the Japanese?
Wait! Now that we have decided.
Is everything arranged?
Yes, boss!
I'll meet them at the restaurant
early tomorrow morning.
You're here. Sit down.
Sorry our boss couldn't make it.
Why isn't he here?
Something urgent came up.
I'll have my car drive you over.
What? We're to go to him?
Never mind. Take us there!
Right! I like straight-talkers.
Let's go!
Where is he?
He's gone.
Forget it. He won't get away.
It's a trick. Be careful everyone!
Leave it to me, Teacher!
The three of us can handle him.
I'll go first.
You? Tang Lung?
Tang Lung.
Are you Tang Lung?
Leave it, he's already surrendered.
Ah Lung, we're lucky this time
not to have fallen into their trap.
Tang Lung, come if you dare!
Ah Lung, don't let him get away.
Tony and Jimmy can take the Japanese.
Tony, are you all right?
I'm hurting all over.
Uncle Wang, why...
Don't blame me, if you must,
blame it on Ah Lung
Yes, Ah Lung got you into this mess
He should not have get in my way.
You... what do you mean?
What do I mean?
Working men have no future.
I have worked hard for half my life
but own nothing.
My wife and children are waiting in HK
If the restaurant cooperates,
they'll pay me a big reward.
Then I can return to HK,
and enjoy luxury.
I've slogged away overseas
I'd like to enjoy an easy life.
Tang Lung, you've got guts.
The man you just saw will kill you.
Lung, you're at the end of your road.
You're at Death's door.
Ho!
Wang, we've failed.
Hold it!
We've been tricked
Tony and Jimmy... look!
Don't get emotional, please!
Listen to me, Mr. Tang.
Now that it's over. I must go.
I'll see you off.
No, Chuan has a car waiting.
Take good care.
In this world of guns and knives,
he's gonna need luck wherever he goes!