Hello, John.
-Hi, Bill.
-See you later.
-Okay, good bye.
Kent Marlowe. Manslaughter.
Sentenced to ten years.
-First time in prison?
-Yes.
Sir, to me.
-Yes, sir.
-How old are you?
-Twenty-four, sir.
Ever served in the army, navy,
marine corps?
No, sir.
-Use tobacco?
-Yes, sir.
Morphine, opium, cocaine?
No, sir.
Frisk him.
You can have your cigarettes.
-Married?
-No, sir.
That's my sister.
-You can have the photographs.
-Thank you, sir.
You'll get the rest back
when you leave prison.
From now on you'll be number 48642.
Give him the works.
Give him 24.
-Two blankets.
-Coat 36.
-Underwear 4.
-Pants 5.
-Shirt 16.
-Cap 7.
-Shoes 8 1/2.
Change your clothes in there.
-Arm length, 35, one half inches.
-35 1/2.
-Scar on the left fourth finger.
-Left fourth finger.
Out this way.
I hate to see a young fellow like you
in here for manslaughter.
It was an accident, sir.
Yes, I remember your case
very well.
-You ran a man down with your car...
-Yes, sir, It was New Year's Eve...
You were drunk.
-Yes, sir.
-Now you're here to pay for that crime...
with ten years of your life.
Do you realize that?
Yes, sir.
Your sentence can be reduced
by good behavior
and close observance of the prison rules.
While you're not in the
common sense of the word a criminal,
I want to warn you against
the influences you'll encounter here...
or In any other prison.
Yes, sir.
So you be careful of your conduct...
and your associations.
Yes, sir.
And remember this.
Prison does not give a man
a yellow streak.
but if he has one, it brings it out.
That's all.
Well, Raggart, what is it?
Do you know who they're putting
that boy in with?
No. Who?
Morgan. The slickest crook
we ever had here.
And Machine Gun Butch.
Yes?
A weak kid like that thrown in
with a murderer and a gun man?
Now, now, Pop, don't you get
chicken-hearted again.
He might have a chance
in a cell alone.
Yes, I warned them at the last
governor's council.
We have 3,000 here
and cell accommodations for 1800.
They all want to throw people
into prison
but they don't want to provide
for them after they are in.
And you mark my word, Pop.
Someday we're going to pay
for this shortsightedness.
Sure, the whole prison system
is cockeyed.
-Yeah?
-Here's a peach for you, Sandy.
-Goes In 265 with Butch and Morgan.
-Okay.
Come on, boy.
Upstairs to the left.
Here we are.
Hello, Jim.
Take off your ear muffs.
I said hello.
Hello.
Make yourself at home.
That's your flop up there.
Thank you.
What's your name?
I said what's your name?
Kent Marlowe.
Mine's Schmidt.
I'm known the world over
as Machine Gun Butch.
You heard of me. That's a cinch.
You never heard of the Delancey gang
being wiped out?
Well, I done the wipin'.
$500 bucks for bumping off three.
That ain't much, it's cheap.
What's your racket?
What you in for?
-Manslaughter.
-Manslaughter!
Well, you ain't no morning glory
after all.
Press the flesh.
Who did you croak?
-It was an accident.
-An accident?
Yeah, I was driving a car...
-Oh, you're all wet ears.
Your nose ain't even dry.
-What do you mean?
-I'll show you what I mean, kid.
I'll learn you a lot of things
before we're through with you in here.
Morg, there's company in the parlor.
Morgan is my name.
Kent's mine.
How are you?
Don't you ever have any air in here?
Sure, plenty. All hot.
How long have you been here?
Three years.
-What for?
-Robbery.
I can't stand thieves.
-Hey, my cigarettes.
-What?
You took my cigarettes.
Why, you dirty little liar,
you didn't have no cigarettes.
Yes, I did, and you stole them.
Stop your belly aching
before I slough you one.
Come on, give me back
those cigarettes.
You're dingy, you didn't have no cigarettes.
Give me those cigarettes!
-Oh, get out!
-I'll show you crooks
I won't stand for treatment like this.
Hey, guards!
Stop your squawking.
Crooks, are we?
-Well, Mr. High Hat, I'll show...
-Let go of me!
Pipe down, pipe down...
Hey, hey, what's wrong in here?
-He took my cigarettes.
-Did he, Morgan?
I don't know, sir.
I was asleep.
Did you take the kid's cigarettes?
No, sir...
They're both lying!
Less noise or you'll spend
your first night in the dungeon.
Aw, don't put the kid in the cooler.
He's clean.
He just went off his nuts.
He won't do it again.
Well, you watch your stuff,
understand?
Well, mister yellowbelly, you're gonna get
your first lesson right now.
You can't squeal and in stir.
That's that.
Now lay off that stuff, Butch,
do you hear?
Aw, he's only stunned.
I didn't bat him hard.
-Put him in his bunk.
-Yeah?
Yeah.
Okay.
Now give him back his cigarettes.
-What?
-You heard me.
Why, I ain't got his old weeds.
Don't lie to me, Butch.
Say, listen, I bumped off guys
for calling me a liar.
Yeah, and look where you are now.
-Who me?
-Yes, you.
Well, look where you are too.
That's right, Butch, both of us.
The quick and the dead,
the clever and the dumb.
What?
You know, from the neck down
you're a regular guy, Butch.
Now give the kid back his cigarettes.
-Who me?
-Yes, you.
Okay.
I was only kidding.
-Just kidding, that's all.
-Sure, I knew that all the time.
Now put them up in his pocket.
I said put them up in his pocket.
Gee!
It reminds me of Sadie.
Gee, Sadie was a good old skirt.
I shouldn't have slipped her
that ant poison.
I should've just battered her
in the jaw a few times.
-Get off of my stones, will ya?
-Get back into line there.
You got everything all set?
Sure, this time...
We heard you're slated
to get out soon.
What do you mean?
Who told you that?
Jim, the trusty over at the warden's office.
He's in on everything.
And he heard something about me?
Yeah, the warden said you're
too nice a kid to keep here.
-They're gonna let me go?
-Sure they are.
How soon?
Just as soon as the warden gets
the ok from the governor.
-Gee, you're a lucky guy.
-Are you Kent Marlowe?
-Yeah.
-Wallace wants to see you.
What does he want to see me for?
To tell you the good news,
that you've been pardoned.
Gee, that's great.
Wait a minute.
Aren't you gonna say good bye?
Sure, good bye.
Be good, Kent. So long, kid.
Hey, where are you heading?
-Captain Wallace wants to see me.
-You can't go in there. Get back.
What's going on out here?
They said you wanted to see me, sir,
about my parole.
Who said that?
They did, that trusty over there...
It's true, isn't It?
They weren't ribbing me, were they?
Sure, they're kidding you, Kent.
Then I'm not going out.
No, you're going to be with us
for a long time.
Go on, beat it.
Sore are you?
What's the matter, boy?
Are you going home?
Hey, you. No ganging up here.
Come on, keep this place clear.
Scatter out.
Hey, Pop, any letters for me?
Move on, now. If there was,
I wouldn't give them to you.
Oh, go on, be a sport,
will you?
Are there any letters for Morgan?
You know, Pop,
if all screws were like you...
Oh, you cut out the apple sauce.
And don't be calling the guards screws.
Yes, sir.
No letters for you, Morgan.
But I've got one for Butch and Kent.
Fine, I'll take them to them.
Thanks, Pop.
-I used to milk a cow all the time.
-Letter for you, Butch.
-Letter for me?
-Yes, you.
Gee, why don't those dames
let me alone?
You're such a deal, Butch.
You can't blame them.
Where's Kent?
Haven't seen him.
Hey, stick around.
I'll bet this is a hot one.
Oh, boy.
Look at that.
Why, it's from Myrtle.
-Myrtle?
-Yeah.
-I thought you croaked her.
-No, that was Sadie.
This girl is nuts about me.
-About you?
-Yes, me.
Wait a minute, I'll show you.
"Dear sweetheart..."
"How I miss my great big boy."
"You have it."
Hot doggy.
"The only fun I get is sleeping...
because then I dream
about you every night."
The rest of this
is too juicy for you guys.
Nobody gets to read this
but me and my pal Morg.
Come on, Morg.
Aw, come on.
Go on, dream about it.
I'm going to read this.
You and me, Morg.
Hey, come on, scram.
-Hey, what's the big idea?
-Get out of here, go on, go on.
Say, Morg...
Who do you suppose
would write me a letter?
I'll read It to you, Butch.
Say, if I even knew
a dame called Myrtle,
I'd kick her teeth out.
Go on, read it.
Who's it from?
Well, it's about your mother, Butch.
-My old lady?
-Yeah.
Gee, she's been holding out on me.
I didn't even know she could write.
Well, It isn't from her, Butch.
It's from a guy named Tony Loop.
-It's about...
-Nothing wrong. Go on, read it.
"Dear Butch,
when your mother was sick,
"She didn't want me
to write no letter and tell you,
"Even when
they took her to the county hospital.
"I went to see her
a couple of times,
"And she said you
had enough to worry
"Without having
to think about her.
"Anyway, she...
"She died yesterday.
"And as we couldn't get enough money
to give her a send-off,
"we had to let the hospital
take care of it.
"Anyway, we sent her
a bunch of flowers,
"And I guess that's all.
Yours truly, Tony Loop."
Gee, I can't believe it, Morg.
Ma's dead.
-I wonder if it hurt her much.
-Oh, I don't think so, Butch.
-She probably just dropped off quietly.
-Yeah?
Yeah, she was pretty old,
wasn't she?
About 70...
And as big as a minute...
And game.
And, say, the last time
I was arrested,
She fought like a wildcat.
It took two bulls
to hold her,
and she almost bit
the thumb off of one of them.
Gee, she was a swell old lady.
I wish you would have
met her, Morg.
So do I, Butch.
Say, Morg...
I'm going to make
a break.
I'm going to get out of here,
and I'm going to give
that little old lady
the swellest funeral she ever had.
Pipe down, will you?
Here comes Oliver.
Hello, Morgan. Got a match?
Sure.
Thanks.
Good news, Butch?
Bad news whenever you come around.
Great kidder, isn't he, Morg?
Yes, and he's not always kidding.
You know, that guy's
a stool pigeon if ever there was one.
I wish I could get
the lowdown on him.
I'll knife him
someday.
Aw, that kind of talk
won't get you anywheres.
I'm going to break
this place wide open.
Yeah, and then what will happen to you?
Down in the dungeon with the rats.
No, we got to take our medicine, Butch.
It's all right for you to talk,
you'll be going out of here
in a few years.
But what do I gain
eating this dirt?
I'd go nuts if I
didn't start trouble once in a while.
I'd rather stand up and fight,
and even if I got the rope,
It's better than sitting here rotting
in this stinking hole.
Aw, cut out that talk, Butch,
do you hear?
-Who, me?
-Yes, you.
Okay.
I was only kidding.
Sure.
Hey, listen, Butch.
How about that hot number of yours?
The gang wants to hear it again.
Go on, read it.
All right, I'll read it once more.
Seen Kent around anywhere?
Yeah. He's around the corner
with Oliver.
What about Morgan?
Morgan?
Who knows anything about him?
But Butch... listen, Oliver.
That guy will kill me someday.
-He packs a knife.
-Oh, he packs a knife, does he?
Don't let that worry you.
That knife's gonna get him into trouble.
Say, listen, you guys.
If I ever catch either one of you
double-crossing Butch,
I'm going to get you.
Do you understand?
-Now, Kent, you keep away from this rat.
-What do you mean?
He's the only guy that's been decent
to me since I've been here.
I was only trying
to give him some good advice.
Yeah?
Well, beat it, do you hear?
I'll give you some good advice, Kent.
You're in a tough spot.
But you've got to learn that whining
and double-crossing
isn't going to get you anywhere.
I'm not whining.
I won't stand for your ribbing.
What right have they got to poke at me...
And you, a robber, bragging about it?
Oh, I see. Too good
for the rest of us, huh?
Well, if you're wise, you'll stand up
and take your joe like a regular guy.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Here's a letter for you.
Get wise, kid.
Play up to Morgan and Butch.
They run the joint here,
and if they're off you,
they'll make it tough for you.
If you're friends with them,
they'll let you in on their plans.
What do you mean?
I'll tell you later.
Oh, I wouldn't do that.
Kid, you trust me.
I'm your friend.
These three dames
were crazy about me, see.
Say, Butch...
Butch, I had a dream last night.
Aw, cut It out. You're full of hop.
A dame said to me, she said,
"if you'll come up...
I...I...I was sitting on a velvet cushion,
And--and about a thousand
beautiful blue-eyed blondes
was dancing all around me.
Aw, gee, I'd go nutty
over a rag doll.
Hey, look.
Ohh... look!
Look. A beautiful butterfly!
Aw, you're crazy.
That's a racehorse.
Look at that sucker run.
I bet he'll make to the top
of the wall in 10 seconds.
Say, look at the build
on that filly.
I'll take the thin one, Butch.
This is mine.
Say, what'll you bet my racehorse
can't trim that one of yours?
You're on.
Hey, Mr. Butch, I'll hold the stakes.
Yeah, who's gonna hold you?
Come on, get up your cigarettes.
Let's have a race here.
Come on, put them out there.
All right, you boys,
make your bets.
I'll cover all your bets.
Two packs of weeds
on my thin one.
All right, make all your bets.
Cover this, Butch.
I'm betting on Morgan's bug.
Come on. Get in there.
I'm covering.
Say, listen, you... what about these?
No, you...you can't
because The Hawk gave me this
to buy him a pair
of s-s-suspenders with,
and if I don't bring them back,
he'll tear my head off.
Aw, come on.
Get in there with them.
Oh, yeah. s-s-s-sure.
All right. Come on, now.
All right, come on, now,
give me the bugs.
I'll warm them up.
All right.
Here you go.
Watch them run.
You all ready?
You all set?
All right, there they go.
Look at him go.
Look at that bug go.
Hey, Butch, your b-b-b-bug
There he goes. Over the line,
over the line.
I win. I win.
That's just too bad.
Chewing gum.
I say, no wonder that bug
couldn't run.
Chewing gum, eh?
Who done that?
Come on.
What porch-climbing crook done that?
You did.
-Who, me?
-Yes, you.
What's the big idea?
You wouldn't double-cross
a pal, would you, Butch?
Any more of you guys
think I pulled a phony?
-You, Joe?
-Not me.
-You, Putnam?
-N-No.
-You can't get away with that, Butch.
-No?
You're asking for it, ain't you?
One wiggle out of you
and I'll give it to you.
Listen, you guys are liable
to get the hole for this.
Yeah, you'll get the hole,
just 5' 10".
They'll have to dig it
big enough for two.
-Oh, yeah?
-Yeah!
Look out, Butch!
Ditch that knife.
Here comes Wallace.
Well, what's coming off here?
Me and Morgan was just
rassling a bit, sir.
Sure you weren't mixing up
a little fighting with it, huh?
Who, me?
No, sir.
You better not, or I'll fix up
a lot of dark days for you.
-Gambling, huh?
-No, sir. Not me.
How did those cigarettes
and tobacco get here?
Well, uh... I was packing them
in my shirt, sir,
and Morgan and me
starts rassling, and I get sweaty,
so I lay them out
on the ground to dry.
-Don't lie to me.
-I wouldn't lie, no, sir.
-Let them alone.
-What's that you said?
I said, yes, sir.
Another move out of you,
and you'll go to the dungeon.
-Who did that?
-I did, wrestling with Butch.
Well, the next time I see you,
you better have it fixed.
You get me?
Bring that stuff.
I hate his guts.
It's a good thing I warned you.
If Wallace had seen that knife...
Yeah. You ain't such a bad skunk
as I thought you was.
-Get a move on, all of you!
-I'll move. I'll move.
I'll move...
Fish again.
-That dirty, rotten, stinkin' codfish.
-Yeah. It's spoiled.
Oh, look!
It's so terrible it's even killed one
of our poor little b-b-bu--
...cockroaches.
Ohh...
Nice tenderloin steak
with mushrooms all over it, gee!
I'd like to ram it down their throat.
-Pipe down, Wallace.
You talking, Butch?
Who, me?
No, sir.
-I'll get him someday.
-He's on the hunt, Butch.
Tell the guys to pipe down.
Pipe down.
I can't eat that stuff!
Who did that?
Me!
What do you think of that?
I want some food.
I don't want any more of this swill!
-Shut up!
-You give me some food to eat!
-I'm not going to eat that junk!
-Shut up, all of you!
Come on, now!
Come on!
Give us some food!
I ain't afraid of your guns!
I ain't afraid of nobody!
Come on, you yellowbellies!
Let's show 'em!
That volley went against the wall.
The next time, shoot to kill!
Butch, sit down!
-Yellowbellies! Cowards!
-Sit down, Butch!
It's your last chance!
Cover all the entrances.
Listen to me, you men.
I have treated you squarely,
and you know it.
If you got any grievances
within my power to correct,
...come to me!
You can't gain anything
by starting a row like this.
So I'm warning you
for the last time.
I'm running this show,
and I'm ready for you.
That's all.
Wallace!
Who started this?
Butch.
Take him out!
The knife...
What?
The knife.
Butch, in the aisle.
-Search him!
-I ain't got nothin'.
No hard feelings, see?
-Nothing on him, sir.
-You had a knife.
-Who, me?
-Yes, you!
-No, sir. Someone's been stringing you.
-In the dungeon!
What for?
I was only kidding.
Sure, I understand.
Well, that little joke will just cost you...
30 days on bread and water in the dark!
Come on. Move on!
I'm sorry about Butch.
-You're what?
-I say, I'm sorry about Butch.
Yeah?
-Who is it?
-Your lawyer.
-Hello, John.
-Hello, Canton. What's up?
-Got a little surprise for you.
-Yeah?
Kid, I got good news for you.
You're gonna be paroled.
Yeah? When?
20 years from now?
Don't be funny. You're gonna leave
this joint tomorrow.
Tomorrow?
Aw, quit your kidding.
I'm not kidding. It's all settled.
Just came from the warden's office.
Yeah?
The next time you'll play it smart.
You say...
Hello, sis.
What's the matter?
You look so pale.
You're not ill, are you?
No, no, but you don't know
how terrible it is here.
What have they done
to get me out?
I'm sorry, dear.
What do you mean?
We've done everything.
I saw the governor myself.
He was very kind.
He said he couldn't do anything.
What kind of a dame
would you like to have me get for you?
Any kind.
How'd you like
a little gal like that?
Say, you're a lawyer, not a magician.
Okay, kid.
I'll be around here with a car
in the morning to pick you up.
-Fine.
-So long.
Oh, Kent, please. I know
you're big enough to see it through.
You've got to.
But you don't know what It's like In here.
Every hour, every minute...
It's torture. I'll go crazy.
Honey, but, listen.
You've got to...
Anne, listen.
Tell them to try again.
All right. All visitors out!
Good-Bye, good-bye,
good-bye..
Good-bye.
Bad news, kid?
I got to serve out
my full time.
No, you haven't.
If you get the goods on somebody,
you get plenty of time off.
And if you block a big job,
it may open the gates for you.
Thanks.
How are you?
[Speaking Russian]
Oh, you're going to be
a great comfort around here.
-Who's that?
-New guy to take Butch's place.
Doesn't speak any English.
What are you doing?
I'm going out
of here tomorrow.
I thought you had
another year.
Yeah, I did,
but good behavior got me off.
And that's a very good thing
for you to remember.
Think of it.
Bright lights, good food, women!
Say, I saw that sister of yours
in the visitors' room just now.
Yeah?
Yeah. That the girl
that owns the bookstore?
-Yeah.
-Swell-Looking kid.
You know, I think it's great, Kent,
the way your family stick by you.
Gee, I wish I had a family.
I haven't even got a home.
Outside, all of you. Come on, Rasputin.
Frisking party.
[Speaking Russian]
-[Speaking Russian]
-Shut up!
This your coat, Morgan?
Yes, sir, but that's not my knife.
No. It's Butch's knife.
You know that.
Smart, eh?
-Trying to cover up Butch.
-No, I wasn't, sir.
You don't think I'd be crazy enough
to do a thing like that
-...the day before I go out, do you?
-Shut up!
Well, this'll just cost you your parole.
-Oh, you can't do that, sir.
I tell you, I never saw that knife before.
It was planted on me.
-Ahh...
-I came In the cell,
took off my coat, laid it on the bunk.
There was no one In there
but this fellow and...
and then Kent...
You did that.
-I didn't do it!
-Don't lie to me!
I didn't do it...
I guess the dungeon
will cool him off a bit. Strip him!
I'll get you
for this, Kent!
Do you hear me?
I'll get you for this!
-On your way.
-Do you hear me? I'll get you!
Shut up.
Cell 48.
Hello!
Who are you?
Morgan.
Morgan, they got you?
Yeah. Where are you, Butch?
Second hole away from you.
What happened?
They found your knife on me.
-My knife?
-Yeah.
You mean it was planted on you.
Who done it?
-Never mind who.
-You tell me, old pal.
I'll get him
the first day I'm outside.
I'll get him myself.
Oh! I knocked over my cup of water!
Oh, forget it, kid!
They'll bring you another cup
tomorrow night, the bighearted buzzards!
Can that noise, will you?
Hey, Morg!
When I get out of here,
I'm gonna make a break, do you hear me?
Yeah?
Yeah, I'll do it if I have to kill
a flock of screws.
How?
-I'm going to use my brains.
-Ha! Your what?
Well, maybe I ain't got no brains,
but I got strength, you hear me?
Sure.
Hey, when my time's up,
I'll bet you I'll still be standing on my feet.
-You hear that, Morg?
-Yeah.
And you... I bet you'll travel
out of here feet first.
You know, that's a swell idea.
-Oh, what do you mean, a swell idea?
Use your brain!
# Goin' home...
I'm a goin' home. #
I wish you would go home.
# Quiet life... #
Gee, but he was a s-s-swell guy,
And s-s-smart, too.
One time he d-d-dug himself
out from underneath a w-w-wall,
And It took him 18 months
to do it in.
Yeah? What did he do
with the dirt?
Oh, he... he ate it.
Well, he s-s-said he did.
Aw, dry up.
That plan of mine would be all right
if we had somebody to work it out.
Yeah, Morgan's the guy to do it.
You know, he and Butch
finish their stretch in the hole today.
Come out of there, Butch.
Come on, come on,
get out of there.
Oh, I'm coming out. I'm...
Well, I'm still on my feet.
Get Morgan out.
I ain't heard his voice now
for a week.
I told him he'd come out
of there feet first.
He's flat on his back.
Bring in a stretcher.
Get Tony out.
You dirty screws! You croaked my pal.
I'll get you for this.
Shut up, or you'll spend
30 days more in the hole.
Morg...
I was only kidding... just kidding,
that's all.
Son of a...
-He's just a weak-kneed guy.
-He ain't got no backbone.
But me, I'm on my feet.
-Shut up!
-Take Morgan to the hospital.
Come on. Let's go.
96.
100.
Slight congestion.
-Doctor?
-Yes?
-Carter has just passed away.
-Carter? Oh, yes.
Put him in the morgue.
Have the wagon
take him away tonight.
Yes, sir.
-Will he be all right, doctor?
-Oh, yes. Yes, I think so.
Number's 44789.
Watch the Canadian border.
Watch the best hotels.
That's his racket.
That's the first break
we've had here in five years.
-We'll get him, though.
-How did he make his getaway?
-Went out in the dead wagons.
-Well done.
I beg your pardon.
Good evening.
If you'll just look around,
I'll be with you in a minute.
Thanks. I'm in no hurry.
-Here's your book, Mr. Garrett.
-How much is that?
$2.00.
-Thank you. Good night.
-Good night.
Have you found what you wanted?
No, I haven't.
-Well, just what were you looking for?
-A book on the Pacific Islands.
A romance?
No, no. Something that would give me
an idea of the life there.
Oh.
I'm quite sure I have something
in a new shipment that came today.
I'll go and get it
if you don't mind waiting a few minutes.
Not a bit, no.
May I help?
Why, yes.
Thank you.
I was just going to look
in these boxes.
I think the picture... the, uh, travel books
are in the bottom one.
Here, let's have a look.
Here. let me help.
Well, thank you.
You don't mind, do you?
Why, no.
Of course not.
It's lovely of you
to go to all this... all this trouble.
Not at all.
I'm glad to help.
-You know, it's a fun--
-Stay where you are!
I thought I recognized you, Mr. Morgan.
I saw you in the visitors' room
at the prison.
Yes, I remember you, too.
Hello... hello.
Give me... give me Police Headquarters.
Yes, please.
Never mind.
Well, why didn't you
go through with it?
Because...
Well, because I just couldn't send you
back there, that's all.
You may go now, Mr. Morgan.
I'll take that gun.
Thanks.
Oh, good evening.
Hello, Miss Marlowe.
Oh, excuse me.
I didn't know you had company.
Oh, that's quite all right.
My friend, Mr. Everett,
Sergeant Donlin.
-Glad to meet you, Mr. Everett.
-Same here, Sergeant.
Face is kind of familiar.
-Haven't I met you somewhere?
-No, I don't think so, Sergeant.
-No?
-No.
No.
Well, maybe not.
Mr. Everett is one
of my best customers.
Is that so?
I thought it was past your closing time
till I saw the lights.
Well, it is, but we were unpacking
some books.
Oh, I see.
Mrs. Donlin like the book I sent her?
Huh?
Yes.
Well, I have another one that
I'm sure she'll be crazy about.
Fine.
I'll get it for you.
It's In the next room.
Don't bother.
She'll drive in tomorrow.
Oh, what's that?
The boys are after someone, I guess.
Well, I'll be running along.
-I'm glad to have met you, Mr...
-Everett.
-Good night, Mr. Everett.
-Good night, Sergeant.
-Good night, Miss Marlowe.
-Good night.
Thanks.
Why did you come here?
To square a bad deal
I got from someone in prison.
What do you mean?
Well, I was framed.
They took my parole away from me
the day before I was to go free.
Do you know who framed you?
Yeah. Yeah, I think I know.
Well, good night, Miss Marlowe.
I won't bother you again.
-Are you going away?
-Perhaps. I don't know.
I think I understand your bitterness.
If you're ever around here again...
drop in.
-Oh, you don't mean that.
-Of course I do.
Gee, you're a peach of a girl.
I picked him up one night
and trailed him to a bookstore.
-He goes under the name of Everett.
-Everett?
Who is she? Is she blond?
He's Morgan, all right, all right.
Plenty smart, too.
I lost track of him
for a couple of weeks.
When I found him,
he was actually working.
I sent out a man
to spot him.
That night
he quit his job.
Working?
Must be a woman in the case.
Yeah.
I know the woman, too.
Then you got a line on him.
Sure. I haven't
lost one yet, have I?
All right, Eddie.
Let's go.
Hello, Dick, how are you?
Glad to see you.
Where's your sister?
She's in the backyard.
-Hello, Anne.
-Hello, darling.
-How are you?
-Fine.
Good afternoon, everyone.
How are you, Mr. Marlowe?
Oh, fit as a fiddle.
Younger than ever.
Me, too.
-Mrs. Marlowe, how are you today?
-I'm fine, thank you.
Anne tells me you're going away,
Mr. Everett.
-We're going to miss you.
-That's awfully nice of you.
You know, coming here
has meant a great deal to me.
Oh, you must stay for dinner.
We're going to have corn bread
and fried chicken.
-And strawberry shortcake.
-Better stop. I'm liable to miss that train.
- Oh, you're not going that soon.
-Yes. Leaving in an hour.
-Oh, that's too bad.
-Oh...
I know somebody
that's going to miss you.
Why, dad!
Don't "why, dad" me.
I wasn't born yesterday.
No. Me, neither.
She's been sighing around all morning.
I wondered what was the matter.
Now, Dad, I'm ashamed of you.
Come on, John.
Don't listen to him.
-You're so subtle, Dad.
-Yeah, I can't help It. I...
Oh, now, don't pick on me, Ma.
You love it!
Oh, I'm glad to see Anne happy again.
Well, Anne, I hate to go.
Oh, you'll
come back someday.
I don't think so.
The minute that dick walked into
that place where I was working
I knew there was no chance
for me to continue on here.
Wouldn't it be better
if you went back to prison
and served out your time?
No. They'd give me
seven more years of it.
I've got a pretty good grip
on myself, Anne,
and I'd like to make a new start.
And my only hope is in some other
country where they can't get me.
Well, I suppose you're right.
But I... we'll miss you.
Will you really?
You know I will.
Anne, I have no right
to tell you this, but...
you know, I get sort of
a choky feeling...
every time I think I'm never
going to see you again.
Oh, don't be angry at me
for saying that, will you?
I'm not angry.
You see, It's the only way
I have of telling you
how much your friendship
has done for me.
Thanks.
What are you going to do?
-Work. Does that please you?
-Hm-Hmm.
You know, as soon as I get
to the islands...
I'm going to get a little plantation.
I've heard of a chap
who made a fortune out there.
Oh, that sounds marvelous.
Doesn't it?
You know, if it weren't for you,
I wouldn't mind going.
And yet, if it weren't for you,
I wouldn't be going.
Gosh, how are you
going to figure that one out?
I don't know.
Hello, Morgan.
Let's see what you've got on you.
I guess you didn't know who
this fellow really was, Miss Marlowe.
That's too bad.
Sergeant, please.
Wait a minute.
I'm sorry this had
to happen here, Anne.
But I...
Now let's get going.
Oh, mother!
I love him!
Oh, if they'd only give him
another chance!
You're going to find things
tougher than ever here.
The state has closed the mill.
You know what idleness
does to a man.
So you'd better watch your step.
Yes, sir.
All right, Morgan.
Let's go.
Yes, sir.
We're gonna have a lot more trouble
with that bird, you'll see.
I think you're wrong,
Wallace.
I believe he wants
to go straight.
Straight?
Two weeks with the old gang
and he'll be right back where he was.
Maybe.
I hope not.
Hello, Morg.
Get back over that deadline
or I'll knock your block off.
-Who, me?
-Yes, you.
Pop's getting tough.
How's all the dames outside?
See my initials carved on many
bedposts, Morg?
-How have you been, Butch, huh?
-Oh, okay.
You know, the food's
getting worse here, too.
Hello, Morg.
How are you?
Well, what's the gang
been up to, Butch?
Planning.
Six of us is going right out
through that gate.
You aren't kidding me, are you?
No, I'm giving it to you straight.
-Me and the gopher framed it.
-The gopher?
Why, he's been the prison gardener
for seven years.
Sure.
He's had an idea
in the back of his bean, though.
There he goes now.
For three months, every day
he's been going to that gate.
The screw's used to it,
don't pay no attention to him.
Yeah?
Every once in a while, why, he has
an extra big bunch of flowers,
and the screw opens
the gate, savvy?
I see. And you six guys go through,
is that it?
-Sure. Simple, ain't it?
-Sure.
What happens when you get
through the inner gate?
We crash that outer gate
and there's a car waiting.
-When does it come off?
-Thanksgiving Day at noon.
Most of the screws
go home to turkey dinner.
We'll give them a bellyful.
You know it means the rope, Butch,
if they catch you.
Who's in on it?
Well, me, and Olsen,
and Joe. and The Hawk.
-The Hawk? That means blood.
-No...
he promised me
he wouldn't bump nobody off.
-Why, he croaked his own mother.
-Sure he did.
He cut her throat.
He was sorry for her.
He's all right.
Anybody else
in on it?
Well, there's that
big Swede and Kent...
Kent?
Say, listen, you're all wrong
about that Kent guy.
It was a Russian that planted
that knife on you, not Kent.
We caught him doing
the same thing to another guy.
Yeah?
Sure.
I was sure it was Kent.
No. After you
made your getaway,
they put the gopher in the same cell
with me and Kent, see?
Kent ain't in on the plans,
but he's got to go out with us.
We ain't tellin' nobody
till we get ready to make the break,
outside of you.
Not for me, Butch.
I'm going straight.
You wouldn't kid an old friend,
would you?
- You got me all wrong, Butch...
-Hello, Morgan!
But I just don't play
a sucker's game, that's all.
-How are you?
-Hey, listen...
don't let that gang know
that you're going straight.
They used to have
a lot of respect for you.
Hello, Morg.
Welcome b-b-back home.
Hey, listen,
don't gang up here.
Come on. Take a powder,
take a powder.
See you later, Butch.
Hey, you.
Come here, you.
Let's see that book.
Where's that Bride's Confession
I told you to get me?
-Well... well, you see, it's wor-worn out.
-Well, you get me Sappho.
Say, you don't mind if I take
a powder, do you, Mr. B-B-B-Butch?
Oh, go on, scram.
Scram.
Hey, Kent.
I want to talk to you.
Morgan, I want to
explain to you about that knife...
Yeah, Butch told me
all about it.
What you've done doesn't interest me.
It's what you're going to do.
Are you in on this break?
-Yeah, they took me in on it.
-I know. It's dynamite.
They haven't told me
all their plans yet.
You keep out of it, do you hear?
Not that I care about you.
But I met that family
of yours, Kent.
They think the world of you.
Now, you've caused them
enough trouble,
and if anything more happens to you,
they'd never get over it.
So you keep out of this break.
It's murder,
and you'll hang for it.
Hey, you.
Morgan trying
to turn you against the gang?
Yeah, that's what
he was doing, all right.
You wouldn't think it
of him, would you?
Aw, he's a rat.
I wonder
what Butch will say.
Think I'd better go
and tell him.
All right.
You tell him.
This guy could catch
fish with his hands.
He'd reach under the rocks
and get a hold of the fish...
Hey, Butch, you take Morgan in?
Morg? Sure.
-You sure he's going with us?
-Sure, he is. He can't wait.
-Don't lie to me.
-Who, me?
-Why, I never told a lie in my life.
-You know he's not going with us.
I just heard him telling Kent
to keep out of it.
-Yeah?
-Yeah.
Said it looked like
a trap to him. Get me?
You suppose Morgan
will go yellow?
-Who, Morg?
-Well, something's changed him.
Yeah, something's changed him.
You don't suppose
he'd rat on us?
-What's that you said?
-You don't think he'd squeal?
Say, listen,
he wouldn't squeal on nobody.
He's changed. That's all right.
But I'll croak the first guy
that says he's a double-crosser.
So Kent's got his ear
to the ground,
and he'll soon have plenty
to tell us.
He thinks the gang
have guns,
but he doesn't know
where they're hidden.
I promised him we'd
cut his time in half
if he brought us this information.
Stool pigeons.
I wish we could
run this place without them.
-Yeah, well, we can't.
-Who's in on it?
All of Butch's gang.
How about giving them solitary?
That would only
keep them quiet for a few weeks.
It isn't any one group.
It's 3,000 idle men
with nothing to do but brood and plot.
You can't put them all in solitary.
We can crush them.
That's what's
happening to them right now.
We've tried to crush them,
with this result.
You search every corner of this prison,
but you find those guns.
Don't worry, sir.
If those guns are here,
I'll have them on your desk
before Thanksgiving Day.
And now to record
our thankfulness
on this glad Thanksgiving Day,
let us rise and sing hymn
number 84.
Ring the bells of heaven.
There is joy today.
A lost lamb is returning
From his sinful way.
Glory, glory.
How the angels sing.
Loud hosannas ring...
with songs of thanksgiving...
Let our voices ring.
Today's the day.
Hear the angels sing.
Open the gates,
Open the gates
Open the gates and let
the king of glory in.
Open the gates,
open the gates,
open the gates and let
the King of Glory in.
And now let us kneel
in prayer.
Our father, who art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name.
Thy kingdom come,
thy will be done
on earth as it is in heaven.
Give us this day
our daily bread
and forgive us our trespasses,
as we forgive those
who trespass against us.
And lead us not into temptation,
but deliver us from evil,
for thine is the kingdom,
and the power, and the glory,
forever and ever. Amen.
The Lord bless you and keep you,
both now and forevermore.
Amen.
Noon.
Noon, Swede.
Come on, scram.
-Butch, what's the dope?
-Noon. Watch me.
Don't go through with it, Butch.
It's a trap. They'll get you.
We'll get through,
if someone don't double-cross us.
They'll mow you down.
Wallace.
- Morgan?
-Yes, sir?
I want to see you
in my office.
Yes, sir.
Who's in on this break?
I don't know anything
about a break.
Morgan, you're a liar.
They've got guns hidden somewhere.
You know where they are.
If I did, I wouldn't tell you.
What kind of a rat
do you think I am?
Not even if we opened
the gates for you?
Is that all you've
got to say to me?
I'll have plenty
to say to you later.
Hold him here.
I can't get anything
out of Morgan, sir.
Don't worry.
I've got the dope from Kent.
-The break is set for noon.
-Noon?
Just one minute.
What are they going to do?
Kent couldn't tell me.
I've doubled the gun guards.
Don't you worry.
Where is he?
Why doesn't he come?
There he is.
Frost is beginning to kill the flowers,
so I picked a whole lot today.
-Make a big bunch, don't they?
-Fine. Thank you.
Grab all those guns.
Get those screws
and take them to the cellar.
Joe! Joe!
-What do you want, Butch?
-We've been double-crossed!
Yes! Morgan done it.
Morgan!
I'll get that guy
if it's the last thing I do.
Joe! Get those screws,
put them in the hole.
We'll need them later.
Come on, you guys.
Come on.
Get in there!
Any of you guys not with us,
come on, clear out of here!
Come on, get out of here.
They're making it
hot for us.
We'll fix them.
Go and get Sandy!
Come here, Sandy.
Come out of there.
Come on.
Get over there.
Over there.
Come on.
You go to the warden.
Tell him to open those gates
and let us go through.
If he don't,
we're going to bump off
every screw in here
and throw them out in the yard.
-Beginning with Wallace?
-Yes, beginning with Wallace, yes.
Here, take that gun.
Hang that out that gate.
All right.
Open it just a little bit.
That much?
All right. Come on.
Put it through there.
All right. Come on. Come out.
Get to moving, you.
Go on, Wallace, get out there.
Butch said if you didn't open the gate
and let the gang out,
they're going to kill all the guards
beginning with Wallace.
I'll see him in hell first.
Let them have it.
Come on out of there, Wallace.
Come on! Shake it up!
Wallace, you said your prayers?
I don't know any prayers.
Go ahead, shoot.
Aah!
Wallace!
Miller! Miller!
Give them the gas bomb.
Open those gates
and let us go through,
or we'll send the rest of these screws
straight to hell!
You dirty double-crosser!
They'll get you for this!
Shut up!
Butch! Joe!
Get me another screw out of there!
What's the matter, kid?
Morgan locked the door.
He's got the key!
Butch!
Butch, come here.
Morgan's got the key.
He's locked the door.
They'll kill me.
They'll kill me!
I didn't mean to squeal!
I didn't mean to...
They made me do it!
They made me!
Don't tell Butch. He'll kill me!
So you double-crossed
the gang, huh?
-You turned them in!
-Don't let them get me, Morgan!
Don't let them get me!
I guess you're not to blame
at that.
You stay where you are.
I'll attend to this gang.
Don't tell, don't tell  Butch.
I didn't mean to do it!
The army tanks are here, sir.
All right. Send them in.
What's that?
We'll get the rope for this, but I'm going
to get that rat Morgan
if it's the last thing I do.
Where's Morgan?
Morgan, you in there?
Come out of there, you rat!
Come out of there,
you rats!
Is Morgan there?
-No!
-All right.
Is Morgan in there?
I know what you're coming for, Butch.
But I'm not going to be killed
for something I didn't do.
If you come
one step nearer...
He shot me
in the arm, Butch!
I warned you, Joe!
I didn't double-cross the gang.
You stick your head out of that door,
and I'll throw a slug between your horns.
-Stand back, Pop!
-Shut up! I'll tell him.
Butch, this Is Pop Riker.
You're all wrong, Butch.
Morgan didn't turn you in.
Even the screws are protecting him.
Come on. Let's go in and get him.
Wait, Butch. My eyes!
I must be losing my sight.
I'm going blind!
You're all right.
It's only the gas.
Morgan, we're coming after you,
you snake.
I warn you, Butch.
Stay where you are! Stay where you are!
Joe! Joe!
Bring me some more bullets, Joe.
Oh!
Sorry, Butch.
Did I get you?
-I'm on my feet, see?
-Don't lie to me.
-Who, me?
-Yes, you.
Listen, Butch, it was Kent who sold out
the gang, not Morgan.
Kent?
You know I wouldn't
double-cross you, Butch.
Sure, I know you wouldn't.
I was only kidding, that's all.
Just kidding.
Just...
Sure. I knew that
all the time.
I want to thank you, Warden,
for all you've done.
All ready for
a new start, Morgan?
Yes, sir, I am.
Have you made
any plans for your future?
Yes, sir.
I thought I'd go to the islands
of some new country
- and take up government lands.
-Good idea.
New friends, new surroundings,
hard work. That's a man's salvation.
Are you going alone?
Well, I don't know, sir.
Well, I wish you luck.
You deserve it.
Thank you, Warden.
-Well, so long, Pop.
-So long, Morgan.
See that you don't
get homesick again.
Subtitles: Lus Filipe Bernardes
Watch Movies, TV Series & Live Sports
www.admitme.app