Out of the sea
That once made her
Secure.
I have loved england,
And still as a stranger,
Here is my home,
And I still am alone.
One moment.
Come in.
I brought you
A cup of tea.
I thought
It might be welcome.
It is...
Very.
You really are
An angel, margaret.
Thank you.
What time is it?
Just on 4 a.m.
Really? Sit down,
Margaret.
Why don't you
Take your cap off
And lie down
For a while?
We were told
To stand by.
There must be some
Very good reason.
It helps to be
Doing something.
You're worried.
Who isn't nowadays?
I thought your son was to
Spend the week with you.
He phoned to say his
Leave had been canceled.
I haven't heard
Anything since.
It's been
5 days now.
I'm terribly
Worried.
So when we were told to
Stand by for emergency,
You made up your mind
He'd be in the thick of it.
Yes, margaret,
I'm afraid I did.
Well, you can be
Wrong, you know.
I hope you are.
Do try and rest.
0435.
Both motors cut.
Sit down, will you?
This is extremely
Confidential, susan.
I've been notified
By the surgeon general
To prepare for casualties
Within 24 hours.
He anticipates
A possible 5,000.
So many?
The matron tells me
We can take 300 here.
Can you have that number
Of extra beds ready?
If you allow us to use
The corridors, yes.
Yes, of course
You may.
I've had a talk
With the matron, too,
About nursing
And surgical facilities.
Will you see that your
Staff thoroughly understands
What will be
Expected of them?
Certainly.
Thank you.
That will be all.
I suppose I mustn't
Ask questions.
My dear, your guess
Is as good as mine.
Obviously
A big show somewhere.
Invasion?
No, hardly. A raid on
The french coast, perhaps.
On a big scale,
By the sound of it.
Is that...
Yes.
They usually
Start at dawn.
It's been a long day,
Margaret.
I never could have
Managed without you.
You sure you won't let me
Get you something to eat?
You haven't had
Very much today.
No, thanks.
Shall I open the window?
It seems a bit warm in here.
All right.
Thank you.
Strange, isn't it,
Margaret?
The way one's mind
Races about.
When one's happy...
When life's
Going along
In its normal,
Peaceful way,
I don't suppose
We think very much-
Very deeply, anyway-
But in times like these,
We think. We wonder.
All sorts of thoughts have been
Going through my head all day.
I know.
When I first came from
America to england as a girl,
I was only going to
Stay two weeks...
And I've spent
My whole life here.
My whole life.
And I have a son
Out there somewhere.
A life is really a very,
Very long time, margaret,
When you look back
To when you were young.
Of course,
You wouldn't know that.
I will soon.
Good night,
Margaret.
Good night.
A very, very long time.
Strange to look back
To the day
So long ago-
The green sea
And the purple haze
And then, far off and low,
England.
I watched the long day start
On that gray shore,
A young girl with an open heart
At england's door.
I had no thought then
Of husband or lover.
I was a traveler,
The guest of a week,
Yet when they pointed
"the white cliffs of dover,"
Startled, I found there were
Tears on my cheek.
Sue, there are tears
In your eyes.
Ha ha!
Oh, are there?
It's just that
I'm so thrilled.
I've never
Traveled before,
And it's so wonderful to see
The things you've read about.
That coast is
Full of history-
Our history.
Raleigh set out
From here to find
A new world
Called virginia,
And so did
The mayflower
With those english
Rebels
To find
A new england.
I suppose I sound
Like a schoolmarm,
But that's
Our background-
That little green
Island.
Her past
Belongs to us,
Her history
And her glory.
The magna carta's
Ours
And milton
And shakespeare.
You think
I'm an idiot
Spilling over
Like this.
I think
You're wonderful.
I'm crazy
About you, sue.
I haven't got a lot to offer,
But it's a good farm.
It's dad's, of course, but
It will be mine someday.
That's why I'm going
To scotland-
To buy cattle,
Improve the strain.
I'm looking for a bull
And some good heifers.
Going to bring them
Back with me-
In the hold,
Of course.
Oh, gosh, I say dumb things.
I'm not like this all the time.
It's just that I'm trying to
Make a good impression on you.
But you hardly know me,
Sam. Don't you think-
Oh, I know
It's kind of sudden,
But if you'll just think about
It. I won't see you in london.
Father, you stayed up after all.
Yes. I got talking
At the bar.
Where's this england
I hear so much about?
There she is.
Ah. Ha ha! Doesn't look
Much bigger
Than martha's vineyard
To me.
Always rains
In england.
That's what they say.
Hmm.
Good-bye, sue. I've
Got to catch my train.
Good-bye, sam.
You don't mind
If I write?
Of course not.
Good-bye.
Good-bye, Mr. Dunn.
Oh, good-bye,
My boy. Good-bye.
Immigration, sir. Can I
Have your name, please?
Hiram p. Dunn.
The "p" is for...
Porter. That's
My mother's maiden name,
Since you're
So interested.
Thank you, sir.
Your age, please?
53.
Occupation?
I'm the publisher
Of the tolliver sun.
That's
A daily newspaper.
How long do you propose
To stay in england?
From april 2, 1914,
Until april 16, 1914-
That's exactly
Two weeks.
You've got adequate means of
Subsistence for this period?
Well, now, let me see.
I, uh-I have with me
Å75 in cash
And a letter of credit
On the security
Trust company
Of providence,
Rhode island.
My bank balance
In the tolliver national bank
Is $1,742.07.
I have 3 bonds
In tolliver utilities,
Par value 3,000.
3 bonds in union pacific
Railroad fives 1932,
And 100 shares of united
States steel preferred.
Really, Mr. Dunn, this
Is hardly necessary.
I have
A fully paid-up policy
That will give me $60 weekly
At the age of 65.
Anything else?
What did I tell you?
It will be like this the
Whole time we're in england.
Suffering cats.
Well, there's no use
Making faces at me, susan.
The lady wants
The window open.
She likes cold air.
It's a national
Characteristic.
Doesn't matter if you and I
Here are frozen to the bone.
Doesn't matter
If my lumbago
Gets to start up
All over again.
No, sir. Give
An englishman a window,
And by heaven,
He's going to open it.
It might be he'll find
A nice, icy draft outside.
Oh! Ah...
Susan, you better
Go down to your dinner.
This food is bad enough
When it's hot.
Did you find out what time
The boat train leaves?
Yes, 10 a.m.
Are you sure you'll be
Able to travel tomorrow?
Oh, I'm going to
Get out of this
If they have to carry me
On board on a stretcher.
And, sue,
When we get back home,
Don't you ever dare give
Me another boiled potato.
And what in heaven's name
Is that?
It's suet pudding.
You put syrup on it
And eat it
For dessert.
Do they eat it?
I've seen them.
What a people!
You've got to
Hand it to them.
They've certainly got
Intestinal fortitude.
No, no, please.
Take this stuff
Out of my sight.
Whew! What an article I'm
Going to write for the paper
When I get home
On my trip to england.
You mean to tell me
You came 3,000 miles
To spend two weeks
In the bedroom
Of a bloomsbury
Boarding house?
Well, I'm afraid so.
My dear child,
You must stay over.
You must see something of england.
I've seen
A good deal of london.
I've seen the british museum and
The national portrait gallery.
Great heavens!
Ha ha ha!
No, thank you.
No, thank you!
British museum, eh?
You saw
The mummies, eh?
Been to any shows,
Any dances?
No.
Speaking of dances, I'm afraid
I can't play cards tonight.
It's the night of millicent
Waverly's ball, and, uh...
I thought I'd like
To go this time.
I hear the king
And queen are going.
Have you received your
Invitation, colonel?
No, by jove,
I haven't.
Oh, I must give
Millicent a ring.
Do you care to come to that
Shindig with me tonight?
I don't know whether that
Sort of thing interests you,
But everybody will be
There from the king down.
Oh, I'd adore it...
If father
Doesn't mind.
Shall I ask him?
Would you? He'd love to see
Someone. He's been so lonesome.
Is that so?
Does he play cards?
No, not much,
But he loves chess.
Does he? Ha ha! I used
To be pretty good at that,
And I've got some chessmen here, too.
You have?
A sort of heirloom. Very
Well, then, I'll venture in.
May I be excused?
Certainly.
Isn't that wonderful?
A real ball.
Oh, it's so different,
So english.
It's like a victorian
Novel come to life.
Oh, and I won't mind
Going home now.
I shall really have
Seen something.
I wouldn't count
On it too much.
I don't understand.
Well, he's a very old man.
He has his fancies.
He's been with me
For 8 years,
And every year he tells me
He's going to this ball.
Perhaps
You don't know, dear,
But the duchess of waverly is the
Most exclusive hostess in london.
Oh, I hope you're not
Disappointed.
I'm dreadfully
If you'll
Excuse me,
I'll see if my father wants anything.
Of course, my dear,
And you'll be busy
With your packing.
Too bad, isn't it? Such
A nice little thing.
Not a bit
Like an american.
No.
Not entirely new.
Oh?
If I'm not mistaken, blackburn
Introduced that variation
In the hastings
Tournament in '95.
Blackburn?
The british
Chess master.
Oh, you're wrong
There, colonel.
Pillsbury introduced
That move.
Are you sure?
Pillsbury?
Positive.
Paris, 1900.
Oh, pillsbury
In paris?
That's right. You can bet
Your bottom dollar on it.
Father, don't be
So cocksure.
It's hardly
Raining now.
I think I'll go out
And look at the shops.
Yeah, do that, dear.
Good idea. Get yourself a new bonnet.
Have a nice time,
You two,
And don't get
Into any arguments.
Charming girl.
Yes.
It's refreshing to see
Someone young around.
These-these are very
Interesting pieces, colonel.
Where did you
Pick them up?
Oh, well,
A family heirloom.
Oh.
Yes, these pieces are
Over 100 years old.
Really?
Well, now, to follow up
The blackburn variation.
Pillsbury-
The american master
Pillsbury in paris, 1900.
I...
Your daughter said
We were not to argue.
Otherwise-
Otherwise what?
I should point out
That this surprise move of a
Pawn is typically blackburn.
Blackburn is not the only chess
Player who can push a pawn around.
Well, perhaps we'd better
Get on with the game.
Yes,
Perhaps we had...
Though your position
Doesn't look any too good.
Huh! That remains
To be seen.
Well,
It's your move.
I'll prove it
To you later.
Prove what?
That this variation
Was introduced
By pillsbury
In paris.
Oh, to the devil
With pillsbury in paris.
Well, credit where
Credit is due, that's all.
Exactly, and I'm
Quite positive
The move originated in the
Hastings tournament in '95.
By blackburn, eh?
By blackburn,
Certainly.
The british
Chess master?
Quite.
Pillsbury was the
Chess master of america.
I'm quite aware
Of that, Mr. Dunn.
You're darn tooting
You're aware of it.
What do you mean?
You're saying that the
British master was superior
To the american master,
That's what you're saying.
Nothing of the sort.
It's a question of fact.
Harry nelson pillsbury
Could play rings around
Any english master anytime!
The english haven't
The knack for chess.
But the americans
Have, you mean?
That's right. Chess calls for
Ingenuity, enterprise, and skill.
Qualities which the english
Do not possess, you mean!
Well-
You go too far, sir!
No, no. Now,
Hold your horses!
It might interest you
To have a look
At this board
On which we're playing.
Dolly madison!
President madison's
Wife.
Where did you
Get this?
My grandfather
Picked it up in 1812.
1812?
When 6,000
British soldiers
Lacking in skill
And enterprise
Captured the city
Of washington,
The capital
Of the united states!
How did your grandfather
Get hold of this chess set?
By the simple act
Of taking it.
He was dining
In the mansion
From which your president
Had fled in some haste.
You mean
He stole it?
My grandfather was flag
Lieutenant under admiral cockburn.
The president's dinner was
Cooked and ready to serve.
The admiral and my grandfather ate it.
This-this is
Stolen property!
They're spoils
Of victory, sir!
Father! Father!
Father, please!
Why didn't you stay to
Protect your property?
Didn't figure you fellas would steal it.
Father, the colonel's
Your guest.
You ran like hares-
Like hares, sir!
The roads were littered
With the guns
Your men dropped
As they ran.
Well, now, colonel,
Probably we were just
Hurrying ourselves
Down to new orleans.
Bah! A deucedly
Disorderly rout, sir!
It seems to me, colonel,
That we won that war
Somewhere down
Around new orleans.
I think I'll just
Take this board
In the name of the
United states government.
Keep your hands off my
Property, you yankee rebel!
Yankee rebel! Do you
Hear that, sue?
Why, for two cents,
I'd-
You are a receiver
Of stolen property!
Ruffian!
Robber!
Barbarian!
Thief!
Father, you must
Apologize.
Well, I, uh...
Oh...
Oh, father.
Oh, I'm sorry, sue.
Gwennie, what the devil
Are you doing?
You've been racing up and down
Those stairs for the last hour.
I'm sorry, ma'am.
The colonel rang.
What does he want?
He wanted me to take a message to
Mr. Dunn. They've had a quarrel.
Then Mr. Dunn rang for me to
Carry an answer to the colonel.
He said he wouldn't take back a word to
Him, but as long as the colonel apologized-
That will do,
Gwennie.
We don't discuss
Our guests.
And then I was helping miss Dunn to
Dress, ma'am. She looks ever so pretty.
The colonel's
Taking her to the ball.
The ball?
You don't mean
To say so.
Gwennie, wait.
Is the colonel dressing?
Oh, yes, ma'am. I had to take
His shoes up, cleaned special,
White tie and tails, ma'am,
And a ribbon around his neck.
Can it be true?
The duchess
Of waverly?
Of waverly's motor
For colonel
Forsythe.
Yes, sir.
I'll tell him.
Well, don't stand there
Gaping, girl.
Run up and tell
The colonel.
Yes.
Here they come now.
The duchess has
Sent her motorcar.
She said she would.
Oh, my dear,
You look charming.
Thank you.
Indeed she does.
Ha ha!
I'm a proud man
Tonight.
Isn't it wonderful?
I'm so thrilled.
Have a good time.
Thank you so much.
Good night.
Well, gives
Quite a tone
To the house,
Doesn't it?
One of our boarders
Gone off to see the king.
Why, walter,
This is nice.
You've been
Neglecting me.
No, no, no, no.
Miss susan Dunn
Of the united states.
My dear, I'm so glad you could come.
Nothing less would have
Brought this old bear out.
See that he finds you
Some acceptable partners.
Thank you. Is that the
Order of the garter?
Mm-hmm.
Instituted by edward iii
In the year 1348.
Oh, right,
I believe.
Are the king
And queen here?
No, no, they always
Come last.
Oh.
But there's the prime
Minister over there.
Where?
Right
By the orchestra,
And he's talking to
Your ambassador, by jove.
Oh, that makes me
Feel lots better.
Better?
Braver.
Not-not so mousy.
Oh, young lady,
I'm the one
That's got to call
Upon his courage.
May I have
The audacity?
Ha ha! It will be a very great pleasure.
Time of my life!
Oh, dear.
I haven't enjoyed
Myself so much for years.
Now you must have
Your reward.
I'm going to get you a
Delightful partner to dance with.
How do you
Like them-
Dark? Fair?
Bashful? Dashing?
Ha ha! I'm going to be hard to please.
I'll be
Back in a moment
With a lucky
Youngster.
Don't let anyone
Run off with you!
John, my boy!
Ha ha! Well met.
The very man
I'm looking for.
Glad to see you, sir.
It's been ages.
I've brought a girl-
A charming girl.
Promised her a topping
Partner, and you fill the bill.
I'm sorry, sir.
The fact is-
A delightful child!
You'll bless me.
Yes, I'm sure I should.
I know your taste.
The fact is, I have a
Sort of an appointment.
Bertie's cousin from australia
- she's a girl I've never seen,
But he's going to be late, and
I promised to take care of her.
Pig in a poke, eh?
That's too bad.
How are you going to find
Her if you've never seen her?
I'm to wait for her
In the adam room.
Of course,
It's early yet,
But I'd like to get
There before she does.
The adam room, eh? Do you
Know where the adam room is?
No. I haven't
Any idea.
Come along.
I'll show you.
Through those double
Doors in the corner-
That's what
You're looking for.
Oh, thanks. I'm sorry I can't
Oblige, but duty must be done.
That's all right.
Good hunting.
Hello, John.
Hello. You must be
Bertie's cousin nancy.
I'm John Ashwood.
Hope I haven't
Kept you waiting.
Ha ha! No,
Not at all.
Well, I came early. I
Thought I'd be here first.
I know it's awful to be hanging
About when you don't know anyone.
Yes, it is, isn't it? I
Suppose the colonel sent you.
No, bertie sent me. He told
Me to tell you he'd be late.
He's detained at the foreign
Office. The weekly crisis, I suppose.
He said you weren't
To wait supper for him.
As a matter of fact, he said you were
To try and behave as if I were he.
Do you think
You can?
I'm sure of it, quite easily,
But you see, I'm afraid-
I hear this is your
First visit to england.
Yes, it is. But you're
Not staying very long.
No, indeed,
Not long at all.
We must make the most of it, mustn't we?
May I have the pleasure of this dance?
I should love it.
This is
My favorite waltz.
Mine, too.
Splendid.
This is a stroke of luck
Meeting you like this.
The joke is,
I didn't want to come.
Had a regimental dinner and told old
Bertie he was no end of a nuisance.
Can you imagine?
I might have missed you.
Oh, what a pity.
Right in the middle.
It's the, uh,
King and queen.
Oh. Oh,
I'd forgotten.
Man: their majesties
The king and queen.
Mercy, they're coming
Right towards us.
What shall I do?
Oh, just curtsy.
Like this?
Ha ha! No,
The usual thing.
I forgot you're
An australian.
Well, put
One foot back
And bend the knee,
You know?
Which one?
Right foot,
Left knee.
Bravo.
You must think
I'm terribly awkward,
But we don't do that
Sort of thing back home.
You haven't been
Presented at court?
Oh, good gracious, no.
I know lots
Of americans are,
But I'm just
A small-town girl.
But bertie said
You were australian.
Oh. Oh, of course.
In all the excitement,
I forgot.
I'm not nancy. I'm not
Bertie's australian cousin.
I'm... I'm an impostor.
Good heavens.
I say,
Are you really?
Who are you?
Oh, I'm nobody
In particular.
I come from a little town
Called tolliver
In the smallest state
In the u.s.a.
Well, why didn't you
Tell me?
You didn't give me
Much time.
Besides...
I sort of wanted
To dance with you.
Did you? I say,
That's splendid.
I say,
Won't you?
I don't really
Belong here.
An old gentleman from our
Boardinghouse brought me
In the kindness
Of his heart.
Not colonel
Forsythe?
Yes! You know him?
He wanted me to meet
You. I turned you down.
Can you imagine?
I say, this is splendid.
You living in london?
No. We're
Going home tomorrow.
But I've just
Met you.
You can't go home
Tomorrow. I can't allow it.
You don't want to,
Do you?
No, I don't,
But my father does.
You see, it's rained
Every day,
And besides, he's a bit
Prejudiced about london, anyway.
What, do you mean
He doesn't like us?
Well, lots of people
Don't, you know.
He had a fearful quarrel
With the colonel
About the war of 1812.
Hmm. We didn't fight
In 1812, did we?
That's the time you
Burned washington.
What, burned
The general?
No, no. The city.
Oh!
We burned it?
Oh, what a pity.
Well, no wonder people
Don't like us.
I say, I apologize
On behalf of england.
I accept your apology.
I would like to talk to your
Father and get him to let you stay.
Do you mean to say you've
Never been out of london?
I've really not seen
Much of london.
I've never seen london
At night.
We have the night
Before us.
Yes. My last night
In england.
Wait here. I'm going
To find the colonel
And tell him
I'm taking you home.
I say, don't you go
Running off again
With the first man
Who asks you.
It's vast,
Isn't it?
Biggest city
In the world.
No. New york is that.
Isn't it?
If you say so.
You're nice. I wish my
Father could meet you.
He thinks english people
Are hard to get along with.
Well, you do
Have to know them.
But we're doing very well, aren't we?
You did get a bit uppity when I
Said I thought titles were silly.
A bit what?
Uppity. You know,
On your high horse.
Oh.
Not uppity.
No. I was
Scared.
Scared? Why?
Guilty
Conscience.
You see...
I have a title.
I'm a baronet.
A baronet? What's that,
A lord?
No, it's not
Quite so grand.
Well, I'm...
I'm sir John
Ashwood.
Sir John.
This will be something to tell
The girls back in tolliver.
Ha ha!
May I?
Have you ever
Been to america?
Oh, yes. I was
In canada last year.
Well, it's not quite
The same, you know.
We're those queer colonists
Who wanted to be free.
Oh.
Who's uppity now?
Ha ha ha!
I'm sorry.
Do you work
For a living?
Yes, quite hard. I'm a captain
In the king's fusiliers.
You know,
If bertie hadn't-
Angels and ministers
Of grace, defend us.
What's the matter?
I never gave it a
Thought until this moment.
Nancy.
I promised
To take care of her.
Bertie will never
Forgive me.
Oh, dear.
What can we do?
Nothing. She can hardly be sitting
Waiting for me in the adam room
At 3:00 in the morning.
No.
It's all my fault.
I'm awfully sorry.
Yes, so am I.
No, I'm not.
You know, I feel
An awful cad,
But if it hadn't happened,
I should never have met you.
How still it is.
I never knew london
Could be so still.
When wordsworth stood here, he could
See green fields in the distance
And tall oak trees.
Don't go back
To america.
I must.
There's so much
To see.
Let me show you england.
We'll drive down roman roads
Where caesar's legions marched
And follow chaucer's
Steps to canterbury.
I'll show you the isle of
Avalon where king arthur died
And the holy grail
Is buried.
Beautiful places.
Old places.
Little villages that were
Standing in the wars of the roses.
And jolly places. You know, there's
A moat at wales where the swans swim
And ring a bell for their
Dinner when they're hungry.
I say,
You're crying.
No. No, I'm not.
I... He's...
Oh, how stupid
You are.
I don't want to go back,
And you're making it worse.
I'm a hopeless idiot.
I ought to be kicked.
I ought to go
And hang myself.
Oh, no. No,
Don't do that.
It was just that last bit
About the swans that got me.
Do they really do that?
Oh, yes. They do.
I've seen them.
There's a little house,
And they all-
Don't.
Don't tell me any more.
Not another word.
I have to go back
To america...
And back to
The boardinghouse now.
Listen.
There's big ben.
I wish I thought you
Minded as much as I do.
Oh, I do mind.
I dropped tears
All over my packing.
Now I mind even-
I mean, it's been
A wonderful night.
When I think of england,
I shall always think of you.
A bit set in her ways,
A bit sure of herself,
But nice.
Very, very nice.
And will you think
Often of england?
I'm afraid I shall.
Miss Dunn-
Please don't say it.
I must go now.
I see the milkman.
Good-bye.
Good-bye...
England.
Mr. Dunn?
Mr. Dunn? Yes, sir.
That is, he's leaving
In a minute, sir.
Yes, I know. I wonder if he
Could spare me one moment?
Tell him sir John
Ashwood, please.
Sir John...
Ashwood.
Oh, yes, sir!
Step in, sir.
A gentleman
To see you, sir.
Good morning,
Miss Dunn.
Good morning, sir.
I know this is an inopportune moment.
I hope you'll
Forgive me.
Father, this is sir John Ashwood,
Who brought me home last night.
Oh. Well, I'm
Glad to meet you.
I'm sorry we haven't much time.
Fact is, we're a bit rushed.
Our train
Leaves at 10:00.
I've come in the hope that I
Can persuade you to miss it.
What was that?
Uh, I hope your lumbago's better, sir.
Yes. Well, it will be when I
Get away from this eternal rain.
It's pretty bad,
Isn't it?
But we seem to be in for
A spell of fine weather.
Oh, are we? Well,
It's about time.
Right you are, sir.
Mr. Dunn, uh... My
Mother lives in devon,
And at any moment, she
May call you on the phone.
My mother would be delighted
If you and miss Dunn
Could spend a week
Or two with us
And see some typical
English country life.
Oh, hold on,
Hold on there.
Well, that's
Out of the question.
Good heavens, man. We're
Practically on the train.
Besides, we don't know your
Mother, and she doesn't know us.
What is it, gwennie?
Please, sir, can the man
Take the trunk down?
Oh, yes.
Come in.
You see, sir, I run a newspaper,
And I have to get back to it.
Oh, yes, of course.
I suppose it
Wouldn't be possible
For miss Dunn to remain behind alone?
What? What's that?
Oh, my mother would take the
Greatest care of her, sir.
The cab's
Here, sir.
Oh. Tell him
We'll be right down.
Can I take
The suitcase, sir?
Yes. You can take
This one.
Now you see, we're going
Now. Come on, susie.
Allow me, sir.
Oh, thank you.
About miss Dunn, sir, I'm sure you'd
Like her to have a little pleasure.
Oh, yes. Well...
I'll put her on
A later boat myself.
Miss Dunn has such a fine
Historical sense, sir.
It seems a pity that she should
Be denied the advantage of travel.
Susan, have you
A half crown?
This infernal money.
Every civilized nation in the
World has a decimal system,
But england has to still cling
To an antiquated-
Right you are, sir,
But that makes for
A certain amount of
Interest, doesn't it?
Are you still here?
I mean the little differences, you know.
What do you want?
Good heavens, man!
I can't leave my daughter behind
In a strange country.
Come on, susan.
We'll miss our train.
It's for you,
Mr. Dunn.
What is it?
Lady Jean Ashwood.
Oh. Well, tell her
We've gone.
My mother, sir.
It's a trunk call!
But I haven't time
To talk to her,
And it wouldn't do
Any good, anyhow.
Well, susan, don't stand there
Like a wooden indian.
Say something.
Tell this obstinate young man
That you can't stay,
That you don't
Want to stay.
But I do,
Father.what?
I want to
Very much.
You see, sir?
You keep out of this. You mean
You'd have me go home alone?
Would you mind
Very much?
I'm holding
The line, Mr. Dunn.
Well, of all
The unfeeling-
Just a week.
Just a week, darling.
I'll take the next boat.
We'll take good care of her, sir.
The cab, sir.
The telephone,
Mr. Dunn.
Oh! Holy mackerel!
The cab, the phone,
My daughter, my lumbago!
Hello? Hello?
Dunn speaking.
Hiram p. Dunn.
I expect you'd like to go
To your room, miss Dunn.
You must be tired
After your long drive.
Thank you, but honestly,
I'm too excited to be tired.
Really? That's
Charming of you.
Then perhaps you'd like
To see the gardens first?
They look lovely
At this hour.
Yes, I would,
Lady Jean.
Suppose you take miss Dunn
For a little stroll, John?
Yes, that's
A splendid idea.
It's so nice
To have you here.
Thank you.
Come on, susan.
I'll let you know
When tea's ready.
We're rather proud
Of our lawn.
It's very old,
You know.
Not bad, eh,
The girl?
Very attractive.
Worried, old lady?
I'm rather
Bewildered.
Well, it looks serious.
An old stick-in-the-mud
Like John
Meets a girl for the first time
Last night
And brings her home
To the family.
I thought there was some
Sort of an understanding
Between John and the hampton girl.
Oh, helen? She's mad about
Old John. Always has been.
I'm worried
About helen.
Not that John is
In any way committed,
But I'm afraid helen's taking
Things too much for granted.
You're fond of helen, aren't you?
She's a sweet girl,
And she's right for John.
Oh, by the by, I'm going over
To the hamptons.
I'll tell helen that John's
Coming home and ask her to dinner.
It might be amusing.
You know, it's odd.
John's like you. He's straight and good.
My precious husband is
An out-and-out rotter.
Thank you.
He's unscrupulous,
And he's crude.
But you love him
Best, don't you?
I have no favorites.
Reggie's like
His father.
I adored his father.
Oh, miller, will you tell sir John
And miss Dunn that tea is ready?
Yes, my lady.
I spent days in that
Manor house in devon.
I roamed with John
Beneath the old great trees
In gardens trampled down
By cromwell's armies,
Through foliage rustling
In the wet, soft breeze.
John showed with pride
The ancient lettered casement
That watched the proud armada
Pass the coast,
Some of the pictured forebears
In the gallery,
And told the legend
Of the family ghost.
Well, here are
The ancestors.
Awful lot of them,
Aren't there?
I thought they'd look
More solemn somehow.
Well, you see, they didn't
Know they were ancestors.
They just mixed in with
Whatever was going on.
Tell me about
Them, John.
Really?
Really.
All right.
But don't forget, you
Brought it on yourself.
The most noble knight,
Percy Ashwood of ash,
1233-1265.
It was probably painted
Some centuries later.
Percy was killed at
The battle of evesham.
And this is his wife,
The first Lady Ashwood.
We're indebted to her
For the family ghost.
The family ghost?
No. Tell me about it.
Well, rumors of the
Battle had reached her,
And as night fell, she heard
The sound of galloping hooves.
She came out onto the
Steps with her ladies
And waited in the light of torches,
Hoping perhaps that her
Husband was returning.
But a faithful retainer
Of the family rode up,
His face white as wax
And his voice hollow
As he gave
The fatal tidings.
And even while
This was happening,
According
To the legend,
Peasants were fishing
His body out of the river.
He'd been drowned fording the
Stream more than an hour before.
It was a ghostly
Messenger?
Riding
A ghostly horse.
Oh, John,
It's wonderful.
And does the ghost
Still ride?
Yes, so they say.
Whenever a male of the clan
Is gathered to his ancestors,
The women of the family hear
The hoofbeats of the messenger
As he rides down
The old roman road.
Do you believe it?
I can't say
That I do.
I've a suspicion my mother does, though,
And she's
A levelheaded woman.
Anyway, she doesn't like to
Hear anyone laugh at the story.
This is the ancestral black sheep.
He guessed wrong on the war of the roses
And was executed
For treason.
Well,
I'm worn out.
Aren't you
Fed up with us?
Not a bit.
It's most exciting.
Yes. This gorgeous officer
Is the present baronet
And your
Humble servant.
How is it you
Weren't called percy?
Well, the eldest son
Is always called percy.
I had an elder brother
Who died as a child.
Here, my... Wife's
Portrait will hang.
Oh. You must have often
Wondered what she'd be like.
Yes, I have...
Until a few
Days ago.
Then, I began to hope
That she'd be...
Oh, tall and fair
With a mind of her own,
And that when my great-grandson
Showed visitors her portrait,
He'd say, "this is
My great-grandmother.
Lovely, isn't she?
She was an american."
Oh, John.
You must have known.
I've been out of my mind since
I first saw you in the adam room.
I meant to wait, give you
More time, but it's out now.
Don't say no, sue.
If you can't... Give me
The right answer,
Pretend
I haven't spoken.
May I do that, John?
For these few days.
I don't want
To make decisions.
I just want to live
And be happy.
You are happy, sue?
Happy here?
When we are
Together, yes.
When we are alone...
What does that mean?
Please don't ask me.
It's just that-well,
It's all so strange.
This place,
Your family.
Sue...
John!
John?
Here, mother.
Oh, there you are.
Is that miss Dunn?
Yes, of course
It is.
Helen's going to sing, John, dear. I
Thought perhaps you'd like to come down.
Of course. Be with you
In a jiffy.
Flow gently,
Sweet afton
Disturb not
Her dream
Thou stock dove
Whose echo
Resounds
From the hill
Ye wild, whistling
Blackbird
In yon
Thorny dell
Thou green-crested
Lapwing
Thy screaming
Forbear
My
Slumbering fair
Thank you, my dear.
That's a favorite of mine.
Yeah. Very nice. Now how about
A rubber of bridge, huh?
Oh, rupert,
It's after 10:00.
Is it?
Shall we go out
Into the terrace?
It's mild
In this moon.
John, helen must
Go home now.
Oh, mother can
Send for me.
No, John wouldn't
Hear of it.
Certainly not.
I shan't be long.
It's just across
The path.
Come and see us
One day, miss Dunn.
Perhaps John will
Bring you to tea.
Do please come,
Won't you?
I should love it.
Come on,
Nuisance.
Good night,
Lady Jean.
My dear.
Good night, all.
Good night.
Is it serious
Between those two?
Oh, it's one
Of those things-
Boy and girl sweethearts,
Parents' blessing.
Yes, I suppose
They're for it.
Mmm, they're
A nice couple.
I should never have taken you
For an american, miss Dunn.
No?
You don't speak
Like one.
American women are
So smart and pretty,
But their voices-
I've no doubt our voices sound
Equally strange to americans.
Yes. Enjoy london,
Miss Dunn?
Very much.
You stayed at the savoy,
I suppose, huh?
Americans always stay
At the savoy.
No, we didn't stay
We stayed at mrs. Bland's boardinghouse
In bloomsbury.
Bloomsbury?
What is it,
Nanny?
It's a telegram
For the young lady.
Michael murphy had to get out of
His warm bed to bring it along.
It's from the ship, he says.
The young lady's father.
May I?
Of course,
My dear.
I would think that some people
Would say what they had to say
While they were still here
To say it, if you ask me.
Nanny?
Yes, my lady?
Thank you,
Nanny.
Foreign ways.
You must excuse nanny.
She's brought up
All my children,
So she thinks she has
The right to bully us.
Better get helen
And John married
And keep her busy with a new generation.
I hope your father's
Recovered from our climate.
I suppose you'll find
Our houses cold.
I suffocated
In new york.
Don't know how
You stand it.
Great city, though,
When you get used to it.
Yes, I met some quite
Nice people there.
You speak as though that
Were rather surprising.
Well, I must admit, I'd only
Met the traveling americans,
And the traveling
American... You know.
Remember those dreadful people
We bumped into in rome, my dear?
But miss Dunn isn't a
Bit like an american.
You don't mean
To be rude, do you?
No, of course
Not.
Why, whatever-
On the contrary, it was
Intended as a compliment.
But sooner or later, you all
Say something of the kind.
"so you're an american, miss Dunn?
Really? You don't speak like one.
So you're an american, miss Dunn?
Really? You don't act like one."
My dear, my sister had no
Intention of offending you.
Just the same, it was tactless.
Utterly tactless.
Well, upon
My word.
It's a compliment not to be
Like an american. How insulting.
A compliment not to speak
Like an american.
I suppose if you wanted
To be altogether flattering,
You'd say I was
Quite english.
Well, I shouldn't
Be flattered at all.
I'm glad and proud
To be an american.
Bravo, bravo.
I came here loving england and all it
Meant to me. I was happy to come here.
I was so sure I'd like you all
Because of John.
I hoped you'd like me.
My dear-
But I was an outsider.
I didn't belong.
You made that
Perfectly clear.
Well, it may interest you to know
My father's entirely of your opinion.
Perhaps I should
Read you his cable.
"been pacing deck
And cursing myself
For leaving you in the hands
Of that englishman."
Upon my word.
"you come right home, my girl,
Without foreign entanglements.
"marry a regular,
Warm-hearted american.
"you're a yankee
Through and through.
"never forget it.
Think of paul revere.
"think of the old
North steeple.
"remember the alabama.
"this is a mighty
Expensive message,
"and that will show you
I'm scared stiff.
I am your devoted father."
Neither you nor my father
Need have any anxiety.
Miss Dunn,
Wait.
Oh, I'm so terribly
Sorry I started all this.
I had no intention
Of hurting you.
Won't you put it down
To my stupidity
And... Forgive me?
Susan.
May I call
You susan?
I've been hoping
You would.
I want you
To understand
That if there's been anything
In my manner to hurt you,
It's been nothing
To do with John.
It's just that-
Well,
Perhaps we express ourselves
A little differently.
Perhaps we do, too.
The english are anything but effusive.
The scots are worse,
And I'm a scot, you know.
So if I've hurt you,
My dear,
It was in my manner,
Not in my heart.
Please
Understand that.
I know. I'm sorry.
I'm so ashamed of myself.
Really.
Here I've made
A stupid scene.
I guess I'm just a little
Homesick, that's all.
I hope you'll forgive me.
Will you tell John
That I have a headache
And that I've gone to bed?
I'll tell him. Good night, susan.
Good night.
The boat train rattling
Through the green countryside,
The girl within it battling
With her tears and pride,
Believing in her blindness
That she was heart-whole yet.
His love, his laugh,
His kindness-
In time, she could forget.
The washington,
Miss?
Yes, please.
Nice, steady
Boat.
Yes. I came over
On her.
John, you shouldn't have
Come all this long way.
I was afraid you'd
Want to see me off.
That's why I ran off
And left a note.
I've not come to see you off, susan.
I've come
To take you home.
Home?
To Ashwood.
I don't know what
You're talking about.
Take my things onto
The boat, please.
I'll give you
My ticket.
Never mind the ticket. The
London train on platform two.
No, please.
You'll find a carriage reserved
Under the name of Ashwood.
No, please. You are to take
The luggage onto the boat.
The london train.
John, this is ridiculous! I was
Awake all night, thinking things over,
And I've made up
My mind.
Shall we...
I'm not at home
In that great place.
It scares me. I live in a
Little house in a little town.
I'm used to simple,
Friendly people
Who don't give a hoot
About family and traditions.
Yes, but, darling-
I've been homesick.
I've got a terrible longing
For our green mountains,
For daddy and his
Tempers-for anything american.
Hot dogs,
Flapjacks...
And your family doesn't
Like me. They resent me.
Your mother wants you to marry helen.
Helen's in love with
You, John. Helen fits in.
She's pretty and conventional and good.
I'm not.
I'm stubborn.
I'm an american
Right through.
I'm not adaptable.
I'm a rebel.
Yes, but, sue-
Oh, I do love you,
John. I can't deny it.
I'll remember you to
The last day of my life,
Only I could
Never be happy.
I could never
Make you happy.
Don't make it
Harder for me.
This has taken courage, John, darling.
How would you like to be
Married at the american embassy?
I have a cousin married
To one of the attaches.
She's an awfully jolly girl.
You'll like her.
Or would you like a country
Wedding? Mother thought you might.
She sends you all sorts
Of kind messages.
She's going to move
Into the dower house.
Says young couples should
Have their homes to themselves.
You know, I've been wondering
About the honeymoon. Paris?
You've never been to the
London theater, have you?
Just imagine.
Thank you.
But, John-
But, John, John-
No. No.
Let me out, dear.
I cabled my father. He's
Meeting me in new york.
Let me out of here.
I brought a lunch basket. Some
Cold chicken and a bottle of wine-
Let me out of here,
Do you hear?
You stupid, arrogant,
Pig-headed englishman.
Let me out!
Why don't you take
Your hat off, darling?
And sit down and lean back comfortably.
John.
Sue, you obstinate
Little beast.
Oh, John.
Sue.
And now, I have the
Honor to propose a toast
To our hostess.
To Lady Ashwood.
Oh, no, no.
Excuse me.
To Lady Jean
Ashwood.
Lady Ashwood
- that's my daughter. Yes.
Little sue Dunn gone
High and mighty on us.
I don't mind telling you that
It was a bit of a shock to me
When I heard the news
Back in tolliver,
And I hustled right back to england
To see what I could do about it.
But the scotch know a good
Thing when they see it.
Hear, hear.
And maybe-maybe my daughter
Knows a good thing, too.
Well, and now I'm going
Back to america alone.
Having lost my daughter
To the british,
I had hoped to take back with me
A certain piece of property
Also looted
From the united states-
From the white house,
To be exact,
But apparently, the gentleman
In possession of this stolen item
Is devoid
Of a sense of shame.
No. Don't get me wrong.
The english are fine.
Of course, they think england
Is gosh-almighty,
But, uh... A people that's managed to
Collar 1/3 of the earth, my daughter,
And a certain article
From the white house
Is no small potatoes.
And that brings me
To my point.
I raise my glass
To a very charming lady.
She's british,
But I kind of like her.
Make a good
Job of it, girl.
I mean to.
Bless you both. I'm very happy for you.
Good-bye, father.
Take care. Bye.
Yacht, ahoy!
The sea gull.
Who are you?
Naval patrol e-2.
Stand by to be taken
In tow.
Get your sails in.
Aye, aye, sir.
We are bringing you in
With us.
What's wrong?
England is at war.
Paper!
Mercury dispatch!
Paper! Paper!
The place is a madhouse. I suppose
Everybody is trying to get home.
By george, they're on
Their way to france already.
I must find a telephone,
Report to the adjutant.
You mean, you think you
Might have to go at once?
We'll see, darling.
Don't worry.
There's a telephone box.
Will you wait for me, darling?
I shan't be a minute.
Sue! Hey, sue!
What a stroke of luck!
Sam.
This is wonderful. I thought
You'd gone back long ago.
You're going
On the boat, of course.
Where's your father? Can
I do anything to help?
Father's in america.
No, I'm not going back, sam.
I'm staying in england.
Staying here?
With the war on?
Yes, sam-
I got the adjutant,
And it's all right.
I have to get up to town
At once, though.
John, I want you to meet
A friend of mine, sam bennett.
This is my husband
Sir John Ashwood.
How do you do?
Oh, well, that was
Silly of me, wasn't it?
Trying to rush you
On board like that.
Married, huh? Well, what do
You know? Congratulations!
I hope you'll
Be very happy.
I hope you'll be as
Happy as all get out.
Not in the army,
Are you?
As a matter of fact, I am, and the
Adjutant tells me my regiment's-
Soon, John?
I'm afraid sue picked a bad
Moment to marry an englishman.
I guess she picked
A good man at that.
But, well,
It's too bad.
All the luck
In the world!
Thanks.
I guess I'm just in the way
Here. I better get going.
No need to tell you
How I feel.
Good-bye, sam.
I'll write to you.
Oh, gee, thanks!
Thanks!
Thanks.
Oh, boy!
What about all this mail for
The third king's fusiliers?
Hold.
Been holding for weeks.
So have they.
In a spot, aren't they?
John dearest,
It is nearly 3 weeks
Since your last letter came.
No letter
For your mother, either.
Nothing from you,
Nothing from reggie.
We know you must have written.
You're so good about writing.
We try not to worry, to think of all
The reasons there must be for the delay.
Your mother is braver
Than I am, I'm afraid.
A letter is
A little piece of you.
Without it,
I feel so much alone.
I miss you so. I hardly knew you,
Darling, before you went away.
God keep you safe.
I love you so.
Hello, davis.
Hello, sir.
Reggie? Reggie!
Are the telephone
Lines still out?
Yes.
The runner get back?
No.
We just hang on.
Those are the orders. Position
Must be held at all costs.
At all costs.
Well, here's to
The last battalion.
I suppose they'll be
Coming in for the kill soon.
Take it easy, davis.
Nothing?
Nothing.
It's been 5 weeks.
I don't think we
Should worry, sue, dear.
Remember
Last spring?
We heard nothing for nearly two months.
Yes. I'd forgotten.
You look tired.
I didn't sleep
Very well.
I know. I saw a light
In your window.
Were you awake?
About 4:00.
What woke you?
I don't know.
I was dreaming, I think.
Sue, you're not more
Anxious than usual, are you?
Oh, no. Why should I be?
Don't worry, darling. We've
Been through all this before,
Then we've gotten several
Letters all at one time.
You're a great comfort
To me, sue, dear.
When I remember
How badly we started-
Well, we know each other
Better now.
If I could only see him.
I love him so unreasonably.
I know, dear.
Sometimes I'm afraid
If I lose him,
I won't be able
To remember,
Hold on to all the things
I loved in him.
I'll lose him dead
As I lost him living.
Sue, don't talk
Like that.
You're killing him
With words.
John's coming home.
Peace will come.
You'll have years
Together.
Am I intruding?
No, no, nanny.
Come in.
I only wanted
To show you this.
It caught my eye this minute
- here in this corner.
Look. The government
Is to allow the wives
Of men who have not had
Leave since last autumn
To go to france
To meet them.
Let me see.
The first bit of sense
They've shown-
The blithering old idiots.
Why, if this is so-
And now you haven't
An excuse in the world.
Dear knows, it's time
You put a baby in my arms.
Oh, nanny, really!
They have now completed
All necessary arrangements.
It's rather wonderful, isn't it?
Yes. We'd better look
Into it right away.
We'll telephone uncle
Henry at the war office.
And take a word from me to master John
That I am expecting him to do his duty
And not be sending you back
With things otherwise this time.
Poor little mite
- he'll be half a foreigner at best.
And it's a queer sort of country
That says it's too proud to fight.
What do you mean?
You get out of here.
You'll find out whether
We're too proud to fight.
Imagine the government
Having a heart.
Course, there'll be thousands
Of wives wanting to go,
But how wonderful to have something
To look forward to, to plan for!
To plan for.
Ha ha ha!
Are you crazy, man? Standing
There with the door wide open,
With the draft blowing
Right up to the attics?
There's
A telegraph boy.
Here it is,
Sir.
Thanks, mate.
It's a fine
Morning.
'Tis that.
,
For her?
It might be
One of them was hurt.
Yes. Will you
Give it to her?
If I must.
Surely she'll not
Be called upon to-
I'll have to
Wait my turn,
But it may not
Be too long.
I must write John
And tell him.
What is it, nanny?
It's a telegram.
Shall I read it
To you?
No.
Give it to me.
It's not John.
Not John.
Reggie.
He died heroically.
Oh, I'm so sorry...
So sorry.
It's all right.
Sue, you must go
To John.
You must go
To John at once.
Oh, how good you are.
How good you are.
And now, my dear, I
Think I'll go to my room.
Porter, pouvez-vous
Me dire si le train-
The train's late,
Isn't it?
When do you
Suppose it-
It signaled,
Didn't it?
Thank you.
Hotel
Normandie?
Hotel normandie.
Sue.
John, darling.
Darling.
Hotel normandie.
Oh, you've changed.
You're so thin.
Hotel normandie.
I'm so happy.
Very good hotel.
Many english.
Let me look at you. You're
So beautiful. I'd forgotten.
And what a lovely hat.
You like it?
Hotel normandie
- prix tres raisonnable, cuisine excellente.
Oh, this is my batman
Jennings.
How do you do,
Jennings?
You must excuse me.
I know my husband
Thinks the world of you.
Thank you,
My lady.
Hotel normandie
- sur la plage, tarifs tres moderes, madame.
I'm sorry.
I have rooms.
Nous sommes au prince
De galles. Je regrette.
Mol aussi, madame.
Infiniment.
Hotel normandie!
You don't know
How wonderful it is
To be able to open my eyes
And find you still there.
You see, all these months, I've
Had to close my eyes to see you.
There'd you be
In some crazy little hat,
And then somebody would say,
"pardon me, sir,"
And I'd open my eyes,
And bang! You'd be gone.
Oh, my love, none of that.
I can't help it. I've
Just got to brim over.
It's so wonderful.
You are here at last.
Madame has been all
Impatience, but now...
Madame is all tears.
But of course. Que
Voulez-vous? She's so happy.
You like the rooms?
Perfect.
Oh, it's the band.
Come and see the view.
Oh, what gorgeous
Weather-
More like june
Than april.
Isn't that a cute
Little bandstand?
That's a cute
Little bandmaster.
It's the mustache
That gets me.
Dear, are you going to cry
The whole time I'm here?
I think so.
Thanks.
Merci.
Merci, monsieur.
Jennings, go and amuse yourself.
I don't want to
See you again.
Very good, sir.
Oh, sue, my darling, I
Simply can't believe it.
You're not going
To cry again?
Yes, I am. I am.
It's so perfect.
Oh, darling, you don't
Know what it means.
It's been
Almost 3 years now-
3 years without peace of mind,
3 years of being afraid.
Now to have you,
To know you're safe-
For these few days at least,
To know you're safe.
For the first time,
I dare to be happy.
I'm going to be very
Happy these few days.
I'm going to hoard up
Every moment.
I know...
As though it had to last us
For the rest of our lives.
I've dreamed of this
A hundred times.
Tackle the champagne,
Will you, darling?
With enthusiasm.
I think it's grand that you
And mother hit it off so well.
Does nanny
Bully you?
Does she? To hear her,
You'd think I was doing it
Just to be contrary
Because I'm an american.
Doing what?
Well, I should say
Not doing it.
Not doing what?
Well-
Sue, you're
Blushing.
You look a little pink
Yourself.
Well, I know nanny,
And it'd be just like
Her confounded nerve to-
It wouldn't have anything to
Do with young percy, would it?
Why, John.
Percy?
The eldest son is always
Called percy, dear.
Not my eldest.
Our eldest.
But I don't like
The name percy.
I don't care very much
For it myself,
But the eldest son
Is always called percy.
Why?
It's a family tradition.
But I want him called John,
After you.
That's very sweet of you,
Darling, but the eldest is...
Always called percy.
The eldest is
Of course, I don't want to ask
To call him hiram after my father-
How is your father? What
Do you hear from him?
You wouldn't be changing
The subject, would you?
Oh, father's all right,
Cocksure as ever.
Want some bread?
The paper doing all right? Quite.
What does he say about things over here?
Father says germany better
Stop pushing our ships around,
Or she's going to get into
Trouble with the tolliver sun.
Getting his dander
Up, eh?
Oh, John, I want
America to come in.
I want it terribly.
I pray for it every night.
I want this war to end, and
They can help so much to end it.
I want you home again.
Darling.
Father says I want to plunge
The whole united states into war
Just to save
One englishman.
Sounds a bit
Drastic, doesn't it?
Champagne for you,
My girl.
Right.
Here's to peacetime.
How lucky we are-
Bright sun in the day
And such a perfect night.
But how fast the days go.
I want to hang on
To the hours a bit.
Only 4 days
And one gone already.
Where's that music
Coming from?
I don't know... But it's
Just right, isn't it?
Perfect.
We heard the sea murmur,
We saw the full moon wane,
Knowing that our happiness
Might never come again.
I, not forgetting
Till death do us part,
Was outrageously happy
With death in my heart.
What are you
Thinking of?
Of us.
Monsieur left his pipe.
Oh, what a pity.
We were rather rushed
At the last.
And the train was
Perhaps late, after all?
No. The train was
Very punctual.
When it came in, I waited
For him nearly an hour,
But this morning, the train
Went out right on time.
And madame's boat
Leave tonight?
Yes, this evening.
It's a long wait.
Madame is sad.
But these were good
Days. Monsieur was so gay.
He laughed so much.
They were wonderful days. I
Shall remember them all my life.
And he will come
Again.
Can I do anything
For madame?
No, thank you, dear.
Madame has not noticed that monsieur
Left a note on the mantelpiece.
Oh, John. John!
What is it?
What's happened?
Yes.
I don't understand
A word.
America
Has declared war!
It's official,
Madame!
America has
Declared war!
Rockets' red glare
Gave proof through the night
That our flag
Was still there
Oh, say, does that
Star-spangled banner yet wave
O'er the land of the free
And the home of the brave?
Lady Ashwood, sir.
There you are!
And none too soon.
What a time we've had. The
Train was late. How are you?
You're looking well.
Where's my young friend?
You haven't come alone?
Certainly not.
Here he is.
Ah, nanny.
John Ashwood, esquire.
Oh! So that's
John's boy, eh?
And mine.
And mine, colonel.
He's a fine lad.
He looks like John.
You know, mrs. Bland,
If it hadn't been for me-
I have a bit of a share
In this young fellow.
You cut things
Pretty fine.
You have no idea
Of the crowds in the street.
The cab simply crawled. We had
To fight our way across the curb.
They nearly tore
The child from my arms.
They're coming!
The yanks are coming!
Mrs. Banks, they're
Coming! The yanks are coming!
Listen.
They are coming.
Oh, I could faint
With excitement!
No point in that.
Look here.
But I've waited so long for this
- to see them myself.
Listen to the music.
It's so american, that song-
So gay and aggressive
And boastful!
There they come!
Nanny? Nanny.
Give him to me.
Be careful,
My lady.
Look, young man, look.
Those are
Your mother's people.
See how well they march.
Your mother's people and yours,
Too, because you're half a yankee,
You little englishman, and I'm
Never going to let you forget it.
Wave your hand, johnny.
Wave your hand.
This is your first glimpse
Of history.
Look, darling,
They're right underneath.
Look how beautiful they are.
They'll help bring us
Peace, darling.
They'll bring daddy home again-
Home to see his son.
Here, I want you to send
These to your father.
The chessmen.
I thought it might give him some pleasure
To return them to the white house.
It's a small return
For what they've sent to us,
But it'll please the
Pig-headed old mule, anyway.
You darling.
Hello? Hello?
Ashwood? He's at
The manor house?
Who's speaking?
I can't hear you.
There's an infernal racket here.
Oh, nanny! Nanny, have
You heard the news?
Oh, you have.
Pity. I thought I'd be
The first to tell you.
Armistice, yes.
It's wonderful, isn't it?
Peace again.
You should hear the bells.
The town's gone mad.
You can't blame them.
She must be delighted, eh?
Let me speak to her.
Lady Ashwood.
What? I can't hear you.
Speak up!
Huh? John?
Dead?
Killed in action.
Oh, no, no, no, no.
,
Poor souls.
I do not remember
The words that they said.
Killed, doual, november.
I knew John was dead.
All done and over,
That day long ago,
The white cliffs of dover.
Little did I know.
Sue, I brought you
A little broth.
You must take
Something.
Please, dear.
You can't go on
Like this.
You make me
Very anxious.
I've left you
Alone all day.
Won't you make
An effort?
Susan, you're
Showing no courage.
One has to go on.
You're not alone,
You know.
You're one
Of thousands.
It's my loss, too.
You have your son,
And when
He grows older,
You'll know just
How much that means.
I knew John
As a little boy.
I watched him
Grow up.
He was
Part of my life
From the hour
He was born
Of my hopes
And dreams.
I died a little
With each of them.
Sue, sue, darling,
You must face it.
Think of him.
You're
Shutting him out.
Oh, darling, can't you
Cry a little for John
Because he's dead
So young?
He'll
Never come home,
Although
Peace has come.
He'll never see
His little boy.
,
Well, here's
The young gentleman
To say good night
To his mammy,
And a very sleepy
Young gentleman it is.
He didn't sleep so well
After his 4:00 bottle.
I think that tooth's
Worrying him a wee bit,
But he's
Such a good baby.
Aren't you the best baby
In all the world?
Come, now. Say good night to your mammy,
And off we go
To the sack.
There we are.
Ho ho!
Look at the fat
Legs on him.
I declare, I never saw
A baby grow so fast.
Why, that little blue coat
You bought for him in august
Is too short in
The sleeves already.
And strong. Feel
The strength of him.
Yes, he's fine
And strong-my baby.
He'll grow up
Tall and straight,
And he'll go
Into the army.
The eldest son always
Goes into the army.
It's a family tradition.
Sue, dear-
A tradition to die young
In a country not your own-
Please, darling.
For honor and glory.
No, I haven't any glory
Now, have I?
They took that, too.
They took it all
Away from me.
They took...
But he'll live out his life.
I'll teach him to do that.
I'll teach him to run and hide
When the drums start playing.
I'll take care of him.
I'll keep him safe.
I don't care how. I'll keep
Him safe. You understand?
Now, me lady-
He's mine.
He belongs to me.
They shan't have him.
They shan't take him
Because he's young and strong
And kill him, never.
Never! Never!
Darling, please. You're
Frightening the baby.
You don't know
What you're saying.
We have peace.
John died for that.
We've learned
A dreadful lesson.
We know now
What war means.
We're all losers,
And we've all
Suffered so much
That good
Must come of it.
Your boy will grow up in a new world.
There'll be no shadow
Of war over his youth.
John gave his life
For that.
You must believe
That, darling.
It wasn't
A vain sacrifice.
John gave his life so
That his son should live.
But the years pass,
And the heart mends,
And life takes up
Its quiet labor.
The bee returns
To the meadow clover,
And the tree grows
As the child grows.
I saw his father
Over and over.
His face looked out
Of my son's face-
His father's smile,
His father's pose.
I watched him
With his boyhood friends.
I watched him with his friends
And neighbors.
Good day, Betsy.
Good day,
Sir John.
I was just looking
At your roof.
Yes, sir. Thank you, sir.
Well, as long
As I'm here,
I think I'll take
A look around.
A very good idea,
Sir John.
That's quite all right,
Mrs. Kenney.
We can't have the rain
Coming in, can we?
No, that we can't, but I'm
Sorry it had to be done now,
Times as they are.
Ben was saying it's worse
For you than it is for us.
We are a bit hard up.
Income tax, you know.
6 shillings on the pound, and next
Year they say it's going to be worse,
But it's improving
The economic structure.
We've had to sell
Quite a bit of land,
And my grandmother doesn't
Like that very much.
And how is
Her poor ladyship?
Granny's a little bit
Better, thank you.
I think
I better go now.
I've got 2 or 3
Things to do.
Good-bye,
Mrs. Kenney.
Sir John.
Good-bye, Betsy.
Good-bye.
Good-bye, sir John.
Mother, I stopped in at the
Kenneys' today about the roof.
Did you, darling?
And how's Betsy?
Oh, all right,
I expect.
Mother, I promised the
Trotters a new fence.
Oh, John, dear, you must be more careful
About promising
Things.
We can't even afford
To mend our own fences.
I know, mother. I explained
To them about the taxes,
But somehow their cow
Got into the pettys' backyard.
It upset the beehive
And got terribly badly stung,
Wouldn't give milk
For days,
And you know they've
Just got a new baby.
Uh, sir John...
Come here.
Do you mind?
You're, uh...
You were deucedly important
This afternoon, sir John.
Yes, sir.
Yes, a real high-toned member of
The stranded gentry, aren't you?
Yes, sir.
Yes, your great- great-grandfather
On your mother's side
Kept a little dry goods store
In tolliver. Did you know that?
Yes.
Did you sleep well
Last night, sir?
Did you?
Not at first, sir.
You see, somebody placed
A very cold frog in my bed.
John!
Well, now, that's
A strange coincidence.
Somebody sewed up
The legs of my pajamas
And put a hairbrush
In the pillow.
Yes, sir.
I did, sir.
It's known as an apple pie bed, sir.
It's a custom
In english schools,
And I know that you're
Always so interested
In our english
Customs, sir.
You rascal!
Oh, father. It's
No wonder nanny scolds you.
Fix your hair,
Johnny.
Mother, can I go down and
See what bridget has for tea?
Why? You want
Something special?
Yes. You see, mother, I've
Invited those two german boys
That are staying
With old Lady berdale.
Yes, rustle up
Some crumpets.
Darn little limey.
Yes.
Germans, eh?
Darling,
This is nice.
Are you sure
You should risk it?
Yes, it's
A bit crisp today.
Of course it is, but
It's no use arguing with her.
She always thinks
She knows best.
I heard that we
Had some young guests,
So I couldn't resist
The temptation.
These are John's friends
Gerhard von vistaberg
And his brother dietrich.
How do you do?
Are you the sons of
The baron von vistaberg
Who was secretary at the german embassy
Some years ago?
No, Lady Jean. The embassy counselor
Was of the linden vistabergs.
We are
The oak vistabergs.
We have an oak leaf
In our coat of arms.
What do you have
In yours, grandfather?
A pipe, a smelly
Old tobacco pipe,
And maybe
A deck of cards.
I could suggest
A proper animal
For your coat
Of arms, hiram.
Yes?
A mule.
A mule? Ha ha!
Why not?
It's not an aristocratic animal,
But it knows
Its way around,
And it packs a healthy
Wallop in its hind legs.
Very useful qualities, my dear Jean.
Perhaps you're
Right, hiram.
Anyhow, unicorns are
Out of date nowadays.
Nothing is out of date
When one loves it.
Thank you, hiram.
Are you enjoying
Your stay
In england,
Herr von vistaberg?
What is it
You enjoy most here?
That's hard to say,
Lady Jean.
We've not seen
Much of london,
But here
In the country,
I admire most
The beautiful lawns
One finds around almost
Every manor house.
Your lawn is one
Of the most perfect.
It would make an
Excellent landing field.
I suppose it
Needs centuries of tending.
Landing field, dietrich?
For what?
For troops. They could easily
Land in gliders on this lawn.
Oh, you mean
Airborne troops
Could land here during maneuvers.
During maneuvers,
Of course, sir.
Yes. Of course.
Boys of dietrich's age
Learn about planes and gliders
In their youth
Organizations,
So of course
They think of nothing
But landing fields
And such things.
All we learn in
School is latin and greek.
I wish they'd teach us
Something about planes.
It's only natural that
Gerhard and dietrich
Should be interested
In military matters.
When I traveled
In germany,
I drove by the vistaberg
Armament plants.
Very impressive,
Too.
Took me almost an hour to pass them,
And all the chimneys
Were smoking.
Of course, they
Weren't making arms.
That was prohibited
By the peace terms.
Exactly. Under
Existing restrictions,
The vistaberg plants produce
Nothing but kitchen utensils,
Perambulators, gramophones,
Agricultural implements,
Cameras, and so on.
Don't forget the
Vacuum cleaners, gerhard.
When father
Gave us the list,
He told us especially not to
Forget the vacuum cleaners.
Vacuum cleaners
And perambulators-
A smiling country given
To ways of peace.
Babies and cleanliness
- I like that.
That makes me
Very happy.
Yes, they've learned
Their lesson.
Germany has learned
Her lesson.
A beaten country-
I beg your pardon, sir!
Yes, gerhard?
Germany was
Never beaten.
We never accepted
The peace,
And we never shall.
The war was
Not fought to a finish.
The next time, we shall
Not be cheated of victory.
We shall be proud and happy
To die on the field of honor.
Yes, well, if you boys are going to
Play tennis, you'd better get going.
Yes, sir.
Come, dietrich.
Lady Jean,
Lady ashford,
I did not mean
To offend you.
You understand, I-
That's
All right, my boy.
Go and have
A good time.
Mother, do you want
Me to play with them?
Yes, John.
They are
Your guests.
Out of the mouths
Of babes.
That was rather frightening, wasn't it?
Oh, here's
Nanny.
I think perhaps I'll rest a little.
Mother, don't you
Feel well?
Nothing.
It's nothing, dear.
I'm all right.
I'm a little tired.
Indeed you are.
I said it would be too much
For you coming downstairs,
But nobody ever
Listens to me.
That was a strange
Outbreak, father, wasn't it?
No.
Susan, I know that as
Long as Jean is here,
You'd never leave, and
I wouldn't want you to,
But someday
I'd like to think
That you'd come back home
To me and bring the boy.
Why, father?
What are you thinking?
Well, I'm thinking that
We might lose him...
The same way
We lost his father.
It isn't only what
These boys said.
I've felt it
For a long while.
I can tell you
Honestly, susan,
There's another war
In the making.
It may come in 5 years.
It may come in 10.
But it's as
Inevitable as death.
Master John.
Johnny.
Wake up,
Master John.
Nanny.
Nanny, it's still dark.
Yes. I know it.
It's 2:00
In the morning.
Your granny's
Asking for you.
Granny?
She's had a bad spell. She's very weak.
Is... Is
The doctor here?
He's on his way.
Nanny...
Is she very ill?
She is that,
And she's going,
Laddie,
But you
Mustn't cry.
You must be very brave and strong.
Promise me.
Are you ready,
Johnny?
Yes, nanny.
The car is here,
My lady.
Thank you,
Benson.
Where's
Grandfather?
He's saying
Good-bye to nanny.
May I help?
Oh, is the car here?
I'm ready.
My, this seems a great big empty place
Now that
She's gone.
God bless her.
I never thought I'd miss her so much.
Think of what I said
About coming home, susan.
Car's here,
Grandfather.
Everything's
Stowed.
Ah, that's fine.
Well, you're not going
To like this, young fella,
But I'm going to
Give you one big hug.
Ha ha ha!
Yeah. You tell your mother
To bring you to america,
And I'll make you sports editor
Of the tolliver sun.
I'm sorry, sir. I'm
Afraid I couldn't do that.
I have to go into my father's regiment.
The eldest son always
Goes in the army, you know.
Yes. If you change your mind,
You just let me know.
Yes, sir.
Ha ha! Well,
Good-bye, suzie.
I'll be waiting
For a letter from you.
Good-bye.
Take care
Of yourself.
Yes, suzie.
And now,
If you don't mind,
I'd like to do
The driving.
May I remind you,
Sir,
That in england one drives
On the left side of the road?
I know, I know. Darn
Foolishness. See you soon.
Bye-bye.
Is he coming back soon?
No. He meant-
I'll tell you later
What he meant.
Sir John!
Good morning,
Sir John.
Good morning, sir John.
Good morning. I've
Come to say good-bye.
We're sailing tomorrow, you know.
Aye.
So we've heard.
It be true, then.
I wouldn't believe it till I
Heard it from your own lips.
Ben was saying you'd
Never leave england.
You see, my mother's american,
And it's
Only natural
That she'd want to
Live in her own country.
We'll be a-missing
You, sir John.
We'll all be a
- missing you. You know, sir John,
Us kenneys have rented
This farm from your family
For nigh on 200 year.
Adam steele's going to be my land agent,
And he's
A good man.
He'll be a good man, sir
John, but it ain't the same.
No,
It's not the same.
Well...
I'll say
Good-bye.
Good-bye,
Mrs. Kenney.
Good-bye, sir John.
Good-bye,
Mr. Kenney.
Sir John.
Good-bye, Betsy.
Good-bye.
Betsy.
Betsy...
It's for you.
What is it?
It's a ring.
I made it out of a
Horseshoe nail of midge's.
You can have it.
A horseshoe nail.
It's for good luck.
Ohh.
Good-bye.
Good-bye, John.
Thank you
For the ring.
Will you like it, nanny,
Living with your sister?
I'll get used to it.
Is she nice?
I hardly know. I've lived
In this house for 50 years.
It's been home and family
To me. I've forgotten my own.
Master johnny!
Look away. Gracious me.
There. Now I'm ready.
You're awfully
Like your father
At the same age,
Master johnny.
You'll be the living image
Of him when you grow up.
Well, I'll be off.
Laddie, will you say good-bye
To me here and let me go alone?
I'll send that lazy jenny
For my things.
I'm afraid I'll break down
Like an old fool,
And I'll not let everyone in the
Kitchen see me with tears in my eyes.
My johnny...
Don't you forget.
I won't forget, nanny.
Good-bye.
Indeed, if I had my life
To live over again,
It's not
A child's nurse I'd be,
Giving my heart to other
People's children and...
Old and lonely.
No more.
Aren't you thrilled going on
A big boat for the first time?
Oh, it'll be
Wonderful.
Did I tell you
Grandfather
Was going to
Meet us in new york?
I expect he's terribly excited about it.
I know I am.
Are you, mother?
Mm-hmm. After all,
That's my home, you know.
I can hardly wait to
Show you the sights.
You're going to
Love it, darling.
I'm sure
It'll be very nice.
Mother, if that man
Buys the manor,
Do you think he'll be
Good to the tenants?
I don't know
Why not.
Granny said that the tenants
Depended on the manor.
She said it was my duty
To watch over them
In return for the privilege
Of owning land.
I don't say that's
Wrong, darling,
But we look at things a
Little differently at home.
At home, mother?
Well, in america,
I mean.
You see, we think a man ought
To start from the beginning,
That he ought to make
His own way in the world.
Yes, but supposing he has
Something else to do first.
What do you mean,
Dear?
I mean, supposing he's
Been left something to do,
As I was.
As you were?
Yes. I mean, the way
Father left me
You and the place
To look after.
Oh.
Well, I don't know,
Johnny.
Wouldn't a chap want to do it just
The same if he were an american?
I guess he would.
That's all I mean.
It isn't so very different over
There than it is here, is it?
You just try and do the thing
That's there for you to do.
Johnny, don't you want to go to america?
Oh, yes, mother...
If you do.
No, no.
Tell me the truth.
What are you thinking of,
Sitting there so serious?
I wouldn't
For the world
Force you to do something
You thought was wrong,
But I do wish you could
See it my way, darling.
I want it so much.
Why, mother?
Because I'm afraid.
I'm afraid
Of what's ahead.
Of another war.
Your father died
When he was young.
He died for england,
Johnny.
But you're half american. You're my son.
You belong to america,
Too, not only england.
Mother, is that why
We're running away?
Running away?
Mother, if there were a war,
I'd want to fight for england.
You wouldn't want me to
Be a coward, would you?
No, johnny.
Mother.
Yes?
Do you think father
Would like me to run away?
No, johnny, I don't.
Mother.
You darn
Little englishman.
You're just
Like your father.
You've beaten me,
Between the two of you.
Mother, do you mind
Very much?
Of course I mind.
When I see
That boat go out,
Playing the star-spangled banner...
No. That's
Not sporting of me.
I'll stay, johnny,
And like it.
Whatever happens,
We'll face it together.
Your american mother
Can take it, too.
You bet she can.
I wanted to go home then,
But your father
Took me by the arm,
Talking the most
Dreadful nonsense,
Led me up a flight of steps,
Over a bridge, across the tracks,
Down the steps that led
To the london train.
I guess you can
Find the way.
Mother?
Yes, child?
You're the best mother a chap ever had.
Thank you, dear.
So we went home again.
My english son did all those
Things that all his sires had done.
No one had taught him,
Yet he knew his part.
The land itself
Was teeter to his heart.
He watched his fields,
He kept his father's place,
A friendly boy
With england in his face,
And often when he walked
Across our hill,
Betsy went walking, too,
As children will,
To gather flowers
With her homework done,
And so they walked
Together in the sun.
If they were more than friends,
I never knew,
For a new spirit
Shaped him as he grew.
There was a different england
In the air.
I liked the girl.
They made a handsome pair.
And so I watched them
And was reconciled.
He was my son, as well
As england's child.
Eton, then sandhurst,
And, of course, at last
His father's regiment.
The die was cast.
And then to see
In anguish and in doubt
The lights of europe
Falter and go out,
And once again the feet
Of marching men
Drum in the dust and darkness,
Once again.
Rumors of battles.
Headlines in the street.
Holland and france.
The desperate retreat.
Our days were busy
With a thousand cares.
Our nights were dark and quiet
With our prayers.
He came from somewhere
In the west that day,
Heading for dover
And the waiting ships.
So little time,
With silence on his lips.
I did not see my son
As he went through.
I thought him far away.
But Betsy knew.
Have you called
Your mother?
No. I thought
I wouldn't somehow.
Johnny, have we
Much time?
Not much, Betsy.
Make sure...
The old horseshoe ring.
It brought me
Luck, johnny,
But-but now I-
Do you remember
When we were kids
And I used to ride round,
See you on my pony?
Yes. All you
Ever said was,
"how's the roof,
Mrs. Kenney?"
I suppose I did have it
On my mind, rather.
It seemed to need
Such a lot of mending.
How is it now?
Fallen in again?
I'm afraid so.
Oh, johnny.
Steady.
And so they
Parted, each to his command.
"the ring," she said
And placed it in his hand
And watched him go,
Then turned
To find her train.
She was not there when
John came home again.
One moment.
Come in.
Word's just come in. The
Ambulances are leaving the station.
Oh, thank you, margaret.
I'll be right down.
Ward 4.
Ward 2.
John.
Mother?
This is an emergency. Blood
Is coming through the bandage.
Call the doctor's
Attention to it.
Yes, ma'am.
Ward 3.
How long?
4, perhaps
6 hours.
Hello.
I've been asleep.
How do you feel?
Not-not bad
At all, mother.
Did you guess
I was in the show?
Worry?
What do you think?
I guess we're lucky.
You know, mother,
I wasn't afraid, really.
I know.
That-that bird...
What, dear?
The bird kept going
Round and round.
Where, dear?
There was
A little bandstand.
At first, it seemed like any
Other misty morning in summer-
Quiet...
And the air smelled sweet.
Suddenly,
Everything broke loose.
The canadians fought
Their way ashore.
We were among them.
I- I don't remember
How I got there,
But I was in a shell hole
With a canadian and american.
The canadian was dead.
The american boy
Was wounded pretty badly.
Only his eyes
Seemed to be alive.
We lay there with the shells
Screaming over our heads,
Watching that bird
Spinning insanely
Over what used to be
That gay little bandstand.
Mother,
Do you know dieppe?
Yes. I
- I was there once with your father.
You remember
That bandstand?
Yes.
I remember it
Very well.
Hello. What's this?
A little
Nourishment.
There's a parade
Coming past the hospital
In a little while.
Some of those new american
Units, they tell me,
Along with
Our own boys.
Would you wheel me
To the window
When they come?
Of course.
Thanks.
Don't try to talk,
Darling.
That chap...
That american...
Yes?
He said he'd really
Start to fight
The day war ended...
For a good peace,
A peace that'd stick.
He said that god
Would never forgive us,
Neither england
Nor america,
If we break the faith
With our dead again.
Write his mother
A nice letter.
Tell her that...
Oh, well, you'll
Think of something.
I say, shouldn't you
Be busy somewhere?
I'm all right,
You know, really.
I know you are,
But you must
Rest now.
In a minute.
Good night, mother.
Thanks.
Good night,
My darling boy,
And god bless you.
You, too, mother.
Here you are, mother.
They're coming...
Some of your americans.
Yes, darling. I saw them
When they came 25 years ago.
So did you.
You were
3 months old.
I held you in my arms,
And we saw them together.
Now we can
See them again.
Tell me how
They look, mother.
Tell me
How they march.
Can you see them yet?
Yes, John,
I see them,
Your people
And my people.
Only their uniforms are different.
How well they
March, John.
March together.
Tell me more, mother.
There's a look of greatness about them,
All the strong
Young boys,
Beautiful and proud with dreams.
Just like you,
John.
They'll help
Bring peace again,
And as your friend said,
A peace that will stick.
You know,
John...
We must
Never forget
What that american boy said to you.
God will never
Forgive us
If we break the faith
With our dead again.
Watch Movies, TV Series & Live Sports
www.admitme.app