We bring you the circus.
The pied piper, whose magic tunes lead
children of all ages, from 6 to 60,
into a tinsel and spun-candy
world of reckless beauty
and mounting laughter, whirling thrills,
the rhythm, excitement and grace
of daring and blaring and dance,
of high-stepping horses
and high-flying stars.
But behind all this,
the circus is a massive machine
whose very life depends on
discipline, motion and speed.
A mechanized army on wheels
that rolls over any
obstacle in its path,
that meets calamity again and again,
but always comes up smiling.
A place where disaster and
tragedy stalk the big top,
haunt the backyard and
ride the circus train,
where death is constantly watching
for one frayed rope, one weak link,
or one trace of fear.
A fierce, primitive fighting force
that smashes relentlessly
forward against impossible odds,
that is the circus.
And this is the story of
the biggest of the big tops
and of the men and women who fight
to make it the greatest show on earth.
- Morning, Mr. Braden.
- Morning, Nick.
- When's the new horse arriving, Brad?
- Tomorrow, Chuck.
Don't rub them thin, Jimmy.
Those bells are 60 years old.
They've rung in some good shows.
- Hi.
- Hi, Mr. Braden.
How are the kids?
Oh, just fine, except they were playing
with Randy Concello a few days ago.
That's nice.
Yes, but Randy came down
with the mumps this morning.
What? No. Any signs?
No, not yet, but baby
gorillas do get the mumps.
I'll have Higgins give
them a shot of immune serum
and double their cod liver oil.
Give them plenty of spinach.
You stay healthy now, boy, you hear?
Say, is it true were only gonna
play a short season this year?
Don't believe all you hear.
- See?
- Go back to Mama now.
I told you there was nothing to it.
- How's Myrtle?
- Stomach.
Give her some gin and ginger.
- Any news about a full season?
- You'll get a full season.
Be sure Myrtle gets all the gin.
- Same old trouble?
- Yeah. Sore throat. All of it.
Well, get a billiard
cue and swab it out.
Better feed your bird, Lou.
Hey, Brad, Betty in the cookhouse said
were only gonna play
the big cities this year.
And then close up like a misers heart.
Well, if they're giving
odds, bet a buck for me.
Why the rehearsal just for makeup, Brad?
Because you left off your eyelashes
last performance last season.
You're gonna need an extra shoe
walking back from Kalamazoo.
I'm supposed to be looking for you, Brad.
Well, are you supposed to find me?
Big brass hollering for you up front.
You found me.
Hey, Brad, this might help.
Too small.
Skim off the cream.
Let the little shows
scramble for the thin milk.
Don't forget what circus
day means to a small town.
John North, you're just
soft about the circus.
It's suicide to play this
whole tour this year.
- You gonna tell that to Brad?
- Yes.
A good circus boss carries out orders.
My vote is 10 weeks
and back to Sarasota.
But for 80 years...
That order about keeping the grounds
clean goes for the top brass, too.
- Hi, Brad. I'm sorry about that.
- Good morning.
I've seen happier heads on canes.
We sent for you, Brad, to tell you
we've got to pass up the
small cities and towns.
- Times have changed.
- Kids haven't.
- Prices have.
- Well stay in the black.
You hope.
Look, Brad, here's the
tour for this season.
That's only 10 weeks.
Sixty percent of our money comes from
the big cities in the first 10 weeks.
The worlds upside down,
Brad. We can't take the risk...
Our people risk their necks twice a day.
Well have a short season,
no red ink and no trouble.
Troubles part of the circus.
They said Barnum was in
trouble when he lost Tom Thumb.
They said he was
through when Jumbo died.
Were the greatest show on earth, and
you can't put 1,400 people out of work
because the world has a stomach ache.
And you can't risk $25,000 a day
on a sentimental journey, either.
If you'll play only the big cities, you'll
cut the heart right out of this show.
In two seasons, you'll destroy what
it took his family 80 years to build.
I might vote a few weeks more
if we had a bigger headline.
- Holly isn't known.
- Well, we've got one.
- Didn't you tell him, John?
- Not yet.
Who is it, Johnny?
Have you brought Gargantua back to life?
The Great Sebastian.
- What?
- Oh, no!
Obviously, you're crazy.
Sebastian's wrecked
every show he's been with.
- But he draws like sugar in fly time.
- Nobody can handle him.
- He's never worked for Brad.
- You're buying trouble, Johnny.
I'm buying the best
trapeze act in the air.
Well, he may be a god in the air,
but he's a devil on the ground.
You mean with women?
Do you know how many
women this show carries?
He's not that good, no
matter what you've heard.
- Things are bad enough as it is.
- No, Brad, it's too big a gamble.
You haven't sold me. I'm still
against going under canvas.
- Are you for Sebastian?
- Yes.
Because the only way we could get him
was to sign him for the full season.
I knew there was a trick in it.
You can't get good acts
for a 10-week season!
Cool off, Brad.
Were going to stay out as
long as were in the black.
Agreed?
- As long as we make money, yes.
- If you say so, John.
Well, I don't like it, John.
Thank you, gentlemen. That's it.
And you'd better start
worrying about Sebastian.
- Let me show you...
- You try to give...
I can't believe it.
Hey, Lucky, keep those cats
covered when you move them.
Okay, Mr. Braden.
- Brad?
- Yeah?
You know Sebastian only
works in the centre ring.
I know it.
Id rather crawl in that cage of cats
than have to tell Holly
she's out of the centre ring.
So would I.
You can blame me if you want to.
Thanks, but it's my
medicine. I'll take it.
Come on, boy. Come on.
Hey, Tuffy, off your
back and on your toes.
And give me a little
more slack this time.
You got ample rope now for a hanging.
One more and I'm going to
do without the mechanic.
No deal. I'll put up a net.
What do you think I am, a fish?
You better use a net for this
one, or you'll break your neck,
and Brad will break mine.
Now don't get sentimental,
Tuffy. Come on, lets go.
If Brad sees this,
he'll chew your ears off.
Snap your legs now.
All the way together, Lena.
Point your toes, Janet.
A little more curve.
Relax, relax.
- Any news?
- Nope.
Come on, now. Lets get over it.
Faster, Loni, faster.
What gives, Buttons?
Holly's hatched up a new
hair-raiser for that centre spot.
Quiet around the centre ring!
Everybody, still a minute, please!
Time...
Terrific, Holly!
Pretty good.
Hi, Brad. Do you like it?
You try it again and I'll ground you.
It's the finish on my new act.
It'll finish you and your act.
Don't you want to see it once more?
No. Come on down.
Okay, you're the boss. Watch
it, Tuffy. Here I come.
- Oh, brother.
- Hey, look it.
- Down on seconds.
- Put it in the act, Holly.
That ankle drop is out. I
want you all in one piece.
That's for making the big
brass give us a full season.
You got that trapeze
wired for sound, pigeon?
But you're the kind of fellow who
could talk anybody into anything.
- You did, didn't you?
- Yeah.
Hey, kids, Brad fixed it.
Were gonna play the
full season! Come on!
Did you hear that,
Klaus? The full season!
Down, move down. Make
him put me down, Klaus.
Why?
Do I have to have an
excuse to leave the room?
You know, I think it is the trousers.
Wherever there are trousers, you go.
- Full season, Loni.
- Oh! He filled it.
The full season will buy
me a sable-dyed rabbit coat.
What you have on, I like.
Well, sugar, like it
a little farther away.
- No layoff, Buzzy!
- Tell him, Daisy.
Were hitting the sticks.
Terrific.
Okay...
A full season, isn't that swell?
You're wonderful!
All right, quiet down,
everybody. Quiet down!
Now, listen, and get this, all of you.
We only stay out as long
as were in the black.
Well be in the black, right?
You mean we all got
to play in blackface?
- And Sebastian, too!
- Sebastian?
- Oh, no, he's not.
- Lock up the girls.
Ain't he in Europe?
- Oh, boy, wait till you see him.
- Who did you say?
Well, I don't know, but I heard
that The Great Sebastian's coming.
Is that true, Brad?
News sure travels fast around here.
He's strictly centre ring, isn't he?
That's right.
- Hi. Ain't it great?
- Terrific.
Oh, boy!
Do you know what this is?
Well, sure. It's my
iron-jaw mouthpiece. Why?
Put it in your gabby
mouth and keep it shut.
- Where'd you leave the props?
- Right over here.
He can take care of us now.
All right. Get your bits,
girls. You, too, Philip.
Well, I guess I know where I stand.
- Holly, listen...
- To what?
More promises about next
year, the year after that?
I was a fool to believe you.
You'd sell out your own
grandmother for a name act.
- You know there's nobody...
- Don't say you're sorry.
I couldn't take that.
I'm sorry there's only one centre ring.
Oh, sure. I know. The show comes first.
I didn't want to do this.
Save your breath. I know
just what you're gonna say.
Oh, Brad, I had the centre ring.
You told me I could have it.
Holly, you want the show
to play the road, don't you?
I worked in every act in this circus.
I'm in spec, I'm in manage, I'm
a rose on the beauty float,
I fill in with the flyers.
I work from start to finish.
Well, so do most of the others. It
was the only way to get a full season.
But my own act,
the one thing that's really mine,
that I've worked on for three years,
that you toss right
out of the centre ring.
Pigeon, look, you're the
best trapeze act in the show.
- Then why don't you leave me in centre?
- Because Sebastian's a bigger draw.
Brad, I'll draw them. Leave me there.
Sebastian's sure. You're a chance.
You don't take chances
with the show, do you?
No.
All right.
I'll move over.
Where do I go?
Ring one.
Oh, Brad,
Id do my act in clown alley
or the horse top for you.
Id do anything if it was just for you.
Pigeon, look, out under the sky,
you know how I feel about you.
But under the big top, one
performers just like another to me.
You've got nothing but
sawdust in your veins.
I've scraped too many of you
kinkers up from the sawdust
to let anybody get under my skin.
Just so the show rolls.
You don't care who it
rolls over or who it hurts.
So it rolls over me.
Be careful someday it
doesn't roll over you.
Don't worry.
I'll have my rigging out of centre
before The Great Sebastian arrives.
- Tuffy, tear down my rigging.
- Okay.
Like peanuts, Harry?
I got everything lined up, Mr. Henderson.
Gaff wheels, novelties for sucker bait,
and two of the best
stickmen in the rackets.
I'll work it just like the Columbia show.
No, Harry, you got a tough guy
here you didn't have at Columbia.
Brad Braden? I'll handle him.
With your brains, you
couldn't handle that hippo.
Listen, if Braden gets in my
way, I'll roll right over him.
He'd break you in two.
Not with you backing me, Mr. Henderson.
He's too smart to tangle with your boys.
I'll cut him in, maybe.
You can't buy men like Braden.
And don't meet him head-on.
Okay, I'll go around him.
Great.
What about the bankroll for the games?
Have some more peanuts, Harry.
Peanuts?
Hi, potato. Getting ready to roll?
What's the potato gag?
- Here, wrap that for me, will you?
- Okay.
Well, there's mashed potatoes and
hashed potatoes, sweet potatoes.
I don't feel very sweet,
except maybe about you.
You're always helping everybody, Buttons.
- Brad asked me to help you.
- Was he sorry about it?
Maybe he was just worried I
wouldn't have my rigging down
before The Great Sebastian arrives.
Could be. Could be.
He doesn't consider anybody's feelings
when it comes to running the circus.
You're telling me. I'm
so mad I could spit.
Well, why don't you spit then?
You know, Brads not
a man, he's a machine,
like the tractors and the generators.
Why, Buttons, I thought
you were his friend.
Well, he broke his word to you.
You could never trust him again.
That isn't true!
Brads been worried sick about
getting us all a full season.
If he had to throw me out, he
had to throw me out and its...
You didn't mean any
of what you just said.
I made you see it his
way a little, didn't I?
Darn you.
- You make me feel like a big idiot.
- Yeah, well, stop acting like one then.
Well, anyway, I'm still mad at
him. And I'm mad at you, too.
Say, that's pretty neat.
Reminds me of a bandage I wore
once when I sprained my ankle.
Buttons, why can Brad hurt me so?
Why do I always want to hurt him back?
They say each man kills
the thing he loves.
A coward does it with a kiss,
a brave man with a sword.
Why, that's crazy.
You wouldn't hurt anyone you loved.
Who knows what a man
will do when he's in love?
Every girl in the
show has tried for you.
But I guess you already
have someone, huh?
Could be.
Is she in one of the
towns were gonna play?
I haven't seen the route sheet.
Is that why you don't try
to romance any of the gals?
No. Clowns are funny people, Holly.
They only love once.
All men aren't that way even
if they act like clowns.
No, I suppose not.
Oh, Buttons, I'm all ache inside,
having a man love sawdust more than me.
Well, maybe he'll have
to make a choice someday.
Choice?
If ever I'm in his arms, his
head will be in the machine shop
- or bedding down the hippopotamus.
- Yeah.
You're lucky. Everybody loves you.
Ten million kids and your girl.
You'll be seeing her pretty soon.
We roll in three days.
Yeah.
Into the sunshine of spring,
the circus rises from
its winter hibernation,
spick-and-span,
and ready for eight months
of excitement and adventure.
The circus trains, like Noah's Ark,
will carry and shelter man and beast
through flood and mud
and heat and storm,
through triumph and adversity.
1,400 souls,
each sure the season will
bring his hearts desire.
- You dropped something!
- Hey, look out, look out.
Why don't you drive where you're looking?
I wish one of your dogs would bite you.
All right, boys! Come on.
All right. Keep it coming.
Keeping it coming. That's right.
Keep it coming.
Get tight in front of those wheels.
Can't locate Sebastian. Tried
the hospitals, the hotels.
Straighten that wagon
out! Come on! Get with it!
We pull out in a half an hour
whether he's aboard or not.
Check both railroad stations and...
- Who's that?
- Sebastian, I guess.
- Hi, Sebastian.
- Hello!
Get a load of that.
Where's the fire at?
Oh, baby!
This ought to be good.
Where is the boss man?
I thought he was.
I am Sebastian. I am
honoured to be with you.
I hope your acts as
good as your entrance.
I've seen them all arrive,
Caldona, The Concellos,
none of them ever came
with a funeral escort.
The police escort, it was not my idea.
- I clocked him at 75 in a 15-mile
zone. - Running a red light.
I got him for cutting
in and out of traffic
on the wrong side of the highway.
In the war, I drive a tank.
Sometimes I forget. I forgot.
Yeah, well, the judge will add
that up to about $100 or 60 days.
$100?
Then it'll be 60 days in jail.
I would hate to be absent the
first two months of the show.
Okay, boys. I'll buy him back.
Take my jeep, Lawson.
Settle it in the office.
Get your baggage aboard.
You can park that heap
in the menagerie house.
I salute you.
We shall get along together splendidly.
Hey!
Don't crowd, mister.
Can't you see an elephant, or
do I have to paint her red?
I was blinded by the memory of
an unforgettable night in Paris.
Blow up your water wings,
girls. Here comes the big wave.
Come on, Ruth.
How come no husband ever shot you?
I never offer a sitting target.
I thought Id seen the last of you
when you got mixed up with
that wirewalker from Lisbon.
You will never see
the last of me, Angel.
Angel!
That will be arranged
when you meet Klaus.
Angel!
Sebastian!
- Hello, handsome. Remember?
- Natalia!
- No, honey ball, Phyllis.
- Of course.
Lovely Phyllis with
the charming iron jaw.
Well, I'm still hanging
on to my job with it.
All right.
It saves your feet. Sure
tough on your clothes, though.
Thanks for the ride, sugar.
You know Sebastian, eh?
- Sure, were old friends.
- How good friends?
Listen, you can worry about
any other guy in the show,
but not Sebastian.
I wouldn't want him if he
were dipped in gold dust.
We will make beautiful
music together, huh?
Yeah, the last time, I
remember a few sour notes.
Oh, Natalia was...
Who is that?
They threw me off the ball team
because I was catching
home runs at second base.
Say, how come the Giants passed you up?
I don't know.
Oh, that's the giant and the fat boy.
No, no. In between.
- Oh, that's Holly.
- Holly?
She's interesting.
I wouldn't meet her
just now if I were you.
- You're poison.
- Why?
- You just put her out of the centre ring.
- I did?
Excuse me.
Music.
- Well, here we go again.
- Did you bring any cards?
- Oh, my feet are killing me.
- Well, then, keep off of mine.
Pardon. Is it true what
Phyllis has told me?
- I wouldn't know.
- Pardon.
Wait a minute!
That they put you out of
the centre ring for me?
I am Sebastian.
- You mean you didn't know?
- How could I?
- I am very, very sorry.
- I'll get over it.
If you're half as good in the
air as you look on the ground,
you are at least terrific.
The boss seems to have other ideas.
Say, they tell me that you
work with two bars like I do.
No. You work with two bars like I do.
Anyway, I'm glad to meet you.
It means so much to
you, the centre ring?
- Don't be funny.
- Excuse me.
Would you hold these, please?
- Oh, yes, Sebastian.
- Thank you.
- Come.
- Where?
- To see the boss.
- What for?
I will insist he put
you right back again.
You aren't kidding me, are you?
- Come and see.
- Oh, boy, will I!
Keep going. This isn't a parking lot.
That was a beautiful
doll you made for Sissy.
I'm glad she liked it. Hello, Holly.
Oh, Buttons!
I want you to meet The Great Sebastian.
This is Buttons. You'll love
him. Everybody does. Come on.
- Why are you in makeup?
- Why are you The Great Sebastian?
Get those runs in,
and were about through.
Mr. Braden, we've got
trouble, 750 pounds of it.
- Yeah, we can't get Tiny aboard.
- Can't even get him through the door.
Go along with Lotus.
They'll make you comfortable in her car.
That hippo? She might get hungry.
Don't worry. She's a vegetarian.
Brad! Brad!
Sebastian's got something to tell you.
Better tie him in so
he wont roll! Has he?
You know what? He wants to
give up the centre ring to me.
Isn't he wonderful?
Yeah. Wonderful.
Where do you propose to go?
I have had the centre ring.
To me, it does not matter.
Ring one or ring three, as you wish.
He really means it, Brad.
He's not just grandstanding.
- Holly...
- Oh, Brad.
I've wanted that ring ever
since I've been a foot high.
Do you know what were paying Sebastian?
You know how his billing
reads? He's the star of the show.
And the star requests ring three.
Who do you think you're kidding?
I'm sorry, Holly, but the
people watch the star.
That's why the star
plays the centre ring.
The people watch the star, do they?
Well, they're going to be watching me.
If you wont let him
give me the centre ring,
I'll take it away from him.
Oh, no, ma chérie.
I may give it away, but
no one will take it away.
Look, Sebastian.
You're a nice guy, and I
hate to do this to you,
but I'm going to make
ring one the centre ring.
If you do something
once, I'll do it twice.
If you do a double, I'll do a triple.
If you stand on your
head, I'll stand on my ear.
Not while I'm around, you wont.
The one place you're not
around is 40 feet straight up.
Maybe that's why I like it there.
I'm warning you, the audiences
are going to be looking at me.
And so will I.
You start any trouble,
and I'll ground you both.
Hello, Brad. Were here to
bless the circus trains again.
It's good to see you, Father.
Could you pour it on a
little extra heavy this time?
- Of course we can.
- I think were going to need it.
All right, boys. Raise
that run up and get it in.
Even.
Loading.
Hurry it up, little Jim!
- Give me your hand.
- Don't fall, now.
Oh, boy!
Bye. See you in Washington.
Bye, Father!
Bye, Father.
...one of the featured attractions
of the greatest show on earth.
Come right on in. Lets everybody go.
...boys and girls...
She's going to swallow
first this curved sword,
and you will notice that
she has to twist her body
in order that the sword
can go down her curved neck.
Do you think it's sharp?
Children of all ages!
John Ringling North welcomes you
to the greatest show on earth.
Brainy bruins with new ideas.
Himalayan, Russian,
Syrian and polar bears.
Sleek and shining as silver dollars,
Roland Tiebor's marvellous, amazing,
sophisticated sea lions.
The internationally
famous riding canine!
He did it, Mama!
Back, boy!
Foot!
Foot! Foot!
That foots pretty rough
to go in a girls face.
- File it.
- All right.
Hey, the duel or whatever you call
it for the centre ring, Mr. Braden?
Yeah? What about it?
I hear they're slapping death
in the face twice a day.
The paper wants to know
if it's on the level.
Coming right on. Take a look.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the sensation of the ages.
In ring one,
the beautiful bird of paradise,
queen of the flying trapeze,
the daring, the incredible,
the death-defying,
peerless and fearless Holly!
And in the centre ring,
the outstanding aerial
daredevil of all time,
the debonair king of the
air, The Great Sebastian!
It sure packs them in. Best
publicity gag in a long time.
It's no gag, brother.
You wouldn't kid me, would you?
Kid you? They're working without nets.
Boy, look at that guy.
Look at her!
If they don't get killed.
It's all done with mirrors, mister.
- Well, what are they going to do now?
- Changing bars.
Should I whistle them down,
Brad? They're changing their act.
No. Leave them alone.
They're doing all right.
Okay. You're the boss.
Hey, Sebastian, try it
without the doughnut!
How long do you think this can
go on before something happens?
That's circus, isn't it?
Do you believe in prayer?
And practise.
- What if one of them falls?
- Nobody's going to fall.
This is packing them in every show.
- We stay in the black or close down.
- Oh, stop talking so tough.
You know, that isn't the
bass drum I hear thumping.
That's your heart.
You know...
I know.
Well, I've had enough.
Well, that was a close one.
Well, are you ready to call it off?
I have not started yet,
but you were magnificent.
- Sure stole it today, Holly.
- Thanks, Bob.
You two had quite a
party up there, didn't you?
Did you notice which
ring they were looking at?
If you really want to kill
yourself, wait till the seasons over.
Well, what do you know?
He was worried about me.
So was I.
From here on, cut out the dogfights
up there and stick to your acts.
Brad, don't be a killjoy.
You don't know what it's like up
there. It's a different world.
Just the two of us
fighting for the crowd.
You feel like you could do
anything. Were not people up there.
Were like two streaks of
light with wings and...
You wouldn't understand.
- Nobody would, except another flyer.
- Like Sebastian?
Yeah.
Like Sebastian.
Come on, come on. We
need people for the spec.
- Did you watch the show?
- Yeah. It was terrific!
- McClosky wants you, Brad.
- Okay.
- Did you follow me?
- Yeah.
- That's not the half of it!
- Please go up to the costume...
You and Sebastian got an exclusive
little club up there in the air?
Get yourself a trapeze
if you want to join.
And don't park your chewing
gum on the moon again, please.
Why don't he look at me anymore?
Have I got too much or not enough?
Don't worry, sugar.
He'll get around to you.
- I'm hoping.
- Maybe he wont.
Did your elephant sit on this zipper?
He says were artists up there together.
He'd tell that to a trained
seal if it paid off.
Maybe he shows his bad side
to you and his good side to me.
Listen, Snow White, you're
not fighting this guy,
you're falling for him.
He was good enough for you once.
Maybe you'd like to have him back.
I wouldn't give Sebastian the right time
if Brad was as nuts about
me as he is about you.
Brad? Are you kidding?
I come fourth. After Ringling
Bros., Barnum and Bailey.
You're eating too many potatoes.
When Brad doesn't come home nights,
you'll know the blonde he's
sitting up with is a giraffe.
Hey, Holly, you trying to corner the
market or just starting a collection?
- My...
- Well, you only work with your teeth.
Get with it, Mabel. Three
minutes. So lets get it all on.
Okay.
If it were only you, sugar,
Id let you ride the roller
coaster all the way down.
But I'm thinking about Brad.
Why do you want to bust up
the swellest guy in the circus?
Sounds like you've got it bad.
He's the only guy that looks at me
that I don't know what he's thinking.
He's thinking circus.
He hasn't thought anything but circus
since he fell out of the cradle.
But if you want him so
bad, what's stopping you?
Maybe because I knew too
many guys like Sebastian
before I met Brad.
Been around too much, huh?
You haven't been gathering
any moss, either.
Brads a one-woman man.
I've got a feeling he
wants a one-man woman.
I don't rate a guy like that.
Angel?
Besides, right now she's got
elephant trainer trouble.
Angel!
You better hurry.
That's not Sabu calling.
That's what I like about
him. He's so gentle.
Who wants them gentle? I like them wild.
Oh, come on, birdie. Get going.
Angel, come along!
You should have seen Brads
face when you took that tumble.
She was too busy watching Sebastian.
- Put your claws away, girls.
- Holly.
Gee, if all the Rangers
looked like Sebastian,
me for Texas.
You and plenty more, huh, Holly?
Look, all I want from
him is the centre ring.
You always have a smile for
that high-flying peacock.
Well, what you want
me to do, cry over him?
I feel like a turret gunner.
Made it.
Okay, batten down the hatches.
Hey, Rich, get me a hot dog, will you?
- We ain't got time.
- Well, I'm hungry!
You always are.
An album of favourite songs.
A circus serenade.
A Disney album.
It's Mickey Mouse. Hi, Mickey!
Come on, Donald!
Look at Pluto!
Hi, Alice!
Oh, and there the Mad
Hatter. The Mad Hatter.
A Gay Nineties album.
A moonlight serenade.
The magic of moonlight melodies,
with the lovely Phyllis
as goddess of the moon.
Nursery rhymes.
The lady who taught you
your first fairy tale,
Mother Goose!
She's big, isn't she?
A barbershop ballad.
A bouquet of American beauties,
with the lovely Holly
as the centre rosebud
singing Only a Rose.
Gee, you have a funny mouth.
- Let me hold him.
- Go away.
Look it. Isn't it pretty?
They've been around
again asking questions.
I'm so worried for you.
Oh, now don't worry. They'll
never find me behind this nose.
Be very careful, dear.
Now how about a nice smile
that I can remember till next year?
God be with you, my boy.
It's all right, Mother.
Only a rose
Here we go!
Only a smile to keep in memory
Until we meet another day
Only a rose to whisper
Blushing as roses do
I'll bring along a smile
or a song for anyone
Only a rose for you
A Stephen Foster album.
A South American album!
Exotic firebirds from
the forests of the Amazon,
a blaze of breathtaking beauty.
A very special surprise
for children of all ages,
our guest star for tonight,
Hopalong Cassidy!
That's him! Sure, it's Hoppy!
A Christmas album.
Jingle bells, jingle
bells Jingle all the way
Oh, what fun it is to ride
in a one-horse open sleigh
Your hair is too red,
your legs are too thin,
you have lips like a cat.
You're no good. You give
me too much trouble.
Flattery rolls right off me.
But you make a fire here.
Well, simmer down, General,
before you melt your medals.
What could be more fitting
for the Christmas album
than Adeste Fideles?
The performance ends,
but the drama never stops.
In the grey, drizzly morning,
the first section of the circus
train pulls into the railroad yard,
long before the city is awake.
But the animals are awake and
looking for their breakfast.
Then comes the unloading.
Two hundred tons of living power.
Sixty carloads of equipment.
Wheels rolling, gears grinding.
A circus is gigantic power
and unceasing movement.
It is a restless giant,
unlimbering its muscles
after the long night ride
before moving in to capture a new city.
Up from the railroad yards
with their faithful escort
of early-rising young fans
who've been waiting since daybreak
to follow these living tanks
as they lumber and sway
to the circus grounds,
where the stakes are being driven
that will anchor the big top
against the beating of
its constant adversaries,
wind and rain.
An army is at work, an army
the audience never sees.
An army that must be moved from
city to city, fed and housed,
a thousand strong, hardworking men,
moving like a finely-geared
machine, with one purpose,
to roll the show.
The all-important baling
ring clangs into place.
Bales of fireproof canvas,
58,000 pounds of it,
are hauled out, unwrapped, rolled out,
stretched, laid on the ground,
where it lies like the skin
of a mighty dismembered giant,
waiting for some magician
to bring it together and give it life,
waiting until, one by one,
the giants ribs rise into place
and are firmly fastened in the earth.
Boys line up for the punt games,
a chance for a free ticket.
The disciplined army never loses
a moment nor wastes a motion.
The boss canvas man makes fast
the canvas to the baling ring.
The lives of all depend on it.
Each of the hundreds of roustabouts
has his place and his job,
a responsible job, for one
mistake, one bit of carelessness,
could cost a life.
The giants skin is stretched out
until it lies smooth and moulded,
like the bowl of a great coliseum.
But eyes watching for trouble
have noticed a little
tear that must be patched
before the searching fingers of the wind
can rip it into a disaster,
before the giant can
stand up and stretch
over his feast of colour and laughter.
Now the giant comes to life.
Slowly, the tons and
tons of his canvas body
rise and swell into the air.
He starts growing to
his full, majestic height
as he catches his first deep breath.
The strong baling rings
slipping along the great poles,
until at last they reach to
the flags flying from the peak.
And as the big top rises in
each town, new risks are taken.
Caution is thrown to the winds
in this battle for the centre ring.
...55, 56, 57, 58,
59, 60, 61,
62, 63, 64,
65, 66, 67,
68, 69...
I warned her not to do
Jenny's act on that rigging.
Yeah. I was there the
night Jenny got killed.
...75, 76, 77,
78, 79, 80,
81, 82, 83,
84, 85, 86,
87, 88, 89,
90, 91, 92,
93, 94, 95,
96, 97, 98...
- Paying for the hay all in silver?
- That's how we get paid.
Holly's spinning like a
weathervane in a Kansas twister.
- Swingovers?
- Yeah.
Her rope isn't rigged for that.
Tell the ringmaster to
whistle in The Zoppes.
- Fast.
- Right.
...107, 108, 109,
110, 111, 112...
Come on.
114, 115, 116,
117...
- What are they doing, Grandma?
- I don't know.
121, 122, 123,
124...
Like a fish on a line!
The red rope!
Hey, you!
You! Are you crazy?
Hauling me down in front of everybody!
Everybody laughing at me!
I was going for a record!
What's the matter, are you jealous?
Can't you stand to see me
work in the air anymore?
You can't do that trick
on a pull-up rope.
- I was doing it, wasn't I?
- Get out of the way.
A hurricane of hazardous horsemanship
displayed by the riding Zoppes!
Why didn't you put her over
your knee and spank her?
That would get some laughs, too.
Haven't you got enough clowns, you
got to make a comic out of her?
- She was trying to break a record.
- Shed have broken more than a record.
You sure saved her a buster.
You better tell her, Brad,
or shell never forgive you.
Alberto Zoppe and Cucciola,
worlds smallest bareback rider!
I would buy you spring violets
from the little old lady
in the Place de I'Opera
and crépes suzettes.
You never eaten them?
Paris is a honeymoon city,
chérie, full of enchantment.
On a night like this, the
Seine is deep and mysterious,
like a woman's eyes.
The lights in it are like jewels.
Did you know, chérie, in your eyes
there are lights like stardust?
No, but keep going.
You are beautiful and
exciting, like wine.
You know women are like wine?
Some are like sweet Sauternes,
some are warm like Burgundy, some...
Which one was Angel?
- Angel?
- Angel.
Angel was like cognac,
all fire in a glass.
But you...
You are like champagne.
Sparkling, tantalizing.
You make a mans head spin.
- You've got a terrific line.
- A line? What is that?
Well, I mean, you've said all
this before to too many girls.
Well, never to one like you.
Oh, I have wandered a little.
But how else could I appreciate
what I have found now?
Id better go.
When we are up in the air,
I fall more and more in love.
- You, too, no?
- No.
A girl may say no, but
the woman in her means yes.
- Do not be afraid of me.
- I'm just scared of myself.
It is not of yourself. It
is love that frightens you.
Feel. My heart beats fast like yours.
- That's the magic of it. You love me.
- No. I mean, I don't know.
Let me go! Sebastian!
Never try to take
anything from an elephant.
Sebastian, do something!
A lion, I'll fight for you. A tiger.
But a redheaded wildcat
with an elephant, no.
You make this two-tailed
jackass put me down!
Did he tell you about
Paris in the spring?
It's none of your
business what he told...
Did he say you were like
cognac, all fire in the glass?
No. He said I was like
champagne. I made his head spin.
Yeah, only you'll be the one
that wakes up with a hangover.
You take care of your love
life, and I'll take care of mine.
No, I've got four
working here. That's all.
Well, if you've got an
elephant missing, go find her.
Joe, send into town.
They had a Republican
convention there tonight.
Hold it. Here's your
missing Jumbo. It's okay.
Come on, move it up,
Ruth. Come on. Move it up.
You...
All right. Put her down.
What's this, a new act?
You nearly lost your
stray lamb to a wolf.
You know, you've got a nose as
long as that elephants trunk.
Keep them both out of my business.
They're looking for this bull
down at the railroad yard.
- Ruth just couldn't resist the hay pile.
- Id hate to have your nerve in a tooth.
Come on, sugar. Lets go. Come on.
I think your coffees kind of cold.
- Why did you do that, Holly?
- I don't know.
There's just something
about Sebastian that I...
Yeah, he's some glamour boy.
He said I had stardust in my eyes.
- I bet you never even noticed.
- Sure, I have.
But you weren't rigged
for that one-armed swing.
I know, just so the show keeps rolling.
Come over here. I want
to show you something.
Just a few more spins up there.
- You would've lost a good act.
- One of the best.
Now, look, Holly, I want you to
soft-pedal this stuff with Sebastian.
- You do, Brad? Why?
- It's gone too far.
I guess you're right. I
have been playing with fire.
But it's all your fault. If
you weren't such a big lug...
I'm talking about your act, this
duel or whatever you call it.
I want you to stop it
before you get hurt.
Is it me you're worried
about or the circus?
- You.
- Brad, do you really mean that?
Why couldn't you say so?
Sure, I'll cut it out.
But I've got pride.
He'll look better than me.
- With a net under him?
- A net? Why a net?
To save his expensive neck.
- Well, I don't want a net.
- All right, then stick to the old act.
Sure, Brad. Whatever you say.
And when Sebastian tones
down, his net comes out, too.
Now, you going to stop
fooling around up there?
Sure, Brad.
- What about on the ground?
- On the ground?
Oh, that reminds me, Jeannie
pulled her shoulder tonight.
Shell be on the ground for a while.
Will you fill in with the flyers again?
Of course, Brad, but you
were just gonna say that...
Line up that pole wagon! Swing it over!
Brad, on the ground...
- Do you want me to stop seeing him?
- On the ground? I...
Doughnuts?
You left a little of your
fragrance behind with your scarf.
May I escort you to the train?
I'm waiting for Brad.
- Till the next time, chérie.
- There wont be any next time.
No?
I think you have stardust
mixed up with sawdust.
Good night, boss man.
And on the ground,
I wouldn't want to meddle
in your private affairs.
To the right and left of the doorway.
Pompom hats, folks. Step right up.
Put your name on them,
your sweethearts name,
your wife's name, even
your mother-in-laws name.
Step right up, folks. Get your
pompom hats before you leave.
- For you, Liebchen, a present.
- Thank you, sugar.
Straight from Paris and twice as classy.
- How does it look?
- It looks good.
Read it, what it says.
Angel, du bist mein. What's it mean?
You are mine.
Listen, sugar, I'm not yours.
And I'm not wearing
any hat that says so.
The sooner you take no for an answer,
the easier it's gonna be for
both of us. Because it is no.
The only thing I like about
you are your elephants.
But, Angel...
Want to win a baby doll?
Wise up. I know dolls.
They're my business. Takes
dough to get a dame like her.
Her heart is ice.
She wouldn't say no to
a hunk of ice like this.
But I could not buy such a thing.
Go ahead, take it. Your
credits okay with me.
- What's the matter, pal?
- My wallets gone.
Are you sure?
I had the wallet in my
pocket when I was right here.
- And I had $10 in it.
- Did you, now?
- You must be mistaken, friend.
- Oh, no. I...
Well, maybe I was.
Harry, you make trouble.
Right this way, folks,
and win a baby doll!
Everybody plays, everybody wins.
Keep your eye on the arrow, folks.
Round and round it goes and
where it stops, nobody knows.
Hurry, hurry, hurry,
hurry. Everybody plays.
How did he get in there?
Waters coming out of it.
Look at that silly umbrella.
Sit down, Son.
Your attention, please.
The greatest show on
earth proudly presents
the most sensational
flying acts of all time,
dazzling, dauntless daredevils
of the flying trapeze,
breathtaking, death-defying
marvels in midair!
Hey!
Hello.
You crazy devil, how
did you get up here?
I bribed your catcher.
- Let me go!
- Kiss me.
Look, you're holding up the act.
I could swing with
you forever like this.
Why will you not see me anymore?
- They're waiting. Please put me back.
- Not until you kiss me.
When I kiss you, I need both
feet on the ground. Let me go.
- You really insist, chérie?
- Yes! Let me go!
Goodbye.
Sebastian wont give up, Brad.
You better marry me quick
or I'm a gone pigeon.
You get back up there and finish
the act or you'll be a dead pigeon.
Yes, sir.
We got trouble on the midway.
- Harry?
- Yeah, his doll concession.
Get yourself a little spending
money. Here we go for another spin.
The more you play, the more you win.
- Lets go, Sam. You can't win at this.
- I got no more money anyhow.
Come on, mister, you can't quit now.
You're bound to hit it this time.
What do you think you're
doing? Let go of me.
- How much did you lose, lady?
- This months egg money, nearly $50.
Take this. Go on in and enjoy the show.
Get rid of the customers, Joe.
Don't mix it, Brad. You'll get hurt.
- You know I run a clean show.
- You're not running me!
Hey, did you see that?
Right in the kisser!
Hey, look out, Brad!
The boss finally caught you, huh?
Nice going.
Do you know who's backing me?
Yeah, and he's backing
your whole dirty setup.
Now get going.
The luscious Phyllis dances and sings
to the sultry south sea strains
of Lovely Luawana Lady!
Lovely Luawana lady
When your hopes and dreams grow fadey
Don't you ever be afraid
He wont come back to you
Lovely Luawana lady
Where those yukes and jukes are played
He dreams of all the dreams he made
And longs that they'll come true
Ever since he's back
There's been no lack of gals
But, gee, they're slow
They don't have that wicky wack
You taught him there
when the moon was low
Now every Susie, Sal, and Sadie
Just becomes a memory shady
Lovely Luawana lady
When he dreams of you
You made a mistake, Mr.
Braden, a bad mistake,
throwing my games off the lot.
They're off, Mr. Henderson,
and they stay off.
It might save you a lot of
trouble if you let Harry come back.
Wherever you operate, the
midways crawling with pickpockets
and crooked gambling.
One rotten apple like you
can ruin a whole circus.
You know, you're not so tough.
You wont stand a chance
fighting my outfit.
- I've never run away from a fight yet.
- And I've never lost one.
There's no smoking allowed
in here, Mr. Henderson.
Don't throw it away.
I'll show you the way out.
Lovely Luawana lady
When your hopes and dreams grow fadey
Don't you ever be afraid
He wont come back to you
Now every Susie, Sal, and Sadie
Just becomes a memory shady
Lovely Luawana lady
When he dreams of you
Are you afraid to speak to me?
The applause, the centre ring, you
do not try to steal them anymore.
I don't have to. The only
net I use is in my hair.
- That net, it was the boss mans orders.
- Safety first.
- Who can be safe near you?
- You can.
Ringmaster?
I have a surprise for you. I
fly from the big rigging tonight.
Oh, Mr. Thompson, when I
signal, will you announce
that I will do a double forward
over the bar through a paper hoop.
- A double?
- Through a hoop?
Through a hoop.
That's not so much with a net under you.
Stop it, you two. You're on.
Chérie...
The net, it bothers you?
- You crazy fool!
- No net.
Thank you, my friend.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the sensation of the ages!
In ring one,
the beautiful and spectacular
queen of the flying trapeze,
the incredible Holly!
And in the centre ring,
the outstanding aerial
daredevil of all time,
the debonair king of the
air, The Great Sebastian!
No net.
And now, for the first time
in this or any other circus,
The Great Sebastian will
attempt a double somersault
over the bar, through a hoop,
scorning a net or any
other safety device.
Hope he makes it.
Sebastian, no! Don't
try it without the net!
Who took that net down?
- He did. You want it up again?
- It's too late now. He's ready to go.
Go on, now.
Keep the show rolling.
Roll up this net. Clowns!
Holly, keep it going.
Go into your swing.
No.
Walk me off.
Do not rob me of my exit.
All right.
Your arm, boss man. Your strong arm.
Easy now.
Keep your seats, please!
The Great Sebastian is
shaken but not badly hurt.
The performance is now continuing!
Resume your seats! Please!
- Birdie, is he dead?
- No, I don't think so.
Draw it back.
- Carefully now.
- All right.
Back to wardrobe,
girls. Back to wardrobe.
- Will he be all right, Doc?
- He's lucky to be alive.
- Thanks for the help, Buttons.
- Okay.
Where did you ever learn
to do a Velpeau bandage?
Well, you learn a lot when
you're a pharmacists mate.
You must've been the best in the Navy.
Gee, he's hurt bad.
The other way. Turn him around.
Don't transfer him. Just
leave him on this stretcher.
Sebastian!
Of all the crazy things.
Why did you do it?
I didn't mean for it
to happen like this.
Only he would try
such a wonderful trick.
- And you almost did it.
- I will do it. The next time.
Sure, you will.
And when you come back, you'll
stand them on their ears.
When I come back, chérie,
you will fall. For me.
All right, get him in there.
Lets get started. Get a move on.
Oh, Brad.
Flyers have fallen
before. They will again.
He wont die, pigeon.
Your rig goes in centre ring tomorrow.
But I didn't want it like this,
not over his broken body.
Under the big top, only two
days count, today and tomorrow.
The circus rolls on whether
flyers rise or flyers fall.
And week after week,
new audiences laugh at
the antics of the clowns
and thrill to incredible
feats of skill and daring.
Hot roasted peanuts. Peanuts.
Get them while they're hot.
Hot roasted peanuts.
I can't watch it.
Higher, higher!
- Take another crack at it, Holly.
- Higher this time. Sky's the limit.
Play it, Emmett. Give me some rhythm.
Yeah, maybe that'll help.
Well, whistle or something.
- Anybody got a lemon?
- You think that'll work?
- Start your jug band.
- Noodle it up.
- Give it plenty of bounce!
- Yeah, pick it up, Ed.
Hit it, Holly!
When things go wrong and life's no song
And you're flat on your back
That doesn't mean you have to lie there
Be a jumpin' jack
Keep on the hop and if you flop
In every single plan
Stand on your head and holler, Hi, there
Be a jumpin' jack
When things go up They must come down
And also vice-a verse
If things look bad, don't fret and frown
They could be ten times worse
Get Emmett!
Your train of luck
It may get stuck
If something's on the track
Take a good jump
And you'll get by there
Be a jumpin' jack
Oh, Sebastian, you're back.
- Hi, there, gorgeous.
- We missed you.
A stitch in time saves more than nine.
I'll bet they took plenty in you.
Hey, you were doing this when I left.
- Hello.
- Sebastian, you're out of the hospital.
Yes, but never out of
danger when I see you.
Hello, Sebastian.
Fine. I hope both your heads are well.
Vita, don't eat too much. You'll
break your sisters pretty neck.
Well, if it isn't Superman!
- Something will get burned.
- It sure will.
If you play with fire, you get
burned. I still have my scar.
Brad! Oh, Brad! Sebastian's back!
Oh, good, good.
Cucciola!
Say, it looks like the
hospital agreed with you.
So did the nurses.
- Hi, Sebastian.
- Hello. How are you?
I'll open your trunk
and lay your stuff out.
Thank you.
Hey, good to see you. Now maybe
I'll get my five bucks back.
Maybe I'll borrow five more.
Sebastian, it sure wasn't
the same without you, fella.
Hello. I practised somersaults
in my bed every day.
But did you do any bedsprings?
Why is it whenever
he's around I'm all wet?
In more ways than one.
If you should slip and lose your grip
Get up and bounce right back
Act just like a rubber ball...
Look, Holly! Sebastian!
Sebastian.
He sure looks good.
- It's been three months.
- Yeah, that's right. So it is.
Hello, Sebastian. Glad
you're out of the hospital.
I'm sorry you weren't with me.
The show missed you.
Sebastian!
- Sebastian.
- Holly.
Oh, jiminy crickets! Oh, gosh!
I've never been so happy to see anyone.
Are you all right
again? Really all right?
Let me see if it's really you.
It was a wonderful hospital.
And such nurses, too.
And we were worried about this big lug.
This calls for a celebration.
He came back when he heard how
good you were in the centre ring.
I was just keeping it warm for you.
- I do not want it.
- Why not?
- You don't want the centre ring back?
Because I just came back
to collect my things.
What for?
- Match?
- No, thank you.
Collect your...
Now I know he's kidding.
No, no. I dropped over
at the Columbia show.
Columbia?
We've been fighting them in
every town since you left.
I ran into somebody over there
I had not seen since Paris,
and very charming.
You know how it is. These things happen.
No. What happens?
You know. A pearl loses
it's luster in time.
Champagne goes flat, doesn't it?
Even the blond bubbling
kind goes flat very quickly.
Well, I will get my gear and rigging.
You don't plan to work
for Columbia, do you?
Let him go, Brad. He's
found some more stardust.
No, he hasn't.
Chérie, I return you to
sawdust. Sawdust to sawdust.
You wouldn't work for Columbia.
You're The Great Sebastian.
You wouldn't give up the centre
ring for anything or anybody,
unless you couldn't hold it.
You've been lying ever
since you came in here.
- Now lets see the truth.
- Keep your hands off...
- You should not have done that.
- That's why you wouldn't shake hands.
You weren't going to Columbia.
There wasn't any girl from Paris.
You just didn't want me to know...
To know what Id done.
No, no, no, chérie.
You have done nothing.
It is life.
No one is to blame.
- Can't something be done?
- No. They have tried.
May I have my coat, please?
There's a job for you in this
show as long as you want it.
One more cripple
hanging on to the circus?
Watching others flying through the
air while I am crawling on the ground?
You are meaning to be kind, boss man,
but you and I both know
it is better that I go.
Don't let him go, Brad!
Holly, he's grounded for good.
Hell go crazy if he stays.
- I did that to him.
- No, he took the chance.
I did it to him, as
surely as if Id shot him.
- You had nothing to do with it.
- Oh, yes, I did, Brad.
I made him take that net down.
I laughed at him. I razzed him into
it. That's what made him take it down!
You two crazy fools.
He was tops in the air.
Now he's tied to a dead arm
for the rest of his life,
a claw hand.
- It would've been kinder if Id killed him.
- Holly, this is circus.
Brad, you can't realise what it
means not to go up there again.
Maybe I can.
That's why it's better to let him go.
- If he goes, I'm going with him.
- Holly, don't be a fool!
You saw the way he hid his arm,
said things to make me hate him.
He said them because he
didn't want me to know...
To know that Id smashed him,
smashed his whole life.
He didn't want me to
know because he loves me.
And I've got to make it up
to him for what I've done.
All right, you smashed him.
Do you think smashing all
three of us will help him?
You don't need me, Brad.
You've got what you love.
You've got the circus. But what's he got?
He's got guts. That guys
tough. He doesn't need sympathy.
He can take this if you leave
him alone. He doesn't need pity.
I'm not going to give him pity.
I'm going to try and give him love.
Yeah?
All right.
- What do you want?
- To help you.
I don't want any help.
I don't need any help.
You come here to cry over me,
go somewhere else. I am packing.
You don't even know where you're going.
Besides, wherever it
is, what could you do
that you couldn't do
here with me to help you?
What do think you could do for me?
Well, I could fold this
cape a little better.
Oh, I see. Now I'm a cripple.
You would dress me,
undress me, cut up my food,
wait on me like a little
child. No, thank you.
If you want to be kind, please go.
I want to be with you, wherever you are.
You are lying. You are sorry for me.
You want to pay me because you
teased me to cut down the net!
That isn't true.
You fell in love with me when I was
The Great Sebastian, king in the air,
a flash of lightning in the centre ring.
On the ground, it is
someone else you love.
That's all over.
Go back to the boss man.
Don't think I am
finished because of this.
If I want someone, I'll ask her myself.
Women are no problem for
me. I find them anywhere.
You came back because you love me.
You would like to believe
that, wouldn't you?
It was for this I came back.
- You did not.
- My rig.
Well, I can sell it anyway.
You should be dressing for the show.
The applause, it is all yours now.
You've got the centre ring.
I can't take it away from you. I
can't even applaud you properly.
Say anything you like.
Hit me if you want.
- It wont change the way I feel.
- Maybe I would like to hit you for lying.
No one is to blame but me. I...
- Please, I must hurry.
- You're not going.
You're tied to the circus, and whether
you like it or not, you're tied to me.
You think I would tie you to this?
It wasn't your arm I fell in love with.
Or your hand.
I fell in love with you.
Id give my other arm
if I could believe you.
What does a girl have to
say to make a blind man see?
Say that you'll stay, that
you'll never leave me, ever.
This is not because
you are sorry for me?
You bet your life I'm sorry for you.
You're stuck with a blonde,
and you'll never get away.
Chérie, how I would love you.
Hey, wait for me, Anita!
Step it up kids, were on.
- Is my hat okay?
- Nobody's gonna see you.
Keep your coop to yourself today.
Picnic in the park.
A regal cavalcade with
Queen Marie Antoinette
and her gay court at
the royal horse show.
Remember, you're supposed to be a queen.
You're for the birds, that's for sure.
Giving up your life to
Sebastian because he's washed up.
Who do you think you are?
Joan of Arc or somebody?
What does it matter to you what I do?
Go ahead. Play noble. That halo
is gonna slip, sugar. It's phoney.
It'll be around your neck.
Where would you wear yours?
Say, why are you so steamed
up about me and Sebastian?
Sebastian?
I don't care if you
break him up for firewood.
He asked for it,
playing around with you.
But Brads on the level. He
didn't have this coming to him.
Brad hasn't got time for love.
- Okay, I'll take Brad the way he is.
- That is, if you're his type.
Who are you calling a type?
Maybe I have been over the
course a few too many times.
But I've got a heart under this
costume with room in it for one guy.
You busted him apart, and
I'm gonna pick up the pieces.
Hell never miss you, sugar.
I'm going to give him
more than you ever could.
Maybe so. You've had
plenty of experience.
You'll never make it.
- Did you see him?
- No. Where?
Here's your toothpick!
When the lights go out on this
glittering realm of sawdust and popcorn,
the circus puts off it's spangles
and climbs into battle dress
for the nightly combat
with time and distance.
The tear-down is a wild tangle
of man, machine and beast,
an orderly disorder of ropes
and metal poles and steel cable
and tons of heavy canvas.
Yet out of this apparent chaos,
these people bring tomorrows show,
fresh and new and gay and hot,
no matter how tangled the
skein of their own lives may be.
Ruth! Don't eat them newspapers!
I told you to leave them lay.
No, no, Ruth, Ruth.
You'll get a tummy ache.
She likes the candy that is stuck to it.
He killed the thing he loved.
Buttons, look.
- You said that.
- Did I?
Well, don't believe everything you hear.
And only half of what you see.
I can believe that.
So you see, chérie? All
men are alike except...
I know. Except you.
Come on, lets go down to the car.
Hello?
No, John North.
Hello, Johnny? It's Brad.
Sure, Johnny, Sebastian's back.
Yeah, he's staying with the show.
No, he can't.
Not his old act, but he's in the show.
Me?
Why do you ask that?
There's nothing wrong with me.
Business is holding up fine.
The advance sale is fine.
Everything's fine.
And were a cinch to keep
going the full season.
Yeah.
So long, Johnny.
- The full season? That's great.
- Yeah.
Aren't you in the wrong wagon?
Not the way this one looks.
- Don't touch that.
- A brass hat.
What's all this housekeeping?
Just housekeeping.
Well, go do it someplace else.
The boys take care of all this.
- You are a sourpuss, aren't you?
- Yeah.
- You want to bite somebody?
Well, pick your spot.
Needs sugar.
I wasn't sure how you
liked it. I'll learn.
- Don't bother.
- Sweet?
Oh. Medium.
- What do you think you're doing?
- Packing your pipe.
Well, don't look so worried.
You never know what you're
gonna like until you try it.
I...
Well,
what do you know?
I used to fill my dads pipe.
I don't remember seeing you before.
You didn't. You only looked at me.
Now, what was that name again?
Minnie Mouse. Even
elephants are afraid of me.
They're smart animals. Women are poison.
But it's a wonderful death.
I'm not dangerous. Honest.
I just think a guy in
trouble feels better if...
Well, if there's a woman around.
Just someone to get mad at.
- Well, don't you want some coffee?
- Sure, sugar.
That's what I came for.
You know, I never knew a
woman could fill a pipe.
Heads up! Big wagon coming through!
Hello, sucker. How
long you gonna take it?
- Pretty picture, ain't it?
- Shut up.
Angel likes that guy.
Why? Because he can give her presents.
He's got the dough, so he gets the girl.
What is mine I keep.
Not without dough. But we can get it.
Get it where it'll hurt, too.
Get with it. You've got
four and a half minutes.
Brad, you better watch Angel tonight.
The grapevine says she's in for trouble.
Klaus, the greatest elephant
trainer in the world,
presents his marvellous
mastodonic mammals,
gracefully ridden by 20
sultry sirens from the East,
starring Angel, the sultans favourite.
Butter-coated popcorn.
Get your popcorn here.
- Hey, one.
- You want some?
Thank you.
Steady. Steady.
Steady. All right.
Foot.
Foot. Foot.
Steady.
Steady?
Steady. Come down.
Steady.
I wouldn't do that
for a million dollars.
Minyak, see how our
angels eyes shine today.
She has found a new love.
Quit clowning, sugar. For this
I don't get paid by the hour.
- Lets get on with the number, huh?
- Oh, you want to hurry back to the boss.
Maybe he has a present.
He likes that funny face, huh?
Tell me, would he still like
it if Minyak leans a little bit?
Klaus, are you nuts? Let me up.
- Up, Minyak! Up!
- Steady.
Be careful. You make Minyak nervous.
Now your eyes shine for me, too,
because you have fear in your
lovely, lying little heart.
Is she all right?
Steady, Minyak. Is
your foot getting tired?
You want to put it down?
No, my sweet.
You will never go to any other man.
Foot, Minyak. Foot, foot.
- You all right?
- That was close to the finale.
- Augie.
- This is my act.
Get your things and get off
the lot. Augie, take over.
- Can you finish?
- Sure. I can do anything for you.
Angel.
Fresh popcorn.
- You fire me because...
- Because you're a jealous fool.
Now get out of here before I
have you up for attempted murder.
Buy a circus souvenir.
Take home a balloon for the...
Would you like a balloon? Good.
Life has made me a clown.
It'll have to make you
a better businessman.
Thank you.
Hey, little one. You are tickling me.
You can feel that?
He's trying to be
friendly, to cheer me up.
Come on, Sebastian.
Don't block the entrance.
Get with it, Buttons.
All right, boys, let them
roll. One buck gets you fifty.
- My dice. I'll bet $3.00.
- Okay, $3.00. Let the dice roll.
Six. Your point.
Harry. What we said, I'll do it.
So you finally got wise, huh? I
got it all figured. It's a cinch.
- Tonight.
- Sure. Haven't you heard?
Were giving a party
in the red pay wagon.
Seven. A loser. Sorry,
friends. No winners. That's all.
- Hey, wait a minute.
- I said that's all.
A fine game you got here.
You don't even get a chance
to get your dough back.
- Everything all right in there, Curly?
- Okay.
But next year, lets carry
the cash in the gorilla cage.
It's air-conditioned.
Well, don't let it
sit here and get rusty.
- Take it away.
- Right.
Mr. Braden?
That's right.
Treasury. Special investigations.
What can I do for you?
You carry a doctor with this show?
Yes. You usually find
him in the privilege car.
Does he look anything like this?
No.
You sure?
Ten years can make quite a difference.
What's he wanted for?
Murder. It's an odd case.
A young doctor killed his wife.
She was dying anyway.
What will he get?
I'm a policeman, not a judge.
- Why pick on us?
- Just a hunch.
He was always chasing circuses as a kid.
You wont see that face around here.
Probably not.
Anyway, I've arranged to fingerprint
some of your people in Cedar City.
Do you mind if I ride along with you?
No. The head porter will
fix you up with a berth.
Thank you.
About here. That'll stop the
red wagon back at the road.
Come on. Snap it up.
First section will be along pretty soon.
Come on. Come on.
- Say, Buttons...
- Here you are, Brad.
- I got the next one.
- Thanks.
You're always around when there's trouble.
You're pretty hard to find
when the news is good.
I got tied up with a
cop who's riding with us.
He's looking for someone.
Anything serious?
Murder.
He used to be a doctor.
You find the darnedest people
around a circus, don't you?
Yeah.
What was this good
news? I could use some.
Good news?
Sebastian, there.
He's got feeling in that hand.
Yes, and if there's still feeling,
complete recovery is very possible.
Is that a professional opinion?
That's a clowns opinion.
Why don't you rile him up a little?
Might get your flyer back.
Yeah, I'll do that.
By the way, they're going to take
some fingerprints when we get in.
Okay.
I'll get revenge tomorrow night.
Always I'm lucky at cards.
You sure it's luck?
You think I cheat maybe?
Why not? You've done it before.
- I do not like this joke.
- It's no joke.
- Steady.
- Wait a minute.
Well, he used his bum arm
to get Holly, didn't he?
You know you lie.
You've got it all figured to get yourself
a meal ticket for life, haven't you?
Latching onto her.
You moved it.
- He sure did.
- You bet he did.
That's why you say these things.
How about it, Doc? Will
he be able to use it?
- It certainly did move.
- Of course he did, Doc.
You know, that should get well.
I believe that with psychosomatic
treatment, that this might be...
You did this for me?
For you? I wouldn't
give you storage space.
But you're a good flyer.
The show needs you.
Now, keep working on it.
You crazy, wonderful fool.
You know that with my wings
clipped, I would never marry Holly.
Yet you raise me into the air again.
Because you are circus.
I must tell Holly.
Maybe we name our first baby Bossman.
Good work, Brad.
Hey, Doc,
what is this psycho whatchamacallit?
Wait till the engines passed.
Unlock the door and don't try anything.
Pass it down.
Can you see the trouble?
Can't see nothing ahead.
Get going. We gotta burn rubber.
- What's that?
- Second section.
Look.
Get out of here. This is the girls car.
Men are not allowed in here.
Who'd you come to see?
What did you do, boy
scout, lose your compass?
Well, what are you
doing in no mans land?
Angel, you are going to be a bridesmaid.
- Who's getting married?
- You are, my darling.
Angel. She's on that train.
So what? We got the dough.
Lets get out of here.
The lights. I must turn the
lights back on the track.
You crazy lunkhead. Give me that wheel.
Were going to turn the
lights on the track.
The train! Stop the train!
Stop the train!
Stop! Can't you see the lights? Stop!
First section! Hold it!
Angel!
Sebastian.
Hurry. Angels caught under here.
Hurry.
Doc? Where are you, Doc?
Bob. Bob, where's the doc?
How do I know?
- Help me.
- Sure, Bill, where are you?
Over here. Help me.
Okay, hold on. I'll get you out.
My legs are all numb.
I can't feel anything.
- You all right, Brad?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
Break out some fusees, Blackie.
Get the road torches
going. We need some light.
If Hanks on his feet,
have him make torches out of
the waste from the journal boxes.
We got to get some light here.
Get this stuff off me. Come on.
How you doing in there, Bob?
Not so hot.
That's a new way to
get thrown out of bed.
Elsie, Jeanne. Where
are you? You all right?
- Some of these kids are hurt.
- I'll get the doctor.
No, no, down there. Through the window.
Rip that sheet. Make some bandages.
Holy mackerel! Get back in
there, you little devils.
Rajah, Rajah! Get
back! Get back in there!
No, you don't. Back.
Come on with those poles.
Get some welding torches.
Get in there.
No place like home, Nero.
Here's another torch.
Put a blanket over the glass.
You can tell that
this ain't the pay line.
You want water, you can get
it here. Busted water line.
It's pretty bad in
there. Where's the doctor?
He was in the privilege car when we hit.
I can hear them. They're
around here somewhere.
Come on, boys. Get me out of this junk.
Hey, Mike, get some men
and round up the cats
before they smell blood.
Right, Mr. Braden.
Somebody check the gorilla cage. The
glass will be broken. Board it up.
- Okay, boss.
- Keep those babies warm.
How many killed, Jack?
Don't know yet.
- Is that the doctor?
- Yeah. He's out cold.
Is that the doctor?
Well, we've got to get some doctors here.
- Stu?
- Yes.
Check the walkie-talkie in
my jeep. See if it's okay.
Sure, Brad.
Come on, boys. Get this
stuff off me, can't you?
Hello, Angel. What's
the score in your car?
It's turned over. A lot of the girls...
Brad, you're bleeding.
No dice, Brad. We gotta rig something.
I know the rig to get.
Tell them to get out the
work bulls. Well need them.
Come on.
Watch out, watch out.
Don't let him into the car.
He's coming back.
There he goes!
Samson!
Don't worry, Minnie.
You'll be walking on
your hands in a week.
Well, my teeth are okay.
Bite off a Band-Aid.
Minnie's got a broken arm.
Hold still. Let her lean against you.
- Hurry up with that first aid kit.
- Here.
Give me the stick. Come
on, Minyak. Come on!
Come on, Minyak!
Minyak, this way.
Get the wagons down to the
highway. Everyone on the road.
You can't move the circus, Brad. This
wrecks scattered over five acres.
Half the animals are loose.
And were rolling into Cedar City.
Broken poles and canvas cut to ribbons?
Then well sidewall, play without a tent.
All right, take the strain on that pry.
Come on. Get with it.
Easy, now.
I wish I could do this like
Buttons did it. He did a...
Say, where is Buttons?
Bring that first-aid kit over, please.
I send her for a doctor and
she comes back with an elephant.
You'd better leave the
little pixie to Phyllis
if you want to say
goodbye to our boyfriend.
- Come on.
- Goodbye to our...
Brad.
Here. Finish Minnie's arm.
The rail wont move.
Hook it on a cage.
Take it away.
No, that's no good, man.
You'll pull our whole car over.
Brad. I didn't know.
I'm glad you're okay, pigeon.
We may miss the matinée,
but well make the night show.
Oh, Brad.
- Get that block out of the way.
- Here, I'll take it.
All right, Minyak, come on, pick it up.
Pick it up. Okay. Here we go.
Stand it on it's side.
Come on. Pick it up. Up.
All right, lets take him over here.
Well put it over there.
Brad, you're bleeding like a stuck fish.
- Birdie!
- Easy now.
Birdie, hurry with that first-aid kit!
Give me something to put on it.
Here. Here, Brad.
Birdie! Hurry!
Thank you, sugar. Thank you.
Birdie. Birdie, come on!
Don't move like a snail!
Birdie, get the gauze.
Well make a compression
bandage, pack it in.
More of it. More of it.
What are you doing here, Birdie?
- Here.
- Go see what's left of your costumes.
We can't give a show without wardrobe.
Well give a show, boss, if I have
to put them in horse blankets.
Holly.
Here, hold.
Hank, any horses hurt?
The horses are okay,
Brad, but you're not.
I'm all right.
I've seen all kinds of
accidents on the lot, Holly.
That's an artery.
Every time his heart beats,
it pumps blood out of him.
What are we going to do? The doctors...
Hell bleed to death if we
don't get someone to him.
- I know someone.
- Good.
- Have you seen Buttons?
- No.
Birdie! Birdie, have you seen Buttons?
He just went by.
Get the Zoppes costumes next.
- Buttons!
- All right, throw them down!
Buttons! Buttons! Buttons.
Brads hurt. He's bleeding.
They can't stop it.
Well, get the doctor working
on him, Holly. I gotta go.
The doctors knocked out.
He was in the same car.
Buttons, that newspaper about the
doctor who killed the girl he loved...
Yeah, well, Brad told me
something about a detective
being on the train
looking for that fellow.
Look, I don't know if you're
the man they're looking for,
- but if you are, you can save Brad.
- No.
Remember you told me once about
killing the thing you loved?
Well, maybe you killed someone
because you loved her so much.
If you are him, you
could save someone I love.
Oh, Buttons. I've always loved him.
Please, please don't let
him die, if you are the man.
Are you, Buttons?
Yeah, I'm the man,
Holly. Come on. Lets go.
See if they can set up a cook tent.
Everyone could use some coffee.
Okay, Brad.
Find out what performers are hurt.
Let me know what acts we can't use.
Lie still, Brad.
Here's the doctors bag. I found it.
Fine, fine. Get something
to put it on, will you?
We've got to get the big top rigged
somehow and put on a performance.
Lie still, will you?
You'll finish this performance
under Gods big top.
Buttons.
If that detective sees you doing
this, he wont need fingerprints.
Well, the circus needs a boss right now.
Besides, I kind of like you.
Brad, please do what
Buttons says, for me.
What are you trying to do,
make my last moments happy?
Is that you, Chuck?
Chuck, how many seed wagons are okay?
- About half.
- Set them up.
Use planks for what's missing.
You have got sawdust in your
veins. You can't even die decently.
Take it easy, Holly. This
isn't sawdust he's bleeding.
You're gonna have to have a
blood transfusion right quick.
You were in the army,
Brad. What's your blood type?
- AB.
Which Rh?
- Negative.
- Negative? Are you sure?
Yeah, I'm sure. Were
out of luck, Buttons.
- What does that mean?
- Well, i's hard to find.
There must be a blood
bank in Cedar City.
We don't have any time for that.
Now, look, some of you go out and see
if you can find somebody
that has AB blood.
- There must be somebody in this show.
- There is someone.
Me. I have it.
- Sebastian.
- Not him.
You're not gonna put
that guys blood in me.
You don't have enough blood
in you now to quibble about it.
Sit down here. Roll up your left
sleeve. Get his wristwatch off.
- All right.
- I think I can rig it with this.
Buttons, find somebody else.
You'll be dead in 20 minutes without him.
Here, soak this in alcohol.
All right, but just take enough
till you can get some other guy.
It hurts me as much as it
does you, but noblesse oblige.
You ought to be grateful.
Grateful? To him?
I've had nothing but trouble
ever since you joined the show.
They warned me about you, but
I had to find out the hard way.
Big stuff in the air.
Upsetting the whole circus,
chopping down your net.
Now you want to be a hero, save my life.
I don't want any part of you.
I do not want to give you my good blood,
but what it will do for you...
Hasn't done much for you.
If he should make love well after
this, pay no attention. It will be me.
- I can't see. Give me the light over here.
- I'll take it.
Go ahead, Doctor.
Yes. Take all you want.
It will make of him a better man.
He will have more fire,
more of what women love.
They may even want to marry you.
And each time you look at one
of your children, boss man,
you will see me.
If any kid of mine ever...
- Brad.
- Yeah?
It's the end of the line. Were licked.
We ain't got no big top,
and our lightings all shot.
- I'm not quitting. Well give a show.
- Brad, take it easy, will you?
- Where's my hat?
- Buttons.
- Give me that stethoscope.
- What is it, Buttons?
Put the ear tips in my ears.
Keep count of these
plunger strokes here.
Now put that over his heart.
A little lower. A little
lower. Right there.
His hearts going so
fast, I can hardly count.
- It must be over 130.
- 130...
Well, I guess that's it.
- I'll get word out were cancelling.
- No, were not.
We couldn't even get into
town on a junk wagon.
- Well bring the town out here.
- Five.
Sell tickets to see the wreck?
- That's not a bad idea.
- Are you nuts?
Maybe. Well get the crowd out here
if we have to drag them by the hair.
If you're putting on this act
for Brad, he can't hear you.
- What's the matter with...
- Now stop shaking the stand
or hell never hear anybody.
What's the matter with all of you?
Brad said wed give a show,
and were going to give it.
We got no big top.
Well sidewall it, set up in the open.
- Where?
- Over there. It's an open field.
I got you, birdbrain. You struck oil.
Jack, get everything together
that can walk, crawl, or run,
floats, midgets, clowns,
anything that can stand.
Tell them it's cherry pie.
Hank, fix up everything on wheels.
If the horses can't pull them, we can.
You're doing fine, Doc.
- Hurry up, do what I said.
- Come on, Bob.
Fred, tell Lloyd to stake out.
- What about the big top?
- Don't argue with me.
Emmett. Emmett, patch up
the clowns for a parade.
- Parade?
- Yes, parade.
- Hey, are you kidding?
- No, I'm not kidding.
Rig my trapeze in a wagon.
Gertrude. Gertrude, help
Birdie with the wardrobe. Hurry.
Dave. Dave, find Merle. Tell
him to get the band together.
If the instruments are
busted, tell him they can sing.
Here. Never mind the wreck.
Get the show rolling. Hurry.
- I can beat a drum, even with one hand.
- Not until I'm through with you.
You're doing all right
where you are, sugar.
What are you doing?
Will you two stop it?
You'll kill this man.
Twenty-five.
So long, Brad.
I'll bring all the elephants that can
walk, and the ones that can't, I'll carry.
You keep him going,
Buttons. Well roll the show.
God bless you.
Thirty.
Buttons,
which one are you
trying to save him for?
Scars covered by grease paint,
bandages hidden by funny wigs,
the spangled pied piper limps into town.
Come on, folks, tie
yourself to a balloon!
Float out and see the circus!
Come on, come on! Follow us!
Come to the circus!
This is the first time
I've been alone with you
since that wonderful night
in Paris, and I love it.
Look, sugar, I love you
because you're Rh negative.
Not to you, chérie.
- Come on!
We've got them, Merle.
They're coming with us.
Hit the circus song.
Come to the circus
The greatest show on earth
See the circus
If were not very careful
Life can overwork us
So take today
And make it gay
For there are too many
tears along the way
So come to the circus
It's circus day today
Come see the barkers
And the gawkers
The bareback riders
And the fearless tightrope walkers
The cuddly bears do their routine
The greatest extravaganza
The world has ever seen
The big calliope will play
And 50 pachyderms will play
You'll see a hawker dressed in grey
Shouting, Peanuts, popcorn and lemonade
The human cannonball will zoom
As trumpets blare and bass drums boom
To entertain your mom and pop
As we go under the great big top
Working on the rig.
Get them ready for the show.
Is that The Flying Comets rig?
Yeah.
We've only got four poles.
Rig it over ring three.
- Hey, Russ.
- Yes, boss?
Have Whitey climb up and
see if they're in sight yet.
- How do you feel?
- Never mind that. Just take off.
- And see if the menagerie...
- Brad, Brad, take it easy.
Doc, maybe you can keep
him quiet. I give up.
You did a great job,
Buttons. A great job.
Thank you, Doc. It's my last.
Looks like you ran
into a little trouble.
If I were in the junk business,
I might make you an offer.
Vultures even follow train wrecks.
Braden,
- you're all washed up.
- Well give a show.
Without an audience?
Hey, you hear that?
Brad? You hear it?
The pied piper.
What's that?
That's a ratcatcher, Mr. Henderson.
What?
You know, great rats, small
rats, lean rats, scrawny rats,
brown rats, black rats,
grey rats, tawny rats.
They made it. Listen to that band.
Hey, Whitey, can you see them yet?
I see them, Brad!
Wow! Look at them come!
They got the whole town with them!
Thank God.
Think I'll go have a look.
I'll say this much for you,
Braden. You're good circus.
I'll wait till you're
back on your feet again,
then I'll knock you off them for good.
Why don't you stay and
see the show, Henderson?
There'll be standing room.
I'm sorry, Doc.
I couldn't take a chance
with that crowd coming.
Yeah, yeah. I know.
Id kind of like to
shake your hand before...
You're all right.
Buttons...
What can a man say?
Well, take care of yourself, Brad.
Tell Holly I'm going to keep that
date with that girl she knows about.
Where's my hat?
Here's a present for you.
Come on, Squeaker.
Do you want a bite of
my candy bar, Buttons?
No, thanks, honey. I'm not very hungry.
Squeaker likes candy, don't you?
- I'll tell you, why don't you take him?
- Don't you want him?
Yeah, I want him, but I
can't take him where I'm going.
Here. Don't feed him too
much popcorn or hell pop.
Thanks.
- Well, keep the show rolling, Brad.
- Hey, Buttons, what's this...
And why don't you tell
Holly Brad wants to see her?
Come on. Lets go.
- You kids want popcorn?
- Yeah!
Merle, spot the band
between those seat wagons.
We got the webs rigged
to the star boom, Holly.
Keep them out of the
way of the Alzana wire.
Antoinette, take your web
girls up to the big pole.
Lou, you work the centre ring
with Loni and The Chaludis.
Honey, use my trapeze. Yours is busted.
Give them a hula bubble bath, Phyllis.
Yes. In the elephant tub.
Hey, Rusty. Follow captain high.
Right, Sebastian.
Well, what happened to you, sugar?
You must have gotten
some of Brads blood.
You walking people, get
back by the bubble float.
Holly, Brad wants you!
Okay. Coffee, everybody, after
the spec at the grease joint.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we bring you a new innovation.
The greatest assembly
of artists in the world
will entertain you under the
blue canopy of the open sky.
Golly, Brad, you sure look
better than when I saw you last.
- Yeah, sure, but...
- No, no! Put The Idnavies in the centre!
Brad, what I said last night.
I'm sorry. I didn't mean it.
- Well, I'm not. Listen...
- Brad, aren't you proud of me?
You should have seen
us. We panicked them.
Were not gonna have enough
seats out there to hold them.
I nearly folded last night.
It made me see what I've been missing.
You know what I'm gonna do? Were
gonna parade around the track...
Would you listen to what I'm
trying to tell you? I love you.
- I know, but were ready to start.
- Holly...
After the show, huh, Brad?
Judas priest!
You got nothing but
sawdust in your veins!
Children of all ages,
the big show is about to commence.
Well, looks like were out in the cold.
Perhaps we should keep
each other warm, huh?
Listen, sugar, the only
way you can keep me warm
is to wrap me up in a marriage licence.
Why not? That would be something new.
Roll it, Merle! Plenty
of brass and make it loud!
Come to the circus
Come on along and see
Hooray for lions
And the camels
You'll have fun And look
at all the other mammals
Come see the clowns
Who play their part
They'll wear a smile
that hides a broken heart
Tremendous
Stupendous
The circus show shall be
The Bengal tiger
And the lion
The trapeze artist does a leap
That's death-defyin'
A land of mirth
Your moneys worth
Come on along to the circus
The greatest show on earth
That's all, ladies and
gentlemen. That's all.
Come again to the
greatest show on earth.
Bring the children. Bring the old folks.
You can shake the sawdust off your feet,
but you can't shake it out of your heart.
Come again, folks.
The greatest show on earth!
Come again.
Watch Movies, TV Series & Live Sports
www.admitme.app