All right. 2:30 tomorrow.
Thank you. Goodbye.
Thanks, Sergeant.
Report of horse rations,
Thirtieth Hussars.
Regimental
and general files.
Now, each of these buttons represents troops.
Do you understand?
Yes, sir.
Good.
The buttons are thickest up near
the Northwest Frontier.
Oh, yes, always.
We have 300 million
people to protect.
And most of the danger
is there.
It's so romantic
to a greenhorn like me.
Kipling and all that,
you know.
Romantic?
Well, at first, yes.
A- another button
to move.
41st Bengal Lancers.
Here, near the pass.
The pass?
Does that mean-
It means nothing
but maneuvers.
As CoI. Stone says
in his report here.
You hear that firing,
Hamilton?
Typical sniping fire, sir.
Yes, and Afridi muskets
every one of them.
Not a shot
from our detachment.
Good. Hendrickson's
a good soldier.
Rough on him,
having those Afridi swine
popping away at his men
and not able
to return fire.
Well, he'll get a citation
if this plan works.
Plan's good enough, sir,
if it were anybody but Mohammed Khan.
He's a clever dog.
Yes, of course he is.
I ought to know.
But he's nibbling
at our bait this time.
And if we can once
draw him down
out of those hills
far enough, out into the open
so that we can
cut off his retreat,
we've got him red-handed!
And that's what
I've been waiting for,
for 15 years, Hamilton.
Afridi swine. When do we
go into action, Hendrickson?
On no account return fire.
CoI. Stone's orders.
ColoneI's orders.
Narain Singh.
Now can we start something?
ColoneI's orders,
McGregor.
But the old fool
couldn't have foreseen this.
I'd like to have you
with me in a war,
but for peace time,
you're a bit too-
Too...
Too impulsive.
Machine guns!
Forward!
Most unfortunate,
the command
devolved upon you.
Of course you didn't
know my orders.
I did know them, sir.
Why didn't
you obey them?
You call yourself
a soldier?
That's all.
The Colonel knows India,
McGregor. You don't.
You're right, I don't.
I'm just a fooI
Scotch-Canadian.
Came into your outfit
to get action.
He's got a ramrod
for a backbone.
He's a terror for drilling,
but when it comes to the real thing-
McGregor,
the Colonel has the right
to act as he thinks best
and say what he pleases.
Mount!
One more thing, sir.
Two replacements come in
today from Delhi.
Paperwork.
When we came into
the regiment as boys,
we didn't know that this
was 9l10ths of soldiering.
No.
We thought and acted
rather like McGregor.
Mmm.
What about
these two replacements?
What are they sending
to us now?
From the Blues:
Lt. Forsythe.
The Blues, eh? Well, that's
a fashionable regiment.
All spit and polish.
Who's the other one?
From Sandhurst:
Lt. Stone.
What?
From Sandhurst?
What, they're sending me
a young cub,
not dry behind
the ears yet? Unseasoned?
Straight from,
fr-from military college
to the Frontier?
Oh, bless me.
Hmm, what'd you say
his name was?
Donald Stone, sir.
Hmm.
And who asked you
to interfere
in my personal affairs?
Will you forget
that you're my coloneI
for a moment, sir?
Yes.
Look here, Tom.
In about two years,
you'll be retired.
So you sent for my son
because you feel sorry
for me, is that it?
Not at all.
The idea was to keep
the name of Stone
in the 41st
after you're gone.
There's no room for
sentimentality in the army.
Hardly fair to ship him home
without a triaI.
Still, he'll measure up
to my standards,
or out he goes.
Of course.
And at the first sign
of favoritism,
from you or anyone else,
there'll be trouble.
And that's an order,
Maj. Hamilton.
Just as you said,
Major.
It's the ColoneI's
privilege
to do
and say what he likes.
McGregor, you'll meet
the two replacement officers this morning.
Lts. Forsythe and Stone.
Yes, sir. S-Stone?
His son.
His what?
I said, his son.
I can't imagine old Ramrod
ever having been that human.
The train arrives at 10:30,
Mr. McGregor.
Yes, sir.
Madam, you'll marry me
Tuesday the 29th.
Be at the church at 10:00.
That's an order.
Furthermore,
you're improperly dressed.
Ha, Ha.
Did you want
to speak to me, McGregor?
No, sir.
I hope he's a nice follow.
He won't be. Ramrod.
I beg your pardon?
One Stone isn't enough.
We have to have two.
There he is,
the younger Ramrod himself.
Everything was all right?
Thank you, sir.
Couldn't be anybody else.
Just as sure of himself as...
Look at the way
they jump around for him.
Look at his luggage,
everything just so-so.
Well, come on,
let's get it over with.
No, I've got
a little business.
You get
your precious replacements.
I'm McGregor, Lancers,
sent to meet you.
Oh, sort of
reception committee, eh?
It's nice to know
I was expected.
The regiment's been
practically breathless for a week.
Oh?
Traveling light, huh?
Well, you see, I did expect
to stay a little while.
That is if you don't
mind too much.
It's all right
with me.
Goodbye.
And thank you very much
for being so kind.
Not at all.
Your luggage and everything
all taken care of?
Everything, thank you.
May I present Mr. McGregor,
Miss Leys?
Very happy.
How do you do?
Goodbye.
Who's she?
I met her on the train,
if you don't mind.
Bad business talking
to strange people out here.
You know, this is India.
You don't know who they are,
and you might-
Oh, I see.
BeautifuI spy meets the young Lancer officer,
makes him give away
important military secrets.
The Empire goes smash.
Melodrama, my dear McGregor,
melodrama.
It might not be as funny
as it sounds, Mr. Stone.
I don't suppose
it matters to you,
but my name isn't Stone.
No?
No, it's Forsythe.
Well, then,
that must be Stone there.
That's very good, you know.
That's really very good.
It's almost brilliant.
Stone? I'm McGregor,
sent to meet you.
That's very nice of you.
Stone, meet Mister, uh...
What did you say
your name was?
Forsythe.
Mr. Stone, Mr. Fort.
We met on the train,
and the name is Forsythe.
Too hot for Forsythe.
Fort, Stone. Stone, Fort.
Stone Fort.
And that's funny.
If you two will hold onto each other,
I'll tend to your luggage.
Pleasant chap.
So friendly.
Isn't he?
Just what
I've always imagined
a real officer
on the Frontier would be like.
Well, my mother kept me
in the States
untiI I made her send me
to Sandhurst.
I've knocked about a bit
in the States.
Scotch-Canadian, myself.
What is this I'm in?
The Foreign Legion?
I didn't even think my father knew
I was at Sandhurst,
untiI this happened.
What?
His sending for me
to his regiment.
Oh?
Sort of, carry on
our tradition, you know?
Naim Shah,
your servant, Stone.
Ali Hamdi, yours.
The night watchman,
the water carrier, the sweeper.
You can hire
the rest of them later.
Those things hurt my ears.
That's odd.
They sound to me
like a Scotch bagpipe.
Your quarters, Stone.
Pretty, huh? And soothing.
Thought I might entertain you.
Wild Scotch airs.
Remind you of home.
Your room.
Someone deeded
all this junk
to the South
Kensington Museum?
That junk represents
the personal belongings
of the man you're replacing.
Killed on the border
last month.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Oh, McGregor, did my...
Uh, the Colonel say anything
about what time he'd see me?
No, he didn't. And my guess is
he won't see you till durbar.
Oh.
Don't let that
get you down.
The old- The old man's
a stickler for red tape.
Durbar. Bugles.
And that's an order.
Ramrod.
Durbar.
Oh, a-already?
I'll be right with you.
I want you to help me
to keep them
in good condition.
You keep then shined
and I'II, uh,
keep them dirty.
Durbar.
Whenever you're ready,
sahib.
Thanks,
old ColoniaI.
Durbar, Barrett.
Not today, old boy.
Where to now?
Over the border.
I wish
I'd taken my mother's advice
and joined the church
instead of the Army.
I wish
I had the job.
Does the Colonel think you're
the only one here who talks Pushtu?
Who knows
what the Colonel thinks?
I agree with you there.
Well, good luck.
Thanks, Mac.
Left wheel, turn!
Good head, eh? Yeah.
How old is she, Major?
Places, men.
Good morning,
gentlemen.
Good morning, sir.
What's this?
An Afridi Ghazi,
Colonel sahib.
Caught in the quarters
of Capt. Norton, with this.
Anything stolen?
He meant to kill
Capt. Norton.
Said Capt. Norton slept
with his feet toward Mecca.
There are trees,
and we have rope.
What have you got to say?
Oh.
Take him
and hang him to a tree,
and then sew the dead body
in the skin of a pig.
Well, that's what will happen
to him if he tries it again.
You tell him that
and let him go.
He doesn't seem to
like pigs.
If that happened, in heaven
he wouldn't get the 48 maidens
allotted by Allah.
Tsk, tsk, tsk. Sad.
Capt. Norton.
Yes, sir?
Have you a compass?
Yes, sir.
Change the direction
of your bed.
Yes, sir.
Yes, that's all.
Mr. McGregor.
The two replacements?
Mr. Forsythe,
from the Blues,
Mr. Stone,
from Sandhurst.
From the Blues, eh?
Quite so.
Well, that's
a fashionable regiment.
I am afraid, Mr. Forsythe,
you'll find us different.
We have a reputation
as soldiers,
and we're proud of it.
Mr. Stone.
You've come to us
direct from Sandhurst,
without previous service.
Is that correct?
Yes, sir.
Yes. Well, you've got
a great deal to learn.
And I trust that you,
and you, too,
Mr. Forsythe,
will measure up
to our requirements.
That's all, gentlemen.
Crusty old...
I'm sorry.
Is it over?
Is that all?
That's all.
Lt. Stone.
Yes, sir?
The Colonel forgot something.
I want you
to take this to him.
Yes, sir.
What's so funny?
You are.
So the rough soldier
has a heart of gold.
Never mind,
it comes out in all of us.
It's the mother instinct.
Is this it, sir?
What?
Where did you
get this?
Mr. McGregor ordered me
to give it to you, sir.
What infernal impudence!
No, uh, not you.
Not-not-not you.
How's, uh,
How- H-How's your mother?
Quite well, sir.
Good, good.
She always
hated the army.
I- I don't understand
why she ever let you
go through Sandhurst.
She had to.
I've kept after her about it
ever since I was so high.
Oh? Wanted to be
a soldier, eh?
We've always been soldiers,
for generations.
Yes.
Still, you're not one yet,
you know?
Yes, sir.
Really, you, uh,
you ought not to be here.
Uh, not on the Frontier.
But I am here, sir.
Yes, but, uh,
don't try to take advantage.
Don't expect
any favoritism.
I don't, sir.
I, uh,
I- I-I'm glad to see you,
of course, and I...
I'm sorry that the situation
makes any sort of,
uh, o-of, uh,
social relation impossible.
And I-I, uh...
No, no, wait! W-wait.
Uh, come back a moment.
You see, uh,
this Frontier,
it's not the same
as home service.
No place for a Cub.
A man's got
to be seasoned.
You've got to start
from the bottom.
Learn everything,
and if you don't measure up,
out.
The service
comes first.
Something your mother
never understood.
Yes, sir.
Is that all, sir?
What? Uh, uh, yes.
Y- Yes, that's all.
That's all.
I'm very glad to see...
Poor kid.
I thought
if I got them alone...
But the old man
has ice-water in his veins.
You don't know
the colonel, McGregor.
Neither do you.
Mr. McGregor.
Yes, sir.
As I remarked to one of
my other officers this morning,
there is no place for
sentimentality in the Army.
Neither sentimentality
nor impertinence,
Mr. McGregor.
Stone.
Interesting, the durbar,
isn't it?
I'm sorry
I sent you in there.
I should have known better.
Should have known
how he'd treat you.
What's a son to him,
compared to
his blasted regiment?
Martinet. Ramrod.
That's what he is.
Everybody knows it.
You might as well
get used to it.
That's a lie.
I'm sorry,
I can't keep my mouth shut.
That's my trouble.
Biggest fooI in the Army.
I'm sorry.
That's all-
all right, Mac.
" Sure I love the dear silver
that shines in her hair "
" And the brow
that's all furrowed "
" and wrinkled with care "
" Oh, God bless you
and keep you "
" Mother McGregor "
Now, when a troop wheels
on the move,
what do the troop leaders
look out for?
Mr. Stone,
I asked you a question.
Yes, sir.
Come on, come on, come on.
Come on.
Got it all that time.
All right.
Bedding should be
changed, Mr. Stone.
Yes, I see now,
Risaldar Major.
We don't have these
beastly ticks in England.
Sergeant, have this
horse's shoe attended to.
Come on!
Give him a good walk
while he cools off.
A good man, Forsythe.
Jump!
See the way
he took that jump?
Yes, they teach them
to jump in the Blues.
Yes. Yes, what?
Oh.
Good work, Forsythe.
Thank you, sir.
Mr. McGregor,
you're improperly dressed.
I'm sorry, sir.
That was a nice jump
you made, Mac.
Thanks.
Hello, Stone.
Hello.
Remarkable man,
your father.
Knows a good soldier
when he sees one.
Appreciates neatness, too.
Well,
how about a spot of scotch?
Thanks. I haven't finished
inspection yet.
Ten minutes for their backs
and five for their bellies.
That's the order
of grooming.
Very touching,
the lad's devotion.
Must warm the maternaI
cockles of your heart.
Eh, McGregor?
What about pulling
a few pegs with me, huh?
I'm in favor of it.
Let's go.
Well, uh,
how about 10 Rupees?
Make it 20.
Ready?
Whenever you say.
They should make
those pegs smaller.
Be more sport to it,
huh?
" Oh, he flew
through the air "
" With the greatest
of ease "
" And the daring young man
owes me 20 Rupees "
Have some tea, Stone?
No, thanks.
Call it for first
in the bath.
Heads.
Right.
You fellows bathe
to keep cooI
and I bathe
because I badly need it.
Every time I do this
I remind myself
of my old man.
Whiskers.
He was a crabby old cuss.
Back in Alberta
I had a colt once.
Lot of class and nerve.
You could tell
he was no carthorse
when he was a yearling.
The old man hooked him
to a plow.
Took all the spirit
out of him.
He broke him in,
as he said he would
and I never forgave him
for it.
I don't think the horse
ever did realize what...
what the old man
did to him.
So I'm the horse.
Very subtle, Mac.
What the blazes do you mean?
I'm no two-year-old. I'm 21.
And if anybody thinks
my old man's going to break my nerve-
What are you talking about?
I wasn't thinking of you at all.
And let me tell
you another thing,
I don't need a nurse.
Now you can go on shaving.
Have a little soap.
You need it.
Do you have to do that?
Why, like you, I have
a softer side to my nature.
It finds its outlet in music.
See? The scales.
Hey, Mac, get me a towel,
will you?
Variations,
one hand, Mac.
Listen, Forsythe.
This Mother Machree business
has gone far enough.
Why, of course, Mac.
I'm sorry.
I didn't realize it.
Well, let's, uh,
just forget all about it. Hm?
Thanks.
Hey, Mac,
that soap's in my eyes.
Give me a towel,
will you?
McGregor.
Variations, two hands, Mac.
How long are you
going to...
Keep playing.
Variations, Mr. Forsythe,
with both hands.
Cobras have
a softer side, too.
Finds an outlet in music.
Of course,
if you-if you stop playing,
You know, you might live
a couple of hours.
I had a friend once
that lived for two days.
Try it with one hand.
Mac!
Allow me.
You might spill it.
For sale, cheap.
One secondhand
musical instrument.
200 feet more.
Plus 200 east.
Elevation, 300.
Mr. McGregor.
Yes, sir?
There's no word
yet from Barrett.
We must get in touch with him.
Yes, sir.
You're familiar
with the roads north east
of Fort Jamrud?
I am, sir.
Yes, good, good.
You'll cross
the Frontier tonight.
Take one subaltern,
one NCO, 10 men,
four spare horses.
And, uh, rifles.
Not lances.
I see, sir.
Ostensibly,
a hunting expedition.
What subaltern
shall I take, sir?
Mmm,
any preference?
Mr. Stone, sir.
No service experience.
Take Morgan.
He's on leave, sir.
Well, then, take Forsythe.
Yes, sir.
Here are your orders.
And this time,
obey them.
Yes, sir.
Forsythe.
Huh?
We're leaving for
the border immediately.
What?
Action?
Can't say.
Oh.
We leave
for the border?
Uh, small expedition.
Only one junior officer.
Forsythe.
Yes?
One junior officer,
so he had to choose-
I chose Forsythe.
I see.
Sir.
What do you mean by
intruding like this?
Why wasn't I chosen
to go with McGregor?
Are you questioning
my orders?
Then it was your orders.
It wasn't McGregor's choice.
It was yours.
Mr. Stone.
I came out to India
to be an officer,
and I've been given
things to do
I learned in my first year
at Sandhurst.
I haven't asked any favors,
and I'm not asking any now.
But if you meant to
treat me this way,
why did you
bring me out here?
Why did you send for me?
I didn't send for you.
Y- you didn't?
Oh.
Are you aware
we're being shot at?
We camp here.
This is no place to camp.
Are you
out of your mind?
They'll rush us in the night
and slit our throats.
This can't be
what the Colonel meant.
Easy to see how much
you learned in the Blues
about Frontier fighting.
No firing.
He's mine.
Rapid fire!
You just missed my ear, Mac.
You're lucky, Barrett.
You got a cigarette?
Yeah.
Thanks.
What shall I tell
the ColoneI?
Mohammed Khan,
is effecting a coalition
of all the tribes.
But don't forget, Colonel,
GopaI's a friendly state.
The Emir's our friend,
as who knows better than you.
Oh, of course, I've known
Othman Ali for 20 years.
Every year or so
I take the regiment
up to Gopal for
maneuvers and pig-sticking.
He's got the best wild pig
north of the Ganges.
Ah.
But two million
rounds of ammunition.
Oh, no, Woodley.
Why, that's enough
to start a small-sized war.
And then, who knows?
Yes, who knows?
But he asked for it.
And if we refused, well,
he mightn't be our friend.
And so he gets it, eh?
Yes.
McGregor, Sahib.
Oh, ask Mr. McGregor
to come in.
Oh, sit down, sir,
won't you?
You saw Barrett?
Yes, sir.
He reports Mohammed Khan
is trying to stir up all the border tribes,
and effect
a coalition of all of them.
They're listening
to him as he's promised
to supply them
with machine guns,
and two million
rounds of ammunition.
Ammunition?
Oh, that's good work.
Thank you, McGregor.
Thank Barrett, sir.
Look at here, sir, I-I know
it's none of my business,
but couldn't we
slip out of here,
a small detachment of us,
anyway, on our own?
Try to get a chance
at him, kill him,
and-and nip the whole
business in the bud?
Are you suggesting
that I should commence
hostilities without orders?
And, uh, ahem,
without reporting this
to the Intelligence?
Intelligence, those fools.
General staff?
You know, sir, they'll send us
anywhere but into action.
To Gopal to stick pigs
for instance, like last summer.
An excellent suggestion.
Sir Thomas,
Mr. McGregor.
Mr. McGregor, Maj. Gen.
Sir Thomas Woodley.
Chief of Intelligence.
Army Headquarters.
Mr. McGregor.
CoI. Stone, your regiment
will leave at dawn for GopaI.
Yes, sir.
Now, get yourself
a couple of hours sleep.
We leave at 6:00.
Yes, sir.
Wish I could go with you.
I always liked pig-sticking.
Pig-sticking.
Well, I seem to remember
feeling that way once.
He's probably right.
Hm.
But he brought
our answer, Stone.
A plain two and two
that makes a very plain four.
Mohammed Khan needs
two million rounds of ammunition.
And the Emir of Gopal asks us
for two million rounds-
Yes, yes, and it's not
difficult to guess,
that Mohammed Khan persuaded
the Emir to ask for it.
He knows we'll have
to let him have it, too.
And GopaI's not only remote,
but far enough removed
from the Khan's home fires,
that we shouldn't
be suspicious.
Very pretty, indeed.
And it becomes
our very pleasant job,
to see that the Emir
really is the one
who gets the ammunition.
That old pussy-footer
gets paid for
being intelligent.
I tell you, Forsythe,
everything's going to smash.
What?
Pig-sticking.
We're going to ride all around Gopal
sticking toothpicks into pigs.
Sounds rather fun.
I ought to be rather good
at that, don't you think?
Hmm.
By the way, McGregor,
I've got bad news for you.
Your ward needs
parental controI, I fear.
That is, if you can find him.
Naim Shah tells me he's been
out every night since we left.
Rolling home
to quarters blotto.
Tonight he's still
out on a binge.
Hm. We leave for
Gopal in two hours.
Oh, without Stone, it appears.
My, what will
the stern father say?
You'd better do
something about it, Mac.
The young fooI.
Let old Ramrod do
what he likes with his son.
It's no concern of mine.
I'm going to bed.
So am I.
What are you doing here?
The same as you are.
Looking for him.
And I wish you'd be
honest with yourself,
and let me know
what you're really going to do.
If you'd just tell me,
maybe I'd get more sleep.
Now that we are here,
what would you do
if you were drunk?
How drunk?
Pretty drunk.
I'd go looking
for that music.
Come on, speed it up, Stone,
or we'll all be
doing stable duty.
I can take care of myself.
Come along, Casanova,
these will make
a new man of you.
Forgot something.
I thought you
might get lonesome.
Get yourself a cobra.
The welcoming committee
from the Emir.
That's his vizier,
bringing gifts
for the ColoneI
from his old paI.
His Highness,
Othman Ali Bahadur,
Emir of Gopal,
bids welcome to his friends
and allies of the Raj.
Welcome, huzoor,
thrice welcome,
in the name of Allah.
Convey my thanks
to your master,
ahem, my old friend.
Uh, m-may he live
a thousand years.
His Highness orders me
to express his wish, huzoor,
that you may live long enough
to be present at his funeraI.
Uh, oh, yes, quite so.
Quite so.
He went the old man
one better that time.
Wicked looking birds,
aren't they?
Hunting falcons, Forsythe.
Swiftest thing in the air.
Full of fight
and trained to kill,
like the rest of these
mangy-looking fellows.
A long-legged man
is always full of wind.
Barrett.
His Highness
invites you, huzoor,
and all the officer sahibs,
to an entertainment
in your honor,
tonight at the palace.
I accept on their
behalf with pleasure.
All my thanks
to His Highness.
His Highness awaits you.
Salaam, Colonel Sahib.
Salaam, Your Highness.
May I present the officers of the 41st
Bengal Lancers, Your Highness?
My poor hovel is yours,
sahiban.
Everything here
is for your pleasure.
Please enjoy yourselves.
Now, this is what
army life should be.
Like the Arabian Nights,
isn't it?
Anything like this
in Canada, Mac?
Quite a teepee, huh?
I sent to London
for that, and you-
My two good friends.
My guest, CoI. Stone.
My guest, Mohammed Khan.
Very glad to
know you Khan sahib.
At last, CoI. Stone.
We almost met once before,
did we not, you and I?
Yes, I-I believe we did.
Just missed you, didn't I?
A blind man wants
nothing except his eyes.
That's an Afghan proverb.
And now,
if you will forgive me,
I must leave
my two good friends together.
I must go to see
my other guests.
Oh, yes,
Your Highness.
No doubt that Khan and I
will find much to talk about.
Highness.
You were not expected
with your lancers.
A hasty trip, wasn't it?
In search of, uh...
Pigs.
There's another proverb:
The little jackal barks,
but the caravan passes.
Won't you sit down,
CoI. Stone?
Yes.
I say, look.
I saw her first.
No, no, no,
no, no, no, Mac.
A direct frontal attack?
That's the wrong tactics.
This requires finesse.
I'll toss you.
The loser stays clear.
Right you are.
Heads.
Now watch closely.
Well, uh, go ahead.
Uh, I'm watching you closely.
Gentlemen.
Uh, two more of my officers
I should like you to meet.
Mr. McGregor, Mr. Forsythe.
This is our friend
and neighbor, Mohammed Khan.
A great pleasure,
gentlemen.
Let me give you some
advice, Mr. Forsythe.
Never make fun of
military Intelligence.
Thank you very much.
And now-
Uh, wait a minute.
That girI and...
I've got some things
to find out.
He plans to leave
tomorrow morning.
I knew he would
as soon as we got here.
We must keep him
here if possible.
I was right.
She came here
with Mohammed Khan.
Aha, so that's how it is.
Diplomatic complications
rear their heads, huh?
Looks like it.
We'd better find them.
Mac, I've been thinking.
I'm very fond
of you, you know.
I have a feeling this is
going to cost me something.
Oh, no, Mac.
Now, you've done
enough for him, really.
This time, I'll take
on the rescue work.
Well, that
touches me deeply,
but how many times have you
told me he was my job?
Uh, we'll both
do it, Mac. Huh?
Mr. Stone,
I'm sorry, but uh,
but Maj. Hamilton
wants to see you.
Very important,
he said.
I beg your pardon. I'll be
back in just a moment.
Surely.
No manners at all,
this younger generation.
Completely forgot
the introductions, didn't he?
My name's Forsythe.
How do you do?
That's McGregor.
Scotch, you know.
Very queer race.
Did you send for me, Major?
No.
I'm sorry.
I made that same mistake
once before.
How are your pigs
this year, Highness?
Pigs?
My land is overrun
with unclean beasts.
Oh, that means
good sport tomorrow.
You'll join us,
Khan sahib, of course?
Oh, I'm sorry,
I'm leaving in the morning.
But if you wish real sport,
you must come to my country.
An invitation?
My land and all it contains
is at your disposaI.
Yes, yes, sahib.
Why, he gives his word,
the word of a prince.
I swear it
upon the Koran.
An oath?
Oh, I'll put it
to the test.
He has you.
What do you
demand of him, sahib?
Postpone your departure.
Join us at
pig-sticking tomorrow.
I- I-I can't.
My affairs demand that-
You must.
You give your oath
upon the Koran.
I am honored, Bahadur.
Tomorrow,
Pig-sticking.
I don't believe
in explaining orders,
but this time
it's necessary.
Mohammed Khan's men
are in these hills,
to seize that
ammunition convoy
before it reaches
our friend, the Emir.
There's no need to tell you
how serious one ill-advised
or careless move
by any of you
might be in this situation.
Oh, of course, we're here
for sport and maneuvers.
And as some of you who are
new to India may not know,
a wounded pig
is a dangerous animal,
so a word of advice
to, uh, the younger officers.
If you wound a pig
and he takes to cover,
do not dismount and follow.
Foolhardiness is not courage.
It's not good soldiering
and it's not good sport.
Good morning, sir.
Good morning.
We shall ride
together, sir?
It will be a pleasure.
You have the advantage
of me, in years.
The older the English fox,
the safer his brush.
Cunning comes with age,
CoI. Stone.
Hunted in the shires, I see.
And you on the border.
We're fairly matched.
But I prefer
your English sport to this.
You prefer hunting the fox?
Mr. Stone.
I'm worried about you.
Such a dangerous sport.
Nonsense. Why,
there's no risk at all.
Good luck.
Old Ramrod's spotted one.
Look at him ride.
He made a direct kill.
Look!
20 Rupees on the first spear.
Right.
" Oh, he flew through the air
with the greatest of ease "
Ho, ho, ho, ho, ho.
Did you see old Ramrod
make that kill?
"A wounded pig is
a dangerous animaI."
What rot.
Pig hasn't a chance.
Think so?
Hey, look.
There's your chance to
find out how simple it is.
Stone!
Mr. McGregor!
You get back on your
horse and stay there.
Mr. Stone! Mr. Stone!
McGregor,
give me your tunic.
No one, you understand,
no one,
must know of this.
Yes, sir.
Mr. Stone, you've seen fit
to disregard my advice.
You will please be good
enough to leave the field.
Yes, sir.
I, uh, I-I should
thank you two.
Well, thank you,
gentlemen.
Now, uh, help me
on my horse.
And you, too,
disobeyed my orders.
I distinctly told
you not to dismount.
Lights out.
How do you
feel, sir?
I, oh, oh, quite
all right, thanks.
They'll be
over at once.
What?
Much better talk to them
yourself, I think, sir.
He's your son, you know.
Better effect than
if it came from me.
And when you talk,
I happen to know there's
quite a strong friendship
between the boy
and McGregor.
Yeah. Yes, yes, of course.
Of course, yes.
Well, all right.
They're here.
Come in.
Oh, yes, yes, of course,
it's you. Yes, I-I...
G- Good evening, gentlemen.
Good evening, sir.
Yes, I, uh,
I- I-I sent for you.
I- I want to talk
to you about something. Uh...
Uh, sit down.
S- sit down, both of you.
No, no, no,
don't go, Hamilton.
It, um, it's about,
uh, um...
Are your quarters
comfortable?
Yes, sir.
Just like
Salisbury Plain, sir.
Yes, yes.
There are three of you
together, I understand.
I- I-I mean, my s-
Uh, Mr. Stone is quartered
with you, isn't he?
Yes, sir.
Yes.
Well, I, uh,
I- I-I want to talk to you
about something.
Uh,
Uh, oh,
Uh, oh, t-try some
of my tobacco, McGregor.
I- I-It's my own mixture.
You know- you know,
that fellow in Jermyn Street.
Lot of perique in it.
Hm.
Too strong for me, maybe.
No. No, not for you,
McGregor.
I- I-it might be for Forsythe.
Of the Blues.
Late of the Blues, sir.
Huh? Oh, yes, yes,
late of the Blues.
Uh, I-I-I knew
your father, Forsythe.
Oh, did you really?
Yes.
Snake charmer, wasn't he?
What? Brigadier General,
a- a snake charmer?
Well, I thought...
Well, you see,
his son plays one of those...
Oh, that's odd.
I- I-I never heard of it.
Uh...
Oh, oh, probably,
it's just as well.
Probably.
Yes, probably, sir.
Yes. Yes, I-I-I knew him.
Uh...
Y- your father must be
very proud of you, Forsythe.
T- t-the army a-a-and all that
sort of thing, I mean.
Oh, he took all that
for granted, sir.
Yes. Yes. Uh...
Uh-uh, you-you ought to make
a good officer, Forsythe.
Oh, you've got a lot
to learn yet, of course.
Oh, yes, sir.
Yes.
W- w-where is your father now?
Cheltenham.
Retired.
Retired?
Yeah.
Well, we-we come to it.
We all come to it.
Not much to look
forward to then.
Not much, unless, uh...
Well, uh, we've had
a hard day.
Now, you-you'd better
get yourself some sleep.
Good night, gentlemen.
Good night, sir.
Yeah, good night, Hamilton.
That fellow in Jermyn Street.
Pour lumps of sugar.
Not much to
look forward to.
So he wanted
to talk to us.
Well,
whatever it was,
he couldn't get it
off his chest, could he?
Say, do you suppose...
Ah, is the light
beginning to break?
I got it.
The old man doesn't know
what to do about his kid,
and wants us
to help him,
but just
couldn't get it out.
That's brilliant, Mac.
That's positively brilliant.
That's it, all right.
I never thought
he cared that much.
he was that human.
Yet the way
he went after that pig
when he thought
his boy was in for it.
Yeah, game old cock.
Those tusks got him a lot
worse than he lets on, too.
Boy's pretty
bitter and ugly.
Largely the old
man's fault, of course.
Partly the old man's,
partly our system's.
But mostly the boy's.
Let's wake him up.
Well, no, Mac. I leave that
to you. He's your ward.
Well, the old man talked
to you, too, didn't he?
That girI.
Ah, youth, youth!
I trust you won't find
the journey
too uncomfortable,
Mr. Stone.
Halt! Who goes there?
Guard, turn out.
Barrett sahib.
As he turned around, we fired
and brought him down, sir.
Thank you, McGregor.
Your version, Forsythe?
Mr. Stone
was not in his tent.
That's all we can say, sir.
You've both tried
to shield him.
All the facts are obvious.
He couldn't
have been seized
in the middle of the camp
without some outcry.
Just slipped out
against orders.
Anyway, he can tell
where they've taken him, sir.
Hamzulla, ask him where Mohammed Khan
has taken my son.
I think I can
make him talk, sir.
Well, try.
Guards doubled
as ordered, sir.
Thank you, Norton.
Barrett?
Bad?
The eyes, and the usuaI...
Mogala.
Thank you,
McGregor.
I learned that
one from you, sir.
Hamzulla Khan,
take him away
and see that he
is well guarded.
Trial of that Afridi,
10:00 a. m. Tomorrow.
Services for Barrett,
at noon.
That's all, gentlemen.
But, sir.
I thought that-
You thought what,
Mr. McGregor?
That you were going
after your son, sir.
This incident will not change
our plans in any respect.
But-But knowing where
he's taking your son
makes all
the difference, sir.
We can be at Mogala
almost as soon as he is.
This regiment
can ride, sir.
I'm aware
my regiment can ride.
I'm also aware that
I am not going to do
precisely what Mohammed Khan
has planned that I should do.
He took my son
to goad me into pursuing him
to draw the lancers
from their position.
He's mistaken his man.
But this-
In our present position,
the regiment holds
Mohammed Khan checkmate.
The regiment stays here.
Then let me go.
I can take
a small detachment-
Mr. McGregor, I cannot
weaken the strength
of the regiment
in this emergency.
And I can't permit you
or any other officer
to risk their lives
for Mr. Stone.
But he's your son, and
we can save him, can't we?
That will be all,
Mr. McGregor.
Then take a look at that.
That's what Mohammed Khan
does to his prisoners.
That's quite unnecessary,
Mr. McGregor.
I know what may
happen to my son
through his own
disobedience and folly.
I'd just begun to think
I was wrong about you,
but I wasn't.
You haven't a human bone
in your body.
There's not a drop
of blood in your veins.
You're nothing but a-
McGregor.
So you'll sit here
with your regiment
while they kill
your son by inches.
Well, I won't!
I'm going after him whether
you like it or not.
Mr. McGregor!
Pending charges
of insubordination
you will please consider
yourself under arrest.
Mr. Forsythe, you will be
responsible for the prisoner.
You fooI.
Can't you see-
So you-
Mac!
Come along.
Well, I must say
you spoke your mind,
old colonial, if
there's any virtue in that.
"Regiment, duty,
you're improperly dressed. "
That's all
he cares about.
So they'll say,
"Very good, CoI. Stone,"
and pin another medal on him.
Or else he's...
Haven't you said enough,
McGregor?
The coloneI's right
and you know it.
You're only making it
harder for him.
If you take my advice,
you'll go over and apologize.
Not me. Apologize
after what he did?
Oh, for heaven's sake, man,
get some sense.
Do you suppose it was
an easy thing for him to do?
His own son?
Why wasn't it?
He doesn't care
about him.
He'd do the same thing
to any of us.
But to sit here and let them
pull his own son to pieces
because of a few
cases of ammunition-
Are you blind, man?
You think he doesn't care?
Well, I know he does.
Well, I suppose
if it were your son,
you'd sit here, too,
like a dummy.
You would not-
No, I should probably
have ordered the regiment out.
That's because I'm not
the man the colonel is.
Nor the soldier.
Well, if that's what
you call being a man
or a soldier, I don't
want any part of it.
Not me.
That kid needs him.
It's his own blood,
and if he cared
a hang about him-
Of course he cares. But
what's that got to do with it?
He loved his wife, too,
but he lost her.
She was American.
Couldn't stick the service,
couldn't understand.
So he chose the regiment then
just as he's doing now.
But that doesn't mean
he didn't care.
I know.
I ought to know.
We were Cubs together.
He put his whole souI
into the regiment,
and that's all he's had.
And he won't have that long,
either. Retirement.
He'll have an armchair
in the club,
and a window over the rag,
and that's all.
And he'll have nothing
if his boy doesn't carry on
in this regiment.
Then he'd have everything?
Of course he would.
That's what it means to him.
But you think
he'd let that make
any difference
to his orders, to his job?
Well, why shouldn't it?
Why can't he be
a little less of a soldier
and more of a man?
Why can't he forget
his blasted duty for once?
Man, you are blind!
Have you never thought
how for generation
after generation here,
a handfuI of men
have ordered the lives
of 300 million people?
It's because he's here,
and a few more like him.
Men of his breed
have made British India.
Men who put their jobs
above everything.
He wouldn't let death
move him from it
and he won't let love
move him from it.
When his breed of man
dies out, that's the end.
And it's
a better breed of man
than any of us will ever make.
Good night, gentlemen.
There's a great deaI
of speaking of minds
going on here tonight.
I didn't think
the old boy had it in him,
but he's right.
According to his way
of thinking, maybe.
It's funny,
your being out here
and thinking of it
in any other way.
On their side, huh?
Well, I'm not. So I'm
going to do something.
There's been enough thinking
and talking, too. I'm going.
Are you really, now?
You know, you put me
in a rather awkward position.
Look, I don't want
any trouble with you,
but I'm going.
Well, when do we start?
What do you mean "we"?
You're my prisoner, you know.
I couldn't let you
out of my sight.
I regret to have
to report, sir.
McGregor and Forsythe
have disappeared.
What, desertion?
I suppose it is,
technically.
Well, what did you expect?
" Sure I love
the dear silver "
" That shines in her hair "
" And the brow
that's all furrowed "
" and wrinkled with care "
" I kiss the dear fingers
so toiI-worn for me "
" Oh, God bless you
and keep you "
" Mother "
" Mcgregor "
Why do they want to talk
so many languages in India?
It's up to you.
You'll have to be
the talking merchant.
I'll be
the deaf and dumb one.
Well,
at least we're in.
I hope getting out
is as easy.
Trying to be funny?
No, I'm not
trying to be funny.
I'm scared stiff.
What are we
going to do now?
Try to look and act
like the rest
of these merchants.
Set up shops.
Sell a few doodads
while we take a look around.
I don't see anything
that looks like a plan.
As far as I can see,
we've just stuck our head
in the lion's mouth.
A very large and
unpleasant lion, too.
Suppose you
were Mohammed Khan,
where would you have put him?
Oh, no, you play first.
It'll be more fun.
All right.
You stay here
and unpack these things
and set up shop.
I'll take a look around.
Don't forget
you're deaf and dumb.
You'd better cut
your prices, Mac,
before I get my throat cut.
Do you think
she recognized us?
I hope not.
I don't think so.
Anyway,
we won't worry about it.
Did you see
anything interesting?
Not a thing.
What's that mean?
Time to go?
Yes.
But we're gonna stay
right here untiI we can-
He's in all right.
No doubt about that.
And doing rather well, too.
Clicquot.
I saw the labeI. Iced.
If that's the way Mohammed Khan
tortures his victims
I'd like to change places
with him for 10 minutes.
That guard's got
a key all right.
If we can last till night,
hit the guard over the head
get the kid out,
try and steal some horses-
Jump them over
a 40-foot wall
and then that mad dash
for the border.
Well, you think
of something better.
Mohammed Khan sent for us.
He wants to see
our rugs and laces.
Do you suppose?
No, I don't suppose.
Don't forget
you're deaf and dumb.
Oh, come, come, gentlemen.
It isn't everyday
that two British officers
prostrate themselves at the feet of
a poor border chieftain.
Mr. McGregor, Mr. Forsythe.
I told you, this Mardi Gras
would be a washout.
I had hoped the ColoneI
might come himself
but since he has so
very cleverly refused,
I welcome you
to my humble home.
You remember,
my dear, of course?
How could I forget?
They were such
charming dinner companions.
Dinner. Yes, of course.
You will dine with me
surely, gentlemen,
to try my poor savage fare?
I know you must be anxious
to meet my guest of honor.
I wouldn't do that
if I were you, Mr. McGregor.
Yes, I've-I've seen
good cricket in my time.
I was an Oxford man,
you know.
But I must compliment you,
Mr. Forsythe,
on your delivery.
Superb.
Oh, charming
compliment.
My only regret is that
it wasn't a hand grenade.
A charming thought.
A charming dinner.
The mutton
was, uh, excellent.
Always mutton.
We have mutton or chicken
up here. But, as you say,
good mutton, quite the equaI
of your English South Down.
Now you put me in a very
difficult position.
Pride of country urges me
to argue the point.
But my position
as, uh...
as a guest,
shall we say-
By all means a guest,
for the time being.
For the time being, huh?
Pass the wine.
My position
as a guest
for the time being,
of course,
inclines me
to agree with you.
Well, a compliment indeed,
that we can approach the excellence
of anything British.
I'm fed up with this
cat-and-mouse business.
Let's talk sense.
You've got us here and now what
are you going to do with us?
Mac, manners,
manners.
By the way, we didn't
thank the Khan sahib
for our charming
and picturesque raiment.
Suppose we stay
with the subject?
I'm quite prepared
to supply you
with horses to return
to your regiment.
You can tell your coloneI
that some of my men
misunderstood his son's
innocent flirtation.
Of course,
when I found it out,
I punished them at once.
An easy explanation of how
I came to set you free.
And, uh,
what's the catch?
You have only to answer
two very simple questions:
By what route is
the ammunition train coming
and just where does
the regiment plan
to meet it for convoy?
Well, when the furry
little animaI
jumped out of the bag
he really jumped, didn't he?
Well, gentlemen.
We have ways
to make men talk.
If you'll forgive me,
I- I have a headache.
Oh, I'm sorry, my dear.
Madame Volkanskaya
finds our methods
in this part of the world
a little too direct
for her taste.
Your brandy, gentlemen.
Take it. We may need it.
I regret this,
but thanks to your coloneI's
cold heart and cold brain
I have no other choice,
and very little time.
Now that we're
no longer guests,
tell him what you
really think of the mutton.
Oh, yes.
As much as I regret
to say this,
your mutton
is undoubtedly-
"Rotten" is the word.
Thanks, Mac.
Come, now, gentlemen,
must I proceed
to these absurd
and unpleasant extremes?
Little bamboo slivers
but when they're driven
under the fingernails
and lighted,
we find them
very effective.
Bring the other two gentlemen
a little bit closer
so they can see well.
I shall proceed first
with Mr. McGregor.
I'll get you some water.
I'd rather have
a cigarette, Mac.
Dentist once in MontreaI
hit a nerve.
It hurt almost as bad.
Well, he's been
to a dentist.
Let me alone!
Come on, Tania.
Don't faiI me, Tania.
Come along,
Mohammed Khan.
Show some speed!
Tania!
For dear
old Forsythe.
Tania! Tania!
Run, jump, do something!
Do anything.
That's right.
Here we go.
Tania!
One jump.
Come on, Mohammed Khan,
take that hurdle.
Ah, Mohammed Khan,
by half a length.
That makes 40 million
Rupees you owe me.
Another day of this,
and I'm broke.
Another day of this, we'll
be going around in circles
like
those cockroaches.
Ah, I wonder when these
whiskers stop itching
and begin to be a beard!
Foulest torture
ever invented.
Keep us in a cell
that crawls
and fix us so
we can't scratch.
All the Khan's horses
and all the Khan's men.
It didn't
take him long.
I'd like to
have seen the look
on the ColoneI's face.
It looks as if they were
expecting trouble.
There's only one answer.
The ColoneI's
after them.
And with all
the ammunition here,
there's nothing to
keep him in GopaI.
With those machine guns
and two million rounds
of ammunition
the regiment
wouldn't have a chance.
The old Ramrod's a fooI
to try it.
He will, though.
There's nothing much
we can do about it.
I wish I had
my toodle-oodle here.
I'd play you some
wild Scotch airs.
Over my dead body,
you would.
You know, that's
rather clever, Mac.
Why don't you say it?
Why don't you say what you're thinking?
Forget it!
I'm to blame. I told them,
that's what you're thinking.
Why don't you say it?
Shut up!
All right, I told them
and why shouldn't I? For him?
To stand there and watch
and know all the time
I was gonna be next
to have your nails torn off
and those pincers
and burning sticks
driven into you untiI...
And things you
can't even talk about.
Why should I stand all that?
For what? For him?
For a service that makes him
like he's been to me?
He left me here, didn't he?
He knew what they'd do.
He wouldn't come
after me, not him.
Regiment, service, duty!
Why should I stand
what you did for them?
Why should I?
Why should any of us? Why?
I told you to forget it.
All right, Mac.
But I still
don't understand why.
Why? Well...
Well, there are some things
they don't teach you
in military college.
Can't, I guess.
India's big, you know.
There are 300 million people
and run by, uh,
just a handfuI of men.
The-The-The job comes first.
Like old Ramrod,
you can't let death
move you, nor love.
And it's like...
How can I tell you
what it's all about
when I don't know
myself?
"'The time has
come,'the Walrus said,
"'To speak of many things
"'Of ships and shoes
and sealing-wax,
Of cabbages and kings. "'
Oh, shut up!
You don't like
poetry?
How should I know?
I never read any.
Perhaps something
more rugged.
"Ever the faith endures,
"England, my England
"Take and break us,
we are yours
"England, my own
"Life is good, joy runs high
"Between English earth and sky
"Death is death
and we shall die
"to the Song
on your bugles blown, England
To the stars on
your bugles blown!"
If I had known I was
going to say all this,
I would have
brought my violin.
You weren't by any chance thinking
how nice it would be
if someone spilled the fire
into that ammunition, were you?
About 200 yards,
I'd say.
Nearer a 100.
My last year in Oxford
I won the 220.
I ran the 100
in 10 flat at McGill.
It's nearer 200.
And where's McGill?
Mcgill's in MontreaI.
And this is a job
for a 100-yard man.
Forget I'm your
superior officer?
Forget you're
my prisoner?
Toss you?
The cockroaches.
If Tania gets to
the wall first, I win.
It's a go?
Mohammed Khan! Come on!
Tania, what's the matter?
Mohammed Khan again!
It's my job.
Your luck's as good
as ever, Mac.
And now all I have to do
is figure a way
to get out of here.
That's all.
Too late, sir.
Hopeless to
attack that strength.
If we retire now
and that ammunition
is distributed
amongst the tribes...
You know what that means.
Yes, a costly job,
sir.
I know.
But it's worth
the whole regiment.
Squadron, wheel into line.
Gallop!
What are you doing?
I'm trying to wear
a hole in the wall
so we can all
climb through.
It occurred to me,
gentlemen
that you might like to know
what is to become of you.
I'm expecting a visit from
your colonel in a few minutes.
I can assure you he will
receive a very warm reception.
In the coming engagement,
if the Colonel escapes
I shall send you all
back to him alive.
If he is captured,
you will all die.
In any case,
I shall have the pleasure
of bringing the ColoneI
face to face with a son
who betrayed his Empire.
Very foolish,
Mr. Forsythe.
You should always temper
courage with judgment.
That's a fooI thing
to do.
We'll get it
soon enough.
Did you get a gun, too?
Just about enough powder
in those, I think,
to blow that lock off.
It took us five days
to think of that.
Us?
Take a little water and mix
enough straw and mud
to seal this lock.
What do we use
for a fuse?
Mac.
Yeah.
This idea, I'm in on it.
It was my fault, all this,
and if there's any way...
I mean-
Sure, I know.
Ready with that wick?
I mean, there's not
much left that...
Well, I couldn't go back,
like he said,
not to the regiment
or to England.
If anybody's going
to take any chances,
I'll take them.
Sure you're in on it.
Never thought of it
any other way.
Just stick close and
do what you're told
till we get this open.
There's someone on that tower
with a machine gun.
Let me get it and cover you
while you make a run for it.
All right.
Look, I've got a hunch
we're going to
get out of this.
We can't let the old man or
anybody know what's happened.
Mohammed Khan!
This way.
All right, Mac,
you keep me covered.
I can make it from here.
Bugles. Trumpets.
Man needs seasoning.
Poetry!
Mac! Mac, I... I...
He did it for me.
To undo what I did!
The last thing
Mac asked you...
the old man mustn't know.
It's just as good a way
of paying what you owe.
Mother McGregor.
Lt. John Forsythe
by command of His Majesty
the King-Emperor,
I confer upon you
the distinguished
service order.
Second Lt. Donald Stone,
41st Bengal Lancers.
For conspicuous gallantry
and devotion to duty.
He attacked single-handed,
a group of the enemy
and killed their leader
thus demoralizing
hostile forces
at a moment when
the success of our arms
at Mogala was in the balance.
Second Lt. Donald Stone
by Command of His Majesty
the King-Emperor
I confer upon you the
distinguished service order.
Lt. Alan McGregor
41st Bengal Lancers,
deceased.
For valor.
At the sacrifice of his life
he destroyed enemy
ammunition supplies
contributing thereby
to the success of our arms
in the action at Mogala.
His Majesty the King-Emperor
has been graciously pleased
to confer posthumously
the Victoria Cross
upon the late
Lt. McGregor.
In accordance with
the custom of this regiment
I place this cross
upon the saddlecloth
of his horse.
Watch Movies, TV Series & Live Sports
www.admitme.app