Here they come.
Hi.
Hi. Kate.
Hi. Anne.
Here. let me take that.
I’ll get that out of your way.
- Kate?
- Hi. babe.
Oh. look at this.
No. don‘t do that.
It’s for tomorrow.
Well. for him
there‘s no tomorrow.
Jack. control yourself.
Please.
Hey. what are
you doing?
I waited 20 minutes in line
for that. Come on.
All right. Give me
some of that. Come on.
Are we all here?
Yeah. Let‘s go.
Hey!
The guy is going away
for a weekend
and he‘s bringing
his whole wardrobe.
Be careful.
Don‘t worry about
the eggplants.
I got five of them.
You got five eggplants?
What do you mean.
the baby ones?
Baby ones?
They‘re like salamis.
13 eggplants.
Isn‘t that kind of a lot?
You can never have
too many eggplants.
Hi. how are you?
Hi.
Claudia‘s at her studio.
Turn left on Christopher.
right on Hudson.
Hey. what happened
to the bread?
What is this.
you started without me?
Need help?
I’m okay.
Hi. Claudia.
Hi.
You brought your work.
I stopped my work
for the weekend.
Danny. please.
You‘re a dentist.
Do you hear this?
I can sculpt a bicuspid
that would fool God himself.
but I’m just a dentist.
Do we-- Do we have
any ginger?
I got two pounds of ginger
and a pound of garlic.
Anne. didn‘t you have
a tree there?
Yeah. but we just...
We had to cut it down.
I miss it. You could see it
from the bedroom.
Hey. we have locks. right?
Two locks. A big lock
and a little lock.
Oh. I love those flowers.
I forgot my cleaver.
That‘s all right.
I got a cleaver.
Would you believe this?
They‘ve been organizing
this one meal for two weeks?
I believe it.
God. look at that.
Wait a minute. Look at this.
How did you trace this?
What do you do.
throw them up in the air?
I took a piece of glass
put the vegetables
on the glass.
and I got--
Wait. That‘s...
That one I want.
Oh. isn‘t that gorgeous?
Is this the way this goes?
Yes.
It looks like a face.
It does looks like a face.
The nose. the eyes. the ears.
Did you try the Pegasus
Gallery in SoHo?
Yes. I just....
I can‘t believe that man.
I just...
I told him
that I had been working
on this series of
pictures for three years.
and do you know
what he said?
He said. ‘‘Three years
photographing vegetables?
‘‘Don‘t you think
that‘s a little constipated?‘‘
Do you believe that?
Well. that all depends
on the vegetables.
What you gonna do
with the cover?
Take it off.
Please take it off.
The chili pepper‘s cooking.
They have to be charred.
Okay. It will be charred.
Oh. come on.
Cook or laugh.
what is this?
Well. do something with it.
Pour water on it.
Pour water on hot oil.
You‘re kidding. right?
My eyes are tearing.
I can‘t see what I’m doing.
We‘re gonna have
chopped knuckles
and hot garlic sauce.
Here. here.
I really can‘t see.
Wait. Come here. come here.
How is that? Is that better?
Oh. terrific.
You rubbed it in
real good. I’m blind.
The oil‘s not hot enough.
Then why have l
lost my eyesight?
It’s not hot enough.
You cannot cook Chinese food
unless the oil is 480 degrees.
Oh. damn.
It’s a scientific fact.
Did Einstein say that?
Newton. Isaac Newton.
The inventor of Mu Shu Pork.
Hey. Anne?
Mmm-hmm?
The magazine
is doing a piece
on the top 10 executives
in the country.
How would you like to
photograph them for us?
Oh. God.
I’d love to be in Fortune.
When do you need them?
By July.
You mean of this year?
Anne.
that‘s two months
from now.
Yes. dear. I know that.
I just...
I don‘t work that fast.
Anne. how are you ever
going to get published?
You have to move.
What‘s the matter
with you?
Just do a story on
the top 10 broccoli
in the country.
Chicken salad.
You got the rice things?
Yeah. yeah. yeah.
Do it now
and they‘ll all be ready
at the same time.
I’ve got this
timed out scientifically.
Yes. sir.
Watch this. Watch this.
You ready?
Yeah. Watch out.
Watch this. Here we go.
Isn‘t that beautiful?
That‘s incredible.
Okay. First course.
And Chinese beer.
Bravo!
Thank you.
Did you leave out the MSG?
No MSG.
Grab your sticks and eat.
Here‘s some rice.
Pass it around.
Wait. wait.
Start with the appetizers.
That‘s
the chicken salad.
Oh. my God. Danny.
That‘s fantastic.
Wait.
Pass it around!
Danny‘s
my genius!
The shrimp
is incredible.
Okay. I have a toast.
Toast. To Nick and Anne.
Yeah.
And to this dinner
which is wonderful.
Watch it. watch it.
watch it.
And to the reason
we‘re here tonight.
Not just to
celebrate your anniversary.
but to that deeper thing
that brings us
all close together.
To what bonds us. and--and
makes us huddle against
the cold winds of divorce
that have blown through
the lives of our friends.
Oh. that‘s lovely.
- Really nice.
- Nice. nice.
Thanks. Jack.
May I say something?
Yes.
I just wanna say
that l...
That was the most
depressing goddamn toast
that I have ever heard
in my life.
Why? Why?
What‘s wrong with that?
He got to the heart
of it.
He faced it.
He told us his fears.
That‘s why
we‘re here.
That‘s why I’m in analysis.
you know.
It’s not why
I’m eating dinner.
Well. I think he‘s right.
That‘s what
brought us together.
I don‘t get this close
with all my patients.
We didn‘t meet through you.
Sure we did!
Oh!
We did! We did!
Didn‘t I do
some legal work for you?
Then we all got to
know one another.
started going out together.
No. I remember
going over your statement.
We did not meet
through the men at all.
No. They think everything
revolves around them.
Anne is
absolutely right.
You and l.
we met at a women‘s
photographers exhibition
and then Anne and l
met Claudia
at an art gallery.
You didn‘t get at their teeth
until months later.
Uh. we met seven years ago.
It was the third week.
Thank you.
The third week in July.
And my first appointment
with Danny was. uh.
for a filling.
It was. uh. September 8.
and it was a Wednesday.
How can you remember that?
Oh. uh. I remember
things like that
because I feel
they‘re important.
Look. the point is
what brings us together.
- Right. That‘s the point.
- Right?
That‘s the point.
We owe the depth. breadth
and height of this friendship
to the world‘s
most ancient emotions:
fear and panic.
Am I right? Am I right?
I love you.
Am I right?
Listen. I spent three hours
buying this
and four hours chopping it
into little pieces.
I’m not just gonna eat it.
I’m gonna make love to it.
You keep talking.
I’ll eat yours.
Wait. Come on.
Cut it out.
Come on.
he‘s down in the orchard.
I--I can‘t get
this damn fender
straightened.
I’ll see you down there.
Yeah.
Hey. you look great.
Don‘t get too close.
Watch your foot.
Come on.
I’ll race you.
I’m going fast enough.
I just wanna dry my hair.
Come on. We‘ll see who
gets to the house first.
Let‘s just see
if we can get there.
How about that?
Hey. you want a helmet?
Of course
I want a helmet.
Oh. that‘s better.
That‘s nice.
Hey. Danny!
Hey! You wanna race?
No.
Come on. Let‘s race a little.
Look.
leave me alone. will you?
You look great on that thing.
Come on. What do you say?
I don‘t wanna race!
Good. You ready?
Go!
Go. Danny. Go! Go! Go!
Whoa!
Watch out! Watch out!
I won!
I won! I did it!
I did it! I won!
I won! I won!
What happened?
Are you all right?
Yeah. I’m fine.
Are you okay?
I am the greatest!
The sexy dentist won!
I won!
Danny. you‘re wonderful!
I love you!
How. how about Indian food
next time?
We can-- We can make
our own mango chutney.
we can fry a little chapatí.
How about Indonesian?
We could do
a whole rice table.
Oh. yeah.
That will be great.
I love that.
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
I think I got it.
What?
It’s 1 :00.
Homemade pasta.
Yeah?
Florentine
Chicken.
Mmm-hmm.
...on a-- on
a bed of spinach.
Oh. yeah.
And a hot antipasto
of mussels
in marinara sauce.
How about that?
Is that good?
Danny. please.
I’m Italian.
Oh. you don‘t think
we can do it. huh?
Didn‘t we make
a great Chinese meal
last night?
Yeah. Well.
look. we‘re not Chinese.
You know?
By us it was Chinese.
What do we know?
Danny. please.
She‘s Italian.
Yeah.
I can make a better sauce
than your mother.
My poor mother
has arthritis.
Of course you make
a better sauce than her.
Before her arthritis.
Will you guys shut up?
You‘re depressing the birds.
How‘s your leg?
Oh. fine.
I’ve been banged up so many
times I hardly even notice it.
In college he played
football with a broken wrist
and then two big guys
picked him up
and threw him on his head
and he was unconscious
for three hours.
Those were the days.
Hey. Hey.
Listen to the water
lapping against
the sides of the boat.
To be with friends
sipping wine.
this is what it is
to be happy.
This.
and being incredibly rich.
I’m a lifetime member
of Equitable‘s
Million Dollar Roundtable.
Gimme some cheese.
will you?
I’m one of
the most successful
estate planners in New York.
But that‘s nothing
compared to this.
Nick. please.
I wish that you would relax.
Please.
He‘s always selling.
What are you
talking about?
You‘re an
estate planner?
insurance salesman.
I don‘t plan estates?
I’m not on
the Million Dollar Roundtable?
Oh. Do you know
what you get
for being in
the Million Dollar Roundtable?
What?
A plastic statue
and a weekend.
a weekend
at the La Cucaracha Hotel
in Puerto Rico.
What are you doing?
I’m gonna make a toast.
Again? Not another one?
Here‘s to us.
Here‘s to apple trees.
to cheese...
Here‘s to cheese?
...and wine and friends
and laughter.
and life itself.
That‘s beautiful. Sit down.
Carefully.
Oh. shit.
What. again?
I don‘t want
this afternoon to disappear
without something
to remember it by.
Some memorial of our
affection for one another.
Yeah. Terrific.
But just don‘t
wave your arms. okay?
This is for all of you
so that we‘ll never forget
this day.
Yeah.
I don‘t believe it!
What are you doing
in the lake?
All right.
I accept that gesture
from my friend.
He‘s not gonna be alone
in doing it.
My only regret is that
I’m not wearing my $500 suit.
I’ll just jump in
with my bread.
Hey. uh...
Hey.
You all right?
Sure.
You look distracted.
I’m okay.
You know.
I think we‘re close enough to
say anything to each other.
Really. Anything.
You and Kate happy?
Yeah. Very.
I mean. happy.
Can you honestly say
you‘re really happy?
Yeah. but not
every minute.
It comes in waves.
At times you hit lows
and you can‘t stand things
about each other.
Like the way
her teeth click
when she eats.
The way I smell my sweatshirt
before I put it on.
Sometimes we drive
each other crazy.
And then there are times
we go through a period
like the one we‘re in now.
It comes over us
like an unexpected wave.
puppy love.
I can‘t wait to see her.
And then when I’m with her
my heart beats faster.
I’d expect it
with somebody
who‘s a stranger.
but not somebody
I’ve spent
half my life with.
It’s wonderful.
I wish I could feel that.
Oh. you will.
It‘ll come back.
Just give it time.
No. I’ve never felt it.
I shouldn‘t have
married Anne.
I was crazy as a kid.
I figured
she‘d be some kind of
stability for me.
Well.
she certainly is stable.
I mean. she‘s a decent woman.
she‘s a good mother
but she doesn‘t
do anything.
Doesn‘t think anything.
I’ve never heard
one stimulating idea
come out of her mouth ever.
When she took up photography.
I thought. finally
she‘s gonna do something.
She spent three years
photographing vegetables.
She‘s not just stable.
she‘s inert.
So work on it with her.
Talk to her about it.
Jack. I’ve tried for 20 years.
I get nothing.
Do you know how painful it is
to want to love someone?
You‘ve no idea
how lonely I’ve been.
Look at her.
She gets obsessed with that.
She‘ll pace up and down
all day long
with the same thought.
turning it over and over
in her head.
She remembers the day
she got her tooth filled.
Can you remember that?
Christ. I can barely remember
the first time I got laid.
I come home from
a day‘s selling.
she wants to
talk about her work.
Fine. You know what
she talks about?
Vegetables.
For a year and a half
we talked about zucchini.
Then for a year.
green peppers.
That was a nice change.
Last night
was the end of 21 years.
And that‘s enough.
Today‘s the beginning
of a new life for me.
What?
That‘s it. It’s over.
You can‘t just quit.
What--what are you...
What are you talking about?
What‘s the matter with you?
I want to make a new start.
I want a new family.
What about your old family?
Lisa‘s 18.
She can handle this.
I want a woman
I can be excited by.
You‘ve got somebody else.
don‘t you?
You got somebody
waiting in the wings.
No. I don‘t.
I swear I don‘t have anybody
waiting in the wings.
Why are you making this
so difficult for me?
I thought
I could tell you anything.
How can you
just throw her away
after 21 years like this?
I mean. what is she
supposed to do now?
Oh. boy.
I thought if I told you.
you‘d be happy for me.
I even had this fantasy that
you‘d handle the divorce.
That I would handle
the divorce?
In the first place.
I’m not a divorce lawyer
and if I were.
I’d probably represent Anne.
I can‘t believe
you would do this.
Jack. please.
This is the hardest thing
I’ve ever gone through
in my life.
All right. I’m sorry.
Oh. God.
Nick. this is awful. Jesus.
Come on. let‘s go.
Want some more of these?
Oh. yes. Thank you.
Good. good.
You know.
beans are very much
misunderstood.
They have a complex set
of amino acids.
lf you eat beans
together with rice.
you never have to
eat meat.
Danny loves to
talk about beans.
Go ahead. sweetheart.
Talk.
It’s the combination
that counts.
Here. you want some of these?
Yeah. I do.
You know. I’ve been
thinking about that.
About what?
Photographing vegetables
in combinations.
not just one at a time.
You know?
I’m not sure yet.
Hey. I did some research
on sailboats for the summer.
That‘s great.
Already?
We only talked about it
a couple of days ago.
I got it in here someplace.
Here it is.
Nick.
you ought to check this out.
You‘re the sailor
in the group.
Where did you get
all this stuff?
Called a couple
of boat brokers.
- No kidding.
- Let me see one.
We can rent one in St. Thomas
and sail around the islands
and fly home. The whole thing
will take two weeks.
This woman‘s fantastic.
Nick. isn‘t this beautiful?
What a boat.
Oh. is that the galley?
Yes.
And you know what?
I think it looks...
It looks a little small to me.
Gorgeous.
Yeah. right.
Oh. l--I think
we‘ll manage very well.
don‘t you?
Oh. I think it‘s beautiful.
Oh. look at that.
Can‘t you sleep?
Nick is getting
a divorce.
How do you know?
He told me yesterday when
we were getting firewood.
Jeez.
Is there somebody else?
He says
there isn‘t anybody.
Why does he have to leave her?
Why can‘t they fight it out?
Hold me?
Good morning.
You got up early.
Oh. god. It’s
gorgeous down there.
Yeah?
There‘s this
enormous turtle.
You didn‘t try to ride him.
did you?
Ride a turtle that big?
Are you kidding?
I was thinking of it.
but I got scared.
Oh. Good morning.
Hey. could you
sleep last night?
Not very well.
What is it with them?
I don‘t know. boy.
Oh. I thought
I smelled coffee.
Good morning. Danny.
Thank you. Good morning.
How are you?
It’s great.
Oh my God.
Daylight.
Claudia thinks
she‘s seasick.
Are you?
No.
I’m just trying out
this new green makeup.
Claudia.
you‘re not nauseated.
Danny. how come
you‘re allowed to have
all these
psychosomatic illnesses.
but when I throw up
into my tote bag
at 2:00 in the morning.
it‘s just my imagination?
Did anyone sleep
last night?
You‘re kidding. right?
With all those mating calls
coming from
the master bedroom?
All night long.
I mean.
who could have guessed
that it would be
so distressing
to listen to
other people humping?
Hi. gang.
Good morning.
Morning.
What a morning!
Oh. boy. smell that air.
Huh?
Yeah.
Now. this is how
the whole world should live.
Uh-huh?
I slept like a baby
last night.
Wasn‘t that
a great night?
Oh. yeah.
It was great. Yeah.
Wasn‘t it peaceful
bobbing around on the water
like that?
Yeah. well.
some parts of the boat
bobbed more than others.
Hey. honey. throw on
your suit and come on up!
Coffee‘s on.
- Hi!
- Good morning.
Good morning.
Did anybody hear anything
about the weather?
Oh. yeah. did you listen
to the radio yet?
Yeah.
it‘s supposed to be clear.
After breakfast.
should we head for St. Croix?
Wait a minute.
You wanna move the boat?
Come on.
once you get used to it
you‘ll be
the most intrepid sailor
of the bunch.
I don‘t see how
we‘re gonna go anywhere
unless we can get
the anchor up.
Well. we‘ll just pull it up.
Pull it up?
Isn‘t that why
we had to stay here
last night.
because we couldn‘t
pull the anchor up?
Nah. if the three of us
give it a yank. it‘ll come up.
Come on.
You boys go pull on
your anchor for a while.
We‘ll be back here.
lf that anchor comes up
out of the water.
there is no God.
Nick just amazes me.
I mean. he‘s so accomplished.
He can sail.
He knows how to choose wines.
Do you know
that he‘s just about
the most successful
estate planner in New York?
Is that so?
Yeah.
He‘s a life member in
the Million Dollar Roundtable.
I hear they send you
to Puerto Rico for that.
Oh. yeah.
He goes all over the place.
We met on my flight to L.A.
I sat with him for an hour
after the dinner service
and...
God. I had just
never met anybody
who knew so much about
actuarial tables.
He‘s a charmer.
Yeah.
How about Danny?
Has he been sailing long?
No.
Well. how about Jack?
Jack saw
Two Years Before The Mast
when he was 12.
One. two. heave ho!
Come on.
We‘re not gonna make it.
This is like
pulling a building.
Okay. Come on.
Danny. watch your foot.
Watch out. Watch out.
It’s stuck on something.
There‘s a big plant down
there or something.
I’ll run her over.
Tell me when it‘s vertical.
You‘re gonna what?
I’m gonna start up the engine.
You tell me when this rope
is straight up and down. okay?
Do you know what the hell
he‘s talking about?
Hey.
What?
Maybe we
shouldn‘t go anywhere.
Everybody‘s worried
that we don‘t know
what we‘re doing.
I know what I’m doing.
Hey.
your nose is getting red.
You better
put something on it.
Well. I just think that
if anybody‘s nervous about it
we should stop
and talk about...
What is this?
I don‘t know.
Open it up.
Oh. my God.
Shalimar?
You are
the sweetest man.
Look at this.
He‘s given me a present
every single day
since we left St. Thomas.
You could make me
fall in love with you
pretty easily.
You mean
it could get worse?
Excuse me.
Okay. I’m gonna move her up.
Tell me when.
More, more, more.
More, more.
More, more, more, more...
Hold it.
Thank you.
You don‘t have to worry about
the anchor any more.
Come here.
You want us down there?
Yes.
At that end
of the boat?
Come here
and ready this sail.
Come on. Ollie.
They‘re really gonna
move it.
I doubt it.
Okay. what do you want us to do?
I want you to
raise the mizzen.
I’ll close the lid.
Close the lid.
we‘ll kill ourselves.
Close the hatch.
Where will I stand?
Right there.
Just pull on the rope
like we did yesterday.
I got it. I got it.
Like yesterday.
Okay.
I got the ribbons out here.
Ribbons?
The gaskets.
I’m pulling
the ropes.
Okay.
Okay?
There she goes!
Jack!
Oh. my God!
Here. Grab that.
Are you all right?
What the hell
are you trying to do?
Here. take this line.
Oh. my God.
The boat‘s moving.
What? What?
Turn the wheel.
Not on my boat.
Don‘t touch anything!
Turn the wheel.
Jesus Christ!
You go ahead. folks.
I’ll catch up.
What‘s that?
I think we‘re stuck.
She‘s gone aground.
We‘re on a sandbar.
On the ground?
We‘re stuck. Yeah.
Look at that.
Oh. shit.
Excuse me.
Sorry.
I’ll just get these
into the water.
Oh. Jesus!
They‘re so dirty.
Look.
my lettuce water.
I gotta clean them.
Oh. now. wait a minute.
wait a minute. wait a minute.
No salt. okay?
Just put the salt
on the sides
of whoever wants to
poison themselves.
He doesn‘t
eat salt.
Salt is bad for you?
I haven‘t used salt
or mucus products
for three years
and I feel just great.
Who eats mucus?
He means
cheese and milk.
Danny. say what you mean.
will you please?
You‘re talking
to humans here.
Don‘t worry about it.
Danny.
This recipe
doesn‘t call for mucus.
- Got a knife?
- Excuse me.
Where‘s a knife?
Excuse me.
I think
I’m gonna die from the sun.
Why does my nose
always have to bother me?
Here. Danny.
let me get in here.
I got something
that‘ll make you feel better.
Here you go.
You put this--
Oh. no. no. no.
What?
You‘re not gonna put
that green. thorny thing
on my nose.
For God‘s sakes.
You take the jelly out of it.
It’s an aloe plant.
It‘ll make it just fine.
What?
You stabbed me
with that goddamn
Hawaiian plant.
Be careful.
I’m sorry.
It’s crowded in here.
Excuse me.
Would you excuse me. please?
I’m doing
the best I can.
Well. don‘t put it
in my lettuce.
Okay.
Jack and Kate owe Nick and me
$1 23 each for provisions.
except for the wine and beer
which Nick brought.
which everybody owes him
$47 each for.
Why don‘t we just subtract
the $47 from the $1 23?
No. no. no. no. no.
That‘s gonna screw it up.
I’ve worked this out
very carefully.
And I’d just like to tell you
that we are now
$350 over budget each.
All right. all right.
I don‘t see any trip
to St. Croix
unless we have
a meeting first.
I don‘t picture us seeing
St. Croix
unless it floats by.
I can‘t believe
he brought her.
How could he do that
to Anne?
How could he do it to us?
But she‘s really nice.
you know.
I mean. I like her.
She‘s wonderful.
I can‘t even enjoy
hating her.
Who the hell
needs that?
Danny is driving me crazy.
He has to be
the expert on everything.
What‘s the matter
with him?
He‘s very needy.
That‘s all.
Needy?
He‘s hypochondriacally.
stingy. bossy. selfish.
compulsive. and paranoid.
He‘s the Muhammad Ali
of mental illness.
Shh. Quiet.
Look. if they don‘t want me
to keep the finances.
I won‘t.
But there‘s
something wrong with them.
These people are vicious.
They‘re ill.
We‘re traveling with
a group of ill people.
I just can‘t believe
that he would bring her
on the boat with us.
Every time
I make a suggestion.
every time I say something
they‘re ignorant of.
do you see the way
they look at each other?
They discuss me
behind my back.
I mean. she walks around
with that hanky on her hips
that‘s supposed to be
a bathing suit.
Oh. God.
I get so depressed
every time I look at her.
These people are vicious.
Vicious and ill.
I don‘t believe it.
They‘re at it again.
They never stop.
Those two
are gonna kill themselves.
They‘re driving me crazy.
Talk about something else.
Something serious
and complex.
We won‘t even...
We won‘t even notice it.
All right. Okay.
Something serious.
Okay. go ahead.
Something serious and complex.
Tell me about
the Simmons suit.
The. uh. Simmons suit.
The Simmons suit.
Yeah. Okay.
Well. it all depends
how the judge interprets
the. uh.
environmental impact study.
Oh. yes.
Part of the problem
with inflation
is that the production
of goods and services
per man hour of work
is falling at a rate
of three percent a year.
What is she doing to him?
You‘re not listening.
Now. will you just listen?
lf productivity falls
three percent.
then wages
have to fall three percent.
Are you listening?
Then the cost
of production rises.
What goes up
must come down.
So--
Again.
Oh. no. not again!
I can‘t take anymore of this.
Do you want
some breakfast?
I’m too sleepy to eat.
Those people are killing me.
I’m gonna make some coffee
and see if I can wake up.
Maybe if I lie in the sun
I can go back to sleep.
Oh. my God.
What?
Down here. Quick.
Oh. my God.
Is the coffee ready?
I can‘t get my eyes open
this morning.
Maybe this‘ll get
your eyes open.
They‘re swimming already?
Where do they get the energy?
Keep looking at them.
What am I supposed
to see?
A-ha.
What‘s the matter?
Is everybody sick?
Come here. come on.
Oh. my God.
You know.
when you really
think about it.
there isn‘t
anything sexual about it.
It’s natural.
People go to
their doctor‘s offices.
they take off
their clothes.
it doesn‘t
mean a thing.
Meanwhile. he hasn‘t
taken his eyes off her
for a second.
I almost got you.
Hi!
Hi.
Oh. they‘re
swimming over.
Oh. Jesus.
Oh. Lord.
Just act casual.
What you mean.
like you?
I’m gonna
make breakfast.
I don‘t wanna look
at my friends naked.
It makes it hard
to have dinner
with them later.
Yeah. I’m gonna go
sit in the shade.
And I think. maybe.
I’ll read a book.
Okay. Danny.
we‘ve all got something to do.
What‘s everybody
getting so crazy about?
You can‘t see anything.
Then what are you
standing there for?
He‘s hoping she‘ll turn over
and do the backstroke.
I was just enjoying
their playfulness.
They‘re like
a couple of porpoises.
It’s a pure animal pleasure
of having fun. that‘s all.
Danny. will you.
for Christ‘s sake. sit down?
What‘s the matter
with this woman?
Huh! Shit.
Hold it.
Okay. hold it there.
Now give me a hand
with this.
Okay. Here we go.
Okay. Danny. start the winch.
Crank it up.
Okay.
That‘s it.
Kate. make sure
that tail line is taut.
All right. come on.
keep going. Heave!
Keep cranking. Keep cranking.
All right. Ginny.
I wanna put
a little more pressure on it.
Hoist that sail.
Okay!
That‘s it.
Danny.
Yeah?
That‘s it. darling.
Now put
a little muscle into it.
Haul it away. That‘s it.
That‘s it. That‘s it.
That‘s it!
Yeah. yeah.
It’s working!
Terrific!
Yes! Yes!
Where the hell
are they going?
Hey. wait for us!
Claudia!
Claudia. back it up!
We‘re headed out to sea!
Isn‘t this terrific?
Put it in reverse!
Okay. tell me when.
Good. good.
Thank you. Thanks. honey.
Why do you think
we love this boat so much?
I don‘t know.
Do you know why I think
we like this boat so much?
I knew it.
What?
He only asked us so he could
tell us his feelings.
Oh. come on.
Go ahead. Go ahead.
sweetheart. tell us.
Why do we love
this boat so much?
Because it represents
our primeval desire
to control water.
Ah. See?
No. think about it.
All our beginnings were wet.
Sloshing around in the womb.
baptism.
first life that came from
the warm soup of the ocean.
From the moment
we rose from the slime
as alligators.
we‘ve been trying
for dominion over water.
You know?
Mmm-hmm?
Jack loves ideas
and he can do so much
with them.
I have seen him take
one idea at a dinner party
and bring the conversation
of a dozen people
to a complete halt.
Ladies and gentlemen.
Clams Casino.
Oh. my God. I love them.
I have this insatiable need
to have dominance
over the clam.
Take forks.
It so happens
that Venus rose from
the sea on a clam shell.
Sexuality was born
in wetness.
It’s easier that way.
Hey.
Mine‘s all closed up.
How‘d that happen?
I don‘t know.
Open it.
Lodge your finger in it.
Right.
Oh. Nick.
That must be some clam.
Look
what he gave me.
What a guy.
I’m beginning to feel
left out.
Hmm. You got something. too?
Sand!
Oh!
Oh. Jack.
That‘s all right.
I’m gonna go down below
for a few minutes.
I think I’ll see
if she‘s all right.
Do you think
they‘re gonna do it again?
You know.
I’m real pissed off at him
for what he did to Anne.
but I have to
tell you.
I get a funny feeling
watching two people
who are that much in love.
How do you suppose
we lost that?
We didn‘t.
Just ‘cause they‘re bumping
into the furniture
and we‘re not.
that doesn‘t mean
that we‘ve lost interest.
Is he still thoughtful?
Yes. Jack is thoughtful.
Does he observe
good bathroom etiquette?
Like what?
Well. like does he
leave the seat up
or does he put it down?
It’s funny
how people tend to forget
little things like that.
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
You‘re not talking about me.
I always
put the seat down.
Sure.
after I yelled at you.
Do you know
how many times in the dark
I’ve fallen that extra inch
onto the porcelain?
Anyway.
I don‘t find them
all that adorable.
They‘re making this trip
very difficult.
They‘re not even
on this trip.
They walk around
mooning all the time
making goo-goo eyes.
My God. if one of them farts.
the other thinks
it‘s Guy Lombardo.
I think it‘s kind of nice.
I don‘t know. l...
I want us all to feel
like we did before.
Hmm.
I wanna feel like them.
God. I love that woman.
She just kills me.
Honey?
What?
It’s not the same anymore.
Everybody‘s different.
Have you noticed that?
Yeah.
What is it?
Is it me or something?
No.
Are you sure?
You‘re not doing
anything.
You‘re a little jealous
of Nick.
No. I’m not.
Sure you are.
I’m not. What are you...
What are you talking about?
Look. honey.
it‘s only natural.
Look.
she‘s a beautiful. young.
adoring woman. right?
Yeah.
And she believes
every single thing
he tells her about himself.
Now. it‘s only natural
for you to want that.
Well. but l...
I’m jealous?
You preen for her.
I do not.
You do. too.
I don‘t.
Jack.
Come on.
You walk around here
you‘re holding in
your stomach all the time.
You--you shave.
You comb your hair.
Well. l... No. I think
you‘ve misinterpreted
something.
No. now. excuse me. l--
Look. forget it.
Enjoy your fantasies.
I don‘t have
any fantasies about her.
Yeah?
Well. no serious fantasies.
Well. you know.
for somebody who likes to
get to the heart of things.
you have
this incredible knack
for denying
your own feelings.
You wish
I were jealous of him.
Why?
‘Cause that would alleviate
what you feel about her.
Hey. you‘re getting angry.
No. no. no. I’m not. No.
lf you‘re angry.
would you do me a favor
and just be angry?
I am not angry.
Don‘t start
with the analyzing.
I am not angry!
And you‘re not clenching
your teeth either. right?
Okay. all right.
that‘s a problem I have.
Sometimes when I get angry.
l--I analyze.
You certainly do.
You know why I do that?
I don‘t care why!
Look. you got a little hate
going there. right?
Admit it.
I am not angry
and I don‘t hate.
so just shut up
about that. okay?
Come on. shut up.
Will you slow down?
Do you know
where the brake is?
We got plenty of time.
You don‘t understand
the soul of a car like this.
It was born for speed.
I’m in complete control.
What are we cramped up
in here for?
We could‘ve used
their station wagon.
A station wagon is a car.
A Mercedes
is a thoroughbred.
Every so often.
it needs to be taken
on the open road
and challenged.
Want some?
Yeah. I’d love a bite.
Don‘t eat!
What?
Why?
The crumbs go down
in the upholstery.
You‘ll never get it out.
The car will look like
the bottom of a bird cage.
Isn‘t that crazy?
I’m starving.
One loaf of French bread
and the resale value
goes down $500.
You wanna eat a $500 sandwich.
it‘s up to you.
How about if
I just eat the insides for $1?
Can you make it?
Claudia.
once we find our kids.
why don‘t you and Danny
drop us off?
Then you can go see Mike
at Wesley.
We‘ll see him tomorrow.
It’s Saturday night.
He‘s probably out
trying to get laid.
What makes you think
your son‘s always doing
something sexual?
Please. I’m Italian.
Hi! There she is!
Bethie!
Hi. guys.
Hi!
God. you look marvelous.
Hello. honey.
Hi.
Hello.
Lisa‘s down there
somewhere.
Where?
Down there.
Come on. I’ll show you.
Guess what?
I got an ‘‘A‘‘ in History.
And this teacher
is such a jerk.
you wouldn‘t believe it.
He wouldn‘t even tell us
what to write about.
I had to figure
the whole thing out by myself.
You don‘t think
he was trying to get you
to think for yourself?
No. Mom. no.
This guy is really a jerk.
lf the jerks had
their own country.
this guy would be president.
There she is.
Lisa! Lis!
I’ll--I’ll go get her.
Hold on. will you?
Wait right there.
Okay.
Oh. God.
she‘s wonderful.
That kid sure takes
a real bite out of life.
Hi ya. babe.
Hi. Dad.
Hi. You look great.
Hi. Lisa.
Hi.
It’s good to
see you again.
Hi. Lisa.
Hi.
Doesn‘t she look good?
Oh. you look terrific.
Just great.
Thanks.
Oh.
I have a present for you.
Right.
Yeah.
I’ll--I’ll go get it. Okay?
So.
you‘re getting enough sleep.
and food and everything?
You look just great.
Thanks.
Can you have
lunch with us now?
We‘re gonna have
lunch at the Inn. okay?
Sure.
You got a ride
over there. right?
Yeah. I’m going
with Beth in her car.
You know the way?
Yeah. yeah. of course.
There‘s a return slip.
if it‘s the wrong
size or anything.
Thank you.
See you later. Lisa.
Okay. we‘ll see you later.
Bye-bye.
See you later. girls.
Oh. boy.
does she look great.
You don‘t think she looked
a little depressed?
Who? You mean Lisa?
Yeah. Lisa.
No. no. no. no.
She has a slow metabolism.
That‘s up. She‘s up today.
Maybe you should
have a talk with her.
What‘s the matter
with you people?
I tell you.
the kid is a survivor.
Just a little talk.
It‘ll make her
feel so much better.
Okay.
Do you lock it now or what?
You wanna hang
onto your purse?
No.
Got your purse.
This is...
Did you know Anne
is here this weekend?
Anne is here?
Oh. no.
Are you sure?
Beth told me.
My God.
how did that happen?
Anne‘s grown up.
She can take it.
What makes you think
we can?
Did you know
she was coming?
When I talked to her
Tuesday.
she said she was gonna
work it out with Nick.
I called her when we said
we were coming up here
just so this
wouldn‘t happen.
Well. I don‘t understand.
Nick. you didn‘t tell her
you were coming with Ginny
and she didn‘t tell you?
I don‘t know.
She might have mentioned
she was thinking of it.
She never does
what she says she‘s gonna do.
She‘s unreliable.
I don‘t listen to
her half the time.
That might be
a small problem right there.
You know. I don‘t
wanna talk her down
but she is
unreliable.
I mean.
Nick has made
three appointments
to meet her down
at his lawyer‘s office
and she‘s never
shown up.
She hasn‘t
even called.
Now. wait a minute.
No offense. Ginny.
but 21 years ago
Nick said he would be there
on the other side of
the bed every morning
and for the last six months
he hasn‘t kept his
appointment. either!
Okay. uh. look--look.
let‘s calm down.
It’s not all that bad.
It’s just
a little embarrassing.
I don‘t see what
the big problem is.
We‘re all adults.
We‘ll just say ‘‘Hello.‘‘
and. uh...
Have a nervous
breakdown.
Ginny. I’m sorry.
The--the-- This--
there is a lot of strain
on the situation
and I get
passionate sometimes.
That‘s okay.
I know you‘re just trying
to be fair to everybody.
You‘re the one
I wanted to make cry.
Why do you have to
open up your mouth again?
Danny. it‘s over
and done with. please.
Come on.
Let‘s have a nice
quiet time. just once.
We‘re gonna have...
All right.
let‘s get a move on.
Shh.
Please. not now.
Hey. you okay?
Yeah.
You sure?
I’m okay.
Do you have a reservation
for Callan. please?
You‘re all registered.
Mr. Callan.
I’m all registered?
Mrs. Callan checked
in a few minutes ago.
Everything
all right?
Oh. yeah.
everything‘s terrific.
Do we have
our rooms?
Wait a minute.
Uh. could I see you over here
for a minute. please?
Could I see you over here
What‘s the matter?
As far as I can make out.
Anne has just
checked into our room.
Oh. no. I knew it.
Oh. my God.
Look. we can just
go someplace else.
On Parents‘ Weekend.
everything‘s booked
within 50 miles of here.
Well. then I’ll sleep
in the car.
I could sit up
all night in the diner.
Maybe the earth will just
open up and swallow me.
Hi. everybody.
Hi.
Hi. How are you?
I’m fine.
Oh. that‘s a nice kiss.
This is wonderful.
You look gorgeous.
Thank you.
It’s great
to see you.
Uh. hi.
Did you see Lisa?
No. I haven‘t yet.
Oh. she looks terrific.
She does?
Oh. yeah.
Oh. good. I miss her.
Hi. I’m Ginny.
Oh. this is Ginny Newley.
How do you do? l--
We‘ve spoken on the phone.
I believe.
Yes. l--I think
we have.
Okay. I got that
taken care of.
Oh. hi. Anne. how are you?
Fine. Nick. I’m fine.
How are you?
I’m fine.
Well. now that we all
know we‘re fine.
is there anything else
we ought to talk about?
Jack. don‘t. uh. don‘t try to
get to the heart of things.
just let it lay there.
Why are we all pretending
we‘re not embarrassed?
Why don‘t we just
say how we feel?
I feel. uh. like I wish you
would just sort of shut up.
Okay.
Lisa‘s on her way
over here.
I’m gonna have
lunch with her. okay?
Okay.
I’ll--I’ll have
dinner with her.
Fine.
More fine. good.
That‘s great.
Hmm.
Listen. it‘s lovely to
see you all. It really is.
Okay. goodbye.
Talk to you later. honey.
Take care.
It was very nice
to meet you.
Of course.
Thank you. Miss Newley.
See. what was
wrong with that?
Claudia. come on.
Do you have my room?
Dr. Zimmer?
There won‘t be any more
Zimmers coming in. will there?
Better not be.
Anne? Hold on.
Wait a second. huh?
Anne.
God. that must‘ve been
murder for you in there.
I’ll get used to it.
Shall we talk?
I have a feeling
we should talk.
Well. uh...
Actually I have the feeling
that. um.
you‘re all deserting me.
Deserting you?
Yes.
You had that. uh. party
on Labor Day
and you asked
Nick but not me.
Anne! That‘s because
he was with her.
We couldn‘t invite you both
to the same party.
We would‘ve been
nervous wrecks.
Anne. we love you.
Uh. look. next week why
don‘t we have dinner?
We‘ll--we‘ll go see
a movie. Huh?
Good. I would like that.
You know.
you‘re right. it‘s true.
We‘ve talked to you
on the phone a few times
but in the last
couple of months.
we have let you
drift out of our lives.
Has it been really tough?
Not bad.
Actually. um.
it‘s been pure shit.
But it could be worse.
How do you get
through the day?
I work.
But I tend to. uh.
lose track.
I get on the bus
and I forget where I’m going
and I watch the streets go by
and I just hope to God
that one of them will
remind me what I’m there for.
Oh. it‘s not
as bad as all that.
I’ve been trying to
get out of my rut.
I am thinking
about. uh. uh. going
to Czechoslovakia.
Why?
Because I’ve never wanted
to go to Czechoslovakia.
And it‘s something new.
and I’m trying very hard.
you know. to be less. uh.
what. uh. compulsive.
To be a little bit
more spontaneous.
Last week. I bought a snake.
You bought a snake?
It felt kind of strange
at first. but. uh.
once you get used to him.
he‘s lovely. He‘s lovely.
He‘s a nice pet.
Yeah?
Yeah.
He‘s disgusting to start with
because he eats mice alive.
You‘ve really been through
the wringer. haven‘t you?
Uh. I’m all right.
I really am all right.
In fact. in some ways I think
I’m stronger than ever.
The only thing is that
every time I think about
going to Czechoslovakia
I. uh. I start to cry.
I’ll--I’lI stop by
for Lisa later.
And we‘re gonna
call you Monday
for dinner. okay?
Okay.
Anne?
What?
Will you call me
at the office?
Because I think I can
get an assignment for you.
I love you.
Do me a favor
and don‘t tell Nick
about the snake. all right?
No.
He thinks I’m crazy
as it is.
I’ll tell you what.
To hell with Nick.
Tell him. uh. it‘s
a goddamn boa constrictor.
I don‘t understand him.
How could he do that
to her?
He‘s got a long history
of doing that to her.
He‘s been having affairs
with other women all along.
Dozens!
Oh. you‘re kidding.
How could you not know?
They even slept
at your apartment once.
Where was l?
You gave him your keys
so he could feed your cat
and water your plants
when you went away
for the weekend.
Didn‘t you notice the funny
look on the cat‘s face
when you came home?
That son of a bitch.
He told you all this?
He told me
some of it.
Some of it came out
when he was under gas.
I don‘t know.
Jeez!
I’ve lost all my illusions
about that guy.
Every time I think about him
I get angry and depressed.
I just can‘t
believe that of him.
Ah. maybe it‘s this
time of the year.
Always hated autumn.
Everybody says
it‘s so beautiful
but for me it‘s just--just
another time of death.
I always get psoriasis
in autumn.
Danny. believe me.
you‘re not gonna die
from psoriasis.
What‘s that
supposed to mean?
I’m just trying
to comfort you.
Don‘t get paranoid.
How come everyone
thinks I’m paranoid?
You discuss this
behind my back. don‘t you?
Danny. relax. would you?
Come on. come on.
I’m sorry.
lf you could just realize
what a terrific person you are
you wouldn‘t think
everybody was out to get you.
Don‘t try to
analyze me. okay?
First.
I’m not your patient.
Second.
you‘re not a doctor.
I’m just trying to help.
You‘re not helping.
you‘re patronizing me.
So cut it out. okay?
Okay. Okay.
Don‘t--don‘t get
so overwrought.
What can I do for you?
First of all.
you can take your arm
off my shoulder
and stick it
up your ass.
Look. sweetheart.
I know what
you‘re going through.
My parents separated
when I was a kid. too.
I hated them for it.
I promised myself
that when I grew up
I’d remember what it was like
and never do that
to one of mine.
Trouble is. now I see
it from the other side.
But you‘ve very mature
for your age.
You‘re resilient.
This will pass
and in no time you‘ll be
singing and laughing.
Believe me.
you‘re gonna be laughing.
Look. your entire world
doesn‘t revolve around me.
You‘ve got your
own life to live.
You‘ve made some friends
at your dorm. right?
Not really.
Most of the people
I’ve met here
have a peculiar idea
of a good time.
Like what?
They get drunk
and piss off the balconies.
What about the girls?
I’m talking about the girls.
You‘re kidding me. right?
I’m kidding you?
You think it‘s a joke
to have to walk home
on a clear night
with an umbrella?
Haven‘t you got
any friends here?
They don‘t interest me.
Oh. come on.
There must be somebody.
Hey!
What about that
kid from. uh. Ohio?
Yeah. Marilyn Oupenski.
Yeah.
She was great.
She was a lot like me.
A lot like me.
Her parents made her go home.
Why?
She tried to swallow
a bottle of pills.
Why didn‘t you tell me?
What for?
Lisa. if the one person
you identify with
in this place
happens to swallow
a bottle of pills
don‘t you think
I’d be mildly interested?
You keep making
all these decisions
that affect my life
without asking me.
That doesn‘t seem
to bother you.
You know what this is?
This is emotional blackmail.
I’m trying to appeal
to your sense of intelligence
and maturity
you sit there like
the Bride of Frankenstein
talking about suicide.
Come on. sweetheart.
You‘re not as morose as
all that and you know it.
You got a great big smile
down there somewhere
and you just won‘t let it out.
Come on. give in.
Let‘s have a nice big smile.
I know you got one
in there.
I can see it sitting there.
dying to come out.
Here it comes.
I can see it curling up
at the corner of your mouth.
Come on. here it comes.
Here comes the smile.
Smile. Goddamn it!
All right. don‘t.
I think you should
apologize to her.
For what?
I got excited.
I spoke my mind
I said I was sorry
and it‘s over and done with.
I don‘t understand
how you can hurt someone
as guileless
and vulnerable as Ginny.
She sure took on
a lot of mystical qualities
once you saw her
swimming naked.
How can you say that?
I just say what I think.
Mmm-hmm.
Well.
maybe that‘s the problem.
Why do you always have to say
what you think?
You think your thoughts
should just fall down
from your brain
onto your tongue
like a gumball machine!
Danny. I am not gonna
start watching what I think
or what I feel!
I am Italian!
I know you‘re Italian!
I don‘t wanna hear any more
how you‘re Italian!
Wait. Wait. here.
Wait.
Just wait. wait. wait.
Hello out there!
This woman is Italian!
All right!
You no longer
have to announce
your ethnic origin
in this state!
Everybody in Connecticut
knows you‘re Italian!
And when we cross the border.
I’ll take out an ad
in the New York Times.
What‘s with him?
I don‘t know.
What‘s with you?
I’m sorry. I just feel
very let down by you.
Why? What have l
done to you?
What is your idea of a close
intimate friendship?
What does that mean to you?
I don‘t understand.
I’ve hurt you in some way?
I happen to know you betrayed
your wife dozens of times.
lf I did. that‘s what
I did to her.
What did I do to you?
You didn‘t tell
either of us.
Hey. wait a minute.
Let‘s take you
one at a time.
You can understand
my not telling her. right?
I can‘t understand you
saying on the one hand
that you could
tell me anything.
And on the other hand
not telling me a goddamn thing
except what suits you.
I feel as betrayed
as she does.
Jack. all I’ve ever
gotten from you
is judgment and disapproval.
You expect me to come
and tell you
every time I’ve had an affair
with a hatcheck girl?
That‘s who you were
having affairs with?
Hatcheck girls?
No!
They were all intelligent.
worthy women.
The top in their field.
I can‘t tell you their names
but two of them were
Margaret Thatcher
and Indira Gandhi.
When you wanna talk
intelligently. I’ll talk.
Otherwise. forget it.
When did you
get this?
Couple of weeks ago.
Do you have any
good friends here?
Mmm-hmm.
I like this.
Who are your friends?
People.
Good.
What about Lisa?
Forget it.
When you were
in high school
you were on the phone
with her almost every night.
Not anymore.
What‘s the problem?
She‘s such a bitch
sometimes!
Sh-she just gets...
I don‘t know.
She says
she‘ll meet me someplace
and she doesn‘t show up.
Sometimes she‘ll just
sit there for an hour
without talking.
It’s like she‘s
trying to test me
and see how much
shit I’ll take.
She probably is.
I hate it!
Hey. babe. come here.
What if. uh.
what if you just accepted her
for what she is. huh?
I do.
Trouble is. what she is.
is a bitch.
Oh.
When she acts like that.
maybe you--
maybe you could
just laugh at her.
You know. like she was
a character in a story.
Mom. that‘s impossible.
Why?
Because it is. Forget it.
Change the subject.
Okay.
What other friends
do you have?
Oh. stop it! Be quiet!
Time to stop talking now!
I’m closing off your breath!
Here we go!
This is so good.
Mmm. I hope
this is homemade.
Just look at all
those calories.
Do you want
a bite?
Oh. God. I got
too much in my mouth.
Thank you.
You are
such a slob.
Okay.
That‘s $23 from Nick
$24.50 from Jack
and $16 from me
But let‘s split it
three ways.
Then why tell us
what everybody spent?
Because if there‘s
a discrepancy
in anyone‘s share
it will benefit
everyone to know about it.
How can I know
what my share was unless
I compulsively added up
my bill the whole time
I was eating?
Oh.
now I’m compulsive.
10 minutes ago.
I was paranoid.
Give me the check.
I’ll pay it.
I’m sorry. I’m not a member of
the Million Dollar Roundtable.
You want the check?
Here. you got it.
Come on.
you‘re a successful dentist.
That‘s right.
And this is a checkup
and cleaning.
Takes me a long time
to scrape. polish.
and poke to make this.
Hey. Danny. calm down.
Please don‘t tell
me to calm down.
This is the second time today
somebody‘s told me
to calm down.
I’m sorry.
it‘s only my first.
lf he wants to keep the books.
let him keep them.
I don‘t want to
keep the books.
I’ll pay the check.
Again. I am not upset.
Don‘t get upset.
I told you.
I was not upset.
Here. take the check.
I don‘t want the check.
I’m not upset.
Don‘t get him upset.
will you?
I didn‘t get him upset!
You got him upset.
I told you.
I’m not upset.
This is ridiculous.
Why do you...
Oh. God.
It really took off
a lot of skin.
What are you doing?
I’ve been out in the cold
all day and my skin is dry.
I wonder if they have
any ice down the hall.
Gee. I don‘t know.
Why don‘t you go see?
Are you mad at me?
You got it.
You picked a hell of
a time to get irrational.
Oh. I’m not irrational.
Rational people get angry!
irrational people
pretend they don‘t.
Okay.
just stop it right there!
I have a very bad temper!
Don‘t make me use it!
Use it.
I don‘t happen to think
there‘s anything
wrong with anger.
I’m going to be
very calm about this.
Why do you resent me?
Because when you fight
you get calm.
You don‘t like that?
It drives me nuts.
I also don‘t
like having to guess
your every need
when you don‘t give
a damn about mine.
I don‘t like that a lot!
What needs do you have
that I don‘t give
a damn about?
Don‘t you ever feel
like going someplace
alone with me?
You want to take
a vacation without them?
I have this perverse desire
to be married to
one person at a time.
I don‘t know. it excites me!
I thought--I thought
you liked them.
I adore them.
but it‘s getting so
I can‘t breathe!
Anne doesn‘t know
how lucky she is to be out!
You know.
Danny probably has
his ear pressed
to that door listening
to everything.
Danny dear.
please don‘t be offended.
You know how fond I am of you
but I think your
Mercedes sucks.
You the one who
organizes these trips.
And I hate it.
Doesn‘t it ever occur
to you that sometimes
I’d like to be the one
with the sore knee?
No.
You handle everything
like the most efficient people
I know!
Uh. nobody can do
what you do.
My God. you‘re perfect.
How dare you
call me that?
How dare
I call you perfect?
Yes.
Yes. isn‘t that
what I heard?
What‘s wrong with perfect?
How can you get upset?
Because when I’m perfect.
I cease to exist!
Y-you don‘t have to
hug me when--when I’m low
or cheer me up with
a bunch of $2 daffodils.
I don‘t surprise
you with daffodils?
You know I do.
When you feel like it!
When it makes you feel good.
but not when I need them!
Goddamn it!
I’m standing here bleeding!
Blood is running down my leg
and we‘re talking
about daffodils!
Because I also resent you
for hurting yourself.
Oh. oh. oh.
And that‘s not irrational.
huh?
You think I like to see
you so jealous of Nick
that you have to tackle him?
You think that
makes me feel good?
We should get to
the heart of this.
The heart of this
is that you wish you had
some blonde nymph
adoring you like he does.
So go on! Go find one!
Christ. how long you going
to hang on to these fantasies?
The reality is you‘re married
to a middle-aged woman
with a good sense of humor
and dry skin!
And if you don‘t like it
then go find yourself a nymph.
Just do me the courtesy
of telling me.
In other words.
and I mean this
in the most loving way.
shit.
or get off the pot!
Katherine.
I’m sorry to say this.
What? Say it!
You ‘re making me furious.
You‘re furious now?
I’m enraged.
How can you tell?
I can‘t see the difference!
Maybe you could learn
to stamp your
foot as a signal.
Look. try this!
Will you shut up?
You know how
that voice carries?
When you‘re mad at me.
I expect to see it.
I don‘t want to read about it
two years from now
in your goddamn diary!
You know how our good times
together come in waves?
Right now I would say
we were in a very deep trough.
Hi. guys.
How you doing?
Great.
God. is Nick sore.
Poor guy.
He just loves
to be babied.
Think that‘s enough?
- Well. see you tomorrow.
- Hurry up!
I’m coming! Bye.
Good night.
Jack! What do you say?
Come on!
Oh. shit!
Wait right
out there.
The doctor wants
us to wait outside.
He really amazes me.
We‘ll see you
in five minutes.
You all right. babe?
I’ll see you around.
What‘s this? Crutches!
Crutches are havoc.
What‘s that?
What?
That. The limping stuff?
What is it?
I got a blister.
Excuse me.
Doctor?
Ginny. I don‘t--
Could you look at
his leg. too. please?
Sure. After
we‘re finished here.
You can hop up
on the table.
There‘s nothing
wrong with me!
You landed awful hard
once. I saw you.
Nick. I saw it. too.
- We saw it!
- I saw that. too.
All right. All right.
All right.
You want to take an X-ray
of my foot. go ahead.
Take my picture.
Which one?
I’ll tell you the funniest
sight in the world was.
It was you
going on that jump.
You looked like
a dying turkey.
The arms and
the legs started to go.
I thought I would die!
Listen. the thing to
do is take the boat
from Southampton
when you‘re traveling.
Oh. yeah?
And take...
It’s climbing
a quarter of a degree an hour.
I’m not going out
in that cold anymore.
That‘s exactly half of us
felled by disaster
on our first day.
So what do you suppose
we should do now?
How about if we talk?
Talk?
Ever since we saw
the kids up at school.
we‘ve been walking on eggs.
I’m gonna get coffee.
What do you mean?
We have dinner.
we talk about the kids.
we talk about the news
but we--we don‘t really talk.
About what?
About us.
You‘re gonna jump over me
but I think we should
clear the air.
Oh. no!
Please. some of us
aren‘t feeling too well.
do you mind?
We should sit down for a while
and hash this thing out.
I’d rather have
my teeth drilled.
What do you want to open up
a big can of worms for?
Because I thought it
was worth it. Forget it.
All right!
Okay. that‘s it.
Did you see this?
I saw it.
Anne‘s got
pictures in it.
Yeah.
She‘s making friends.
she‘s working.
she‘s never been better.
And you‘ll notice.
these are pictures
of people.
not kumquats.
I saw it.
Hey. guys.
why don‘t we
have some fun?
You know that roadhouse.
about 15 miles from here?
Yeah?
They‘re going to have
music tonight. right?
I mean. we can‘t all dance
but we could sit
and have a beer.
listen to the music.
Here we go.
I’d like to get out of here.
I think that‘s
a swell idea.
I’m not against
having a good time.
Let‘s have fun.
Don‘t hurt yourself laughing.
When are you
going to forgive me
for marrying Ginny. ever?
You can do anything you want.
Oh. thanks.
Where‘s the warmth
you‘re always talking about?
You‘re as cold
as that frozen lake.
I adore Ginny. I have nothing
but the deepest affection
for both of you.
But you won‘t
forgive me?
Is this man crazy
or what?
No. he‘s not crazy.
You want us to
level with one another?
The truth is
we‘re all mad at you.
We love Ginny but we‘re upset
because Anne isn‘t here.
Maybe they‘re mad.
but I’m not.
Well. good.
As long as
we‘re all honest and open.
Is this the fun part?
Are we having fun yet?
Ow!
Damn it!
What can I get you. folks?
Beer for me.
And I’ll have a J&B
on the rocks. too.
Great band.
You know. I always
wondered what happened
to the old Glen Miller
arrangement.
So you don‘t think
I’m honest. huh?
Okay. Jack. forget it.
I’m sorry I said it.
No. say
what you think.
Do you really
want me to?
Yeah.
Well.
I think sometimes
you are a little cold.
There‘s a little part
of you always. uh.
that hangs back
and judges.
You always want to get
to the bottom of things
but only so long as you
can make the rules.
Mmm-hmm. I see.
That‘s all right.
it‘s human.
Okay. fine. I’m human.
I don‘t mind being human.
As long as we realize
you‘re human. too.
Yeah. I’m human.
As long as
we realize that
it‘s also human to be
the world‘s foremost authority
on everything
from the roast beef
to the nervous system
of the newt.
To be so completely obsessed
with your own body
that you take
your temperature
at the dinner table!
Look. I think maybe
you better just cool it.
No. it‘s all right.
don‘t worry.
You‘re going
a little too far.
No. it‘s all right.
Let me tell you something.
Jack.
I’m 10 years
older than you. right?
All right. I just hope
that when you get to be my age
you don‘t smell
the foul breath of death
and disintegration
hanging over your shoulder
the way I find it
hanging over mine.
I mean.
I go to sleep at night
on an ache so bad
that it simply
will not go away.
I wake up in the middle
of the night sweating
hearing my own bones decaying.
I have shifted into
a state of entropy
that‘s progressing
geometrically.
You see. ‘‘entropy.‘‘
‘‘progressing geometrically.‘‘
Y-you talk like
a bad textbook.
Why don‘t you
just speak English?
Goddamn it! I just told you
my deepest fear!
Why can‘t you
listen to what I’m saying
instead of how I’m saying it?
I mean. do you have
any idea. any idea.
what it is to be
afraid of death?
I can‘t eat my
bowl of cereal anymore
because I have
an irrational fear of milk.
I stand there in hallways...
I stand there in hallways
afraid to press
strange elevator buttons.
I almost threw away
my jockey shorts because
I have this fear of elastic.
Don‘t laugh at him.
Go on. go on. what?
Laugh. good.
I’m a fool. right?
No. Danny.
I’m a collection
of eccentricities.
You think because I’m quirky.
I don‘t hurt?
No.
Well. you have it wrong.
I’m quirky because I hurt.
Oh. Danny. I’m sorry.
All right.
Come on.
Are you really
afraid of your underwear?
I’m dying. she‘s laughing.
We‘re not laughing. Danny.
Honest.
We are.
Forget it. Forget it.
Let‘s listen to the music.
No. it‘s all right.
Forget it.
Okay. come on.
Danny. let‘s dance.
Come on.
No. thanks. No.
I don‘t want to dance.
Danny!
Dance.
Come on.
Go head. dance.
Go on. dance.
Go boogie.
I’m having one
hell of a time.
All right!
Strangers in the night
Fire.
I’m dying for some coffee.
Oh. get us
some coffee.
Coffee! Hello!
Anybody home? Coffee!
Come on. give us
a little smile. Come on.
Coffee!
That‘s nice.
You trying to
get us thrown out?
There‘s nobody here.
I bet we‘re the only
people in this building.
Throw me the newspaper.
Want some coffee?
Who wants coffee?
You want coffee?
Danny wants coffee.
Danny needs
some coffee.
What? What?
Oh. God.
I think Danny‘s upset.
Oh. he‘ll be all right.
We‘ve been joking
around all night
and he hasn‘t joined in.
I think he‘s hurt.
I think maybe we owe
him an apology.
What. because
I laughed at him?
Well. yeah.
Look. Ginny.
when people have been
friends as long as we have
it‘s not
such a terrible thing
to kid somebody
out of a depression.
So don‘t get upset
about what you
don‘t understand.
I’ve just about
had it with you people.
What‘s the matter?
I’ll tell you what‘s
the matter. I’m mad.
Ginny?
I fall in love
with this man.
and all of a sudden.
in addition to him
I’ve got four
constant companions!
I have to work out
a new relationship
with somebody who
is going through
the worst period of his life.
only I can‘t do it alone
I’ve got to do it in
front of four other people!
And it‘s not as if
my privacy was invaded.
you all have let me
know every single day
that I have been
intruding on your territory!
Let me tell you something.
As far as I’m concerned
you‘re all demanding
and unforgiving.
every single one of you.
Everybody is sweet
and warm and simple
but everybody ignores me.
I’m like a leper.
I’m--I’m a blank spot
where Anne used to be.
I’m going to go
take a run in the snow.
I hope she‘ll be
all right out there.
Wish I hadn‘t
said that.
What happened?
Ginny! Ginny!
I’m going after her!
Nick!
You got a broken ankle.
She might fall
down in the dark.
So what? She fell down
in the daylight.
she didn‘t hurt herself.
In the dark
she might hurt herself.
Nick. she‘ll be okay.
Rest your foot.
I’m not going to run the risk
of her falling down out there.
Why not?
Because she‘s pregnant.
Because she‘s pregnant?
Watch this.
Here‘s some real
heartwarming acceptance.
You‘re 43 years old.
you‘re going to
start having babies?
I don‘t believe this.
I have to check
everything with you?
As a matter of fact.
I told you I wanted
to start a new family.
With babies?
With what? Airedales?
Look. do what you want.
Oh. thanks very much.
I really appreciate that.
Fellows. come on back inside.
It’s freezing out here.
Come on. you can‘t go
after her like that.
Come on.
Nick. please! Come on.
It’s starting to get bright.
Where the hell is she?
You know.
when she ran out of here
I started to think of
all the friends
we‘ve had over the years
who‘ve jogged
out of our lives.
All the ones who‘ve. uh.
who‘ve been inconvenient
to stay friendly with
and it scares me.
They move to another state
or they‘ve gotten a divorce
or else we‘ve just gotten
friendly enough with them
to realize they‘re a kind of
a pain in the ass
and pretty soon we
never see them again.
I’ll tell you something.
Jack.
I don‘t want to
be one of two people
alone in the world
at the end of my life.
I want to have friends.
When I get old
I’d like you all
to still be there.
Okay?
Why can‘t we
just let them be?
In other words.
I’m the problem?
I have to have
everything my way.
I’m unforgiving and cold
and judgmental. right?
Right.
We‘re talking about me?
Jack. you know
those probing questions
you ask all the time?
You‘re the only
one who answers them.
Everybody dances to your tune!
That makes me
sound like a tyrant.
Well. so what?
I am not a tyrant.
Goddamn it!
No matter what crap
I get from people.
all I ever give
back is a smile.
I never give
a response that‘s anything
but fair and rational
and cheerful!
Be careful!
Why don‘t you
let your anger out
once in a while?
You want anger?
There! How‘s that?
Is that angry enough for you?
How about that?
Now is that angry enough?
Here. how about this?
What the hell you doing?
You know what
I expect from you.
I expect closeness
and warmth
and unconditional acceptance.
And all I get from you
is secretiveness
and neurosis and a lot of...
Goddamn it!
Jesus Christ!
Put it down!
I’m not paying for this!
This is your expense!
Yeah. bet your life!
All right. stop that!
Is that angry
enough for you. huh?
Stop that!
All right. stop it!
Stop it! That‘s enough!
That‘s all. stop it!
Come on! Settle down!
Come here. Sit down.
Shh. Shh.
I wonder what other people do
on their vacations?
Oh. God. I’m sorry.
Jesus. look what I did.
So you freaked out a little.
So what?
I lost complete
control of myself.
Jack. nobody cares.
Hey.
What?
You‘re not the best
little boy in the world.
I hate to break this to you.
but you‘re not
the worst little boy. either.
You know.
sometimes when you say
things like that
I really hate you.
Thank you.
You know.
sometimes I hate you.
Nick. what are you doing?
I got to go find her.
Wait a minute.
You stay.
I’ll go find her.
No. I can do it.
Nick. look. please.
I want to.
Let me go. please.
Thanks. but I can do it.
No. I’ll do it.
No. I’ll do it!
You sit down
and wait for me.
I’ll be right back!
Will you get out of my way?
Jack! Don‘t be ridiculous!
He‘s got a broken ankle!
You‘ve got a torn ligament.
You guys wouldn‘t get
10 feet in that snow.
I’d get farther
than he can.
than both of you.
What do you guys think
a pregnant woman is?
An invalid?
I’ll be back
in two minutes.
Better start
fixing up this place.
That moose is going
to cost a fortune.
Ginny! Don‘t move.
I’ll be right there!
Stay right there!
Oh!
Hey. wait! Help me!
Help me!
Run to the lodge!
Go get help!
I can‘t get out!
Run! Go faster. faster!
Help! Help!
Are you all right?
Danny went through the ice
and he can‘t get out!
Jack!
Please help.
Help! Help!
Quick!
Jack. don‘t go too far out!
Okay. Danny!
Lift up your arms!
This side.
Wait a minute.
Ready here!
Get your arm around that!
Get it under your elbow!
God damn it.
lift your arm up!
Danny. get it around!
Okay. hold onto the rope.
I got
the blanket.
Okay. go!
Back it up.
Okay. go back.
Go ahead.
Go back slowly.
Easy! Easy! Easy!
Pull the rope!
Easy.
That‘s it. Danny.
Go on. keep going!
Keep going!
All right. hold it!
Danny!
Danny?
How is he?
Danny!
Don‘t say that!
Danny?
Breathe. honey!
Little more!
Rub--rub his legs.
Come on.
Come on. sweetheart.
Thank God!
Danny. are you all right?
Are you all right.
honey?
You almost drowned.
Keep covered up.
Thanks. I’m okay.
I’m okay. Thank you.
I almost died. and thank you.
Get him up!
Oh. my God! My Mercedes!
How could you drive
my Mercedes on thin ice?
Oh!
Danny. come on. get up.
Come on.
Oh. God!
Get off
the blanket.
It was brand new!
In three years.
I could have gotten
twice what I paid for it!
Danny. Danny. we‘ll get
someone to fish it out
for you.
What the hell am I going to do
with a rusty Mercedes?
It’s gone!
It’s gone.
It sank like a stone.
Danny!
You are alive.
You have your life.
You have us and we love you.
so shut up!
Come on. Dan.
Go in. You‘re going to
freeze to death.
Get into
the lodge and get warm.
Sorry.
I just got a little crazy.
I’m sorry.
What do I care about the car.
It’s you I care about.
Let‘s go! Come on!
To hell with the car.
thank you.
Oh. my God.
you sank my car!
Get back.
Get back to the lodge
and shut up!
All right. I’m okay.
To hell with the car.
It’s you I love.
Come on. let‘s go.
Why‘d you have to
take it on the ice?
Will you shut up.
for Christ‘s sake!
We just saved
your goddamn life!
What were you trying to
rescue me for. anyway?
I was fine!
I’m sick of this
macho bullshit!
No more stunts. okay?
Okay. yeah.
You guys really
piss me off. you know that?
Yeah. we heard you.
It’s gone.
I’ll never see it again.
Please. Danny.
I say we come back
next winter.
Will you listen to me.
Follow this...