I'd like another shot
at that prize money.
Okay for next Sunday?
No, Jim. It ain't okay.
- Now, look, Bice, I know...
- No, you look.
All of my drivers are 18, 19.
You're too old for
these kid snorts.
You're liable to
get hurt in there.
You used to be a big track driver.
Ain't you got no pride?
I ran out of pride when
I ran out of cars.
Jim, you gotta look at yourself.
Okay, you start out all right.
You win a couple of tracks,
you think you're on your way.
But it didn't work out, did it?
Much obliged.
You need any money?
Nope.
Hey...
What do you do with this stuff?
It's for a friend.
Hey, how'd it go?
Okay.
- I brought you something.
- Oh, thanks.
Oh, the poor thing.
I'll find a good spot for it.
You got hurt again.
- So?
- One of these days,
you're gonna get
wiped out entirely.
Why you gotta be a driver?
Maybe that's not
your thing, racing.
How about all those car
agencies down on Van Ness?
I bet that a top
mechanic there gets
a lot of good bread laid on him.
What is the matter with everybody?
Can't you understand?
I'm not a mechanic.
I'm a driver.
I know just how you feel, Jim.
Hey, I used to think that I was
happy painting flower seeds.
Then one day, inside me, there
was this little voice, says,
"Tennessee Steinmetz."
I said, "What?"
It said, "You ain't
happy." Well, I...
Tennessee, would you
tell me something?
Why is it the only thing we ever
have in this house is parrot food?
I mean, we don't have a parrot.
Hey, eat that. That's good.
That's pressed kelp.
That aerates your liver.
Then this voice inside of
me continued as follows...
"This is nowhere. You
gotta make a new scene.
"You gotta change your bag."
That's when I split.
I went to Tibet, to a mountaintop
with swamis and monks.
I discovered my real self.
It was wonderful.
I don't have to go to Tibet.
I know who I am.
I know what I want.
Hey, there are dirt track races at
a carnival near
Bakersfield this week.
If I can get over there, I can
pick up a couple of bucks.
Okay to use your wheels?
Yeah, okay, but I'm
afraid you're gonna have
a little trouble
getting it started.
Where's the beast?
You didn't cut up the Edsel?
Came over me all of a sudden.
It was the only
decent thing to do.
Believe me, Jim. It'll
be happier up there.
Are you all right? Are you dizzy?
Oh, no. Well, there's a slight
racking pain in my head.
Oh, I think you'd better sit down.
I'm really terribly sorry.
Well, it's not your fault.
I didn't mean to startle you.
Looks like you've been running
into all sorts of things lately.
Yeah. Oh, oh, this
is just a little...
Oh, lady.
Oh, really, sir.
Excuse me.
Over 400 cubes...
Dual quads, all synchro
box, zero to 60 under five.
All right, Miss Bennett, I'll
see to this gentleman myself.
May I be of service, sir?
I see that you're a person
who appreciates fine things.
You're no doubt aware that this is
the celebrated Thorndyke special.
And allow me to say, sir,
that I think this car
would suit you very well.
Yes. Yes, it would.
Yes, may I offer you a glass
of sherry and a biscuit?
Go right ahead.
I take it that the
question of price
does not greatly concern a
gentleman like yourself.
Oh, I wouldn't haggle,
if that's what you mean.
What price range did
you have in mind?
About $75.
$75?
I could go 80 in a pinch.
What do you have in the way of
cheap, honest transportation?
Cheap, honest transportation.
I will bid you good day, sir.
Good day.
Hey.
Havershaw.
Now, where did this come from?
Mr. Thorndyke, yes, sir?
What is this thing doing
in my showroom, may I ask?
Oh, I believe Miss Bennett may
know something about this.
Yes, you remember when Mrs. Van
Luit purchased her new Bentley?
Well, she also
requested us to buy a
small used car for
her upstairs maid.
Then why isn't her upstairs
maid in her blasted vehicle?
The car was returned this
morning, Mr. Thorndyke.
She was having some kind
of difficulty with it.
- Get it out of here.
- Yes, sir.
What's that for?
I beg your pardon?
Why don't you let the
little car alone?
Are you presuming to tell me what
to do in my own establishment?
Okay, I'm outta line.
It just bugs me to see somebody
abusing a decent
piece of machinery.
Fascinating.
Well, now that we've had the
benefit of your point of view,
shall we regard our
relationship as terminated?
Havershaw.
Get this eyesore out
of my showroom.
And if ever I find it here again,
someone is going to find himself
in a great deal of trouble.
Yes, sir. Watch your
knees there, boys.
Here we go.
Sorry. None of my business, is it?
Perfectly all right.
Goodbye.
Oh, goodbye.
Good morning.
Good morning. What do you want?
Police.
Right. What do you want?
Forgive me for pointing, but have
you ever seen that car before?
No. No, I haven't.
Hey, he's a cute little fella.
Hey, wait a minute.
I think I saw that car
at an agency yesterday.
Now permit me to inform
you of the following.
First, say nothing that would
jeopardise your
constitutional rights.
Second, the minute
that you get downtown,
I would advise that you
get a good lawyer.
Shall we go?
Go? What for?
On suspicion of grand theft.
Look, now, wait a minute. There's
something cock-eyed about this.
How did that little car get here?
I share your curiosity.
Shall we go?
I'll do it. Okay.
I'll do it, but I
just want to go on
record. I have seen
some crummy stunts
in my time used to sell cars,
but this beats everything.
To plant this bug in the
possession of an innocent man
and then to accuse
me of stealing it.
How dare you, sir.
Are you suggesting that I
would stoop to such tactics?
That's exactly what
I'm suggesting.
In the first place,
it might interest you
to know that under
normal circumstances,
I would never sell
a car to someone
with whom I'm not, well, shall
we say, socially compatible.
Socially compatible?
Please, please, let's not
go through that again.
I think we've worked
it out very well.
Mr. Douglas needs a car, and
for a very low amount down,
and the usual monthly payments,
the car will become his.
Very well, even though
my personal inclination
is to have Mr. Douglas
tapped into jail,
and this four-wheel contrivance
dropped into the bay.
I think Mr. Thorndyke
is being very fair.
Fair? It's not fair.
I'm being muscled.
I just want you to
know that I know
I know it, and I don't like it.
I'll draw up the papers. Would
you come with me, please?
Then get Mr. Douglas
and his acquisition
out of here before
I lose my temper.
What the...
What's the matter? You
from LA or something?
Fine. I thought we'd run over
to that new restaurant...
Have you gone mad?
Okay, what's the joke?
What do you mean?
I don't know how you rigged it,
but I'm sure that
car's a real cutup
when a convention comes to town.
If I wanted a trick
car, I would've
bought one in a joke shop.
Allow me to say that I
haven't the slightest idea
what you're talking about.
You come blithering up in
that beastly little car,
and assault my
personal Rolls-Royce.
I brought it back.
I want my money,
I want the papers I signed, and
then I'll get out of here,
and you two clowns can
have your little laugh.
Mr. Douglas, if there is
anything wrong with the car,
would you be good enough
to tell me what it is?
There's nothing essentially
wrong with the car.
It's just that it wants to go one
way, and I'd like to go the other.
Whatever it is, none
of it is covered
in our gilt-edged guarantee.
Oh, I'm sure of that.
If you examine paragraph 12...
Excuse me, Mr. Thorndyke,
but if I sold this
gentleman the car,
I feel a certain responsibility.
Do you mind if I try it?
Miss Bennett.
Our dinner engagement.
I won't be a minute.
Seems to be acting all right now.
Sometimes new car owners have a
tendency to exaggerate
their problems.
We get that all the time.
Believe me, when I was in
this car alone, it was...
Just treat it gently at first.
It really is quite a
fine little automobile.
Have you had much
experience with cars?
Look, lady, by profession,
I'm a racing driver.
Oh, that Jim Douglas.
What do you mean,
"That Jim Douglas"?
Let's see. Two years ago at
Laguna Seca, you spun out,
and hung a beautiful Buick
Special on the back fence.
At Willow Springs... Was it
a year ago last February?
You sprayed a Lotus
all over the infield.
How do you know all that?
I have trouble with names and
faces, but I never forget a car.
I like good machinery.
Now, why don't you give this
little car a fair chance?
You bought it. Enjoy it.
You can drive me back now.
How about it, Dad?
Want to give that
doodlebug a workout?
I'll go easy on you.
Be serious, will you?
Did you see this thing take off?
One of your showboat
tricks, Mr. Douglas?
I tell you, I had
nothing to do with it.
Hey, we were turning.
Out of sight, man.
I wouldn't have believed it.
Groovy, Pop. Groovy.
Well, as long as the customer
finally seems pleased,
I'll just step out and
find myself a taxi.
Will you stop the car, please?
I'm trying. Look.
It's just like I told you.
This thing's starting
to act up again.
How very odd. When I was driving,
there was no problem whatsoever.
I can't seem to do
anything with it.
Mr. Douglas, I'm
asking you nicely to
pull over to that
kerb and let me out.
Look, I'm sorry about
your date. I really am.
I didn't want you to miss
your dinner engagement.
What's the rush, tiger?
We got all night.
Goodbye, Mr. Douglas.
Here, I'll help you.
I can get out, thank you.
What'll it be, chief?
Oh, hey, look, we have
a little problem here.
Would you mind helping the young
lady get her car door open?
Look, I'm busy.
And furthermore, I
ain't no mechanic.
All I do here is sell food,
and that ain't too good.
You want something, or don't you?
- Help.
- Two hamburgers and a coffee.
Help.
Can you help me, please?
Help. I'm a prisoner.
I can't get out.
We all prisoners, chickie baby.
We all locked in.
A couple of weirdos, Guinevere.
What... Wait a minute, now.
Hold it, hold it.
Let me open the door.
Hey, knock it off, will you, sis?
I ain't saying this is the
classiest joint in town,
but we gotta draw
the line somewhere.
Come on, back in your seat.
Why don't you go up
to Seabreeze Point?
Fuzz don't bother
you much up there.
Thanks.
I wish there was some way I could
make up for those hamburgers.
Mr. Douglas, please
don't go on about it.
I'm quite sure that
if I were driving,
none of these things
would've happened.
It's all yours.
Now I think you'll
see what's what.
This is very embarrassing.
Yes, it is.
I would've preferred knowing
you a little longer first.
Just a minute.
You don't for one solitary instant
dare to think that I drove
you here on purpose?
Oh, don't try to explain.
The point is, you brought me here.
I did not bring you here.
It's this nasty little car.
But you said yourself earlier,
it's a very nice little car.
And as you said before, it does
have some peculiar traits,
and I agree with you completely.
As a matter of fact,
bring it in tomorrow,
and I'll find a
replacement for you.
I don't want the car replaced.
As a matter of fact, I'm
beginning to like it.
Oh.
Don't panic, don't panic.
There must be some place
I can call a taxi.
Hey.
You know, for a moment there, I
thought you weren't going to stop.
What's the matter now?
Hey, look, this is ridiculous.
Let's get back in the car, huh?
Hold it. Hold it, everybody.
Just a moment, please.
Something the matter?
Is this man bothering you?
No, not exactly.
It's okay, we're together.
Is that your car?
My...
Well, yes. Yes it is.
Okay, then. Move along.
- Hey, bud.
- Yeah?
Not too smart wandering
around the park at night.
Right.
I'll drive.
She'll drive.
I should've given you a citation.
You ought to have enough sense
to put your brakes on while
your car is stopped.
Well, then if everything that
you say about this car is true,
it's already starting to happen.
What's starting to happen?
Us human beings.
We had a chance to make
something out of this world.
We blew it. Okay.
Another kind of a civilisation
is gonna take a turn.
Give me an 11 mil wrench, will ya?
I'm sitting up on top of
this mountain, right?
Right.
I'm surrounded by these gurus
and swamis and monks, right?
- Right.
- I'm looking at my stomach,
I'm knocking back a
little rice wine.
Got some contemplation going.
I see things like they are.
I could have told you
all this was coming.
What's coming?
Jim, it's happening
right under our noses,
and we can't see it.
We take machines, and we
stuff them with information,
until they're smarter than we are.
Take a car.
Most guys spread more love and
time and money on a car in a week
than they do on their
wife and kids in a year.
Pretty soon, you know what?
The machine starts to
think it is somebody.
I'm not saying that a mechanical
thing, it can't be a friend.
Like, when I was broke one summer,
there was this giant claw machine
in the Sutro Amusement Park.
And it would grab
cameras and watches,
and drop them down a hole to me.
And I would hawk
them and buy lunch.
- You follow me?
- Yeah, yeah.
I think you were up on
that mountaintop too long.
Contrariwise, the traffic light
down the street hates my guts.
I don't know why, but
in the last six weeks,
I haven't caught anything
but a stop signal.
And it makes me wait six seconds
longer than anybody
else. I timed it.
There's things like that happen
to lots of other people, too.
But the other people, they
don't tell no other people,
because the other
people would say,
Tennessee,
that traffic light is a
lot of nuts and bolts.
This little car, lot
of nuts and bolts.
Everything explains itself
one way or the other.
You're not listening to me.
Don't lose your grip, old buddy.
This little car didn't
do one thing tonight
that can't be explained in
terms of short circuits,
sprung doors, grabbing
steering, worn knuckles...
Maybe some advertising gimmick.
I'll fix it.
I don't think you got the picture.
I got a beautiful picture.
This baby happens to have
an extra turn of speed,
which is the only
thing I care about.
You don't understand
what happens, do you?
They make 10,000 cars, they
make them exactly the same way,
and one or two of them turn
out to be something special.
Nobody knows why.
I know why.
I may be kidding myself,
but I think I can
make something out
of that sad little
bucket of bolts.
Save these. They'll
be famous someday.
I'm your friend.
Want to take a ride?
I want to check those
adjustments I made last night.
- Okay.
- Be right with you.
Hey. Come here.
All right, you guys,
get out of there.
Out. Come on.
Who do you guys think you are?
Stop clowning around, will you?
Play it straight.
Don't give him any trouble.
You could have a good home here.
What's all that racket?
- Nothing, nothing.
- Oh. Hop in.
What'd I tell you?
Now it handles good.
All the bugs are gone.
Herbie's all right.
Who's Herbie?
This little car, named
after my Uncle Herb.
He used to box middleweight.
Preliminary mostly.
Gradually his nose got
shaped more and more
like to remind me
of this little car.
Do you mind?
Whatever you say, Tennessee.
Herbie.
I'll take them.
Thank you, sir.
What's that for?
An oil job.
Huh?
I got a small knock
in my conscience.
Thanks.
Now we get down to business.
You gonna race?
What do you think?
Oh, boy, won't Herbie love that.
Le Mans, Monte-Carlo,
thrills, glamour, the
roar of the crowd.
He really does drive.
If you could give
me one good reason
for bringing me down to
this ridiculous desert...
Isn't that the scruffy little
car we had in the shop?
Now we're going.
You're doing terrific, Herbie,
but don't make it look too easy.
Play it smart.
Okay, Jim, go ahead.
You're raring now.
So who cares? I'll
tell you one thing,
I certainly don't intend losing
any sleep over that absurd car.
Come on. Come on.
Now, Herbie, now. Now.
The winner, number 53,
Jim Douglas, driving
a class D special.
- Congratulations.
- Thanks.
- Good race, Jim.
- Thanks, Ray.
Oh boy, was Herbie
ever great today.
Hey, I was out there, too.
Wouldn't you say that was
a fair piece of driving?
Hey, I'm not trying to take
anything away from you,
but you gotta admit that this
little guy backed you all the way.
Yep. It's a nice little car.
You know something else?
For the first time
in a long while, I
felt my real self out there today.
I mean, a sense of authority, like
the top drivers have, you know?
I kind of felt you felt that.
Tennessee, I wouldn't admit
this to anybody else,
but I was beginning to think
I'd never be anything more
than a piston-happy,
lead-foot punk.
Then this starts to happen.
I'm glad for you, Jim.
You know that.
Well, hello.
I see you finally learned
how to handle this car.
- Congratulations.
- Thank you.
What have you done to this thing?
Oh, an adjustment here,
an adjustment there.
Do you want to sell it back?
I own most of it anyway, you know.
Still 23 payments to go.
Well...
I'll tell you what
I'll do. I'll take
the car and give you $1,000 clear.
Now what do you say to that?
No. You don't want to do that.
It's all right, Tennessee.
I know what I'm doing.
I think Mr. Thorndyke
is a little mixed
up as to who or
what won that race.
And what does that mean?
Someday I'll teach you not to
confuse the car with the driver.
I should welcome the opportunity.
Mr. Thorndyke, I think that's
a very good idea of yours.
What is?
You're racing in the Libra Open at
Riverside the end of
the month, right?
Yes.
I'm sure that Mr. Douglas
would like to get
the remainder of his
payments off his back.
No doubt.
But why should I think
that's such a good idea?
Well, if Mr. Douglas
entered the race,
he could bet his share
of the little car
against the remaining payment.
What do you say, Douglas?
Winner to become the
sole owner of the car.
A moment ago you mentioned
teaching me a lesson.
Do I now detect a
note of timidity?
Racing.
That's the name of
the game, isn't it?
Win or lose, put up or shut up.
You got yourself a
deal, Thorndyke.
Splendid.
The drivers' meeting is over.
Now the third race
of the afternoon
will get underway
here at Riverside.
You keep your eye on your
friend in the bug, my dear.
I'm going to squash him.
Clear the grid.
Clear the grid, please.
Can't help feeling yippie.
If anything goes wrong, we
lose Herbie altogether.
I thought you were the guy with
all the faith in this car.
Yeah, I got it, yeah.
And now the starter has
his flag in the air.
The engines are started,
and in just a moment
we'll have the start.
All the cars looking
very smart on the grid.
Drivers signify that
they're ready to race
with their hands
extended in the air.
The flag is up, and there they go.
All cars getting off
to a very nice start.
Off the grid on the
way to turn one.
We'll see how they shape up
as they go into turn one.
Cars stretching out now.
All cars off the starting
grid and through turn one.
To the open now.
Down the backstretch,
all by himself now.
Here is the number
14 car of Thorndyke
going into the sweeper turn.
The rest of the field
all stretched out
as they charge down
the backstretch.
Not yet, Herbie. Not yet.
The standings at lap 23...
Thorndyke still leading,
Lesser running second,
and Erwin in third place.
Now, Herbie, now.
Now car number 53, Douglas,
starts to make a move.
Picking up cars as he
goes by car number 20,
into the sweeper
very hard and fast.
Going through traffic,
passing number 23 now,
is car number 53, Douglas.
He has just come alive and is
making a challenge in this race.
Passing cars as he goes
down the back-straight.
Car number 53, Douglas,
making his bid.
Into the straight now is
Thorndyke, car number 14.
Now the pressure's on.
Douglas, number 53,
is drawing close
on Thorndyke in the number 14 car.
Douglas has just come alive and
is pressing the leader now.
Now making his bid to
pass but he can't get by.
He's being shut off by Thorndyke
in the number 14 car.
Goes slightly off course,
takes out some oranges,
and apparently is out of control.
And goes crashing into the
number four shut off card.
Thorndyke continuing on as
the number 53 car left...
Now he's making his re-entry.
Look out.
Hey, nice going, champ.
Thank you very much.
Hey, what a champ. Way to drive.
Just a moment, Mr.
Thorndyke, you don't have...
I demand that this thing
is impounded and checked.
I tell you, there's more going
on here than meets the eye.
Mucha luck, señor.
Thank you.
A usted también.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
You don't look well in
these pictures lately.
How could I look well?
I haven't been able to sleep.
That rotten car is
driving me piffy.
Has it occurred to you that
it may not be the rotten car?
Perhaps it's the way
Mr. Douglas drives.
Balderdash. There isn't
a driver in the world
who can get that speed
out of a car like that.
No, he's done something to it,
and I've got to find out what.
You've become obsessed
by this whole thing.
There are other cars, other races.
Why don't you just forget it?
My dear child, how
little you know me.
Yes, Mr. Thorndyke.
Carole?
How long have you been with us?
A year and a half,
almost two. Why?
You know, I'm afraid I've
been a little remiss
in not telling you long before now
how very well you've
proved in all your duties.
Well, thank you.
And Carole?
As I realise you have
the best interests
of this organisation at heart,
I want you to accede to a
somewhat unusual request.
Oh?
Peter Thorndyke.
It's for you.
All right, you can take it here.
Thank you.
Yes, good afternoon.
Oh, I think that should
be quite all right.
7:30 will be fine.
Yes, bye.
I think I'll...
I'd like you to see
this Douglas fellow.
Get to know him.
Who knows? If he has the talents
of which I believe him capable,
perhaps we can give
him the opportunity
of joining our organisation,
racing under our
colours, but first
we must know something about him.
- How about tonight?
- Very good.
At 7:30?
Very good. Why waste time?
Oh, and, Carole, another thing.
Leave your car.
Take the special.
He likes that one.
Thank you.
I think I ought to
tell you that that
was Mr. Douglas who just called.
Excellent. Strike while
the iron is hot.
In all honesty, I should
like to point out
that I agreed to
have dinner with him
before you suggested it.
Well, I salute your
honesty, my dear.
A quality not necessarily
to be despised.
Thank you.
A very loyal girl.
Got Herbie all
polished out for you.
Carole Bennett called back.
She's gonna pick me
up in the special.
You mean you're not taking Herbie?
He's looking forward to some
relaxation just like you are.
The car is...
See you later, Tennessee.
Some thanks after what
Herbie did for you.
Don't let it get you, Herbie.
Jim didn't mean it.
Don't forget, he isn't the first
guy ever to lose his head
over a bucket seat
and a paint job.
He'll come to his senses.
Good evening.
Sorry, the other rats are
out for the evening.
No, no, please.
I didn't come by to
see Mr. Douglas.
I just came by to pay my respects
to that gallant little car.
Huh?
There it is.
What a marvel it is, indeed.
I don't get you, fella.
Oh, come, come, sir, I know a rare
bit of machinery when I see one.
And after all, who should
know it better than I?
I, who have been trounced time
and again by this paragon.
You will forgive me for saying so,
sir, but it does
take class to know
when it has been
defeated by class.
You know something, Mr. Thorndyke,
I may have misjudged you.
Well, thank you.
I've been misjudging a
lot of people lately.
Would you like a drink?
Some Irish coffee?
Speciality of the house,
my own mother's recipe.
That's very kind of
you, I'd love it.
I'll be back in a jiffy.
Well, that's most kind.
Thank you so much.
It's just incredible,
isn't it, to think
that this innocent-seeming object
is capable of such great deeds.
How, indeed.
The trick is, always remember
to have asbestos gloves
when you make coffee this way.
Definitely, yes.
Yes, quite fascinating.
Here we go.
Ooh. Oh. Oh...
How very refreshing.
Well, thank you.
Up the Irish.
To the little car, a
gallant adversary,
and may the best car
win at Riverside.
- May the best car win.
- Yes.
Oh, that's very good, isn't it?
Very good, indeed.
Like it?
What do you think?
I can't stand that
hungry look any longer.
Take over.
You know what I said to myself
the first time I saw you?
What?
I said to myself, now,
there's a real lady.
This is how it ought to be.
Me and these kind of wheels.
Excuse me asking, but aren't you
doing all right with
the little car?
Sure.
But can you imagine how I'd make
it with equipment like this?
Is it so important to you?
Without a real car,
I'm only half a man.
What part of Ireland did you
say your mother came from?
Coney Ireland.
Ha, ha, ha, ha.
I'm gonna make some more coffee.
Well, would you like
a spot of this?
I like a spot of anything.
I'm so sorry.
Then we're gonna drink to Herbie.
Greatest little car
in the whole world.
Yes, quite right. Hear, hear.
Hear, hear.
To Herbie.
To Herbie. I'm so sorry
about your hand.
I do apologise.
Herbie.
What do you know?
The engine stalled.
How about that? Door's stuck.
That's how it is
with cars sometimes.
Yes.
Guess we'll have to wait
and see what happens next.
Well, as someone very
wisely once said,
"That's how it is
with cars sometimes."
I just said that.
Oh.
I wonder if your reputation
is altogether true.
What's my reputation?
Oh, I've heard that Jim Douglas
is only interested in
fast cars and easy money.
Not true.
Oh?
You know something else?
What?
When the light hits
you just right,
you're as beautiful as General
Grant on the $50 bill.
Oh, dear me.
You want to know the
secret of the little car?
I do, indeed.
I'll tell you the secret
of the little car.
No, just a minute.
All right, tell me.
It's heart.
That's what it is... Heart.
Heart.
Yes, well, I'm certainly going
to make a note of that.
Headache gone?
All gone.
Anticipation of victory is
the purest form of aspirin.
This is my day.
Clear the grid.
Clear the grid, please.
You seem very confident.
You know, I believe I am.
There is some passing as they
leave the starting grid.
Going for turn one.
Field stretching out now.
Everybody into the
turn went very nicely.
Very fine field of cars here,
and coming through traffic now,
making a move is Peter Thorndyke
in the number 14 car,
picking up a few
cars in that turn.
Now he comes by and picks up three
more cars, going
into the lead now.
Thorndyke leading this
race in car number 14.
Now making a move is car
number 53, Douglas,
who also picks up
about three cars as
he goes charging into the traffic,
and is in hot pursuit of
Thorndyke in the number 14 car.
As they go down the back-straight,
coming on very hard to pass now
and Douglas, number
53, making the pass.
Attaway, Jimmy boy.
Go, Jimmy. Ha, ha, ha.
So far Jim Douglas seems to have
everything pretty much to himself.
He comes through the S's into
turn six well in control.
As we come down the back-straight,
Douglas is slowing down
and Thorndyke goes rocketing
by into the sweeper turn.
It looks as though the Douglas
car is having trouble.
Yes, number 53 is fading fast.
It is developing a
problem of some kind.
Come in. Come in.
Come in.
Irish coffee.
I'll be here all night if
necessary. Ha, ha, ha.
I can take any amount of this.
Right, there we are.
Don't worry, little guy.
You'll be home soon.
There we are.
Right, right you are.
Do you mind standing clear?
They want me on my own.
I'll see you in a minute.
Poor little fella.
You got a temperature.
Don't worry, Jim
will be back soon.
He never would have left if it
hadn't been something important.
I know, nothing worse than
an Irish coffee hangover.
That you, Jim?
Mind if I come in?
Sure, come on.
I wouldn't blame you
if you threw me out.
On account of what Thorndyke did?
How can I blame anyone?
Thorndyke ruined the little
car right under my nose.
- Where's Jim?
- Don't know.
He went out as soon
as we got back.
Didn't say a word.
Left Herbie and me flat.
Doesn't he take care of
his car after a race?
Can you do something?
Like what?
Well, help the little car.
I'm not a mechanic, but
I think it's suffering.
Suffering?
Please.
Mind if I use those coveralls?
Right.
Oh, look, I want to tell you
so you don't have to worry.
I'm not with Peter
Thorndyke any more.
I don't think his way.
Oh, I know that.
How do you know?
Well, Herbie wouldn't
like you, otherwise.
Herbie wouldn't like me?
Miss Bennett...
I gotta level with somebody.
I can't talk to Jim.
Oh, it would destroy him.
You don't know what it was like
before the little car came along.
Jim was defeated. It was murder.
He couldn't get a job.
He got into trouble.
Everybody was on his back.
Then Herbie came into his life.
You remember that day?
I remember.
Well, Jim started
winning races again,
he got his self-respect back.
What am I gonna do?
Tell him that it was Herbie
winning those races, not him?
Was it Herbie?
Well, I...
You fix the little car.
I'll tell you what's going on.
I didn't know nothing.
Then I went to Tibet.
I plugged into this
contemplation thing...
How's that sound?
Like the song of a bluebird.
Well, the fuel lines are clean,
plugs are clean,
wiring checks out.
Looks like we're in
pretty good shape.
Herbie and I sure appreciate it.
You don't believe a word I said
about this little car, do you?
Well, there's always a first time.
I imagine Adam thought woman was a
pretty funny piece of equipment
when he met Eve.
Well, that's a start.
You can't believe
it all right away.
It takes time.
- Well, hello there.
- Hi.
What's this?
You ever see anything
so beautiful?
Very nice.
What's the big idea?
You already got a car.
Not after what happened
today I don't.
Ah, shut up. You want
Herbie to hear you?
Now don't start that
again, Tennessee.
Look, the El Dorado is coming up.
There are real cars
lined up in there.
I need something that can cut it.
Herbie's cut it so far, hasn't he?
Of course he has.
Now, hold it, you two.
I've done great with
this little car
so far, thanks to a
few changes I made
and, if you don't mind, some
pretty fair country driving.
But I gotta stop kidding myself.
I need a big, strong car.
Now I got it.
Don't pay any attention.
Don't even look at it.
Hello?
Peter Thorndyke here.
Well, well.
Yeah, yeah, Thorndyke, I
know what you did to my car.
You need your brains kicked out.
Well, you can imagine
how I must feel.
You see, I'm simply
not responsible
when I've been drinking.
You know how it is.
Forget it. And goodbye.
Wait, wait, wait.
I understand from a friend of mine
that you purchased a
new Lamborghini today.
So?
I'm also informed that you owe
a great deal of money on it.
Now, myself, for sentimental
reasons, I like the little car,
and I'm perfectly willing to
increase my previous offer
and give you $1,500 for it.
Now, immediately.
I'm in the vicinity.
Thorndyke, I don't like you.
But I can use your money.
You got yourself a
deal. Come and get it.
What do you mean you
got yourself a deal?
- I'm selling the little car.
- You're what?
Don't make a fuss.
I need the money.
You crumb. You can't
do that to Herbie.
Carole, will you
tell him how it is?
Out in the real world?
Me? Ha.
Well, near as I can figure it,
I'm not too smart either.
I get rid of one heel just
in time to find another.
Well, now, what happened to you?
I thought you'd be on my side.
Not when you do something
like this to Herbie.
Has everybody gone
nuts around here?
I can understand how
Tennessee feels.
He's just in off a
flying saucer. But
you... I thought you made sense.
Something tells me it's very, very
wrong to sell that little car.
Well, thank you for your opinion,
but what am I supposed to do?
Now, I need the money.
Tennessee, if I don't sell...
Don't talk to me.
I'm sorry.
I shouldn't have butted in.
You're absolutely right.
As a matter of fact,
I don't know...
What are you doing here?
I wish I knew.
I really wish I knew.
If I weren't so young
and innocent, a
certain thought might
enter my mind.
Such as?
Such as you went out
with me last night
so that Thorndyke could get
a shot at the little car.
Is that what you think?
You gotta admit it's tempting.
Okay. Okay, you want to
know what I was doing here?
Well, I felt sorry about
what happened today.
So I quit Thorndyke and came over
here like a full-grown idiot
to find out if I could make
up for it in some way.
Well, isn't that a beautiful
thought for the day?
Very touching. Makes me glow.
I think it's just
about time someone
told you what the score is.
You see, Tennessee's
too tender-hearted.
You really think it was
you winning those races?
Yes, I think it was me winning...
What do you mean it
wasn't me winning...
Pardon me.
All right. Do you want me
to tell you something,
my windbag friend?
I admit, I didn't believe it
when Tennessee told me before,
but now I see it makes
all kinds of sense.
What?
That thimble head of yours
has gotten all swelled up.
You're not winning
any of those races.
You couldn't win a game of marbles
from a 12-toed myopic rhinoceros.
Let me... Will you knock it
off out there, Tennessee?
Can't hear myself think.
I'm not out there,
crumb, I'm here.
Well, hold it down. I'll...
Well, then what's this noise?
No.
Stop it. Stop it. You don't
know what you're doing.
Look. Look what it did to my car.
Okay, okay, maybe it
was a little jealous.
Of course it's jealous.
It's always been jealous
because I get credit for
winning those races.
Go on. Realise what you're saying?
At a time like this,
whatever kind of time it is,
I always say that money
serves to ease the pain.
Good evening, my dear.
Here you are, sir.
$1,500 for the small
car, just as I promised.
I note it's not in mint condition,
but I am nothing if not
always a man of my word.
2,000.
What about 2,000?
It's the least I can do to help a
fellow human at a time like this.
Shall we consider it a deal?
$2,000?
Yes.
$2,000 for that little
beat-up car. Why?
Well, I suppose you could say I
have a warm place in my heart
for the dear little thing.
You don't have a warm
place on your whole body.
What do you want it for?
You don't want it. I
do. Take the money.
- You. You, too.
- There's no need to be abusive.
I'm simply trying to
give you some money.
I don't want your money. What
do you want the car for?
Well, I...
You believe it. You
believe it, too.
Believe what?
Jim, it don't matter whether
you believe Herbie or not.
Herbie don't believe
in you no more.
What?
Well, where'd he go? Where is he?
Took off. What do you expect?
Well, come on, let's find him.
This is a private thing
between the two of you.
Good luck.
Herbie.
A rum lot you've taken
up with, my dear.
You better find that car
before I do, my friend.
Operator.
Mobile KQX2942,
I want 567-3998.
Havershaw? I shall
require the personnel
of both our day and night shifts.
We have a small task to perform.
Herbie.
That's it.
Excuse me.
Havershaw, tear it apart.
All right, boys, you heard Mr.
Thorndyke. Tear it apart.
I'm gonna find out
what makes it tick.
- After it.
Go on, grab the brute.
Hang onto it, you fools. Hang on.
Herbie.
(SPEAKING CHINESE)
Give me police station.
Hello. Police station.
Herbie.
Hey, you.
Did a little car come by here?
Yeah, just did without
paying the...
No, Herbie. Don't.
Herbie.
Herb. Back up.
Herbie?
Come on, baby, it's gonna be
a beautiful day tomorrow.
Oh.
Herbie, give me some help.
Herb?
I can't hang on much longer.
Boy, was he lucky.
This little car saved his life.
What do you mean, the
car saved his life?
That's what it looked like
for a moment there...
You know how funny things can
look in the fog sometimes.
I think you've been up on that
Haight-Ashbury beat too long.
(SPEAKING CHINESE)
Swing that light over here.
Aha.
- What's that thing?
- It's a dried squid, Sergeant.
- Here's the damages.
- Can you pay it?
I'm sorry. I have no money.
Then your car will be impounded.
My guess is, the judge will
order you to sell it at auction
and the proceeds given to Mr. Wu.
Wait a minute.
May I please speak to
the gentleman, please?
I spent some time up on
a Chinese-type mountain
teaching English to some of them.
You taught English?
Let's don't get personal. It's a
matter of talking their language.
You have a little
feel for tradition
and some courtesy,
you'd be surprised.
You can unscrut the inscrutable.
Go ahead.
(SPEAKING CHINESE)
Ah...
- Herbie?
- Herbie.
Oh.
Oh. Things are shaping up.
He's a car buff.
Good, good.
(SPEAKING CHINESE)
Wow.
- What's the matter?
- We just got a new problem.
He likes the car so much
he wants to keep it.
Okay, the car is
his, but he has to
let me drive it in the El Dorado.
Now, if I win, tell him he
gets to keep the prize money,
but he has to sell Herbie
back to me for a dollar.
Now you speak my language.
Attention, drivers and owners,
report to Mr. Granatelli
at the president's headquarters.
Further, you must remain
on the secondary roads,
which have been
posted for this race.
Other than that, we've tried to
reduce the rules to a minimum.
Instead of all this technical
mamby-pamby there's
so much of today,
we're putting the emphasis on
speed, endurance, and courage.
The way it used to be.
As you know, this is
open formula racing.
Anything goes.
Any style of car
and crew you wish.
The object, gentlemen, is to win.
I wish you all the
very best of luck.
Tang Wu, I understand that you are
the new owner of the Douglas car.
As I, too, am interested
in the vehicle,
I took the liberty
of looking you up.
Thank you.
You will therefore
forgive me, sir,
when I say that you are perhaps
not quite as naive as you look.
In point of fact, you are
a very shrewd operator,
one who has managed to acquire,
by one means or another,
legitimate means, of course, a
number of varied enterprises.
It is truly written, one
cannot lose them all.
In the light of this, would you
entertain a sizeable wager
on the outcome of the race?
Wager?
The goddess of fortune will always
find me her most ardent suitor.
Splendid, splendid.
Shall we step in here?
A little more private.
You're Mr. Thorndyke. I've
always wanted to meet you.
You've heard of me? How charming.
Are you not the gentleman who
originated the idea of small print
on bottom of automobile
sales contract?
The very same.
A most worthy adversary.
You are most kind.
And now, sir, the
terms of our wager.
What would you like?
What have you got?
Ahem.
Okay, let's mount up.
How's our little friend?
I hope it holds together.
Holds together?
It was so beat up, I had to cut
the frame to straighten it out.
Excuse me.
Is this the morning bus to Fresno?
Thorndyke, this little car goes so
fast, we need three people inside
just to hold it on the ground.
Well, you certainly
picked the right crew.
Toodle-oo.
Break a leg, Thorndyke.
Havershaw, I trust you've
not been wasting your time.
Spent a few useful moments
with the small car?
Yes, sir.
Based then on what you now
know, what would you say
are the chances of victory
for the Douglas car?
I would say that they range
from slight to impossible.
Havershaw, you are a rat
after my own heart.
Thank you, sir.
Gentlemen, start your engines.
You're giving it a nice ride.
Okay to uncurl my toes
now? We past everybody?
Everyone but Thorndyke.
Let's go to work.
They're coming up on us, sir.
Well, we're not too
concerned, are we?
Now, Havershaw, aren't we coming
to that rather dangerous,
oily spot in the road?
Coming right up, sir.
Come on, push.
Push, you worm.
Jim, that's water.
Here we go.
Mr. Thorndyke, that isn't me.
Give me something
to wipe my goggles.
Havershaw, did you ever
think of having a manicure?
There they are.
Now watch me blow
them off the road.
Who's the guy in the fur coat?
This is no time for
eating, you fool.
Where are we? How far
is Chinese Camp?
What's the matter with you?
Don't you even know
how to open a map?
At the moment, the
leaders of the race
are approaching the historic
mining towns of the mother lode.
In first position,
as he moves past
checkpoint three, is Jim Douglas.
Peter Thorndyke, in the special,
has regained his relief driver
and is rapidly making
up lost ground
as the two pacemakers
near the famous
old mining community
of Chinese Camp.
- Now what?
- I don't know.
We can't be out of gas this soon.
Here.
Wait a minute. I got a suspicion.
What's the matter?
Just as I thought... Water.
They did it again.
Now what do we do?
Give me the map.
All right, it looks like Chinese
Camp's about three
miles from here.
Now, if we come down the...
Hey.
What goes?
No sweat, man.
This is Uncle Wu's car.
You don't think he'd let
anyone put it down, do you?
Easy, fellas.
The Jim Douglas car appears
to have run into trouble.
There has been no sign of
him past checkpoint nine.
Peter Thorndyke is
refuelling at Chinese Camp.
Come on, come on, will
you? I'm in a hurry.
Sure thing. I tell father.
(SPEAKING CHINESE)
My father say hurry is waste.
Waste is cracked bowl,
which never know rice.
I don't care how cracked
your father's rice bowl is.
What I want...
Hey. Some of you people
get over here right away.
Okay, you're on your way.
Hooray. Hooray.
I'm getting out of here.
Not full. Can't go yet.
Oh, just you watch me.
As we come to the midway point
in the first day's racing,
Peter Thorndyke, after a
delay at Chinese Camp,
is beginning to catch up
with the rest of the field.
That knocked him off the
Christmas tree, sir.
This is our kind of terrain
from here on out, all downhill.
How true it is that the best ways
are the simplest ways after all.
That's what I always say, sir.
Oh, shut up.
We should be coming
soon to what is
either a rail tunnel or a bridge.
Oh, here's a tunnel.
That must be it.
What are you doing?
It's an elevator.
But Herbie doesn't fit.
Everybody out.
No sign of them.
You may open the
wine now, Havershaw.
It's chilled the way
you like it, sir.
All right, give me a hand.
Altogether now.
To you, sir. My
unbounded admiration.
Thank you.
You know something
about champagne, sir?
Havershaw, if you tell me that
the bubbles tickle your nose,
I shall probably kill you.
Eek.
Get rid of that slop.
Shouldn't that wheel
have come off by now?
It's long overdue, sir.
I'm terribly embarrassed by the
delay. I don't know what...
Stop whimpering.
I'll just give them
a friendly nudge.
Hey, where'd that wheel come from?
Hold it.
All right, don't do
anything sudden.
Is it all right if I
just cry real soft?
Carole, put your feet
back here on the bumper.
Now give me your hand.
Let go, let go. Give me your hand.
I'm trying, but my mind
don't get the message.
Come on, come on.
Now come right over the top.
Atta-boy.
All right, let's get
the spare wheel
on and get Herbie
back on the road.
Thorndyke again.
He made a pizza out of it.
And now, here in Virginia City,
the terminal point for the
first day of the El Dorado,
we're all looking down
the road from the west.
And, actually, at any moment now,
we should be seeing
the car that will
complete the first
half of the El Dorado,
the run for the gold.
Up in the judges' stand,
the judges and the
timers are ready.
Just a moment.
The first car is coming
in sight right now.
He is really flying down the road.
And there he goes by us.
You making it all
right, Tennessee?
Waah.
Whoa.
Stop, Jim, will you?
Waah.
Now, don't anybody breathe.
Ready?
Actually, at this hour, only
one car is unaccounted for.
There's been absolutely no
word of the Douglas special,
which figured so
very prominently in
the early stages
of the race today.
Well, I see the judges are
closing down for the night,
and, by golly, so are we,
but we'll return to the El
Dorado at 7:30 tomorrow morning
to bring you the start of the
second and the final lap
back to Yosemite Valley.
Good night, everyone.
A little bird's nest
soup never hurt anyone.
Thanks.
Oh, thanks.
I hope this holds together. I'm
putting welds on top of welds.
Mr. Wu, the wiring is
mostly all burned off.
The cylinder walls are scored.
The carburettor is a mess.
The body's sprung.
This little car ripped itself to
pieces trying to get us here.
It gave us everything it's got.
Now, maybe we could
patch it back together,
I don't know, but...
How can I send it back into
that rat race tomorrow?
It's got nothing left to give.
It's your car.
What do you say?
A wise man once said...
"When you come to last page,
"close the book."
You let that little car get
under your skin, didn't you?
I don't know.
There's a lot of gloop
been written about it.
The bond between a man
and his automobile
and how he hates it sometimes,
mostly, how he loves it.
Showers gifts on it in the way
of accessories and all that.
He gets hysterical if
somebody scratches the paint
or makes it lose
face on the freeway.
Maybe some of those feelings got
into the machinery, I don't know.
Tennessee thinks so.
Don't you?
There is something real
about that little car,
something that doesn't
even have a name.
What I don't understand is, out of
the millions of
people in the world,
why it picked a dog-eared
second-rater like me.
You stood up for it once.
I guess it thought you were
worth belonging to.
I understand that.
Ah, Douglas.
Didn't mean to disturb you.
We'll just take the car and go.
Take the car? What are
you talking about?
I understand that you
are out of the race.
What does that have
to do with you?
Speaking as the new
owner of the car, I
regard your question
as impertinent.
I'm going to hoist it
up and drag it out.
Hold it.
Who said you were the
new owner of the car?
Perhaps Mr. Wu would
like to explain
how he wagered the car on
the outcome of the race.
Even as you, I believed
in the little car.
I thought it would win.
More honestly, I could
not resist the odds.
Thank you.
Good sir,
would you say that
this is a compact car?
You do not answer.
Well, let me tell you that you
have never seen a compact car
until you see what I'm
going to do with this.
Mr. Douglas, I have a
friend with a claw and hook
auto wrecking company
in San Francisco,
and he's going to
work on your car.
Maybe he'll transform
it into a birdbath.
Or what about a nice doormat so I
can wipe my feet on it every day?
Well, it's too bad this thing
doesn't have the gumption
to get up to the starting
line this morning.
I should've enjoyed beating it.
Oh.
Why, you...
Take your hand...
Get your hands off.
Ooh.
Stop. Herbie, stop.
Hey, you know something?
Small car very angry.
And very strong.
The strength of 40 horses.
What do you think about
that race coming up?
You know... I think now is chance
to remove egg fu Yung off face.
Well, this morning, the second and
the final lap of the El Dorado,
from Virginia City to Yosemite,
the run for the gold.
Out there, we see in first
position and all ready to go,
Peter Thorndyke in his
Thorndyke special.
Don't worry... Hey.
Whoa.
These mechanics have done a real
fine job in keying
these engines up.
Come on, baby.
Come on, save it for the race.
One more foul-up like this,
Douglas, you're disqualified.
It seemed to be trying
to get at us, sir.
Of course it was, Havershaw.
It's no use trying
to blink the fact.
It's either us or it this time.
We're now getting reports from
our checkpoint number 14,
and this one tells us
that the Thorndyke car
is still holding first
position at this time.
And while here in Virginia City,
we're preparing to dispatch
the last of our contestants.
That would be the Jim
Douglas special.
Hang tight. This may
be a fast take-off.
Now.
Good stuff, Herb.
No more shortcuts like
that last one, Jim.
Oh, this won't be anything
like that last one.
Thorndyke.
Nice going, Herbie.
We've almost got him.
Hooray.
What fool laid out these streets?
But you're driving superbly.
Hey. You got something against
driving on the streets?
Any sign of them?
Not a glimmer, sir.
Very well, then.
Now I've finished being
generous George.
He's moving up.
There are times like this when I
really don't like
myself very much.
What happened to it?
I'd say it's gone for that
last big lube job up yonder.
Ow. Ow.
Whoa.
Here it comes again, sir.
Havershaw, I am not a cowardly
man, but I am beginning to sense
that that thing is out to get me.
Now, none of that, sir.
We're not losing
our nerve, are we?
Blast you, Havershaw. How
dare you patronise me.
I am not losing my nerve.
No, sir. No, sir. Of
course not, sir. No, no.
I think Herbie did something
to himself that last fall.
What do you mean?
Well...
Like maybe he won't hang
together much longer.
Yeow.
What happened to Thorndyke?
I don't know. It was
like he disappeared.
Do you hear something?
Sounds like one of the cylinders.
That's impossible. The
cylinders are in the back.
That's a point I find puzzling.
Get me out of here.
- Oh, my goodness.
- Get that side.
Oh. Ooh.
Here. Turn him around.
Okay, on your way.
Let's go.
Havershaw.
The leaders have now passed
the final checkpoint.
We're now moving outside and
we should be seeing them
at the finish line in
a very few minutes.
The word is the Douglas
car is in the lead,
but the Thorndyke
car is moving up.
Oh. I think we got a problem.
Carole, turn around.
Grab hold of that strap and pull.
Ooh.
You okay?
Fine.
Look. There's another one.
I got it.
What goes on?
Just keep driving.
Try not to think about
what I'm doing.
Well, that's that.
Yaah.
I can't weld that.
Give me your hand.
What are we gonna do, jump?
- No, pull.
- Why?
Whoa.
Whoa. Jim, help.
I think you better stop
before someone gets hurt.
No dice. Herbie
doesn't want to stop.
There it is.
I'll bomb the thing off the
road once and for all.
Rotten sportsmanship,
if you ask me.
Here at the finish,
we're still waiting
for our first glimpse
of the leaders.
Yes. Yes, there they are.
The Thorndyke car now seems
to have a slight edge
on the Douglas car, which
is hanging right in there.
You have him now,
sir. Don't falter.
I'm not going to
falter, you dimwit.
Good-o, sir, good-o.
You can't lose.
You can't possibly lo...
- We won. We won.
- Ha, ha, ha.
The little car takes first...
And third place.
Whoa.
Come on. Give us a picture.
Beautiful. One more.
What? Kiss? You
better believe that.
- Oh.
- Come here.
"Couldn't lose," I think you said.
I don't like to remind you, sir,
but if only you'd read the terms
of that stupid wager
you made with Mr. Wu.
Havershaw, you're despicable.
Havershaw, I shan't pretend I
don't know what you're thinking.
However, I pride myself on being
a good judge of character,
and when I ask myself,
"Could this man be capable
"of such an act of
pettiness and base...
"Base ingratitude." I
accept that as your answer.
Ha, ha...
Thanks, Herbie. So long, Mr. Wu.
- Goodbye.
- Goodbye, Mr. Wu.
- Bye, Tennessee.
- So long, Jim.
It's none of my
business, but where
are you going on your honeymoon?
We don't know. Herb
hasn't told us yet.
Let's go, Herb.
Goodbye, Herbie.