[instrumental music]
[dramatic music]
[babbling]
[instrumental music]
[cooing]
[chuckles]
[babbling]
[music continues]
[dramatic music]
♪♪ Belly up belly up
to the bar boys ♪♪
♪♪ Better loosen your belts ♪♪
♪♪ Only drink
when you're all alone ♪♪
♪♪ Or with somebody else ♪♪
♪♪ Belly up belly up
to the bar boys ♪♪
♪♪ Let your money be seen ♪♪
♪♪ Only drink by day or night ♪♪
♪♪ Or somewheres in between ♪♪
♪♪ Belly up belly up
to the bar boys ♪♪
♪♪ While the weather is clear ♪♪
♪♪ If 'tis isn't rainin'
rain you know ♪♪
♪♪ It's rainin' ale and beer ♪♪
♪♪ Belly up belly up
to the bar boys ♪♪
♪♪ If it isn't your day ♪♪
♪♪ A quart and pint
mixed up just right ♪♪
♪♪ Will cure you right away ♪♪
♪♪ Away ♪♪
♪♪ Away ♪♪♪♪
Whoa!
Come in and sit a while, Murphy.
Aye.
We'll open the jug
and toss a few.
Bring in the feed, Mol.
[rooster crowing]
[cow mooing]
[screams]
Urgh!
Argh!
You've been feelin'..
Whoa!
Jam! Joe! Get her!
Get her, Jam!
Joe, get her!
- Ugh!
- Get her!
Joe, don't let her
get away! Get her!
[indistinct shouting]
Joe, come on!
There she goes! Go get her!
You guys, come on!
- Hey!
- Don't let her get away!
(Molly)
Huh! Oh, ha ha.
- You're not gonna get me!
- Come on, get her, Joe.
Hey, you guys!
Ha ha ha!
- Come on. Come on.
- Here we go! Whoo-ho-ho!
Never, never, never..
You got her.
Come on, Joe! Come on!
Here you go.
You get off of me!
- Oh.
- Holler uncle, Molly!
- Holler uncle!
- Let me go! Let me go!
I ain't down yet!
Holler uncle!
You're down, Molly!
I ain't never hollerin'
uncle to nobody!
I ain't no down!
And even if I was
you'd sure
never hear it from me!
- Holler uncle!
[grunting]
(male #1)
'You're tuckered, Molly.
Why don't you quit?'
Sure, I'm tuckered,
and I might give out
but I won't give in!
How could anybody say I'm down?
Look! I'm blinkin'!
I'm also thinkin'
how to break through!
- Maybe...here!
- Oh!
- Maybe here!
- Get her, you guys.
She's gettin' away, get her.
Maybe no place!
But there will come a time
'cause nothin'
nor nobody wants me down
like I wants me up!
Up where the people are
up where the talkin' is
up where the joke's goin' on!
Now, look at here.
I'm important to me!
I ain't no bottom to no pile!
I mean much more to me
than I mean to anybody
I ever knew!
[panting]
Certainly more than
any Siwash
yazzy-hampers like you guys!
Go ahead! Break my arm!
Me say uncle? Heh!
Doesn't make
a bit of difference
for you to keep
tellin' me I'm down
till I say so too!
Do ever try steppin'
on a chigger bug?
- Huh?
- Well, there's one now!
Jump him!
Thinkin' you got him?
You thinkin' he's quick?
Well, he don't think so!
There he goes!
And you can be
positive sure
I'm as good as any
chigger bug ever lived!
Oh! I hate
that word down!
But I love the word up.
'Cause up means hope
and that's just
what I got hope.
For someplace better, someplace
I don't know,
that's-that's cleaner
and-and shinier and..
Oh, hell.
If I got to eat
catfish heads all my life
can't I have 'em off
a plate once?
In a, in a red silk dress.
♪♪ When there's girl
enough on me ♪♪
♪♪ To wear one ♪♪
♪♪ And then ♪♪
♪♪ Someday ♪♪
♪♪ With all my might ♪♪
♪♪ And all my main ♪♪
♪♪ I'm gonna learn
to read and write ♪♪
♪♪ I'm gonna see
what there is to see ♪♪
♪♪ So if you go from nowhere
on the road to somewhere ♪♪
♪♪ And you meet anyone
you know it's me ♪♪
♪♪ I'm gonna move
from place to place ♪♪
♪♪ And find a house
with a golden stair ♪♪
♪♪ And if that house is red ♪♪
♪♪ And has a big brass bed ♪♪
♪♪ I'm living there ♪♪
Well now.
Who do you
think you are?
I could be anybody.
Even a queen
if I wanted to be.
♪♪ Doot doot doot doo ♪♪
♪♪ We just been wrestling ♪♪
♪♪ With the queen if you please ♪♪
♪♪ Doot doot doot dee ♪♪
♪♪ Who'd recognize her
with all that dirt ♪♪
♪♪ On her knees ♪♪
♪♪ Doot doot doo ♪♪
♪♪ And with her mop head ♪♪
♪♪ And all that goes ♪♪
♪♪ Doot doot doot doo ♪♪
♪♪ And that contraption
she calls her nose ha ha ♪♪
♪♪ A queen can never be queen ♪♪
♪♪ Without any throne ♪♪
♪♪ Doot doot doo ♪♪
♪♪ So here's
the fanciest throne ♪♪
♪♪ That you'll ever own ♪♪
♪♪ Here is your scepter ♪♪
♪♪ Here is your crown ♪♪
♪♪ Now won't you please
sit down ♪♪♪♪
[instrumental music]
[music continues]
[grunts]
Howdy there, partner?
[whistling]
Oh!
Ugh!
Ah-ah. The queen.
- Uh.
- Hmm, hey!
Ah!
Hey! Hah!
How you doin' there, queenie?
Hey, look at me!
I'm flyin'! I'm flyin'!
- I'm flyin'! Whoo!
- Okay!
- Uh.
- Uh-oh-oh.
- Uh, ah.
- Oh!
- Oh, oh.
- Oh-oh.
- Oh!
- Ha!
- Yahoo!
- Yay!
Yahoo!
♪♪ To show ♪♪
♪♪ That you know ♪♪
♪♪ You got to show
you know you know ♪♪
♪♪ I'm gonna learn
to read and write ♪♪
♪♪ I'm gonna see
what there is to see ♪♪
♪♪ So if you go from nowhere
on the road to somewhere ♪♪
♪♪ And you meet anyone
you know it's me ♪♪
♪♪ I'm gonna move
from place to place ♪♪
♪♪ And find a house
with a golden stair ♪♪
♪♪ And if that house is red ♪♪
♪♪ And has a big brass bed ♪♪
Ooh. Oh, oh, God.
♪♪ I'm living there ♪♪♪♪
Urgh, why, I ought to..
Aah!
[all shouting]
This place could sure
use a woman.
I got Molly.
Yeah.
'Course, she can't cook
worth a damn
and devil a bit of talent
she's got for housekeepin'
as you can see,
but she does her share.
Does most of the huntin'
and fishin'.
Ain't it about time
somebody told
that motherless lass
she's a girl?
'She hunts and fishes,
whistles like a calliope'
'and my boys here tell me
she swears like a bargeman.'
[chuckles]
Been doing that
since she was three.
Uh, she's reached the age
for getting into trouble.
About time to
marry her off, Shamus.
(Shamus)
'Marry? Who'd marry Molly?'
Well, there must be somebody
who doesn't know her.
Hey, whatever happened
to that Johnson boy
who was hanging around
here a while back?
He tried to show her
his pa's hayloft.
She tied a can to his tail
and sent him
r-rattling down the road.
[laughing]
That's been the only one.
There's your boys.
Molly?
[laughing]
- Molly.
Molly!
Molly! I love you, baby!
[laughing]
[instrumental music]
(Shamus)
'You leavin' home, Molly?'
It's time, pa.
I've thought it through.
There's nothin' for me here.
Here you're just
born, and you
live, and you die.
What more is there,
Molly girl?
Somewhere there's just
got to be things
to see and do
more than
what there is here.
I'm gonna marry me
a-a rich man
like Katie Spinner did.
Be careful about the love
of money, Molly girl.
Oh, it ain't
the money I love, pa.
It's the not havin' it
I hate.
I'm gonna somehow
get me to Denver
and I'm gonna find me a man
with means enough
to put a real roof
over our heads
a roof that don't leak
rain and cold.
'I'm leaving at sunup, pa.'
I'll miss you, Molly.
I'll miss you too, pa.
It's time I thanked you
for pullin' me out of the flood
and...and raisin' me
like your own.
I guess, I didn't know much
about raising a girl.
Could be I done it wrong.
You done fine.
Nobody could have done better.
I'll send for you, pa.
I promise that.
And you'll have
a room of your own
where you can stay
in bed all day
with a jug
of the best liquor.
I do that now.
Let me give you a word
of advice, Molly girl.
Learn to serve God
and a hot breakfast
and in your search for that roof
that don't leak rain
beware of men that
offer you a roof
and forget
to mention marriage.
Find yourself a good man.
A good Irish Catholic
and settle down.
The man I marry is got to be
more than just Irish Catholic.
What more can a man be?
Well, if he's gonna
crawl in next to me
he's gonna have to be
the richest Irish Catholic
next to the pope!
(male #2)
'Howdy!'
[echoing]
'Howdy! Howdy! Howdy!'
'Howdy, Colorado!'
[echoing]
'Colorado! Colorado!
Colorado!'
♪♪ Colorado my home ♪♪
♪♪ Sweet home ♪♪
♪♪ Sweet ♪♪
[laughing]
[laughter echoes]
♪♪ Hear yourself laugh
and you'll laugh a lot more ♪♪
♪♪ Gives a man confidence ♪♪
♪♪ To holler in the mountains ♪♪
♪♪ Mountains mountains
mountains ♪♪
♪♪ Hey there Rio ♪♪
♪♪ Hey there Rio Grande ♪♪
♪♪ Where else Rio ♪♪
♪♪ Did you learn to roar ♪♪
♪♪ Well I'll tell you ♪♪
♪♪ Let me tell you Rio ♪♪
♪♪ Like me ♪♪
♪♪ You would be
only a small time trickle ♪♪
♪♪ Without the mountains
of Colorado ♪♪
♪♪ My home ♪♪
♪♪ Sweet ♪♪
♪♪ Home ♪♪
♪♪ Sweet home ♪♪
♪♪ A sky full of rockies
for my roof up there ♪♪
♪♪ A great golden meadow
for my rockin' chair ♪♪
♪♪ A claim and a cabin
and some breathin' air ♪♪
♪♪ Colorado my home ♪♪
♪♪ And here till the judgment ♪♪
♪♪ I will stay ♪♪
♪♪ Here till
the ponderosa walks away ♪♪
♪♪ Here where I'm proudest
when I hear me say ♪♪
♪♪ Colorado my home ♪♪
♪♪ Here's where
the silver finds you ♪♪
♪♪ Together with the gold
that will stick on your shoe ♪♪
♪♪ Missouri Mules
and plain damn fools ♪♪
♪♪ May leave us for a little ♪♪
♪♪ But they'll all come back ♪♪
♪♪ Someday ♪♪
♪♪ There ain't seven wonders ♪♪
♪♪ Only three ♪♪
♪♪ The mountains and meadows
far as a man can see ♪♪
♪♪ And somewhere
a rocky mountain gal for me ♪♪
♪♪ Colorado my home ♪♪
♪♪ Colorado ♪♪
♪♪ Rado rado rado ♪♪
♪♪ My ♪♪
♪♪ My my my ♪♪
♪♪ Ho-home ♪♪♪♪
[instrumental music]
[Molly whistling]
[whistling continues]
[music continues]
- How long you been there?
- Long enough.
Humph! A nice pastime
for a grown man.
- Yep.
- Go away.
This here's my land.
You're trespassing.
Oh.
What are you doin' here?
Washing off the dust
of the road.
My feet hurt.
Been walkin' for three days.
- Alone?
- 'Why not?'
How far is it to Leadville?
Long ways, maybe ten miles.
'Where'd you sleep
last night?'
Under a tree.
You're welcome to spend
the night in my cabin.
Oh, I am, am I?
If you think you're reading
my mind, missy, you're wrong.
I ain't that needy.
'Besides, you ain't
that much, you know.'
[gasps]
We.. You're no prize!
Heh, back home
where I come from
we drown runts
of the litter like you.
[chuckling]
Hey.
When-when did you eat last?
Yesterday mornin'.
I got a pot
on the stove up there.
You can sleep under a tree
if you're that mistrustful.
You'd better
stoke up on some stew.
Come on, let's eat.
Uh, that's real
kind of you, mister, uh..
Brown. John J. Brown.
[instrumental music]
Come on in. Set.
Rest your feet.
It sure.. It sure smells good.
What are you, uh,
gonna do in Leadville?
Uh, it's just
a stoppin'-off place for me
to get some money.
The place I'm really
heading for is Denver.
Oh? What's in Denver?
Beautiful people.
Rich people.
I'm gonna get me a fine man
a rich man, a millionaire!
Hmm. Sounds like me.
Huh! I'm gonna
learn to read and write.
Can you read?
Sure!
Schooling till I was nine.
Read me what this says.
''Best regards from
Katie Spinner.''
- What does that mean?
- What does what mean?
Regards.
Uh..
Uh, it-it means
not just regards
but, um, best regards.
Uh.
I see.
Best regards.
Whatever the hell
that means.
And this one.
Um, ''Christmas greetings
from Katie Spinner.''
That must have been
at Christmastime!
Must-must have been.
[chuckles]
Ain't that beautiful?
Look at them big buildings.
What's the printin' say?
Uh, it's, uh,
''Pennsylvania Avenue
Denver, Colorado.''
Pennsylvania Avenue.
That's, uh..
That's where
the rich folks live.
I'm gonna live.
Before or after
you hook the millionaire?
After.
[laughing]
'What are you
gonna use for bait?'
Uh, Chick-a-Pen, I-I'm sorry.
You got a, you-you got
a real nice...face.
I'm probably the only man
in 20 miles
that knows you're
a-a...woman.
Capital W and two-two O's.
Uh, uh, let's eat.
I got to get goin'.
There's plenty of time.
Leadville's just over the hill.
Just over the hill?
'Mm-hmm. Maybe a mile.'
You said
it was a long ways.
You said maybe ten miles
and welcome to spend
the night in your cabin.
Oh, you scabby he-goat!
My pa warned me about this
but you're sure
a smooth one
flimflammin', sweet-talkin'.
Here I am under that roof!
Wha-what's the roof
got to do?
Now, I'm gettin' outta here
you double tongue,
low-minded sneaky
scheming polecat!
[whistles]
(Molly)
No, uh..
'Oh, I knew,
I was gonna go the..'
[instrumental music]
Howdy, Christmas.
How's business?
There ain't any.
They all been
over at the Nugget
since yesterday.
That's 'cause, they got
entertainment, Christmas.
You ain't got
no entertainment.
Yeah. I know.
I hear tell they got a gal
over there that sings.
Her sister plays the piano.
Yeah, huh, and every
once in a while
the singing one see,
she kinda
bends over to turn the pages
for the one playing
the piano.
Ooh. It's a great show.
[chuckles]
Hey, you taken
to doing the sweeping
yourself now, Christmas?
Well, Henry left.
I gotta find me
another helper.
I'm a helper.
It's a job for a man.
Oh, I can do it.
I can do anything.
You're new in town.
I just got here,
and I gotta find me a place
to-to sleep and something to eat
and-and I'm willing to work hard
whatever the risk 'cause..
(together)
I got no money.
[laughs]
Alright.
[chuckles]
Alright!
I'll give you a try.
Come on.
Okay.
Hey, Christmas,
maybe she can sing.
[laughs]
Something smells real good.
Got a ham cookin'
in the kitchen.
Say, can you sing?
Oh. I could sing the hogs
out of the hills.
Hmm.
Get you a fancy dress
and, uh, fix your hair
you might look almost as good
as 'em hens across the way.
You sure you can sing?
Oh, sure. Sure.
What's the matter?
Oh. I feel kind of funny.
I...I guess I'm awful hungry.
Oh, we'll get you
somethin' to eat.
Can you handle a box?
- A box?
- Piano.
Can you play it?
Oh. Piano.
- Hmm.
- Sure. Sure.
Well, if you can play
the piano and you can sing
you got yourself a job.
I'll get you
a fancy dress and fix your..
♪♪ Belly belly ♪♪
♪♪ Belly ♪♪
♪♪ Belly belly belly
belly belly ♪♪
♪♪ Belly belly belly ♪♪
♪♪ Belly be.. ♪♪
♪♪ Belly up
belly up ♪♪
♪♪ Belly up to the bar boys ♪♪
Yes!
♪♪ Belly up.. ♪♪
Hmm.
Where'd it go?
♪♪ Belly belly belly ♪♪
♪♪ Belly belly belly ♪♪♪♪
[plays note]
[instrumental music]
[music continues]
♪♪ Belly up belly up
to the bar boys ♪♪
♪♪ Better loosen
your belts ♪♪
♪♪ Only drink
when you're all alone ♪♪
♪♪ Or with somebody else ♪♪
♪♪ Yeah ♪♪
♪♪ Belly up belly up
to the bar boys ♪♪
♪♪ Better have a few more ♪♪
♪♪ I never whirl
with a three-toed girl ♪♪
♪♪ Or a discontented ho-- ♪♪
♪♪ Horrible example ♪♪
♪♪ Like the girl
whose name was Carrie ♪♪
♪♪ She carried her charms
to everybody else ♪♪
♪♪ Her I had to marry ♪♪
♪♪ Or die die die ♪♪
♪♪ Had to marry Carrie ♪♪
[cheering]
[music continues]
♪♪ Belly up belly up
to the bar boys ♪♪
♪♪ Let your money be seen ♪♪
♪♪ Only drink
by day or night ♪♪
♪♪ Or somewheres in between ♪♪
♪♪ Belly up belly up
to the bar boys ♪♪
♪♪ Very good
for your mind ♪♪
♪♪ Uh both feet
on the rails ♪♪
♪♪ Will make you
fall on your be-- ♪♪
♪♪ Hidle-deedle-didle-didle ♪♪
♪♪ I call her Fazelda ♪♪
♪♪ She giggles at me
and everybody else ♪♪
♪♪ Had to marry Zelda ♪♪
♪♪ Or die die die ♪♪
♪♪ Got to wed Fazelda ♪♪
♪♪ Or die die die ♪♪♪♪
[instrumental music]
[cheering]
[music continues]
[instrumental music]
[crowd cheering]
[drum roll]
[sniffles]
[crowd cheering]
[whistles]
[cheering]
[drum roll]
[indistinct chatter]
[laughing]
[instrumental music]
[indistinct chatter]
[music continues]
[cheering]
[instrumental music]
Thank you, Mr. Brown.
You left it in my cabin.
Mm-hmm.
Thought-thought
you might want it.
Oh, yes. Uh..
I-I wouldn't wanna lose them
picture postcards of Denver.
Don't-don't know
what's the use of them
if you can't read them.
Oh, but I'm gonna
learn to read.
Well, who's gonna teach you?
You?
(Molly)
'''The cat sees the rat.'
''The rat sees the cat.
''The cat runs after the rat.
''This is my hat.
It is a red hat.''
What happened to the rat?
Cat ate it.
Oh.
Huh?
''The little girl's
name is Mary.
''The little boy's
name is Tom.
''This is the barn.
''Mary and Tom
are in the hayloft.
''This is Mary's mother.
She is baking a pie.''
Hmm, she better stop bakin'
and go take a look in the barn.
[sputtering]
''My name is Molly Tobin.
My teacher is Johnny Brown.''
- It's real nice.
- Oh, thank you.
Um, guess you'll be
leavin' real soon.
I hear the money's rollin' in.
Hmm, I'll have to buy
some new clothes.
I've got $50.
It ain't enough.
What'd be enough, Molly?
I don't know,
enough so's me and my pa
could have a roof
over our heads
that don't leak
rain and cold.
Go on, Chick-a-Pen.
I got to know.
Enough so's I could have
a stove for heatin'
and a stove for cookin'
enough so's I could
have my own brass bed
have saucers
that match the cups.
And enough so's my pa
could stay in bed all day
with a jug, if he
had a hankerin' to.
And enough so's folks
would call me a lady.
Well, that'd take a helluva
lot more than $50.
That's why I got to find me
a miner with a rich claim.
I got a claim,
side of Hippo Mountain.
- Plenty of silver in it.
- Oh-ho!
No foolin',
a gentleman from New York
has been trying to buy it.
I ain't got much use for money.
I do alright.
If the Hippo Mountain
claim runs out
I'll find me another.
Find you another?
Just like that?
Sure. It's easy.
'Cause I got a talent for it.
Gold and silver
they just holler out to me.
Well, hell's fire!
Why don't you listen?
I take all I need
out of it..
...and I got my other piece
of land
with a cabin on it.
Well, that's real pretty land
with a stream and all.
Remember?
But-but it needs a woman.
Hmm.
Get yourself one.
A gal could be
happy there, Molly.
Why won't you settle
for happiness?
♪♪ I'll never say ♪♪
♪♪ No to you ♪♪
♪♪ Whatever you say or do ♪♪
♪♪ If you ask me to wait ♪♪
♪♪ For a lifetime ♪♪
♪♪ You know I'll gladly wait ♪♪
♪♪ For a lifetime or two ♪♪
♪♪ Just to look at you ♪♪
♪♪ I'll smile when you say ♪♪
♪♪ Be glad ♪♪
♪♪ I'll weep
if you want me sad ♪♪
♪♪ Today is tomorrow ♪♪
♪♪ If you want it so ♪♪
♪♪ I'll stay ♪♪
♪♪ Or I'll go ♪♪
♪♪ But I'll ♪♪
♪♪ Never say ♪♪
♪♪ No ♪♪
Oh, I-I'd never
even think twice.
I'd never even blink twice.
Ask me. Ask me
anything you want!
I want a house with
a lookin'-out window
over the valley.
One lookin'-out window
for the lady!
♪♪ I'll never
say no to you ♪♪
- I want a red silk dress.
- Yes.
- I wanna go see Denver.
- I want my own brass bed.
- Yes!
Oh, go jump in the lake.
Yes!
No, Johnny!
Ha ha!
♪♪ I'll never say no ♪♪
♪♪ Never say no ♪♪♪♪
[instrumental music]
No. No!
You stay away
from me, Johnny Brown!
You've got a danger sign on you,
big as a house.
And I swore I'd get me
a rich husband in Denver.
A rich husband,
love or no love?
That's right!
[sighs]
Uh, I left home to get away
from a scrawly life.
A-and the only way is
to marry the right man.
What makes you think
I ain't the right man?
'Cause you don't care
you and that mind
you don't work.
So...so just-just-just
stay away from me, Johnny Brown
'cause...'cause...'cause
I can't lie.
I-I-I do have
a feelin' for you.
♪♪ I'll smile ♪♪
♪♪ If you say ♪♪
♪♪ Be glad ♪♪
♪♪ I'll weep ♪♪
♪♪ If you want me sad ♪♪
♪♪ Today is tomorrow ♪♪
♪♪ If you want it so ♪♪
♪♪ I'll stay ♪♪
♪♪ Or I'll go ♪♪
♪♪ But I'll ♪♪
♪♪ Never say ♪♪
♪♪ No-o-o ♪♪♪♪
Oh!
[laughing]
Let me go!
[groaning]
- Let me..
- Aah!
You let me go.
Let me go.
Nobody's gonna stop me.
Nothing's gonna get me down!
Ah.
Argh!
[screaming]
[instrumental music]
♪♪ I'll ♪♪
♪♪ Never say no ♪♪
♪♪ To you ♪♪
[laughing]
♪♪ Whatever you say or do ♪♪
♪♪ And if you tell me ♪♪
♪♪ You want me to wait
for a lifetime ♪♪
♪♪ You know I'm gladly
going to wait ♪♪
♪♪ For a lifetime or two ♪♪
♪♪ Just to look at you ♪♪
♪♪ I'm gonna
break right out laughin' ♪♪
♪♪ If you tell me that you
want me to be glad ♪♪
♪♪ I'm going to cry
like a baby ♪♪
♪♪ If you say that you
want me to be sad ♪♪
♪♪ I'll laugh or cry ♪♪
♪♪ I'll sob or sigh ♪♪
♪♪ I'll stay or I'll go ♪♪
♪♪ But I'll never ♪♪
♪♪ Never ever ♪♪
♪♪ I'll never ever ♪♪
♪♪ Say no ♪♪♪♪
Howdy?
Ah, the way
you're prettied up
you think we was
going to church
instead of showing me a mine.
Didn't say I was gonna
show you a mine.
You said you was gonna show me
what you've been workin' on.
That's right. Hup!
[instrumental music]
Johnny Brown, I know this place.
You're taking me to that
little old cabin of yours.
You know better than that.
Now, hold your britches, missy.
I ain't taking you
to my little old cabin. Ho ho!
Oh, it's my big, new cabin.
(Molly)
'Oh, Johnny.'
Well..
...dip me and fry me.
Wait till you see
what I got to show you.
This here is the porch.
Two rockers for settin' out
on summer nights.
(Molly)
Ah, how nice.
This here's the main room.
I got a stove for heatin'.
And a, and-and a stove
for cookin'.
And-and cups with saucers
that match.
Oh.
Oh..
...you sure do remember things,
Johnny Brown.
Things you say, Chick-a-Pen.
Come-come on. Come on.
Come on.
There's a room for your pa.
You built a room for pa?
And a jug on the table
just waitin' for him.
- Oh.
- Come on. Come on.
[instrumental music]
Oh! Oh.
Oh.
You got yourself a bed.
I'll say that
for you, Johnny Brown.
You, you like it, Molly?
Oh.
Oh, I..
It's the most beautiful thing
I-I ever seen.
- Oh!
- Um, look here.
Now you can do your bathin'
inside the house.
Golly. Ain't that somethin'?
Oh, it sure is pretty.
Oh...oh..
...that bed.
It's so soft.
But real strong.
Oh, it come all the way
from Denver.
You done all this for me.
Nobody never done
nothing special
for me before...just for me..
...in my whole life.
We're gettin' ma-married today.
It's against all the things
I ever dreamed of.
It'd be against nature
for me to say no.
Besides, I-I sure couldn't stand
anybody else sleepin'
in that beautiful brass bed
with the stars shining--
- Ready?
- Ready for what?
What?
♪♪ Here comes the bride ♪♪
Come on. Come on, everybody.
♪♪ Here comes the bride
here comes the bride ♪♪
♪♪ Here comes the bride ♪♪
♪♪ Here comes the bride.. ♪♪♪♪
You look so lovely, my dear.
Congratulations, Molly darling.
Hurry up, father,
before she changes her mind.
I got her softened up real good.
Now, go on. Get started.
- You got the ring?
- Huh?
- The ring.
- Oh, the ring.
Yeah, I got the ring.
The ring. Uh, ring. Ring. Ring?
- I forgot the ring!
- It's alright.
- 'This will do for now.'
- This will do for now.
Come on...inside. Come on.
Oh, I forgot.
You, come on.
It's your weddin'.
[indistinct chatter]
Ha! Whee!
- Congratulations!
- Christmas, it's that way.
- That way.
- Come on. Goodnight.
Goodnight!
Goodnight, Polak!
[crying]
That was...beautiful wedding
I've ever seen.
Some-something wrong,
Mrs. Brown?
[crying]
A paper ring..
...and no wedding dress..
...and you're sozzled.
So was everybody.
It was a fine weddin'.
Not for me.
Not for me!
Oh, what have I
gone and done?
Oh, I've gone and married me
a-a drunken,
good-for-nothing miner
who don't even work
at minin' and..
And what's the use
of cups and saucers
if you don't care?
I let myself be bamboozled
by a b-brass bed
and a, and a cooking stove
and-and a room for pa
and a, and a lot
of fine talk and..
...and-and my heart
that went waboom
when you touched me.
[Molly crying]
'What have I gone and done?'
[crying]
Johnny?
Johnny!
[echoing]
Johnny! Johnny!
[instrumental music]
[music continues]
It's me, Chick-a-Pen.
Oh, Johnny!
Are you alright?
Sure, darlin'.
Oh..
That's good!
Now, I'm gettin' out!
- What for?
- 'What for?'
Leavin' me alone here
for three days
worryin' my heart out.
Wait, Mrs. Brown, don't you
wanna know where I've been?
- Oh, I can guess.
- No, you got it all wrong.
Now, here, look.
Lookie here.
Oh...whoa...whoa!
Three hundred thousand dollars.
Sold my claim to that
gentleman from New York.
Ah, it took me a while
to find and sign these papers
and get the cash but now
I'm back home and you
you ain't mad at me, are you?
Oh! Oh, Johnny.
I thought you was mad at me
for carrying on so
after the weddin'.
I-I thought you didn't want me.
- Oh, Chick-a-Pen!
- Oh, oh.
Calm down, girl.
Oh, I-I've been travelin'
for three days
and I ain't fit for
a bride in a fine brass bed.
Well, I better
go get washed up.
Uh, w-what are you gonna buy
with all that money?
Oh, my! I don't know.
Well, first,
we'll send for pa
and then, and then
we'll get you a fine gold watch
A-and you'll have
a real gold wedding ring..
...and a, and a red dress..
...and a, and a go-to-hell hat!
[laughing]
Oh...oh..
Oh...oh, my..
Uh...oh..
Oh, my.
Oh.
[instrumental music]
[music continues]
[dramatic music]
[paper crumpling]
[exhales]
[instrumental music]
[music continues]
[laughing]
[shivering]
[intense music]
[fire sizzling]
(Molly)
'Johnny? Is that you, Johnny?'
It's me, darlin'.
Having a little drink
to warm myself up.
That water sure is icy.
Your-your hair's real wet.
Oh, I was shaking
with the cold.
- Yeah.
- I...I'm fine now.
My backside's
hot as a griddle.
I was warming it by the fire.
Fire.
- Fire? What fire?
- The stove.
No! No! The money, no!
- 'What?'
- No!
Molly girl, what is it?
Oh, the money!
The money!
What-what's the matter?
You gone crazy?
No, oh, I hid the money
in the stove.
- Ow! Ooh!
- Water.
- Water!
- Oh! No, no, no.
[grunting]
Molly, girl,
you-you'll burn yourself!
- No. No.
- Get away from there!
Molly!
It's too late, Molly!
My ring's on fire!
My ring, look it's ashes!
Oh, the money
and my ring!
Everything's gone!
- Aah!
- Wait a minute!
- No! No.
- Now, Molly, wait, now listen.
- No, now, look!
- No! No.
Now, listen.
Look, it's only money.
I can get us more. No
- Listen to me, darling.
- No! No!
- Darling? Darling!
- No! No! No! Uh.
Darling?
[Molly grunts]
You ain't gonna wallop me?
What for?
It's me who lit the fire.
You ain't m-mad at me?
[scoffs]
Of course not!
Well, then what was you chasing
me around the room for?
'Cause you was runnin'. I
thought you's out of your skull.
- What was you running for?
- Uh..
Well, I was..
...I was just...scared,
that's all.
What?
I was just...sc-scared.
Of me?
Well, I-I thought..
...I thought
you was gonna wallop me.
I will wallop you if you don't
come on back to bed!
[sobbing]
- Oh, Johnny!
- Oh, now, now, come on.
You don't wanna keep
that sobbing up all night.
- Shh, shh, shh.
- I-I-I just can't seem to stop.
Oh, I don't want you
crying over the money.
- Now, shh, shh, shh.
- I ain't.
It's you being
so forgiving that..
[Molly crying]
Now we'll never
get to Denver!
[Molly crying]
[sighs]
Well, if you're gonna keep up
that weeping and wailing
might as well go out right now
and find me another mine.
Johnny? Come back!
Talk to me,
gold and silver!
Holler loud, 'cause I got
a gal that burns money up!
Johnny! Johnny!
Come back!
You gonna stop that crying?
Yes! Yes!
Oh, yes, Johnny! Yes!
Say you love me.
I love you, Johnny.
[laughs]
That's better.
[pickaxe clangs]
Oh, Joh.. Joh..
- Oh-oh!
- Yee-haw!
[screaming]
Ladies and gentlemen
we are now entering
Pennsylvania Avenue.
Up and down
this beautiful avenue
are the homes
of the Sacred Thirty-Six.
The Creme de laCreme
of Denver.
The house on your left..
...is the home of Mrs. McGraw
the acknowledged leader
of Denver Society.
And this is the new showplace
of Pennsylvania Avenue.
'It has just been remodeled
by Mr. and Mrs. J.J. Brown'
owner of the little Johnny Mine
the richest gold strike
in the history of Colorado.
This mine has already
produced $10 million.
(male #3)
'Fourteen million,
and plenty more'
'where that come from.'
Good-bye, folks!
Have yourself a nice ride.
And don't believe everything
that fellow tells you.
- Pa!
- Goodbye! Goodbye.
I told you you mustn't do that
every day, now, pa.
- It ain't elegant.
- I got nothing else to do.
- Funny.
- Leave it lay.
How many times
do I gotta tell you
I like a lived-in feeling
in one room of this fancy house.
Alright, pa.
And tell Hotchkiss to fetch me
a fresh jug.
Ooh. Sure, pa.
Thank you, darling.
Hotchkiss!
- Yes, madam?
- Get my pa another jug.
Yes, madam.
[whistling]
What's that?
Present.
Ooh! What is it?
It's a new wedding ring.
What's wrong with this one?
That ain't the one
you was married with.
[Molly chuckles]
I got you another, more fitting.
Now, don't you never,
ever take it off
unless I tell you to,
Chick-a-Pen.
Promise me.
I promise.
Oh! A-A cigar band!
Injun head and all!
And-and rubies
and sapphires and diamonds!
The-the-the man said there ain't
another like it
in the whole world.
Oh, it's real
beautiful, Johnny.
Thank you.
I'm glad you like it.
What do you wanna do today?
I don't know.
Wanna go out and buy something?
- We done that yesterday.
- Mm.
Wanna go for a walk?
Mm-hmm.
Yeah. Let's play another game
of blackjack.
[knock on door]
- Yeah?
- Excuse me, madam.
Mr. Cartwright from the bank is
downstairs.
Well, you tell him
we'll be right there.
Thank you, madam.
Johnny, you go down
and talk to him.
I gotta find my shoes. Oh!
- Hurry up.
- Yeah.
Uh! I'll be right down!
Oh...oh!
[instrumental music]
[panting]
Howdy, Mr. Cartwright!
Nice to see you.
Good afternoon, Mrs. Brown.
How's things at the bank,
Mr. Cartwright?
- Fine.
- Have a seat, Mr. Cartwright.
Thank you. Nice weather
we've been having.
- Oh, yes.
- Oh, sit here.
This one's a good chair.
Cost a pot of money.
- Thank you.
- Oh, my.
Oh, it's a, it's a pleasure
to be seeing
one of Denver's
Sacred Thirty-Six in our home.
- Yeah.
- Sit-sit-sit down.
Oh, uh, it gets kinda
lonesome around here.
That's why we thought
it'd be a fine idea for you
to come here this time, instead
of us running to the bank.
Yes, I understand.
I have the money right here.
Oh, that's fine.
Now-now, you just sit a while.
Oh, no, I must get back
to the bank.
(Tobin)
'Hotchkiss!'
Hotchkiss, where's me jug?
Pa! Say hello to Mr. Cartwright!
Mr. Cartwright,
say hello to my pa.
Howdy, Mr. Cartwright.
Nice to see a new face.
It gets pretty lonesome
around here. Hotchkiss!
You think with the place
crawling with flunkies
a thirsty man could
get a jug now and then.
Well, don't you
want to count it?
- Oh, guess you've done that.
- Yeah.
Here.
Oh, how about some fudge?
Not right now, thank you.
Well...oh, you keep that.
- Yeah.
- Thank you, no.
I-I-I must get back to the bank.
- Oh.
Well, uh, drop in and see us
again sometime, Mr. Cartwright.
- Uh, yeah. Bring your friends.
- Yeah.
Oh, bring Mrs. Cartwright.
- We're always here.
- Yes.
Good heavens!
I've never seen anything
like that before.
(Mr. Cartwright)
'Eh, it's solid gold!'
Eh, yeah, that's what it is.
Uh, I presume
the ''B'' stands for Brown?
Well, it don't stand
for backhouse.
[both laughs]
Oh, uh, Mr. Cartwright,
you come back real soon.
Well, ha-ha thanks again,
Mr. Cartwright.
You come see us real soon.
- Yes.
- Yeah?
Oh, uh
'what's going on over there?'
Oh, it must be the caterer
delivering things
for Mrs. McGraw's party.
Party? What party?
Mrs. McGraw gives a party
every year
when her roses bloom. Goodbye.
- Uh, bye.
- Bye.
Oh, ain't that wonderful?
What?
She gives a party
when her roses bloom.
Oh, my.
[instrumental music]
Oh, good evening, father!
I believe you all know
Monsignor Ryan.
You've been fortunate
in the weather, Mrs. McGraw.
- The garden is most attractive.
- Oh, thank you.
I, uh, I haven't been here
since the house next
door was remodeled.
Oh, yes. Dreadful, isn't it?
But at least the noise
of the remodeling is over.
I've seen Mrs. Brown
on the Avenue.
She's a little...strange.
- Oh!
- They overpay their servants.
The entire economy
of Pennsylvania Avenue
has been affected.
I'm told they drive up and down
the avenue while she shouts
greetings to passers-by.
- Oh, dear.
- Well, perhaps they're lonely.
Have you called on them
to welcome them, Mrs. McGraw?
Mrs. Fitzgerald?
Uh, monsignor, have you
seen the roses?
Thank you, Jeeves.
Oh, my!
Ooh! Evening, folks!
Uh, Molly Brown's the name.
Uh, this here's Johnny Brown
owner of the Little Johnny.
'And richest man
in the United States.'
- 'Molly.'
- Oh, there you be, neighbor!
(Molly)
'Howdy!'
Uh, Brown's the name.
Uh, we, we're the ones from
that little shack next door.
How do you do, Mrs. Brown?
Great!
Uh, to tell you the truth
the Denver water is a little
hard on the kidneys.
But we love it here.
Oh, uh, Mr. Brown!
- Hmm?
- 'Say hello to Mrs. McGraw.'
Sure. Howdy.
Uh, oh, we-we was out
for a walk and, and saw
your lights was on,
so we just thought we'd drop in.
Uh, may I present
monsignor Ryan?
Well, hello there, monsignor.
Glad to make your acquaintance.
- Yeah. Mr. Brown.
- Howdy.
Oh, uh, I read
about your school fund
in the paper, father.
Here's $5,000, and good luck.
[indistinct chattering]
Well, I hardly know what to say.
- God bless you, Mrs. Brown.
- Oh.
Well, what you standing
there for, Mr. Brown?
Match my 5,000.
Or be high-class and double it.
(Johnny)
'Why, sure. Glad to.
Here, father.'
One, two, three..
Already took a few million
out of God's good earth.
Guess he deserves
a little kickback.
That should see them
into heaven.
Well, maybe it'll grease
the gates a little.
...nine, ten. Ten thousand.
I'm sorry it's all in ones.
God bless you both.
- Fifteen thousand dollars.
- Uh, think nothing of it.
Once took 20 times that
just to warm J.J.'s backside.
Besides, this here's
our home now
and-and-and we want to belong.
Got to keep up with Mrs. McGraw.
How much did you kick..
Uh...how much did you
kick in, Gladys?
Oh, well, as a matter
of fact, I..
...I haven't made
my contribution yet.
- You haven't?
- No.
What's the matter
with you, Gladys?
You got plenty, I hear!
- Now, Roberts!
- Dinner is served, madam.
Thank you. Well, shall we?
[indistinct chatter]
Oh!
Oh. Hi.
Howdy.
Well..
[sighs]
Uh, Mrs. McGraw regrets
that there isn't room
at the table for two more.
(Roberts)
'Uh, she hopes
you will excuse her.'
Oh, well, we just popped in.
Uh, tell her
it was great meeting her
and-and not to give
the Browns a second thought.
Yes, madam.
I'm sorry you aren't staying
but I assume
you had other plans.
Oh, yes. We're pretty busy.
You-you go on inside
before your supper gets cold.
Goodnight.
May God go with you.
- Goodnight.
- See you in church.
Yes.
- Come on.
- Oh, wait. Oh, wait.
Oh, I just gotta see
how they do.
Uh, come on.
[instrumental music]
Oh, my!
Ain't that pretty?
Well, uh, there's, there's
plenty of room at that table.
[chuckles]
It sure smells good, Gladys.
Eat hearty, folks!
[music continues]
[[door closes]
Come on, Moll. Come on.
[instrumental music]
Wasn't that fine?
All them beautiful people.
Everything trimmed so gorgeous
and, and the people
as trimmed, too.
Oh, the good lord outdid itself
on Pennsylvania Avenue
when we're right smack
in the middle of it.
- Mm-hmm.
- Did you have a good time?
Mm. We had more fun back
in Leadville by accident
than they're having
there on purpose.
They're a bunch of cold fish.
Come on.
Oh, no, that's dignity,
Mr. Brown.
Dignity.
And we're gonna get us some.
They could have made room
for us.
There was plenty
of room at that table.
- Well, howdy!
- Howdy, Shamus!
- 'Howdy, folks!'
- She knows my name.
I know plenty.
Come in, come in,
you pretty thing.
- Evening.
We're havin' a bite to eat.
Come in and sit awhile.
Thank you kindly.
- 'Howdy!'
- Howdy!
Hey, how about,
uh, dish of stew?
Oh, I'd rather have a beer.
Oh, pa.
Well, that was sure
a dreary party, wasn't it?
- Was you there?
- No, but I was watching.
I'm Mrs. McGraw's ma.
Well!
Well, howdy, Ms. McGraw.
Not Mrs. McGraw. Grogan.
Me daughter Gladys
married a McGraw
but I'm Mrs. Grogan,
Buttercup Grogan.
How come you ain't
at the party, Buttercup?
Ain't never invited
to Gladys' parties.
She keeps me hid upstairs.
- Hid?
- When she has company.
She's the leader
of Denver Society, you know.
Well, now, that ain't a nice way
to treat you, Mrs. Grogan.
Oh, I don't mind.
Them friends of hers with their
pinkies up,
ain't my kind of folks.
[laughs]
Well, it's sure good to be here.
Took me a little time
to get up the nerve to come.
What are you going
to do about it?
About what?
About Gladys and the way
she gave you
the brush-off tonight.
(Buttercup)
'Wasn't neighborly,
and that's a fact!'
Well, there wasn't
any room at the table.
- Bull-sugar!
[both laughs]
Gladys is giving you
the treatment.
Don't you let her.
Nah, Moll doesn't need
Mrs. McGraw.
Well, she does.
You're living here.
You've got to belong.
But Denver's giving
you the go-by!
It is true. We get pretty
lonesome around here.
Hold your tongue, pa!
We're doing fine!
No, we ain't doing fine
and that's a fact.
You ain't going
about this right.
You can't just yell ''hello''
to folks in the street.
You must invite them formal
to your house
with printed invitations.
A party!
With invitations
printed in gold!
That's the ticket!
Oh, we'll give the biggest
high-tone hellbender of a party
Pennsylvania Avenue ever seen!
- A flaming tote!
- A randy dan!
With a band playing music,
like at Mrs. McGraw's
only bigger and louder!
[laughing]
[all laughing]
[instrumental music]
Come on back, Chick-a-Pen.
If anybody was to come,
they'd know for sure
this here is where
the Browns live.
Hell, honey, you've got it
writ on everything
from the weathervane
to the hitching post.
Now, come on.
It's after 10 o'clock.
[music continues]
I'm sorry it turned out
like this, Molly.
I bet it was Gladys
what gave you the axe.
I should have known.
I am walking
Buttercup home, Moll.
- Goodnight, Buttercup.
- 'Goodnight, Molly.'
Thanks for coming.
[door closes]
I'm sorry there ain't
no party, monsignor.
Sit down a minute, Molly.
Johnny.
I guess the Sacred Thirty-Six
just don't want no part of us.
Molly...Molly..
...this is not New York
or Paris.
Denver society is only
in its second generation.
The veneer is thin.
Now, true aristocrats
might accept you.
But here, you're
a painful reminder
of where they came from.
You're unschooled,
and you're full
of unharnessed enthusiasm
and Denver isn't
sophisticated enough
to appreciate that.
Ah, we should have stayed
in the hills where we belong.
May I make a suggestion?
Shoot, father.
Take a trip.
'A nice long tour of Europe.'
'You'll enjoy it
and you'll acquire'
'a little polish.'
Polish.
Like what?
Learn something
about art and music.
Learn manners.
Get a smatterin' of languages.
All that just to show
Mrs. McGraw?
Go ahead, father.
I'm learnin' already.
I've said enough.
I think you understand.
I'll say goodnight now.
Thanks for the advice, father.
You're right.
We sure are ignorant.
But we're gonna get schooled and
harnessed
and, and-and be second
generation if it kills us.
It won't.
Goodnight, Molly.
- Johnny.
- Goodnight, father.
Thanks, again.
Look at it, Johnny.
Ain't it beautiful?
Pennsylvania Avenue,
I'll admit you gave me
a nose full of splinters
but it's all good wood
from the very best doors!
Come on, Moll.
Now, we're going back
to Leadville.
Never.
Oh, we ain't staying here
where we're not wanted.
Johnny!
I can't go back to Leadville.
We gotta go one way
or the other
and ahead is better
than back.
I know what's back there.
Ahead is something new.
Maybe better, maybe not.
But I got to find out.
We don't belong in Europe!
They'll split their satin
britches laughing at us.
♪♪ I'll never say no to you ♪♪
I mean it, Mock-Moll.
♪♪ Whatever you say or do ♪♪
We ain't going!
♪♪ Today is tomorrow ♪♪
♪♪ If you want it so ♪♪
We're going back to Leadville,
where we belong.
♪♪ I'll stay or I'll go ♪♪
♪♪ But I'll never say.. ♪♪♪♪
Oh...we'll go to hell
and back if you like.
Oh! I love you, Johnny.
- Oh.
Now, Mr. Brown..
♪♪ We're gonna learn
to read and write ♪♪
♪♪ In French ♪♪
♪♪ Ha ha ♪♪
♪♪ We're gonna see
what there is to see ♪♪
♪♪ In French ♪♪
♪♪ For every one step backward ♪♪
♪♪ We'll go two steps forward ♪♪
♪♪ Till we stake us
a claim on dignity ♪♪
♪♪ In French ♪♪
[both laugh]
Uh, hear that, Mrs. McGraw?
The Browns are having a party!
[Johnny laughs]
And we ain't down yet!
- Yeah!
- Woo-hoo!
- Ha!
- Yeah!
- Ha ha ha!
[both shouting]
[instrumental music]
[music continues]
Monsieur.
Sieur. Sieur.
- Sier.
- Sieur.
- Sieur
- Bon. Sieur.
- Pa..
-No, pas ah.
- Eur. - Ah!
- Eur. - Ah.
- Eur.
- Ah.
- AH.
- Eur. - Ah!
Eur.
[off-key piano music]
[whistling]
[instrumental music]
Psst!
[music continues]
[both laughing]
Moll! Hey, we got a new friend.
And guess what.
He's a real live prince.
Oh, ain't that something?
Oh, 'cause look what I got
and she's a grand duchess.
(Johnny)
'Well!'
Howdy.
Howdy?
Oh! Oh-oh-oh, howdy.
[both laugh]
- Well, howdy.
- Howdy, madame
Ohh! Whoop-de-do!
[laughs]
Pardon.
Bonsoir, Elise Cherie.
Oh, Cher Louis.
Oh, you two know each other.
Ain't that nice?
Yeah.
[all laughing]
[operatic singing]
[speaking in foreign language]
[all laughing]
Molly, dear, you are funny.
Here I'm funny.
In Denver,I'm vulgar.
I guess it's like,
here you eat snails
at home, we step on them.
[all laughing]
She has finally learned
to eat snails.
Mmm. With this sauce,
you could eat erasers.
[all laughing]
[indistinct chatter]
Thank you. Thank you.
Uh, thank you.
My, I, uh..
...I-I can't,
I can't find words.
You know
that's unusual for me.
Uh...I want you to know
I appreciate how sweet
you've been to I and J.J.
Uh...J.J. and me.
Me and J.J?
Well, anyway, as we say,
merci beaucoup!
- The candles, Molly.
- Oh!
[cheering]
Oh, thank you.
Oh...thank you.
Um, grazie.
Many happy returns, Molly.
Oh, you Frenchies sure are
a kissy bunch of bananas.
[all laughing]
It's because we love you, Molly.
You've been a breath
of fresh air, you know.
Oh! I'm a bag
of wind, alright.
No, darling, it's true.
You're a stimulant
to all of us.
You like everybody
and everything.
I'm interested in everything
'cause I don't
know nothin'.
That's not true, Molly.
Oh, but I'm learnin'.
I'm really learnin'.
I-I can, I can sit through
the opera without going to sleep
and, here you are,
and I can paint a bowl of fruit
that'll draw flies.
[all laughing]
And I can say
''hello'' and ''how much''
in ten different languages.
Hell, I'm, I'm just
a hog for knowledge.
[all laughing]
Molly, what did Johnny
give you for your birthday?
Ohh, something real sweet
with a lot
of sentiment attached.
A $300,000 in cash
and a box of matches.
- Ohh!
- Oh!
Yes, he told us how you
burnt the money
in your little stove.
[all laughing]
Ecouter! Ecouter.
(all)
Oh!
♪♪ Belly up Belly up
to the bar boys ♪♪
♪♪ Better loosen your belts ♪♪
♪♪ Only drink
when you're all alone ♪♪
♪♪ Or with somebody else ♪♪
♪♪ Somebody else ♪♪♪♪
It wasn't very nice
of you to stay away
from my birthday party.
You went without me.
I had to leave early
with the Grand Duchess
to arrange the place cards.
You said you'd join us.
I didn't think I'd be missed.
Not with the prince there.
In case you don't know,
and I think you do
he's gone on you.
Hmm, so what if he is?
That's the way in Europe.
- Hmm.
- You're in a mood.
I am?
You've been in a mood for days.
I sure have.
I'm going plumb crazy.
Oh, it ain't the prince.
I know that ain't serious.
It's just that I've had
culture up to here.
I've drunk tea till my eyes are
bubbling. Wine till I'm woozy.
I can't get the hang
of their lingo
and their manners.
I'm homesick for my own country.
- Do I get to talk?
- All the time!
- I got something to tell you.
- Ladies first, Mr. Brown.
I just wanted you to know
I-I thought
it was time we went home.
Well, that's what
I was gonna say!
You-you ain't fooling me?
Mm-mm.
[laughs]
Colorado! Home!
I'll get the tickets tomorrow.
Oh, you better get about, uh,
about ten of 'em.
- Ten of 'em?
- Mm.
I've invited the crowned heads
of Europe to be our guests.
Tonight at the party I promised
the grand duchess and prince
we'd show 'em Denver.
'Of course, they have
to bring along their friends'
'cause royalty don't even
go to the shed unescorted.
How's that go again?
You're showing off Denver
to the crowned heads
or the crown heads
off to Denver?
And Mrs. McGraw.
Mrs. McGraw? Humph!
I wouldn't give a widow's wart
for Mrs. McGraw.
Mm, Molly Brown,
you're either lying
to me or to yourself.
When you gonna stop
trying to be Mrs. McGraw?
You ain't got it in you
to be like her.
I can be anything I want.
Maybe.
I liked the old Molly best.
Well, that's too bad, J.J.
'cause the old me ain't..
...isn't no more.
I've had a grand time
putting the new me together.
And I'm sorry
you don't take to us
'cause it was you
who paid the bills.
I'm going to keep right on
paying them, Chick-a-Pen.
'Cause I love you
with a heart and a half.
♪♪ We got dignity and culture ♪♪
♪♪ We can parlez francais ♪♪
♪♪ We've spent
a million dollars ♪♪
♪♪ On the rue de la paix ♪♪
♪♪ But none of that will matter ♪♪
♪♪ Once we're on our way to ♪♪
♪♪ Colorado our home ♪♪
♪♪ Colorado ♪♪
♪♪ Our ♪♪
♪♪ Home ♪♪♪♪
[instrumental music]
[crowd applauding]
[crowd cheering]
Howdy, everybody.
Welcome. Glad to see
you're here at last.
[indistinct chattering]
- Good evening.
- Good evening, Mrs. Brown.
Good evening.
Oh, how do you do?
- How do you do?
- Oh, thank you for coming.
- I'm happy to be here, dear.
- Oh.
Good evening, father.
- Molly, you look beautiful.
- Oh, thank you.
And they're all
here this evening.
Good evening. Ah..
Good heavens.
Look at this place.
It's frightening.
What period would you call it?
I'd call it the reign of terror.
Touch of red might help.
She likes red.
- Good evening, Roberts.
- Good evening, madam.
I figured I needed him
a lot more than you did.
- Welcome, Gladys.
- Thank you.
You know Mr. Broderick,
of course.
I don't know as I do.
Then let me introduce you to one
of your guests, Mrs. Brown.
This is Mr. Malcolm Broderick
of the Denver record.
Oh, how do you do,
Mr. Broderick?
- How do you do?
- You're the society writer.
Uh, I used to read your
society talk every day.
Thank you, Mrs. Brown.
I hope you found it interesting.
No, but it was good practice
for my reading.
I see.
And how do you find Denver
after being away so long?
I don't know, mon ami.
But I'm going to find out.
One thing's for damn sure
this time we ain't putting up
with no rocky mountain rudeness.
We're second- generation now.
Oh.
Uh...may I quote you,
Mrs. Brown?
Uh, bet your bottom.
Write it all down.
And talk about your
Sacred Thirty-Six
wait till you take
a look at my royal flush.
Now, Roberts.
Shall we?
[fanfare music]
His Highness,
Prince Louis de Laniere.
[instrumental music]
Bonsoir, Molly.
- Toujours si belle.
- Merci. Permette-moiz.
[speaking in French]
Mrs. McGraw.
Mrs. McGraw..
[speaking in French]
[Louis speaking in French]
(Roberts)
'The Count
and Countess Feranti.'
- Buona sera, Molly. - Buona sera.
Buona sera, signora
[speaking in Italian]
- Buona sera, signora.
- How-how-how do you do?
(Roberts)
'Baron Karl Ludwig
von Ettenburg!'
[Baron speaks
in foreign language]
[Molly speaks
[Baron speaks
in foreign language]
Ooh!
Oh, what a beautiful painting.
Is it one of yours, my dear?
Uh, yes, Herr Baron.
I have one
of Mrs. Brown's paintings
hanging in my schloss.
Guten abend. Guten abend.
That's his castle on the rhine.
- How do you do, Mrs. McGraw?
- How do you do?
Do you paint, my dear?
Uh, no.
What a pity.
How do you do?
Her Royal Highness
the Grand Duchess
Elise Lupavinova!
You're supposed
to curtsy, Gladys.
She's a royal highness.
[instrumental music]
Molly, dear, I've been
admiring your magnificent piano.
I hope you'll play us
some Chopin later on.
Do you play, Mrs. McGraw?
Oh, no, Duchess..
Uh, Your Highness.
Your royal, uh..
Roy-roy..
No.
- Sorry.
- What a pity.
How do you do?
Mrs. Buttercup Grogan!
Hello, Gladys.
[chuckles]
[laughing]
[band music]
Surprise! Surprise!
[all screaming]
Uh, ladies and gentlemen..
...these are our
amis from Leadville.
Amis, hell.
These are our friends!
(all)
Yeah!
[all laughing]
♪♪ Standing here
is Christmas Morgan ♪♪
♪♪ Sings in the choir
and pumps the organ ♪♪
♪♪ If I should yell
I'm a-drownin', Morgan ♪♪
♪♪ He'd come chargin' in ♪♪
♪♪ He's my friend ♪♪
♪♪ And he'll stay my friend ♪♪
♪♪ Doesn't matter what
the other people say ♪♪
♪♪ He's my friend
to the bitter end ♪♪
♪♪ Even though
the bitter end's ♪♪
♪♪ A million years away ♪♪
♪♪ Call him Tobin
or call him Shamus ♪♪
♪♪ Beat him in a fight
and you'll be famous ♪♪
♪♪ If I should yell
they got me, Shamus ♪♪
♪♪ He'd come chargin' in ♪♪
♪♪ He's my friend ♪♪
♪♪ And he'll stay my friend ♪♪
♪♪ Doesn't matter what
the other people say ♪♪
♪♪ He's my friend
to the bitter end ♪♪
♪♪ Even though
the bitter end's ♪♪
♪♪ A million years away ♪♪
[instrumental music]
♪♪ This wee lass
is my good friend Buttercup ♪♪
♪♪ Makes me heart
go flip and flutter up ♪♪
♪♪ Talk behind my back
to Buttercup ♪♪
♪♪ She'll come chargin' in ♪♪
♪♪ She's my friend ♪♪
♪♪ And she'll stay my friend ♪♪
♪♪ Doesn't matter what
the other people say ♪♪
♪♪ She's my friend
to the bitter end ♪♪
♪♪ Even though
the bitter end's ♪♪
♪♪ A million years away ♪♪
[instrumental music]
♪♪ Denver ladies next
to a Duchess ♪♪
♪♪ Sashay around like
they're walking on crutches
♪♪ If anyone bothers
this here Duchess ♪♪
♪♪ I'll come chargin' in ♪♪
♪♪ She's my friend ♪♪
♪♪ And she'll stay my friend ♪♪
♪♪ Doesn't matter what
the other people say ♪♪
♪♪ She's my friend
to the bitter end ♪♪
♪♪ Even though
the bitter end's ♪♪
♪♪ A million years away ♪♪
♪♪ The most extraordinary
thing in town ♪♪
♪♪ Is the perfectly
charming Molly Brown ♪♪
♪♪ And if anyone
dares to presume ♪♪
♪♪ To display
a disparaging frown ♪♪
♪♪ They'll have me
to reckon with ♪♪
♪♪ And me ♪♪
♪♪ She's my friend ♪♪
♪♪ And she'll stay my friend ♪♪
♪♪ Doesn't matter what
the other people say ♪♪
♪♪ She's my friend
to the bitter end ♪♪
♪♪ Even though
the bitter end's ♪♪
♪♪ A million years away ♪♪♪♪
[crowd cheering]
[music continues]
[whistling]
[shouting]
[laughs]
And, yeah.
[music continues]
[crowd cheering]
[growling]
[laughs]
Yee-haw!
[crowd cheering]
[music continues]
[laughing]
[cheering]
Shocking.
It's a dance for a...
a bawdy house.
My dear, that's the way she
earned her living in Leadville.
[laughing]
Oh, no.
[intense music]
[all screaming]
- Mother!
- Shut up, Gladys!
Timber!
[screaming]
[grunts]
No!
No. Please stop!
[grunting]
[instrumental continues]
[all screaming]
Well, at last,
this place looks lived-in.
- Good morning, Mr. Tobin.
- Mornin'.
Molly sure knew
what she was doing
when she made this place red.
The blood don't show.
You're a better man
than I thought, Mr. Roberts.
You did fine last night.
Thank you very much, sir.
It's dreadful, simply dreadful!
You know, Mr. Broderick
isn't a reporter.
He's an ignorant,
spiteful barbarian.
But it's lies, all lies.
Everybody knows
the Merry Christmas saloon
ain't no fancy house.
And the things he
quotes me saying
all those blanks
that stand for bad words.
Well, I guess I did
let a couple go.
''One thing's for blank sure
said Mrs. Brown.
''This time,
we ain't putting up
''with no blank, blank
rocky mountain rudeness.''
And worst of all, it ain't
even on the society page.
It's on the sports page.
It isn't
only Broderick, Molly.
It's all
of your Sacred Thirty-Six.
They've been sending
flowers and invitations
to Louis, to me,
and to the others.
But nothing
for you and Johnny.
I've never known
such uncivilized behavior.
Things were pretty uncivilized
here last night..
...but it wasn't your fault.
[sighs]
Louis and I both think
that we should go home
as soon as possible.
- Yes.
- All of us.
You've outgrown Denver.
You cannot exist
here, my darling.
The air is much too thin.
Sail with us on the next boat.
Oh.
You are not
the same here, cherie.
You were free
and happy in Europe.
Come back, let me make
a happy world for you again.
Louis..
...let us go and
tell the others.
(man on speaker)
'You all read
in this morning's paper'
'about a free-for-all battle'
'that took place last night'
'in this million-dollar
pile of rock.'
No!
No! I'll fix you!
...named ''Leadville''
Johnny Brown
the guests were attacked
by drunken miners.
It is generally known
that although Mrs. Brown
now buys her jewels
by the bushel
only a short while ago,
she was a bar girl
in a mining town saloon.
[gunshots]
[screaming]
Get out of here
before I load up again!
Get out of here,
you lying, stinkin' polecat!
Molly! Are you out
of your skull?
Oh, they came sightseeing.
I'll give them
something to see.
They ain't turning us
into no side show!
Looks to me like you're making
it a three-ring circus.
Firing out the window like
a liquored-up redskin.
Liquored-up?
You're a fine one to be
bellerin' about liquored-up.
You and your
Leadville friends.
Well, let me tell you something.
I wish we'd kept
at it till we had
this whole house
tore clear to shreds.
I hate this place!
Good, because we're leaving.
We're going home to Europe.
No, we're going home,
alright, to Leadville.
No, we are not.
I ain't living in Colorado.
The air is much too thin.
Then you'd better learn
to breathe it
'cause we're living
in Leadville.
- I'm living in Europe.
- You're my wife.
You live under the roof
I give you.
And it's gonna be in Leadville.
Don't talk so bossy,
Johnny Brown.
I got only one life to live
and I ain't living it
in Leadville.
Europe's been good to me.
I learned a lot.
And if you're too plumb stubborn
or too plumb lazy
or too plumb stupid to learn
then the devil with you!
[dramatic music]
Maybe we're mismatched,
Mr. Brown.
What you and me
want out of this life
sure is different.
You don't know what you want.
You got rich too quick.
You-you're all mixed up.
I'm asking you
for the last time.
You coming with me?
[music continues]
Alright. You go to Europe
with your prince.
I'm not going.
I'm saying ''no'' to you at last.
No. No!
[music continues]
[dramatic music]
[sighs]
[music continues]
Molly, what happened to us?
[echoing]
To us..
♪♪ I'll never say no ♪♪
♪♪ Never say no ♪♪
♪♪ Never say no ♪♪♪♪
Damn you!
[echoing]
Damn you, Molly Brown!
Molly Brown!
[echoing]
I just got one favor
to ask you, Molly.
We said goodbye, didn't we?
Alright. Now just stay away.
Don't you never come back.
When you say goodbye,
mean goodbye.
Remember? I said goodbye
to Leadville once.
Well, I meant it, didn't I?
♪♪ Said goodbye ♪♪
♪♪ And walked away ♪♪
♪♪ Walked away ♪♪
♪♪ From all I know ♪♪
♪♪ From the sky and the trees ♪♪
♪♪ And the snow-capped
mountains ♪♪
♪♪ Said goodbye
and left forever ♪♪
♪♪ Because ♪♪
♪♪ I loved you ♪♪
♪♪ Oh I could say goodbye ♪♪
♪♪ To many things ♪♪
♪♪ Deep ♪♪
♪♪ Inside my heart ♪♪
♪♪ I could easily
take that heart ♪♪
♪♪ And tear it free ♪♪
♪♪ From every kind of memory ♪♪
♪♪ And I could say ♪♪
♪♪ Goodbye someday ♪♪
♪♪ To life itself ♪♪
♪♪ No matter when.. ♪♪
Would you stay away, Molly?
Just stay away!
♪♪ For I could never ♪♪
♪♪ Say goodbye to you ♪♪
♪♪ Again ♪♪♪♪
[instrumental music]
I ordered a Nebuchadnezzar
of champagne.
Good thing he's a prince.
I sure couldn't afford a king.
[laughing]
With Molly, I am a king
because she is a queen.
Well, a toast to our own queen
Molly, international Molly
queen of the world.
Hear, hear.
[dramatic music]
Queen of the world..
...at last.
Queen of the world.
Here is my scepter.
Hmm. Here is my crown.
[crowd laughing]
I'm queen of the world
so bow.
[crowd laughing]
I'm Molly Tobin,
queen of the lard pail.
Bow.
Curtsy.
[music continues]
Well...drop my drawers.
It's Gladys McGraw.
Aren't you going to curtsy?
No, I guess you aren't.
And why should you?
I'm a vulgar,
extravagant, ignorant
nouveau-riche
American expatriate.
Clowning for
a bunch of people
I don't know
and don't care about.
Just a figure of fun.
[music continues]
Nice to see you, Gladys.
[indistinct chatter]
And this is what I've become.
I guess last of all
comes something
you can't buy with money.
Last of all, it's just
living with yourself.
Maybe I'm getting there.
Maybe that's
where I'm getting.
Johnny used to say
''why don't you
settle for happiness?''
But I thought happiness
was all the things I was doing..
...was what I wanted..
...was what I dreamed of.
I don't know.
[sighs]
Seem to be saying that
pretty often nowadays
''I don't know.
I don't know.''
A letter from Johnny.
''Dear Mrs. Brown,
the time has come.
''You can take the ring off now.
''Sincerely...J.J. Brown.''
Hmm.
He can't even
spell ''sincerely''.
But he was the one
who taught me to read.
[Molly crying]
Oh. Oh, uncle.
[sobbing]
Uncle!
Uncle?
It's an old
American expression..
...for when you're down.
And I'm down.
I'm down real low.
[music continues]
You and I, Louis..
...we're just fooling ourselves.
Forgive me.
I know it's been rough on you.
I have tried..
...but it's against my nature.
Love is funny.
It's a lot harder to mine..
...gold or silver.
I had a rich claim..
...but I wasn't working it.
So-so I lost it.
[music continues]
Do you really believe
he no longer means
what he wrote
inside this ring?
Inside the ring?
The inscription.
Didn't know there
was an inscription.
Never had it off since
the day he put it on.
Made me promise not to.
''Always remember two things
''that I love you..
''...and the name
of the bank.''
[sobbing]
Maybe I...ain't down yet.
[instrumental music]
(female #1)
'Good evening. It's cold.'
[intense music]
[thud]
[foghorn blaring]
[siren wailing]
- Oh, my God. George!
- 'Mama! '
- George!
- Don't get excited.
- Now, now.
- We're all going to die.
Stop it!
Stop it! Sit down!
Sit down!
You're rocking the boat!
Stop yelling!
[sobbing]
We're going to die.
No, we ain't!
I ain't ready to die!
Hell, I'm just
learning how to live.
There you are, honey.
Now, you keep warm.
- Thank you, dear.
- Now stop crying.
You too, crying
ain't gonna help.
Here. Take these.
Now, you hold on real tight.
Huh?
I don't want to die.
Oh, God!
Ladies and gent..
...did I ever tell you
about the time
I was a bar girl in a saloon?
I sang a song and I'm gonna
teach you now..
...and you're gonna
learn all the words.
- Oh.
- You, too.
(female #2)
'We'll never make it.
We're gonna sink.'
Not with Molly Brown on board.
That ship may be down,
but not me.
I'm unsinkable! No!
I survived the Colorado floods
when I
was six months old,
so this is nothing.
So we're gonna be alright
if we keep our heads.
Hey, let's sing!
[band music]
''Denver's heroine,
our own Mrs. J.J. Brown
''who's now known
throughout the world
''as the Unsinkable Molly Brown
''returns to Denver today.
''When interviewed
''during her triumphant week
in New York
''she made light of her heroism
despite the glowing reports
''from her fellow passengers.
''She said,''I sure
as blank wasn't ready
''''for a blank,
blank watery grave
''''so I just blank well
''''took the others
along with me.''
''On her last day in New York
''the Unsinkable Mrs. Brown
''was decorated
by the British government
''for her courage.
''When asked about the medal
''she said
''''a girl can always use
''another piece of jewelry.''''
[all laughing]
Ooh, she's here!
She's here, madam.
Yes. Sir?
Thank you.
[crowd cheering]
Oh! Oh, my goodness. Pa.
Oh, Buttercup.
- Oh!
- Christmas!
Polak!
- Hello, father.
- Molly, Molly, Molly.
- Johnny not here?
- Hey, Moll, look who's coming.
Welcome home, Molly.
Thank you, Gladys.
It's very nice
of you to come over.
- Come on, Gladys. Tell her.
- Yes, yes, dear. Mother and I--
We're throwing a party for you
to celebrate your homecoming.
The Sacred Thirty-Six
is ready and waiting for you.
Now, get out of them
traveling clothes
and get into a party dress.
Hurry! Hurry!
Yes. I'll join you
as soon as I can.
Thank you, Gladys.
You're a good sport.
Molly, you're quite a woman.
Hurry up now.
Molly, darling,
you should see
all the telegrams and flowers
and letters and all.
Pa, any letter from Johnny?
No, but he was never much
for writing letters, you know.
(Buttercup)
'Shamus!'
- Go on.
- Coming!
Hurry up, darling.
[instrumental music]
- Hello, Roberts.
- Welcome home, Mrs. Brown.
Thank you.
[music continues]
[dramatic music]
♪♪ I'm gonna move
from place to place ♪♪
♪♪ To find a house
with a golden stair ♪♪
♪♪ And if the house is red ♪♪
♪♪ And has a ♪♪
♪♪ Great big shiny brass bed ♪♪
♪♪ I'm living there ♪♪♪♪