We can't hold out much longer, sir!
General Hummel,
you've gotta get us outta here now!
I won't let you down.
I won't let you down, son.
Goddam it, sir! How long do we have to wait?
I've lost 15 men already!
Sir, they're lightin' us up like a firestorm!
This is General Hummel.
You gotta get my men outta there!
We don't have clearance
to go behind enemy lines, sir.
They're not coming for us, are they, sir?
Congressman Weaver and esteemed members
of the Special Armed Services Committee,
I come before you to protest a grave injustice.
Aim!
It has to stop.
I miss you so much.
There's something I've gotta do, Barb.
Something I couldn't do while you were here.
I tried.
You know I tried everything.
And I still don't have their attention.
Let's hope this elevates their thinking.
But whatever happens...
please don't think less of me.
Marine, inform the garrison C.O.
that General Hummel's coming on board
with a security inspection team.
Yes, sir.
Sir, it's an honor having you, sir.
Ya know, at least we can get some-
- A long time before guard meeting, huh?
- Yeah, I'll tell ya.
I got the access card.
We've got 30 minutes till those darts wear off.
Move it!
The access card, sir.
Let's do it.
Twenty-four hundred magazine check.
- Man, it's wet out there!
- Check me through, will ya?
Clear!
- I want 16, Major!
- Move it!
Evac!
Seal the door!
- No! No!
- Come on, man! Seal it!
- No! Help!
- Seal it!
Let me outta here! Oh, God!
Let me out! Let me out!
Clear out.
Get outta here!
Sorry.
Let's move out.
Two more cc's of acetylene chloride.
- That'll be five dollars, Isherwood.
- You suck.
You guys have too much time on your hands.
Yes! She's here! Bring it to me now.
Thank you, Phil!
What's that?
Why'd you get it sent here?
Carla wouldn't approve.
She thinks it's dumb to spend $600 on an L.P.
Carla's right.
Why don't you just spend $13 on a CD, man?
First of all, it's because I'm a Beatlemaniac.
And second, these sound better.
Could be serious.
Could be sarin gas.
A dog out of JFK caught a whiff of something
in this package
postmarked to a Bosnian refugee camp.
It could be detergent,
or it could be sarin gas.
Bosnian refugee camp?
Half a million Serbians reside in the U.S., Marvin.
Serbians don't like Bosnians.
You guys wanna get suited up?
- You bring the cockroaches?
- Got 'em.
We have air lock, Stanley.
You're all set to go.
October 1, 0900 hours.
Agent Stanley Goodspeed,
Agent Trainee Marvin Isherwood
initiating exam of wooden crate.
Suspicion of sarin gas inside.
- Marvin, sarin is a-
- G.B. aerosol.
That is correct.
Now, let's see.
We have some dirty magazines.
Stone Age Cave Girls in the Raw. Kinky.
And, uh-
Not a good sign.
Hello, little baby doll.
Look it, Stan.
- Hi there, Stanley.
- Marvin, don't!
- Hi, Stan.
- Shit! Move back! Move back!
- I want the exhaust.
- Hang on, guys.
We'll have that room clear in 50 seconds!
You're gonna be okay.
Jesus Christ!
Okay, I've got some bad news
and some really bad news.
The bad news is that the gas is corrosive
and it's eating our suits.
It's all over my hand, man!
The really bad news is there's enough C-4 and poison gas
to blow the whole chamber
and kill everybody in the building.
- Detonation too heavy.
- Everybody, out of the room now!
Seal us inside.
- Where are the sprinklers, Lonner?
- The acid's eating my su-
It's eating my fucking suit!
All right? Shit!
- Just wash us off!
- Where are my sprinklers?
We're working on it. It's coming.
It's just a flow problem.
Well, that's a pretty big friggin' problem, Lonner.
Fix it now!
We're working on it!
How much time do you have on that detonator?
A minute ten.
- Look at this!
- We're gonna have the room clear.
- Tell 'em to take the atropine, now!
- The atropine, Isherwood.
- What?
- Where's my water, Lonner? One minute!
Marvin, the atropine, now!
Inject it in your heart before your suit melts.
Shit!
Make him take his dose.
- Where's that water?
- Get that away from me!
Come on, Phil, fix it for Christ's sake!
Take the atropine now, Stan, for Christ's sake!
We're fucked.
The poison's mixing.
What the fuck are you waiting for, Stanley?
You take the fucking needle now!
- Fuck! Shit! Oh, fuck, shit!
- Forty seconds!
If that suit melts-
If you die, we all die!
Inject your heart and then diffuse the bomb!
- Come on, just do it, Stan!
- What if I miss my heart? I can't see shit!
Do it now!
Look how big this is.
You want me to stick this into my heart?
- Are you fucking nuts?
- The sprinkler's coming! It's coming!
Okay, here we go, man!
Sprinkler activated.
How much time left?
Twenty seconds!
We're not gonna make it.
Fifteen.
Oh, come on.
Clear!
Get me the fuck out of this gas chamber!
I almost stabbed myself in the heart with this thing.
Please lock me away...
- Stan?
- Hey, darlin'.
Hi, baby.
I had such an interesting day today.
Yeah, I had kind of an interesting day myself.
Oh, okay, you go first.
Oh, just some terrorists decided to send
a little care package, box of goodies,
which had to be neutralized
before blowing up the office.
So I took the rest of the day off.
Glass of wine, little guitar.
Just relaxing.
Wow!
I mean it, honey.
The world is being Fed-Ex'd to hell on a handcart.
I really believe that anyone
who's even thinking about having a child in this world,
is coldly considering an act of cruelty.
I know, I'm rambling, I'm complaining.
I'm sorry.
- What's your news, baby?
- I'm pregnant.
I'm sorry?
I'm pregnant.
- Really?
- Yeah.
- Wow!
- Is that all you're gonna say, is "wow"?
- You're pregnant?
- Three weeks.
How do you know?
I mean, h- how do you know?
Blue!
Just turned blue so I went to the doctor.
Well, you didn't mean what you just said, did you?
When?
Uh, just right now when you were talking
about bringing a child into the world,
and having it be an act of cruelty.
I meant it at the time.
Stanley, at the time?
You said it seven and a half seconds ago.
Well, gosh!
Kind of a lot's happened since then.
Look, we're not even married.
I know.
It's funny you should mention that.
It's funny?
- Do you love me?
- Of course I love you.
Good.
Will you marry me?
Whoa! Whoa! Wai-
Hey, Marriage Police, pull over!
Come on, Stanley.
I'm proposing to you right now.
The Rock is the most famous
and was the most feared prison ever built.
Is it really true that there's never been an escape?
Ah, that's true.
From 1936 until '63 when the prison closed,
there were 14 attempts.
No one is believed to have made it to shore,
alive at least.
No, uh, h-h-hey, hey, fellas.
I'm sorry, but tourists are not allowed back here.
- I don't really give a shit! Do you?
- No.
- Come here, fruity.
- Move!
Hey, girls? Hi.
You all havin' a good time?
Yeah.
Will you do something for me?
It's really, it's really important.
Tell your teacher that you need to get back on the boat
and go home right now.
Ladies and gentlemen, welcome to Broadway!
This cell block housed
the most awesome scum in America.
Ladies and gentlemen, I, Ranger Bob,
cordially invite you to become inmates of Alcatraz,
temporarily, of course.
On the line!
Pretty tight quarters, aren't they, huh?
Like being a caged animal.
Spend a couple of years in there-
What's the matter, fellas?
Something wrong with the tour?
The tour's over, Bob.
What kind of fucked-up tour is this?
General Hummel,
Captains Frye and Darrow reporting, sir.
Welcome to the Rock, gentlemen.
Land the choppers on the back side
and deploy as planned.
- Aye, aye, sir.
- Move out!
I'm not allowed to carry a gun.
Oh, you're not allowed to carry a gun?
I got a goddam gun.
If I'd've known this was gonna happen,
I'd have brought my motherfuckin' gun! Help!
All right, gentlemen, this'll be our new home.
Tom, I want my command center right here.
- I want Coms up.
- Roger that, sir.
Put the satellite over there.
I wanna be up at 1600.
Let's move it.
Systems up.
Possible penetration point in the shower room.
- We're setting anti-intrusion.
- I brought a personal touch, sir.
It's an anti-motion trembler device.
It's custom-made.
Nobody knows about it and nobody expects it.
- What's it do?
- We head-fake 'em with the laser beam.
And then if they disturb Mr. Backup here,
we own 'em.
Ladies and gentlemen,
you're being detained against your will.
For that, I apologize.
It is not our intention in any way to harm you.
You will not be detained one minute longer
than is necessary for us to complete our mission.
Attention on deck!
Stand easy, men.
Make no mistake about it, gentlemen,
we are now in harm's way.
For Major Baxter and I,
this is the last campaign in a career datin' back to Tet '68.
Likewise for Captain Hendrix, Gunnery Sergeant Crisp,
who cut their teeth under my command in Desert Storm.
Captain Frye, Captain Darrow,
this is my first operational situation with you and your men.
And I have to say,
thus far your conduct reflects your reputations.
- Thank you, General.
- Thank you, sir.
We have achieved our position through poise,
precision and audacity.
To this we must now add resolve.
We'll be branded as traitors,
the gravest capital crime.
Punishable by death.
A couple hundred years ago,
a few guys named Washington, Jefferson and Adams,
were branded as traitors by the British.
And now they're called patriots.
In time, so shall we.
God willing, in less than 48 hours
you will evacuate this island in gunships
under cover of hostages and V.X. gas warheads.
Your destination:
a non-extradition treaty country.
You will each be paid a fee of $1 million
for services rendered.
But you can never again set foot on your native soil.
- Can you live with that?
- Yes, sir!
The men of Marine Force Recon
are selected to carry out
illegal operations throughout the world.
When they don't come home...
their families are told fairy tales
about what happened to them,
and denied compensation.
Well, I have choked on these lies my entire career!
Well, here and now the lies stop!
God be with all of you.
Man your positions, men.
This is FBI Director Womack.
Director, be advised.
Eighty-one, I say again,
81 civilians are under my control as of this moment.
You are to take measures to assure this remains
a need-to-know classified fact.
Who is this?
Mr. Director,
you have a very serious problem.
A battery of V.X. gas rockets is presently deployed,
to deliver a highly lethal strike
on the population of the San Francisco Bay area.
I will call again at 0100 hours to state my demands.
I want to know who I'm talking to.
This is Brigadier General Francis X. Hummel,
United States Marine Corps, from Alcatraz.
Out!
- I'll cancel your reservations.
- Get the Pentagon.
And call the San Francisco office.
It seems Alcatraz was just reopened.
Last night General Hummel,
using brutal but nonlethal force
under the guise of a security exercise,
walked off with 15 V.X. poison gas rockets.
He lost one of his own men in the process.
That's General Hummel in Vietnam.
I think he was a major at the time.
Three tours in Vietnam,
Panama, Grenada, Desert Storm.
Three Purple Hearts, two Silver Stars,
and the Congressional Medal of-
Jesus!
This man is a hero!
Well, I think "legend"
might be a better description, Mr. Sinclair.
Well, now we can add kidnapping and extortion
to his list of accolades.
Mr. Sinclair, General Hummel is a man of honor.
General, it's him.
Frank, it's Al Kramer.
Hi, Al, how you doin'?
I don't know, Frank.
Ah, why don't you tell me.
Got a lot of very, very worried people here, Frank.
I'll come straight to the point.
Eight-three Force Reconnaissance Marines have died
under my various commands.
Forty-seven in northern Laos and southern China.
Southern China?
We never admitted we sent troops into China.
Who is this?
Identify yourself.
White House Chief of Staff Hayden Sinclair, General.
- How old are you, Chief of Staff Sinclair?
- I'm 33.
Well, Mr. Sinclair,
you've probably got no fucking idea what I'm talking about.
By your ninth birthday,
I was runnin' black ops into China,
and my men were responsible
f- for over 200 enemy kills.
Al, put some rigging tape over Mr. Sinclair's mouth.
He's wasting my time.
Ah, you want to continue, Frank?
Remember Operation Desert Storm?
Those surgical hits made by our smart bombs,
covered so well on CNN?
It was my men on the ground
that made those hits possible by lasing the targets.
Twenty of them were left to rot outside Baghdad
after the conflict ended.
No benefits were paid to their families.
No medals conferred.
These men died for their country,
and they weren't even given a goddam military burial.
The situation is unacceptable.
You will transfer $100 million
from the Grand Cayman Red Sea Trading Company account
to an account I designate.
From these funds,
reparations of $1 million will be paid
to each of the 83 Marines' families.
The rest of the funds I will disperse at my discretion.
Do I make myself clear?
Except for the Red Sea Trading Company.
What is that?
- Identify yourself.
- This is FBI Director Womack, General.
It's a slush fund where the Pentagon keeps proceeds
from illegal arms sales.
Jesus, Frank!
This is classified information.
You alert the media, I launch the gas.
You refuse payment, I launch the gas.
You've got 40 hours,
till noon day after tomorrow to arrange transfer of the money.
I am aware of your countermeasure.
You know and I know it doesn't stand a chance.
Hummel from Alcatraz.
Out.
All right. We have to identify the hostages
and contact each of their families.
Uh, tell 'em somethin'.
Make up a story, and we've got to keep this undercover.
If this comes out, the city of San Francisco will be in chaos.
I am talking anarchy.
Wait a minute, wait a minute.
What is the potential casualty rate
for a single rocket armed with V.X. poison gas,
General Peterson?
- Sixty or seventy.
- Well, that's, that's not so bad.
- Thousand. Seventy thousand dead!
- Oh.
One teaspoon of this hits the floor,
it's lethal up to a hundred feet.
One teaspoon of this shit detonated in the atmosphere
will kill every living organism in an eight-block radius.
Get the point?
Uh, what did Hummel mean by your countermeasure, General?
Standard poison is countered by napalm.
It burns it up, consumes it upon detonation.
Now, the problem with V.X. poison gas is
that it's designed specifically to withstand napalm.
That's where, uh, thermite plasma comes in.
General Peterson?
Thermite plasma incendiary systems
can burn hot enough to consume V.X.,
but they're still in the test phase;
it's not operational.
Hummel knows this.
We are dealing with one smart son of a bitch.
What's it gonna take
to equip a flight of F-18s with thermite plasma
within the next 36 hours?
- An act of God.
- Excuse me?
All right, we can try.
But I strongly urge you to consider the use of this
as a secondary initiative.
Then we have to go to our primary initiative.
Uh, Admiral?
Sir, I'd like to bring in our SEAL ground commander,
Commander Anderson.
Mr. Womack, who is your best chemical/biological man?
- Oh, that's interesting.
- Oh, yeah.
That's very compelling.
- You like my pigtails?
- Oh, yeah, the pigtails are very naughty.
Naughty. Naughty.
Just the Amaretto cream with peach sorbet persuasion.
- This isn't happening.
- No, Stan, don't answer it.
- This isn't happening!
- No, just don't answer it. It's okay.
I have to. It's the office, baby.
They know I'm home.
How could they possibly know that you're home?
It's the FBI.
Stanley!
Goodspeed.
Uh, yeah. O-Okay, yeah.
I'll be, I'll be down,
yeah, downstairs in ten minutes.
No, you won't.
- I have to go to San Francisco.
- No, you don't.
Stanley, no,
you do not have to go to San Francisco.
Are you kidding me right now?
You need to stay here and talk to me about things.
- I've got to go, baby.
- Oh! I am Catholic! Do you realize that?
I am pregnant and I am unmarried.
And this causes a serious problem for me.
I cannot believe you.
No, no.
I love you.
I will marry you.
I just didn't plan on this, that's all.
- Come to San Francisco.
- Really?
Yeah, I'm sure it's just a training exercise.
Check into the hotel.
Order up some champagne.
- And we'll finish what we started?
- Exactly.
- Baby, you're gonna marry me?
- You know it.
You're gonna marry me!
- Honey, come on. Just a really quick one.
- Oh, oh, I gotta go now.
A night-time airdrop incursion is out
due to the full moon.
Likewise a frontal seaside attack.
If we're compromised and shots are fired,
Hummel might launch.
Our only alternative is an attack from within the prison.
We penetrate the island through the tunnels
under the prison buildings undetected,
and emerge in its center;
that way we can jump the Marines from behind.
And if we're lucky,
take their rocket positions without a shot fired.
I don't understand.
You-you've studied the architectural plans?
They're useless.
Alcatraz has been ripped up and rebuilt for years.
- Under there is a maze of shit.
- Well, there's no question, gentlemen.
We need firsthand intelligence of the tunnel systems.
- So what about the former warden?
- Died in 1979.
All the guards we contacted were useless.
Um, there is someone who I think can help us.
- This is for the sake of national security.
- No!
It's the sake of national security
that got us here in the first place 33 years ago.
I knew!
I knew someday this would come back to bite us.
Forget it!
He does not exist.
He does exist!
We just chose to forget him for 30 years.
- We locked him up and threw away the key.
- Oh, and a lot of goddam good it did us.
He broke out of two maximum security prisons.
And if he hits the streets-
He's not gonna hit the streets, Jim.
Thirty years ago he was a highly trained SAS operative.
He is my age now, for Christ's sake!
I have to get up three times a night to take a piss.
We can't risk letting him out.
He's a professional escape artist.
- Gosh. Neat, uh- Neat, neat plane.
- Yeah.
Dr. Goodspeed. James Womack.
- A pleasure to meet you, sir. Thank you.
- Welcome.
You come very highly recommended.
B.A. Columbia; M.A., PhD, Johns Hopkins.
Biochemistry, toxicology.
Well, I'm one of those fortunate people
who like my job, sir.
Got my first chemistry set when I was seven.
Blew my eyebrows off.
We never saw the cat again.
Been into it ever since.
What do you know about V.X. gas?
Liquid.
Failed pesticide discovered by a mistake in 1952.
Uh, actually,
it's kind of like champagne that way.
The Franciscan monks thought they were making white wine.
Somehow the bottle carbonated.
Voilŕ! Champagne.
- And then the whole thing just-
- The gas, Dr. Goodspeed.
It's very, very horrible, sir.
It's one of those things
we wish we could disinvent.
This isn't a "train" exercise, is it?
No, Dr. Goodspeed, it's not a training exercise.
- Hello, sir.
- Good morning, Director.
This is Ernest Paxton,
agent in charge of the West Coast operation.
- Dr. Goodspeed.
- Pleasure to meet you.
How do you do, sir?
It's been a fairly interesting day so far.
The prisoner's here. Shall we?
Now, my boys, they haven't been able to find a file on this guy.
Who is he anyway, sir?
His name is John Mason, a British national
incarcerated on Alcatraz in 1962, escaped in '63.
I was under the impression
that no one ever escaped Alcatraz, sir.
Paxton, don't argue!
This man has no identity,
not in the United States or Great Britain.
He does not exist.
Understand?
I want one thing:
how he escaped the Rock.
Specifically the route he took through the island's bowels.
- The papers are in order, sir.
- We're prepared to offer him a full pardon.
And Paxton, no strong-arming Mason.
I know him too well.
Well, if you know him,
then why don't you question him?
No, he'll remember me.
I don't want his anger clouding the issue.
All right, I'll take care of him.
Mr. Mason, I'm Special Agent in Charge,
Ernest Paxton.
In charge of what?
Fucking me over for another three decades?
I don't know anything about your previous matters.
I'm here because
a special situation exists
that we feel you might be able to help us with.
Well, what might that be?
I've been in jail longer than Nelson Mandela,
so maybe you want me to run for president.
- Not exactly.
- Mmm, a pity.
I feel rather like Alcamedes.
Who?
Alcamedes.
He was imprisoned by his king in ancient Greece.
- Like Sir Walter Raleigh. The same fate.
- James the First.
Even someone as bright as you
must be aware that, uh,
there's a certain pattern emerging here.
Aleksandr Solzhenitsyn?
Yeah, I heard of him.
Didn't he play hockey for the fuckin' Red Wings?
- That's the chap.
- Get this straight, pops.
I don't like you any more than you like me.
But I'm here to make you a legitimate offer.
You wanna hear what I have to say or not?
By all means, dear Paxton.
By all means.
We got a problem in a place that I think you know.
There's a hostage situation on Alcatraz.
- Hostage?
- Eighty-one tourists.
The Rock has become a tourist attraction?
Why don't we cut the shit, huh?
You know the Rock.
- You broke out.
- Yes, successfully.
Yeah. So why don't you do yourself a favor
while you're helpin' us?
I mean, it'd be nice to get out of jail
while you're still vertical.
Hmm? While you got a little lead
left in your pencil.
While I'm considering your offer,
I want a suite in the Fairmont Hotel.
You know I'm here to cut you a deal.
I am not here to bend over
and take it up the ass from you.
Here. Here's a quarter.
Do yourself a favor. Call your lawyer.
You're goin' back to jail.
- Y-You're sending him back to jail?
- I'm not sending him anywhere.
I'm just givin' him somethin' to think about.
With all due respect, sir,
I don't think we have time
for him to just sit around and think about it.
- Oh, really?
- No, Goodspeed's right.
You go talk to him.
- Me?
- Yes.
- Sir, I'm not qualified for that.
- You're an FBI agent!
- W-What is your specialty again?
- Chemical weapons.
Don't mention that!
- You want me to lie?
- Yeah, lie.
We got less than 24 hours.
Give it a shot.
Okay.
Hi.
I'm an agent with the, uh, uh, F-Federal-
FBI. Uh-
- Eh, well, my- I'm Stanley Goodspeed.
- But of course you are.
Well, at least he got his name right.
- Of course I am. Huh.
- And you have an emergency.
That's right.
And you need my help.
Exactly right.
- Coffee.
- No, no, I'm fine. Thank you.
Offer me coffee.
Oh, yes!
Well, that was, in fact, gonna be my next-
Can we get a cup of coffee in here, please?
And offer to take these off.
Mr. Mason, really.
- All kidding aside.
- As a gesture of your good faith.
Prisoner requests to have his handcuffs taken off.
No, no, no, no.
Why don't you go ahead
and have his handcuffs taken off, please?
Well, I guess that's one way to go.
This is a pardon and release contract
from the attorney general's office.
Now, it makes you a free man
provided you cooperate.
So if you'll just, uh, sign,
uh, at, uh, where it says-
- "Signature"?
- That's- Yes. "Signature".
Well, timeo danaos et dona ferentis.
"I fear the Greeks even when they bring gifts."
Oh, an educated man!
That rules out the possibility
of you being a field agent.
In point of fact, I am a field agent, Mr. Mason.
- Really?
- Yes.
- In which field?
- Antiterrorism.
Then you're trained in weaponry,
explosives and mortal combat.
Well-trained.
Then it's the Fairmont Hotel.
Okay.
I want a suite, a shower, a shave,
and the feel of a suit.
May I also suggest, uh, a haircut?
Am I out of style?
Unless you're a 20-year-old guitarist from Seattle.
- It's a grunge thing.
- Grunge?
Yeah, well, uh, uh-
Okay, thank you very much.
All right. Call the Fairmont.
Close the floor if necessary,
but I want him sealed off.
And he gets two hours max.
Great job, Goodspeed.
Why didn't you throw in a trip to Tahiti
while you were at it?
- I'll deliver this to the attorney general.
- Uh, no, you'll give it to me, Reynolds.
And take Attorney Reynolds outside.
There's a car waiting for you. Thank you.
That's a signed federal document, sir.
Isn't that illegal?
You're not acquainted with the full facts, Goodspeed.
With all due respect, sir, I'd like clarification.
I gave that man my word.
Damn it! You're on a need-to-know basis,
and you don't need to know.
It's, uh, it's, eh, kind of curious, but, uh,
Sir Walter Raleigh, Alcamedes, Solzhenitsyn,
they, um, well, they were all wrongfully imprisoned.
Womack! Now, why am I not surprised,
you piece of shit!
Eh, peace! Peace!
Hey, we're not home.
Leave a message.
Hi, darling, it's, uh, it's me.
Uh, listen, don't come to San Francisco.
I repeat, do not come to San Francisco.
- Stanley, no!
- Carla.
- Like hell I'm not coming!
Wait. Car-
Who's Carla?
And why don't you want her to come to San Francisco?
You're on a need-to-know basis,
and you don't need to know.
Watch it, he'll bite you.
Good. Mobile Command is fully operational.
- We'll be there in approximately two hours.
- I'm not armed, sir.
- I am unarmed, sir.
- Well, where's your issue?
I left it in my, uh, my sock drawer.
A gun?
For what?
You're a chemical freak.
No, I'm a chemical super-freak, actually.
But I still need a gun.
Give him a goddam gun.
Have you fired one of those things since the Academy?
If you're going to San Francisco
Don't forget to wear flowers in your hair
If you're going
To San Francisco
You're sure to meet some gentle people there
And you come for-
If you're going to San Francisco
Uh, uh, room service?
Ah, listen. This is the penthouse.
Do you do snacks, drinks? Huh?
Hello!
- You the barber?
- No. Stylist.
Barber.
Just clippers. No scissors.
No scissors?
You've got to be kidding me, no scissors!
I mean, did they tell Picasso,
"No brush"?
With scissors, this man could kill you.
I can't cut anyone's balls off
with a trimmer now, can I?
Why don't we do this outside?
Get some sun.
Oh, who did this to you? This is just not right.
In fact, it's nasty!
Well, it's a grunge thing.
Well, it's some kind of thing.
Do you think we have time for a sea kelp protein pack
and maybe some color?
No.
Okay.
Not very nice, is he?
No, he's not.
Hey, somebody ordered it.
Can't let it go to waste.
Don't you ever stop eatin'?
Not when it's free.
- We're supposed to be on duty.
- Hey, don't worry. He's an old man.
The boss is watchin'.
Come on, have- Try some of this lobster.
- Mm-hmm.
- My secretary here will settle the bill.
So what do you have in store for me, Womack,
when this is over?
You'll get your life back, Mason.
But you could've given me my life back years ago.
- Why should I trust you now?
- You've got my word.
Will you shake on it?
- Freeze, mister!
- Oh, man!
Help!
Drop the gun or I drop your boss.
You will not!
Get!
- He's getting very heavy.
- Then pull him up.
Please don't!
Help! Shit!
Come on, have a scallop.
Come on, catch.
You hoist him!
Help! Help! Help!
- Where's Mason? Where is Mason?
- Help! Hang on!
- Where's Mason?
- Mason's gone!
Gone?!
Clear.
Living room's clear!
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
All units, this is Caretaker.
We have a Signal Six. He's in the hotel!
Okay, I don't wanna know nothin'.
I never saw you throw that gentleman off the balcony.
All I care about is,
a-are you happy with your haircut?
Easy!
Watch it, you fuckhead,
you're gonna pull my arm out!
Watch out!
Oh, no!
Watch it!
- Hey, watch it!
- He's over there!
Hey!
This is my Humvee.
I don't want any dings, dents or scratches,
or I'll have your ass. Hey!
Hey! Stop! Hey!
Hey, I was inside the bedroom with Jack Powell!
Hey, call the guard! Go!
FBI.
Move!
Whoa! Whoa!
Suspect is in a black Humvee,
heading west on California.
Speed approximately 70 miles per hour.
Get out of the way!
I want a net put on this son of a bitch,
you hear me?
This guy's hittin' every fuckin' thing in sight
tryin' to block us!
I hope you're insured!
Oh, well, why not?
You're goin' down!
Hello?
I'm only borrowing your Humvee!
Information?
San Francisco?
Uh, Jade Angelou.
That's A-N-G-
Welcome aboard, y'all.
How y'all doin' today?
Hang on!
Holy shit!
Whoa-oa!
Oh, no!
We're gonna crash!
Save yourselves!
Oh, my baby!
Oh, no!
Oh, no.
Oh, God!
Hey, man, you just fucked up your Ferrari.
- Oh, no! Baby's goin' down in flames!
- It's not mine.
Neither is this!
Damn! This sucks!
Where's that son of a bitch at?
I'm gonna hunt him down!
That motherfucker ain't safe nowhere.
Chem weapons. Isherwood.
Marvin, look up Wolfburg Federal Penitentiary.
The inmate is Mason, John.
Hey, Stan, listen,
I'm gettin' out of this government shithole.
I'm goin' over to Orkin to design roach motels.
Cool, huh?
Look, I just stole a kid's motorcycle.
I'm not really feeling too good about it, okay?
Wolfburg. Got it?
Yeah, I got it.
All right, Magrane, Masconi, Masters. No Mason.
Go to February '76.
Who was transferred to Wolfburg from San Quentin?
This is weird.
They got medical records.
They got place of birth. Glasgow.
Uh, but they don't have a name.
Uh, wait a minute, wait a minute.
They have next of kin.
A Jade Angelou of 32 Stenson Drive, San Francisco.
Jade?
No, Stacy. Jade's friend.
Were you afraid to come alone?
Yeah.
- It's okay.
- I'll be over here if you need me.
The last photograph I had of you,
you were about ten.
Yeah?
Well, I found a picture of you among my mom's things
when she died.
Oh, yeah? Well, uh-
Why don't we take a walk?
I got 'im.
Palace of Fine Arts.
Your mother, uh-
Yeah, well, sh-she was very special.
Yeah, she was.
But I don't think that we should romanticize
what happened between you and her.
Meeting in a bar after a Led Zeppelin concert.
Head out, and I was the result.
Well, I'd like to think it would've led somewhere
if only-
If only what?
Six federal marshals hadn't kicked down our door,
and dragged you back to prison?
- I'm sorry.
- It's all right.
- So, they let you out?
- Yeah.
That's good.
What did you do?
J-
Jade, I don't have a great deal of time here.
But I'll be coming back.
And, uh-
- Maybe we can...
- What? We can what?
You know, you're almost the only evidence
that I exist.
But I don't know you.
That's what I want to change, eh?
I've rehearsed this speech a thousand times
on the chance that we would meet.
Here we are, and I'm lost.
Well, I don't know
how I'm supposed to be feeling either.
Jade, I'm not an evil man.
If you can believe that, then it's a start.
Okay.
Is this about you?
You broke out of prison again, didn't you?
Why did you come to me?
FBI, ma'am.
Your father's working with us.
He's helping us resolve a dangerous situation.
- He is?
- Yes, ma'am.
Well, gee whiz, John,
I guess we oughta get goin', huh?
Whatever you say, Stanley.
Thank you for that.
You could've handled it differently.
What do you say we cut the chitchat, a-hole?
You almost got me killed twice.
And my jaw hurts like hell!
- Good.
- Cocksucker!
If I had my way,
you would be shipped back to Wolfburg in leg irons,
and caged like an animal
for the rest of your natural fucking life!
You wrecked half the city!
Now, tell me about the tunnels.
If you know the system,
it will take you wherever you need to go.
All right, there's an intake pipe here, below low tide.
Is that our best access?
Yes. That's exactly where I had come out.
Then beneath the cistern,
there's a connection to the abandoned septic system.
How many feet is that?
Uh, 57 paces.
Where do we go from there?
That's a good question.
- I have no idea.
- What?
I mean, I'll know it when we're all inside.
No. You're not goddam goin'.
Show us on the blueprints.
I can't! My blueprint was in my head.
I was underground for three days in the dark,
just waiting for the tides to be right.
But don't worry.
It'll all come back to me.
You're not going anywhere, Mason.
Wait a second.
Now, this piece of work
might be the only chance those people over there have.
If he's not going,
then why the hell did we get him out of jail?
He's smart.
I got him out to get you people in,
not go with you.
If it's the only way of getting the intelligence I need,
then he goes.
He'll fuck with you.
You compromise my men's lives,
and I'll bury you out there.
Now, Womack...
you're between the Rock and a hard case.
How is your bowling arm?
Dr. Goodspeed, the goal is to take out the launchers,
then neutralize the V.X. chemical rounds.
Well, we know the poison's being kept in the prison morgue,
from the satellite thermal imaging which is right here;
these colorized dots.
Have you ever actually seen one of these devices?
No, sir, but I've studied them.
I should really begin briefing your guys
on defusing and detoxification.
Got a really neat layout over here of the chem round
as well as the rocket,
- so let's get rolling.
- That won't be necessary.
Oh, it's very necessary, sir.
The power of this chemical
is way beyond anything you can imagine.
An ecological disaster, sir.
Plus the devices themselves are complicated.
That's why you're coming with us.
- I am?
- You're the expert. What's your problem?
You mean I'm going, going out there, under the water?
Well, earlier today you wanted a gun.
Now you're getting a gun and a wet suit.
Have you ever been in a combat situation?
- Define "combat," sir.
- Shep?
An incursion underwater to retake an impregnable fortress
held by an elite team
of U.S. Marines in possession of
81 hostages and 15 guided rockets,
armed with V.X. poisoned gas.
Oh. In that case, no, sir.
Excuse me.
- Here.
- Ah, thank you.
You don't look too good.
In fact, you look like shit.
My stomach's doing hula hoops around my ass.
You all right?
I mean, you gonna make it through this thing?
I don't know.
I always expected something like this
was going to happen,
but nothing prepares you for it.
Now I'm- I'm responsible
for a whole city.
Look, I know this isn't easy for you.
Remember you were trained
for this kind of a situation,
and believe me, it'll come back to you.
Besides, you got the best SEAL team in the country
backing you up.
Okay.
You're right.
I- I'll be on the wire.
I'll help talk you through it.
There's something else.
It's terrible.
N- No, it's wonderful,
except it isn't.
My girlfriend's pregnant...
and she's just flown in to see me.
You keep your mind
on what you're going to be doing out there tonight.
And I'll send someone to pick up your girlfriend,
and bring her here to the command center.
- Hummel!
- Hello, Frank. Lou Linstrom.
I'm at the White House with General Kramer.
Uh, Frank, uh, we're havin' a few problems
with the account transfer.
- Don't tell me problems, tell me solutions.
- Now, we've spoken to the president,
and I know that you're well aware
of his stance on terrorism.
- So what we'd like to do is-
- This isn't about terrorism.
This is about justice.
It's about reminding you people
who found it politically convenient to forget.
This is goin' nowhere, Frank.
Well, then, let me tell you what is.
Fifteen V.X. gas rockets into the heart of San Francisco.
You've got 17 hours to deliver the money.
Or be prepared to reap the whirlwind, gentlemen.
- What's the word from Mojave?
- General Peterson can give us
no definite assurance on the thermite plasma.
That is the word.
Green light to SEAL incursion.
Fall in!
All right, listen up.
Mr. Mason will run point for us.
Lieutenant Shepard will be attached to his hip.
You breathe, he breathes with you.
You piss, he helps.
Understood?
Dr. Goodspeed is our specialist.
When he neutralizes the threat,
we launch green flares and we wait for the cavalry.
Make no mistake, gentlemen.
We're in the fight of our lives
against maybe the greatest battalion commander
in the Vietnam War.
I shit you not.
Any questions?
Let's load up!
After you, ace.
Pass out and activate the minicams.
Everything set here?
Minicams operational?
Roger that, sir.
We are on-line.
Shep, what's the status
on the special operational gear for Mr. Mason?
Uh, let's see.
We have, uh,
one quart of kerosene in a squeeze bottle.
Three washers and waterproof matches.
Use the green flares to signal
when the threat has been neutralized.
Now, this is atropine.
If you come in contact with the gas,
you have 20 seconds to inject it into your heart.
Don't fuck with me on this.
It may save your life.
I have three incoming bogeys bearing 275.
Range: 6,000 meters.
FBI Command Center?
Oh, I would just love for you to tell me
what is goin' on.
Nope.
Listen, Stanley Goodspeed is my boyfriend.
Actually, he's, um, my fiancé.
- Where is he?
- Classified, lady.
Okay. Well, you just sit here
and act like a Bureau bonehead, then.
Hey, where are you g-
Goddam it!
Decoy choppers commencing run to Alcatraz.
I just lost one, sir.
I just lost one.
We only got two flying in.
Shit!
In my day, we did it all
with a snorkel and a pair of flippers.
- Your day?
- Yes. Didn't you read my résumé?
I don't-
I don't know anything about you.
- Hmm. I know something about you, Godspell.
- Goodspeed.
Goodspeed, Godspeed, Godspell...
you never went to any antiterrorist school.
So just make sure you don't get us all fucking killed.
- We're goin' dark.
- Night vision!
Raider One has dropped below radar coverage,
heading around Treasure Island.
Sir, we've got two bogeys
bearing due east and closing.
Decoys?
- Prepare to deploy!
- Good luck, Commander.
Sir, Raider One is at the drop zone.
Stanley's not a very good swimmer.
I mean, he can't even snorkel.
- Everyone, good to go?
- Good to go!
- Good to go! Good to go!
All right, so the S.D.U.s have been deployed,
and the Eagles are in the water.
Major, I want the perimeter patrolled
to the west end of the island.
- Double-time it.
- Yes, sir. Hendrix!
- You lead the patrol.
- Aye, aye, sir.
Let's move. Move out!
Move out! Move out!
The Eagles are on the Rock.
They've entered the cistern room.
Thank you very fucking much, Mr. Mason.
You've led us into a room with no exit.
- Any ideas, Dillinger?
- Figure it out soon. We're sitting ducks.
We're a little tight on time.
You stand by the door until I open it.
I'd like to know how you plan on accomplishing that?
Through here.
- You're shitting me.
- I memorized the timing.
I just hope it hasn't been changed.
You catch one of those flame bursts,
you're a corpse.
Thank you.
Commander, you said never to leave his sight,
but, uh-
Stand fast, Lieutenant.
Have a nice day.
- Where'd you dig up this guy?
- That's classified.
Clear here, sir.
No motion sensors tripped.
- Nothing.
- Well, tell 'em to stay out there.
Sweep forward!
Looks like he fucked us, Commander.
I knew it.
That son of a bitch jumped ship.
Welcome to the Rock.
- Mason.
- That's a no-no.
That's the subway.
That'll drop you into the tunnels.
Do it!
Sir, the Eagles have breached the tunnel system.
You enjoying this?
Well, it's certainly more enjoyable
than my average day.
Reading philosophy,
avoiding gang rape in the washroom.
Though it's less of a problem these days.
Maybe I'm losing my sex appeal.
We've got seismic activity in one of the storm grates.
North side.
Continue patrolling the area.
Sweep forward!
Commander, halt.
We've got movement.
- They're hearing sounds above, sir.
- Stand fast.
Down, down, down.
West storm drain's clear.
Ninety-seven paces to the shower room.
The Eagles are now at the access tunnel.
They're right under the shower room, sir.
Fiber optics.
- Something's not right.
- I got a bad feeling about this.
Quiet.
Motion sensors.
- Beams cutting across the manhole covers.
- Deal with it.
Commander, the beam is hitting
some sort of reflective device.
Possibly a prism.
I want to use a mirror to cut the beam,
send the beam back to its source
and then I'm gonna move the prism.
We've got motion on a trembler in the shower room, sir.
We've got visitors.
Let's move.
Got it.
Good to go.
- Fuck, man! I knew this would happen! Fuck!
- Move!
Stand fast.
We'll secure the area.
They're entering into the shower room, sir.
They're securing the area.
Just sit tight.
Drop your weapons!
Drop 'em!
- Stand fast!
- Hold your fire!
- Drop your weapons!
It's a fucking trap.
This is General Hummel.
Drop your weapons.
Drop 'em!
Anderson here, General Hummel.
Commander. Team leader.
Commander Anderson,
if you have any concern for the lives of your men,
you will order them to safety their weapons
and place them on the deck.
This is not happening.
Sir, we know why you're out here.
God knows I agree with you.
But like you,
I swore to defend this country against all enemies,
foreign, sir, and domestic.
General, we've spilled the same blood in the same mud.
You know goddam well I can't give that order.
We're dead.
Your unit is covered from an elevated position, Commander.
I'm not gonna ask you again.
Don't do anything stupid.
No one has to die here.
Men following the general,
you're under oath as United States Marines!
Have you forgotten that?
We all have shipmates we remember.
Some of them were shit on and pissed on by the Pentagon.
But that doesn't give you the right to mutiny!
You call it what you want!
You're down there, we're up here.
You walked into the wrong goddam room, Commander!
- Stand fast!
- Goddam it, Commander, one last time.
You tell your men to safety their weapons,
drop 'em on the deck.
- I cannot give that order!
- I am not gonna repeat that order!
- I will not give that order!
- What the hell is wrong with you, man?
- Stand fast!
- Oh, my God!
Let's waste these fuckers.
One last time.
You order your men to safety their weapons-
Cease fire!
Don't go.
Shit! Goddam it!
Let go of me.
Let go of me!
Don't. Don't go.
It's over.
Oh, God!
Mason.
We got some movement.
- Who?
- Two of 'em!
- Who is it?
- Eagles 11 and 12.
- I-It's Goodspeed and Mason.
- I knew it.
I've gotta get a team together right now.
We've gotta move with the second option.
What, and invite another massacre?
No way.
We've got a 60-year-old convict and a lab rat.
I'm telling you, it's over.
Not for Mason, it isn't.
Goodspeed, I'm not gonna kill you.
- Where are you going?
- Off this bloody island.
What? Wh-Wh-What for?
Goodspeed.
Goodspeed, do you read me?
It's for you.
- Sir?
- What's the status?
The status is they're dead.
They're dead!
It's just me and Mason.
Now he says he's leaving.
That is unacceptable.
Do you hear me? Unacceptable!
Well, there's a problem, sir.
He's got a gun.
What do you have, a fuckin' water pistol?
- No, sir.
- Go after him and stop him.
I didn't want this.
- Jesus, I didn't want this.
- You knew this might happen, Frank.
- Well, maybe now they'll pay up.
- Maybe now they won't, Captain.
Then maybe we need to execute a few hostages.
- Got a live one!
- Put a bullet in him.
- You heard him. End it!
- Holster that sidearm, Captain.
Sir?
You made a terrible mistake.
And more of our brothers have died in vain.
Damn you for forcing me into this position.
I need to talk to you right now, alone.
Now you told me I'm on a need-to-know basis.
And I'm tellin' you right now,
I need to know
who the fuck John Mason is right now, sir.
All right, you wanna know?
1962, J. Edgar Hoover
is head of the FBI, some say the country.
It's no secret he kept microfilm files
on prominent Americans and Europeans:
de Gaulle, British members of Parliament,
even the Prime Minister.
I mean, this guy had dirt on everybody in the world.
Yeah, I know all the cloak-and-dagger stories.
Where does Mason fit in?
Mason was the British operative who stole the files.
But our Bureau agents caught him at the Canadian border.
Of course, the British claimed they'd never heard of him.
And we held him without trial
until he gave up the microfilm,
but he never did.
Well, I'm surprised Hoover
didn't use his daughter as leverage.
Hoover was dead in '72.
She wasn't born yet.
Today, well, it's a different Bureau.
So you held this guy without trial his whole life!
No wonder he's pissed.
This man knows our most intimate secrets
from the last half century:
the alien landing at Roswell,
the truth about the J.F.K. assassination.
And Mason's angry, he's lethal,
he's a trained killer.
And he is the only hope that we have got.
Mason! Mason!
There are 81 hostages still up there.
Yeah, like me.
All right, you wanna play tough?
You wanna play tough with me?
Okay. FBI!
Freeze, sucker!
- I'll fire.
- No, you won't.
- Throw down.
- You're not the sort.
Let's find out.
I could; you, no.
Besides, your safety's on.
Goodspeed, have you resolved the situation?
Not yet.
- He's got all the guns now, sir.
- Shit!
You're right,
I don't use guns and I don't kick down doors.
- This is what I do.
- I haven't got my glasses.
What it says is Chemical Weapons Specialist.
That's right.
I got a lunatic up there, man,
with 15 missiles armed with some really funky stuff.
That lying Womack.
You could've told my daughter.
It was classified.
Look, I'm in the same situation.
They've got my girlfriend in the city
with a baby on the way.
Look, I can defuse the rockets.
I really can.
But I'm gonna need your help,
and I'm gonna need it right now.
Sir, this man's weapons and tack radio are missing!
Shit, we got a rodent problem.
Flush the pipes.
There's probably a maze of tunnels on this island.
Check every access you can find.
Sir.
Even if you escape from the island,
you can't escape the rockets.
So, where are you gonna go? Go where?
What are, what are you gonna do?
- Show me where the morgue is, Mason.
- I'm out of here.
What about your daughter?
Mason?
Rodents located.
The way I see it,
you don't really have any choice, do you?
I don't think you do.
Move!
They're onto us.
Burn 'em out.
This mother's gonna blow big.
I don't understand.
How could we lose radio contact all of a sudden?
We've lost comms.
Still got 'em on locaters.
- So what's it gonna be?
- What?
How do you like your choices?
- I don't.
- That's what I thought.
All right, come on.
This is the oldest part of Alcatraz.
Did you know it was originally a Civil War fort?
Oh, really? Huh. Yeah, wow.
You know, I like history, too,
maybe when this is all over,
you and I can stop by the souvenir shop together.
But right now I just- I just-
I wanna find some rockets.
Don't tempt me.
We are going to the morgue.
- You sure you're ready for this?
- I'll do my best.
Your best?
Losers always whine about their best.
Winners go home and fuck the prom queen.
Carla was the prom queen.
- Really?
- Yeah.
Locaters have them approaching the morgue, sir.
Come on, come on.
You can do it, Doc.
You must never hesitate.
I think you're shooting too close to the rocket.
Him, but not the rocket.
Any other news, Professor?
Not the rocket!
Not the rocket.
I got a little somethin' for ya.
Oh, yeah, okay.
That's just about the most awful thing I've ever seen.
Mason,
the second you don't respect this,
it kills you.
Put it over there.
You've been around a lot of corpses.
Is that normal?
- What, the feet thing?
- Yeah, the feet thing.
Yeah, that happens.
Well, I'm having kind of a hard time concentrating.
- Can you do something about it?
- Well, like what? Kill him again?
Listen, I'm just a biochemist.
And most of the time I work in a glass jar
and lead a very uneventful life.
I drive a Volvo, a beige one.
But what I'm dealing with here,
is one of the most deadly substances
the Earth has ever known.
So what do you say you cut me some friggin' slack?
A really elegant string-of-pearls configuration.
Unfortunately, incredibly unstable.
Well, what exactly does this stuff do?
If the rocket renders it aerosol,
it can take out the entire city of people.
Really? And what happens if you drop one?
Happily, it'll just wipe out you and me.
- How?
- It's a cholinesterase inhibitor.
Stops the brain from sending nerve messages
down the spinal cord within 30 seconds.
Any epidermal exposure or inhalation,
and you'll know.
A twinge at the small of your back
as the poison seizes your nervous system.
Do not move that!
Your muscles freeze, you can't breathe.
You spasm so hard you break your own back,
spit your guts out.
But that's after your skin melts off.
My God.
Oh, I think we'd like God on our side at the moment,
don't you?
So what I'm doing now
is removing the guidance system chips,
so the rocket will splash down after 500 feet.
All right, let me have that.
You can let go of it.
All right, just back away. Just back away!
Sir, morgue team has not checked in.
Blackbird One, this is Blackbird.
Over.
Come in, goddam it!
Somebody's still there.
Let's move!
Rats alive! Close on the morgue.
Close on the morgue.
Go, go, go, go, go, go, go.
Frye, Darrow, hustle up.
We got more company!
Hold it.
Converge on the morgue.
Move out.
Goodspeed, come on.
Come over here.
Good. I love pressure.
I eat it for breakfast.
Come on. Time's up.
There's three rockets somewhere else.
We have to find them.
Come on!
Clear!
I'm too old for this.
- Where's it go?
- I've no idea.
Sir, all the guidance chips are gone.
Captain, I guess you didn't quite take care
of the rat problem.
No, sir.
Well, there are two dead men here
who strongly suggest you go finish the job.
Yes, sir.
Yes, sir!
Rio, Royce, let's go!
Move out!
- You really don't know where this goes?
- No, I don't know where it goes.
Well, it's starting to pick up speed.
Do you know how to slow it down?
No, I don't.
God.
Mason, you all right?
Yes, perfectly okay, you fucking idiot!
- They're coming.
- Who?
- The Marines!
- Where?
- What the fuck's goin' on?
- Let's cut him off.
No! No! No!
Mason!
You motherfucker!
Die! Die! Die!
I'm rather glad you didn't hesitate too long.
How do you do it?
Oh, I was trained by the best.
British Intelligence.
Come on.
But in retrospect,
I'd rather have been a poet or a farmer.
Okay.
Okay, the president arrives in three hours.
His directive is to string Hummel along
until the air strike is operational.
- What's the word from Mojave, General?
- The same as last time, Lou.
They're going as fast as they can.
- Do it over here.
- On your knees. On your knees!
Navy SEALs, listen up.
You've got something that belongs to me.
Twelve guidance chips, to be precise.
Let me remind you there are lives at stake,
civilian lives.
Speak up.
- Speak up!
- I, uh, uh-
- Tell them your name.
- My name is Larry Henderson.
- Oh, man.
- And I'm a father of three.
And, uh, they've got a gun to my head.
You've got exactly three minutes
to return the guidance chips to the exercise yard,
- or Mr. Henderson won't have a head.
- Oh, no.
Hey. Wha-
Now, three to go.
You find them and defuse them, okay?
- All right.
I'll try and delay Hummel and give you more time.
Hey, what about Mr. Henderson's head?
Okay?
What do you mean?
Okay.
- General.
- Who the hell are you?
I'm all that's left of the enemy.
Bingo.
Stand easy.
Thought I'd been in the service a long time.
- Name and rank, sailor.
- Well, it's Army, actually.
Answer the question.
And address him as "General, sir."
Captain John Patrick Mason, General, sir,
of Her Majesty's S.A.S.
Retired, of course.
You're a long way from home, Captain.
How the hell are you involved in this?
Oh, I have a unique knowledge of this prison facility.
I was, uh, formerly a guest here.
Hi, sweetie.
Hey, come back here, little boy.
Did they bother to tell you who I am,
why I'm doing this?
Or are they just using you
like they do everybody else?
All I know is you were big in Vietnam.
I saw the highlights on television.
Then you wouldn't have any fuckin' idea
what it means to lead some of the finest men on
God's earth into battle,
and then see their memory betrayed by their own government.
I don't quite see how you cherish the memory of the dead,
by killing another million.
And, uh, this is not combat.
It's an act of lunacy, General, sir.
Personally, I think you're a fuckin' idiot.
"The tree of liberty must be refreshed,
from time to time,
with the blood of patriots and tyrants."
Thomas Jefferson.
"Patriotism is the virtue of the vicious",
according to Oscar Wilde.
- Thank you for making my point.
- Where are the guidance chips?
Where are the guidance chips?
- I destroyed them.
- That was a bad move, soldier.
Does that mean you'll execute us both?
You're lucky that old man Hummel wants you alive.
'Cause I'll take pleasure in guttin' you, boy.
I'd take pleasure in guttin' you...
Boy.
"I'll take pleasure in guttin' you, boy."
What is wrong with these people, huh, Mason?
Don't you think there's a lot of, uh,
a lot of anger floatin' around this island?
Kind of a pubescent volatility?
Don't you think?
A lot of angst, a lot of:
"I'm 16, I'm angry at my father" syndrome?
I mean, grow up!
We're stuck on an island,
with a bunch of violence-for-pleasure-seeking
psychopathic Marines.
Shame on them!
Anyway, I only got one chem round.
There's two left.
- Mason?
- Yes, I'm here.
I was just thinking how wonderful it was,
when the inmates weren't allowed to talk in here.
Not allowed to talk.
How'd you do it?
Uh, nurtured the hope that there was hope.
That one day I'd breathe free air.
Perhaps meet my daughter.
Modest hopes, but, uh, they kept a man alive.
What'd they put you away for, John?
Oh, that's a long story.
Well, I'm not goin' anywhere.
When was the last communication from our men on Alcatraz?
Seven hours.
Thermite plasma is operational.
- Get me the president.
- Be seated.
Gentlemen, consider yourselves on ground alert.
If we receive launch authority,
your mission is the complete thermal destruction
of Alcatraz Island.
The entire island is to be blanketed,
not one square inch missed.
Eighty-one American civilians
and a number of U.S. Marines
will lose their lives in this air strike.
Why didn't you just tell them where the microfilm was
and, and create a solution?
Hmph. The moment they had the microfilm,
they'd suicide me.
- Some solution.
- And you ended up here.
Which brings me to another question.
When you broke out-
Let me see if I can get this straight.
You went down the incinerator chute,
on the mine cars,
through the tunnels to the power plant,
under the steam engine-
That was really cool, by the way.
And into the cistern through the intake pipe.
But how, in the name of Zeus's butthole,
did you get out of your cell?
I only ask because in our current situation,
well, it could prove to be useful information, maybe!
Trade secrets, my son.
Wow.
General, two operational rockets left.
One's at the lower lighthouse
and there is one on the roof.
And both of the birds are ready to fly, sir.
- G-General, can you hear me?
- I heard you, Captain.
Oh, just makin' sure.
Should we prepare for launch, General?
I'll handle the strategy, Captain.
Yes, sir.
The hour is approaching, sir.
Just letting the general know of the time, sir.
- I'm very aware of the time, Captain.
- Aye, aye, sir. Lettin' you know.
Me and my boys are ready to cock, lock,
and ready to rock.
Mason, where're you going?
Thirty years ago I vowed
I wouldn't die in this toilet.
You're not leaving!
There's a madman in there with his hand on a, on a button!
Shh. Some sniper's gonna get his ass.
Stop moving, Mason.
Mason, stop moving.
Hummel won't do it.
He's a soldier, not a murderer.
- I read it in his eyes.
- You read his eyes?
Oh, well, then, everything's just fine!
- I can't afford to take that chance.
- Why don't you talk louder?
Three minutes to go, sir.
- They're not gonna call, Frank.
- Oh, they'll call.
They'll call if we fire
one of our rockets up their ass.
Sir.
- Hummel.
- Hi, Frank. It's Al Kramer here.
- How's it going out there?
- How do you think it's goin'?
- Listen, we're gonna need another hour.
- You've got three minutes.
Listen, uh, Frank,
we have to get final authorization from the president.
You've got three minutes.
Frank, please don't do anything stupid.
They want another hour.
Well, that's bullshit.
That's bullshit, General. They're lyin'!
They're calling our bluff, sir.
They're playing you for a fool, sir.
Order the launch, General.
Come on, General.
Let's be all we can be.
The mission's not complete!
Well, mine is.
When this is over, you'll go back home,
driving Carla and your baby insane
in your beige Volvo.
And I'll be dead or back in prison,
which is the same thing.
You're not leaving.
All right,
I'll do it myself.
I got three weeks' weapons training.
I'll kick the-
Out of a platoon full of Marines.
No problem.
- Major, patch me into Roof Battery.
- Aye, sir.
Fire open control circuit coordinates to the roof, sir.
Let's go!
Laser powered up!
- Oh, no.
- I said, on your knees!
My name's Stanley Goodspeed.
I'm a chemical weapons specialist for the FBI.
- Uh, glass or plastic?
- What?
- Glass or plastic? Glass or plastic?
- Shut the fuck up!
Because if the winds change
after you launch those rockets,
- we're all gonna die.
- Shut up!
And you're gonna end up in either a glass jar
or a plastic bag.
So, what do you say you do the math,
h-hand over the gun-
- and let's go find some rockets?
- I said shut the fuck-
- You made the right choice.
- I decided I didn't want your child
growing up without a father.
Hey, the last time I swam this channel I was your age.
So, I'm fucked either way.
So, come on.
Weapon is hot.
I am standing by for the launch command.
Man, killing Navy SEALs is one thing...
- Is this for real?
- Hey, it's business.
Access code entered.
Weapon available for release.
Launch coordinates:
six, seven,
five, four, five, niner.
The weapon is hot.
I'm standing by for launch command.
That's affirmative.
Standing by for command.
I'm waiting for launch command, General.
- Fire.
- Fire!
Missile loose!
Origin: Alcatraz, 67253725.
- What's the goddam heading?
- Heading 185 degrees south southeast.
Speed?
Three hundred knots.
It's headed right at Oakland.
Football game.
Oh, my God.
Missile radically changing direction.
New direction: 275 degrees west.
It's headed out to sea, sir.
Oh, Christ!
Missile losing altitude.
Falling.
Falling, 300 feet, 200, 100.
Bogey detonated under water.
What the fuck?
It missed.
- Well, that's great.
- Extremely great.
But there's still one left.
What happened to the rocket?
What the fuck happened to the coordinates?
What the fuck is going on?
Sir! Major!
- Captain, step outside.
- Talk to me, sir.
Captain, step outside!
Get me the Pentagon.
What the hell was that, Frank?
- I said, what the hell-
- I heard what you said!
If you're gonna be insubordinate,
I'd appreciate it if you'd do it with a little more respect.
Cut the crap, General.
- What the hell are you doing?
- I'm not ready to kill these people.
- Call the Pentagon. Ask for more time.
- No!
Do it, Frank!
We're coming loose.
You're coming loose.
The rest of us are in complete control.
- We're askin' 'em for a new deadline.
- Put the phone down.
- The men are falling apart.
- The men are Marines!
Are they?
- I wanna talk to General Kramer.
- You've been asked by an old friend.
- Put him on the phone right now.
- You've been ordered by a superior officer.
This is Major Baxter.
Now you're being given your last chance
by a man with a gun.
Put the phone down.
- I thought you weren't ready to kill.
- I'm warmin' up.
At ease.
They need a decision, Mr. President.
These past few hours
have been the longest, darkest of my life.
How does one weigh human life?
One million civilians against 81 hostages.
And in the middle, Frank Hummel.
That we have ignored,
abandoned or marginalized
a great soldier like Frank Hummel,
and that American boys have paid
for that neglect in blood,
is equally real and equally tragic.
We are at war with terror.
Fighting a war means casualties.
This is the worst call
I've ever had to make.
Air strike approved.
Red Thunder to tower.
Request clearance.
With the amount of firepower
they're gonna drop in there...
- Tower this is Strike Leader. Prepared to go.
- it'll be over in a few seconds.
Flight time to drop point.
17 minutes.
Excuse me, General, sir, with all due respect,
but what the fuck is going on?
- You changed the coordinates, didn't you?
- That's affirmative, Captain.
So, now they think we're gutless, the Feds?
They think we won't actually do it.
They're gonna come at us with everything they've got.
Air and sea.
They're gonna bomb our ass back to the Stone Age.
They don't know we missed on purpose.
Great. We're not gutless, we're incompetent.
That right?
I don't think I like your tone, Captain.
We planned for this contingency.
Load the V.X. into the choppers,
take four hostages and evacuate.
The consequences of our actions I'll face alone.
Excuse me, General,
but what about the fucking money?
There is no fucking money.
Mission's over.
Bullshit it's over.
You're talking to a general, soldier.
Maintain discipline.
I'm not a soldier, Major.
The day we took hostages we became mercenaries.
And mercenaries get paid!
I want my fucking money!
This mission was based on the threat of force.
I'm not about to kill 80,000 innocent people.
Do you think I'm out of my fucking mind?
We bluffed. They called it.
The mission's over.
Whoever said anything about bluffing, General?
Stand down, Captain.
Stand down, Captain!
Major, I'm ordering you
to take these men to the choppers and evacuate.
- That's a simple order, Major!
- It's not so simple, Frank.
Sergeant Crisp...
secure the General.
I'm relieving you of your command, sir.
Sergeant!
- I'll have that sidearm, sir.
- You mean this sidearm?
Major Baxter, you're either with us or against us.
It has been the greatest honor of my life
to serve with you, General.
But like he said...
it's over.
Let's get him.
Mason!
My God, what have I done?
Where's the last rocket?
- Where's the last rocket?
- Lower lighthouse.
- Go!
Darrow, go to the lighthouse.
I'll take care of this fucker!
One, two, three!
Eat that!
Did it.
Come here.
Come here, you little chicken shit!
You shoot me, I drop this.
We're both dead.
Well, come on. Come on.
Don't be scared. I won't hurt ya.
- Come on.
- Do you know how this shit works?
You know how this shit works?
Come on. Come on.
I don't need the gun.
I'll put it down.
Come on, let's play.
Come on. Come on.
Listen, I think we got started off on the wrong foot.
Stan Goodspeed, FBI. Uh-
Let's talk music.
Do you like the Elton John song, "Rocket Man"?
I don't like soft-ass shit.
Oh, you- Oh, oh.
Oh.
Well, I only bring it up because,
uh, it's you.
You're the Rocket Man.
No!
- How do you like how that shit works?
- Second rocket's away!
It splashed into the bay, sir.
No detonation.
Shit!
Darrow!
Open up!
Come on.
Hey, you mother!
Oh, I'm gonna get you now, baby.
Okay.
I got ya.
I got you, baby.
Come on.
Fucker!
Red Thunder Strike Leader.
Time on target: seven minutes.
English prick.
I tell you my old man was Irish?
Maintain air speed 450 knots.
Fuck!
It's me and you, pal.
I want that fucking chip!
I love pressure.
I know you're in here,
and I know you can hear me.
Now, pay the piper and come out like a man.
Increase speed to 500 knots.
You motherfucker!
Die!
I'm gonna choke my million bucks out of you.
You're gonna die.
Eat that, you fuck!
All right, team, inbound.
Time on target: 60 seconds.
Come to course heading 142 degrees.
When he neutralizes the threat,
we launch green flares
and we wait for the cavalry.
- Let's tighten up that formation.
- May God have mercy on their souls.
Please don't let this happen.
There has to be something you can do. Please.
Let's drop to the deck.
One hundred feet below radar.
Target acquired.
Rolling in.
This is Red Thunder.
Master armed. Master armed.
Time on target: 12 seconds.
T.O.T. ten seconds.
Stay tight, gentlemen.
I got green smoke.
I got green smoke!
This is C.Q One, C.Q One! Green smoke!
We have green smoke! Over.
- Eh, gimme that! Gimme that! Abort!
- Abort!
- Flight leader, abort, abort, abort!
- Jesus Chri-
I already dropped them!
- Oh, goddam it!
- Oh, my God!
Get out of my way.
Let me through, please. Let me through!
The cells did not get hit.
The bombs hit on the back of the island.
I'm fed up saving your ass.
I'm amazed you ever got past puberty.
I suppose all this
will make a great bedtime story to tell your kid.
You're insane, Mason. The kid'll have nightmares.
Spend all my money on shrinks.
Goodspeed, come in.
Goodspeed, Goodspeed, do you read me?
Come in!
- Scanning all radio frequencies.
- Goodspeed, do you read me? Come in!
Goodspeed, do you read me?
Come in!
This is Goodspeed.
- Are the hostages alive?
- Every one of 'em.
Goodspeed, it's Womack.
What about Mason?
- He's dead, sir.
- How? When?
Just come and get me.
Womack tore up your pardon, John.
But, of course. I knew he would.
The S.D.U.s and the scuba gear
should still be where we came ashore.
If you can get to the Pan Pacific Hotel,
there's clothes in my closet,
$200 in the Bible. Room 26.
Well, it's been a long time
since I've said thank you to anybody.
But thank you.
Well, Stanley, uh,
this is when we go our separate ways, huh?
But, uh, I'm sure you know
the etymology of your name "Goodspeed".
Yeah, Godspeed:
to wish someone a prosperous journey. Why?
Well, if you fancy a journey...
I recommend Fort Walton, Kansas.
I was thinking of Maui.
No.
Forget Maui.
"St. Michael's Church, Fort Walton, Kansas.
Front pew, right leg.
Hollow."
Is this what I think it is?
Mason?
Congratulations, Dr. Goodspeed.
You did it.
Thank you, sir.
You know, for a while there,
I didn't think you were gonna make it.
Well done, son.
So, where's Mason?
Vaporized.
Blown out to sea.
Blown out to sea, huh?
Yeah.
Poor bastard.
Goodspeed, where's Mason? Where's his body?
I wanna see that son of a bitch!
Vaporized, sir.
Excuse me, gentlemen.
What? Vaporized?
A body can vaporize?
Oh, yeah!
Absolutely, sir.
St. Michael's Church, front pew, right leg.
Front pew, right leg.
Vandals! Vandals!
Oh, yes, baby, come on!
- Stop! Vandals! Stop!
- I'm sorry!
- Come on, baby!
- I've got it! Okay, let's go!
- Stop! Stop!
- Sorry!
Stop! Hey, hey, you!
Vandals! Vandals!
Honey, uh, you wanna know who really killed J.F.K.?