Left, hut.
Left, march.
Left, hut. March.
One. Come on, number 47.
Detail, halt.
One, two, three, four. One...
Eyes left, boys.
One, two, three, four.
Left.
Detail, halt.
One, two, three, four...
Right, face.
Recruit detail to be sworn in, sir.
Major Donovan.
You are about to take the oath
of allegiance to your country
and to a regiment
that in hard battle on many fields
has earned the nickname,
"The Fighting 69th."
No man has ever let the regiment down.
Don't forget that.
Now raise your right hands and uncover.
And repeat after me.
Take your hat off!
- I...
Say your names.
...do solemnly swear...
...to bear true faith and allegiance...
...to the United States of America.
That I will serve them
honestly and faithfully...
...against all their enemies whomsoever.
- That I'll obey the orders...
- That I will obey the orders...
...of the President of the United States...
...and of the officers appointed over me...
...according to the rules
and articles of war.
- So help me, God.
All right, Corporal.
Right face.
Forward hut.
One, two, three, four.
Column right.
Can you read that?
I say, can you read that?
Only the letters.
I don't know what it means.
Go on, read the letters.
"B" is for Brooklyn, "Y" is for Yonkers,
"Q" for Queens, "H" for Harlem
and "X" marks the Bronx.
Come on. Get moving.
- Open that shirt. Over there.
- Thanks.
That's a funny crack, ain't it?
Breathe deeply.
Hey, you, I been all through this before
over in the Armory. What's the big idea?
- Oh, really? What's your name?
- Plunkett. What's yours?
Put Private Plunkett on report.
"Addressing medical officer as
"Hey, you." Insubordination.
"What's the big idea?"
- Yes, Major.
- Major?
You're in the army now.
Stand up. Breathe.
I'm sorry.
Roll your sleeves up, way up!
Ouch!
Fine bunch of soldiers,
can't even take a little pin prick.
It ain't that.
It's the serum that makes you keel over.
What are you trying to hand me?
All right, keep moving, fellows.
Keep still, will you?
Just a little bayonet practice, buddy.
What? No backbone?
Get off that table!
- Does it hurt much, Doc?
- Not much.
Oh, Mr. Doctor,
please don't hurt me. Please.
Sir, I've already had these here shots.
Fine. You'll be twice as healthy.
Oh, I never saw such a mob in all my life.
Go ahead, Admiral. Shoot the works.
Thanks.
Four union suits, wool, long.
Union suits, wool, long.
Two shirts, OD, 16.
- Say, I wear only 14.
- They'll shrink.
Britches, OD, 42.
- What do you mean, 42?
- One hat.
What's the matter with you?
I can't wear these pants.
- They're four sizes too big.
- Next.
Hey, wait a minute, you.
Come on, here. Keep moving.
Don't hold up the war.
But these pants are too big.
They'll fall down.
That's your problem. Get going.
You big, thick donkey.
- What'd you say?
- I said it was nice and cool out.
Come on, you fellows! Get out of it!
Come on!
Rise and shine!
Come on! Get it together!
Roust out of there, dope heads!
Rise and shine.
Come on, Cleopatra, vacate that couch!
So the lady says,
"Can I help it if my son worries?"
Come on, shake a leg. Snap out of it.
Well, well, well,
who's this darling little sleepyhead?
Beg pardon,
but as a personal favor to Pershing,
- would you mind dragging out of here?
- Go on, beat it.
Listen, are you gonna come quiet like
or do I gotta...
Oh, it must be a nightmare.
Go away, will you?
- Tell me. Do you know what that tune is?
- Yeah, I know.
It's 15 minutes to reveille
and I don't like it.
I don't like you, either.
Now, go on, tell the Colonel he wants you.
Why, you big, Irish, no-good heel, you...
Smart guy.
One, two, three, four.
What's the matter, Plunkett?
You got two left feet?
One, two, three, four.
One, two...
Come on up there, Wynn.
Squads, left about! Hey!
Close up there.
Squads right, hut.
Oh, that's beautiful.
A lot of baboons on roller skates
couldn't do better.
One, two, three, four.
Bayonet exercise. Guard!
That elbow down, Wynn.
Ready. Thrust!
Ready. Lunge!
No, no, no, no.
What do you guys think you're doing?
Tickling your grandmas?
Them's bayonets, not bodkin needles.
Give me that rifle.
When you lunge, lunge.
Get him or he'll get you.
Stick him in the throat
or in his chest, or in the belly.
Don't waste your steel, see?
And when you lunge, six inches is enough.
And if your bayonet gets stuck,
don't put your foot on his chest.
Pull the trigger and shoot it out.
Now, you got that, lame brain?
Come, on, snap into it.
Make believe that dummy's
the guy you hate the most.
Ready. Lunge!
That's for you, Mike. How do you like it?
Inspection. Arms!
Order. Arms!
Wake up, Wynn.
As you were.
What's your name, lug?
Sure, me name's Mike Murphy,
Sergeant Your Honor.
Well, stand fast
till you get the orders to move.
Right.
- Did you say your name was Murphy?
- I did, Your Worship, saving your presence.
- What were you born?
- Sure, I was born a boy.
Pipe down.
- What name were you born with?
- Mischa Moskowitz.
- Where'd you get the Murphy?
- I took it.
You see, sir, I wanted to go over
with the Fighting 69th.
Okay?
Okay, Mike. Oh, look at young Wynn.
With a chest like a sparrow.
- Suck it in! Stick it out!
- Hey, cut it out, will you, Mike?
It's Sergeant Wynn to you, and like it.
I'll make a soldier out of you yet.
Now, one more thing.
Don't you fellows go wandering
too far away after chow.
I've got good news for you.
Major Donovan's taking the battalion
out on night tactics, with full packs.
Pipe down. Or you'll never get dismissed.
I'm sick and...
Fasten that collar! Suck in that gut!
Try and look like a soldier! And you, too.
You're no privileged character.
Heave those shoulders back!
Dismissed!
- What are you so tired about?
- I don't know. Maybe you make me tired.
What's that?
I joined this outfit
to go over there and fight,
not to stay around here
doing "squads, east" for six months.
- Is that so?
- Yeah. And another thing.
I ain't used to getting up
at 5:30 in the morning
to take 25-mile hike
and get pushed around by you.
And you don't like it, huh?
There's a lot of things
in this man's army I don't like.
Well, now, that's really tough.
But I think I know what you need.
A little diversionment.
Now, there's a great big pile of potatoes
that needs peeling.
And you're gonna peel them
and keep on peeling them
until we leave Camp Mills.
Button up that collar!
Night tactics in this weather.
Well, that fixes us.
Give me a cigarette, will you, soldier?
Look, Crepe Hanger,
don't you ever buy any of your own?
For what? I'll take that match.
Do you know how many guys
have died of pneumonia
on night tactics in the last 10 years?
What's the use
of going out at night, anyway?
You can't see the enemy in the dark.
Quit your crabbing.
It's all part of the game.
Yeah, some game.
Get shoved around
by that Wild Bill Donovan
and that big, thick mick
of a tough Sergeant.
Hey, listen, you.
Lay off of that "thick mick" stuff.
Listen, flannel-mouth,
I'll say what I please.
- And if you don't like it, I'II...
- Hey, Wynn.
Keep away from that loud-mouth Plunkett.
He's a wrong soldier
and he'll get you into trouble. Savvy?
All right. What are you sore about?
I might as well be in the cavalry.
Yes, and a horse at that.
All I get is riding from you.
"Snap into it, Wynn. Snap out of it, Wynn."
Keep your shirt on.
I can't let the rest of this mob
say I'm playing favorites
with me own kid brother.
- Sergeant.
- Attention!
As you were.
What's the big idea keeping
the company in formation
after the others were dismissed?
Listen, John, just because we're...
Lieutenant to you, and don't you forget it.
Nobody's gonna accuse me
of playing favorites.
And that goes for you, too.
Button up that collar.
What do you think this is, Coxey's Army?
What would Ma say if she could see you
streeling around like this?
Say, you could use a hair cut, too.
Did you hear from Ma, sir?
Or would the lieutenant be
so condescending
as to tell us how she's feeling?
Or do I get a court-martial for asking?
She's feeling fine and she wants us to see
that he brushes his teeth.
- I'll tell Corporal Healey.
- Say, now listen...
- Pipe down!
- Quiet!
Go back into your quarters
and put that blunder-buss away.
The hunting season hasn't opened yet.
Hang this up in my tent
while you're about it, too, will you?
You...
You know, it's a shame to keep riding him.
How's he doing?
Well, I hate to say it,
but I think he's all 69th.
Left,
hut.
Left, hut.
- Hello, Jack.
- Father.
- How's Mrs. O'Keefe?
- Expecting again, sir.
Now, I didn't ask her condition.
I asked about her health.
- Oh, she's fine, thank you, Father.
- Good.
The division's filling up, Father.
The 4th Alabama's coming in.
Well, you'll all be making history
in a few months.
Maybe sooner than you think.
We'll need your prayers, Father.
When did an Irishman ever need a prayer
in a fight?
What are you reading there?
Oh, by the way, did you ever
get up the courage to talk to Kilmer?
I've been intending to.
Do you think he'd mind?
- Oh, Joyce.
- Yes, Father?
Lieutenant Ames has a favor to ask of you.
Yes. Would you autograph this for me?
I'd be very pleased to, Lieutenant.
- Do you have a pen?
- I have.
Thank you.
You're quite welcome, sir.
- Goodbye, Father.
- Goodbye.
- Going my way, Corporal?
- Yes, sir.
- Goodbye, Father.
- Goodbye, son.
Got a match, buddy?
Thanks.
- I don't think I met you yet.
- I been around.
Plunkett's my name. Jerry Plunkett.
Smiling Jerry they call me on account
of my disposition. What's yours?
Fiery Frank. Duffy for short.
Irish, huh? I am, too, but I don't work at it.
I don't like these flannel-mouth micks
who go around singing
Molly Malone all the time.
I think maybe you're in the wrong outfit.
This regiment has certain traditions.
Oh, don't give me that malarkey.
We both joined up for the same thing.
To come back dripping with medals.
Big shots, the world our oyster.
- Our what?
- Oysters.
You know, you eat them. Oysters.
- How did you leave things in Brooklyn?
- Swell.
- How did you know I was from Brooklyn?
- That was my third guess.
Hey, you ain't so dumb for a soldier.
You steer me right around here, Duffy,
and we'll get places.
Now, just to bind our friendship,
a friend of mine gave me
one in the Fifth at Saratoga.
You can have it. Look.
Rest!
Hi, buddy.
Tell you what.
Let's and me go AWOL tonight, huh?
I got some swell numbers here.
Good-Iooking dames, right here.
Am I glad I transferred out
of them Engineers.
This outfit eats right, don't it, boy?
- Hey, soldier. What's your outfit?
- 4th Alabama.
- That's down South, ain't it?
- You know it's the truth.
One thing you gotta have
if you're gonna soldier proper,
and that's chow.
Well, there's nothing to kick about here,
is there?
Hi, dixie.
Did you bring any corn pone with you?
- Done better than that, friend.
- Yeah?
You all better come over tonight
for a mess of possum pie.
Say, what kind of a trip did you have
coming up here?
Well, when we got up
as far as Pennsylvania
the temperature dropped right down to 99.
- Like to froze to death.
- You don't say so.
- Hey, when are we going overseas?
- Don't be in a hurry.
They're holding the war back
for you Alabama fellows.
- What outfit do you all belong to?
- Why we're the Fighting 69th.
The Fighting 69th? Quite a handle.
Where'd you get it?
- Oh, Civil War. What's your outfit?
- 4th Alabama.
Wait a minute. You say your Civil War
fighting got you that name?
Sure thing. Ain't you never heard of us?
You wouldn't be
the 69th New York Irishers, would you?
Sure are. So you heard about us, huh?
I'll say we have.
Hey, folks, these is the 69th New York.
Want to know if we remember them.
Hey, what's so funny?
Do we remember you?
Do you remember us?
You ought to.
We shot the pants off of your outfit once.
Say that again.
Who shot the pants off of who?
We did. The 4th Alabama.
We shot the pants off you,
the 69th New York
at Mary's Heights in 1862.
Hey. Look, a fight.
- Who's fighting who?
- What do you care? Come on.
- Well, it's a good fight all right.
- Yeah. But somebody's gonna get hurt.
- The saps.
- Help me break it up, Jerry.
Not me, pal. You don't get medals
for that kind of fighting.
Hey, break it up.
Break it up.
Break it up here!
Break it up. Break it up.
Terence. Casey. Clanahan.
Come on.
Beat it, gang. Donovan!
Come on, break it up.
Break it up, you men.
The Major!
Get back in your rank.
Here comes the Major. The Major.
Get back in your ranks.
Attention. Back, I said.
Just a minute.
Who started this ballet russe?
Them razorbacks said they shot
the pants off of us in the Civil War.
We did.
- He's right. They did.
- What?
At the battle of Fredericksburg.
This outfit, the 4th Alabamans,
broke up the charge of the 69th
and stopped us right in our tracks.
And you cheered your heads off
because you respected a game enemy.
Now, those men on both sides
were Americans.
They fought
and then rose above their hatreds
to become one people again.
And that's the way it should be,
or do you think the whole nation
is out of step but you?
Our two regiments
are now brigaded together.
Their very names are even changed.
The 69th New York, to the
165th United States Infantry.
The 4th Alabamas to the 167th.
Every day, more and more are joining us.
Outfits from all over the country.
Well, they're not coming here
as Easterners, or Southerners
or Alaskans, or New Englanders.
Those men are coming here as Americans
to form an organization that represents
every part and section of our country,
the Rainbow Division.
But there's no room in this Rainbow
for sectional feuds
because we're all one nation now,
one team,
an all-American team, pulling together
and known as the United States Army.
So if you must fight,
wait until you get overseas.
Believe me,
you'll get a belly full of it over there.
Now, go on. Get back to your ranks
and behave yourselves.
- Are you hurt, Father?
- Hurt? Now, who'd hurt me?
Oh, it's Father Duffy, is it?
And who am I?
Patsy Dumb-Cluck, I suppose.
Me pal, stringing me along.
You know they can't get away
from these Dominus Vobiscum salesmen
even in the army.
Well, maybe it's because
the saints have their eyes on you, son.
Don't give me that.
I can take care of myself.
Well, maybe you can,
but I thought if you ever did need me...
Now look, hard collar, once and for all...
Go on. What do you mean
snapping at Father like that?
Take your hand off of me,
you big, thick mick.
Why, I got a good notion to chew you up
and spit you out.
Go on. Beat it.
My, but it's a violent man you are.
Come on, Jerry,
let's get the mud off your smiling face.
Come on, break it up.
Button your collar!
Come on. What's holding you men back?
By the time you get into position
the enemy would have
a dozen machine guns on you.
Come on! Double up.
I'd like to see you double up
and I don't mean from running either.
Why, when we get to France that
guy's going out on patrols some nights.
I'm gonna hang bells all over him.
All right, all right. Spread out and fall.
Fall, I said!
Burke, get that stern down!
Come on, come on, simulate firing
as soon as you hit the line.
Now, cease firing and follow me.
Wouldn't you know it,
as soon as we get comfortable,
we gotta get up and at 'em?
Come on, put some swing in it.
You're not dead yet.
No, we're not dead yet.
We're just muscle-bound, flat-footed,
fed up and far from home.
Outside of that, we're all right.
A lot that slave-driver cares
whether we are or not.
- Pipe down.
- You want to get in trouble?
You ain't no bargain yourself.
Hey, you guys, what are you trying to do,
win the war over here?
How much overtime you get?
You guys are sure gluttons
for punishment.
What are you training for, the Olympics?
No. We're just
Wild Bill Donovan's chain gang.
So this is the insignia
of the Rainbow Division, huh?
- Every color in the spectrum.
- Squads left!
- What's the matter? Don't you like it?
- Oh, indeed I do.
I was just thinking the boys
in the 69th might like it better
if there was a little green in it.
Squads left. March.
Bill, don't you think maybe
you're a little hard on the boys?
Night hikes and forced marches.
After all, they're not used to that grind.
I'll handle the military end of it.
You look after their souls, Father.
- I'm sorry, Bill.
- No. I'm sorry.
But war's a brutal business. I know.
I've seen what's been going on over there.
That's why I've been so hard on the men.
I've got to be, so they'll be able to face
what's coming later.
These kids of mine are going up against
veterans, schooled in three years of war.
They've got to be able to out-endure
and outfight them,
not just to be led in half-trained
like sheep led to the slaughter.
Don't you suppose
I've wanted to let up on them?
I didn't dare. I've got to think of the future.
- All ready, sir.
- Thank you.
And now, the future has come.
I couldn't tell you this before,
but this isn't just another night hike.
This is it.
Give me your blessing, Father.
Amen.
Thank you.
Column of squads.
First Company, squads right.
- Squads right.
- Hut.
Almighty God, in thine infinite mercy,
grant unto me, thy servant,
the wisdom to guide my young flock
through the trials of war.
Oh, Father, they're so young.
So young and they know so little of life.
And nothing at all of that terrible and
bloody altar towards which they move,
carrying so eagerly
the bright sacrifice of their youth.
Their need will be great, O Lord,
and I am weak.
Therefore, I beseech thee
through thy Son, Christ, our Lord,
grant me the strength
to keep them steadfast
in the faith, in decency and courage
to the glory of God,
their country and their regiment,
in the bad times to come.
And if in battle you see fit
to gather them to your protecting arms,
thy will be done.
But let them die like men,
valiant and unafraid.
Come on. Company A fall in.
Come on here.
Come on, fall in here.
Come on, get back in line there.
Come on, fall in, men. Snap it up.
Make it lively. Come on here.
- Get in line there.
- Come on, you fellows.
Throw those cigarettes away. Get in here.
Form this line. Come on.
Snap it up, you mugs.
You move like a lot of sailors.
Come on, put those pipes down.
Right, dress.
- One.
- Two.
- Three.
- Four.
Count off.
- One.
- Two.
- Three.
- Four.
- One.
- Two.
- Three.
- Four.
- One.
- Two.
As you were.
What's the matter with you?
You're three, ain't you?
All by myself.
Why, you swivel-necked far-down...
Three. Now, let's get on with the war.
I came over here to stuff those Dutchmen
back in their sausage skins.
And all we do is stand around...
The first thing you know,
you'll stuff yourself right in the clink.
And, now, Mr. Funny Man,
before it slips my mind,
suppose after retreat you report
to the mess Sergeant
and tell him that you'd like to do
a little extra duty as kitchen police.
And stuff that in your pipe and puff on it.
Count off!
- One.
- Two.
- Three.
- Four.
- One.
- Two.
Now, remember, men,
we're the first American soldiers
to march through the streets of Grand.
I know we're all pretty tired,
but let's show the natives
the old 69th has what it takes.
Column squads, first company.
- Squads, left.
- Squads, left!
Squads, left!
March!
Eyes, right.
Front.
Eyes right.
Wonder what we're gonna get to eat
when we get billeted?
I heard the Sergeant
just say something about slum.
I figure it's about time.
We ain't had any slum since last night.
I got an awful mean feeling, boys,
awful mean.
If they don't let us
at those Boches pretty soon,
I'll have to carve me up a top Sergeant.
Don't mind him, Sarge.
He's his own worst enemy.
Not while I'm alive, he ain't.
Our present orders
are to march to Luneville,
starting the day after Christmas.
It's going to be tough going through
the Vosges foothills and forests
over these icy roads and in this weather.
Think your supply train
can keep up with us, Mangan?
It will, sir, if my men have to carry
the horses and pull the wagons.
Father Duffy, how about
your midnight mass tonight?
Everything's all set, sir,
barring the conversion of a few heathen,
present company no exception.
- And facilities for the non-Catholics?
- It's all taken care of, sir.
Lieutenant Holmes,
the Methodist chaplain,
is going to arrange services
for the protestant boys.
Oh, and of all people, Mike Murphy
is going to build a pulpit for him.
I've wired to GHQ
for chaplains for both
the Alabamas and the Illinois.
You know, Colonel,
if a lot of the people back home
knew how well the various faiths
got along together over here,
it'd cause a lot of scandal
to some pious minds.
Well, gentlemen, I guess that's all.
Oh, boy.
Give me a cigarette, will you, McManus?
- Don't you get tired bumming cigarettes?
- No.
- Hello, Father. How are you?
- Hello, boys.
- Glad to see you.
- How are you?
Hey, Father, you're looking pale.
You know, you gotta look after
your health in this funny climate.
Yes. It's beginning to get a lot of the boys.
- First, your arms go to sleep.
- They do?
And there's a slight buzzing in your ears.
And the most fatal symptom of all,
there's a light feeling in your head.
Father, I got it.
And that means you need exercise.
And the finest thing in the world
is pumping an organ at midnight mass.
It'll make a new man of you.
You're gonna pump an organ.
That's one on me, Father.
Paddy, would you like to
sweep out the church?
Oh, I wouldn't like to, but I will.
I'll say you will.
I think I'll go to your mass tonight.
That is, if it's okay.
Oh, sure.
That is, if you're sure you want to.
Well, why not?
You know, you're such a swell guy, Father.
- I think I'd go to the devil with you.
- Oh, you would now?
- Well, that is, if you asked me to.
- If I asked you...
Well, I mean,
if there's anything I can do to help,
I'd be glad to do it.
Attention!
Hiya, Saint Francis? How's all the monks?
On your feet
when an officer comes in the room.
And take that cigarette out of your mouth.
All right, boys. As you were.
- Merry Christmas, Father.
- See you later.
- Yeah. Right, sir.
Okay.
Oh, don't forget midnight mass.
And confession's this afternoon.
- Okay.
- Okay. We'll be there.
If you need any help, Father,
we'll be right outside.
Give us a break and need some help,
will you, Father?
It would be a pleasure.
You know, Jerry, you're getting yourself
so well liked in this army
they'd rather machine gun you
than the Germans.
It was bad enough at Camp Mills.
But instead of improving
you're getting worse.
- That's what you think.
- No, that's what everyone thinks.
They're beginning to call you a misfit
and a troublemaker.
Well, now that's tough.
I'm gonna bust right out crying.
Sit down a minute. I want to talk to you.
You know, Jerry,
I don't think you're as tough as you think.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
You're only kidding yourself.
You're your own biggest sucker.
- Oh, yeah?
- Sure.
I've seen too much of life and men.
You know, son,
there's only one thing wrong with you.
You're Ionesome, that's all.
Me Ionesome? That's rich.
Oh, sure, I know.
Smart boys don't need anyone.
They can take care of themselves.
But there are some
pretty dark days ahead, Jerry,
when a man will have need of a friend
he can depend on.
You haven't made any friends.
And that's where I thought
I might come in.
To help you find him.
We're going into the trenches
right after Christmas.
You're not kidding me, are you?
Well, that's great.
That's what we came over here for.
The sooner the better.
And when was the last time
you were to confession?
Oh, I knew you'd worm around to that
sooner or later.
- There's midnight mass tonight, Jerry.
- Yeah, so I hear.
And I don't think Christmas is a bad time
for any of us to take stock and check up.
Come on, now. What do you say?
Why don't you join the boys tonight?
Now, look, Chaplain.
Get this once and for all.
I came over here to soldier, not to pray.
I don't go for that Holy Joe stuff.
So there's no use trying to convert me.
I'm not trying to convert you, son.
I'm asking you
to come back to your religion
and recognize the fact of Almighty God.
Well. Merry Christmas, Jerry.
"If a man have a hundred sheep
and one should go astray,
"doth he not leave the ninety and nine
in the mountains
"and go seeketh that
which is gone astray?
"And if it so be that he find it,
"verily I say unto you,
"he rejoiceth more of that,
"than of the ninety and nine
which went not astray."
Hey, where do we sleep tonight?
The same place as last night,
on the side of the road.
We ain't been on a road since Tuesday.
Ain't you heard, we ain't stopping tonight.
We're going right on.
Anyway, we ain't got nothing to stop for.
The rolling kitchens is back there
halfway to Brooklyn.
Yeah, and am I hungry.
You're hungry?
Never mind that.
Pull over at the side of the road
and get that kitchen through.
Come on, men. Hey!
Come on, snap into it.
Get them over the side of the road.
Boy, what I could do now
to a big grilled steak
with lashings of mashed potatoes
and gravy.
- Oh, shut up.
- I'm hungry.
I ain't had nothing for three days
except hard tack and a can of dog meat.
An army ain't an army unless it eats.
It's just a walking famine.
And you were the guy who said
you could find chow
in the middle of the Sahara.
Well, I wouldn't call this the Sahara.
Come on, Mahonies, you're doing all right.
- How are you doing, Ryan?
- Okay, sir.
- Not a big out of order, huh?
- No, sir.
- Getting tired, Scully?
Let me have your pack,
will you, O'Mahoney?
No, sir. No man's carrying my pack.
My name's O'Mahony, not O'Mahoney.
What's so funny?
I was just thinking, the Navy rejected me
because I had flat feet.
This walking's awful tough, Father.
You should have
joined the cavalry, Terrance.
Not me.
When the shooting begins
and I gotta get out of there,
I don't want to be hindered by no horse.
Well, look at you.
All dressed up like a tinker's donkey.
- I'm doing all right, ain't I?
- Ah, you're just showing off.
Yeah, sure. And how I can show them.
Wait till we get up in the lines.
Foot slipped.
Yeah. I know.
I can't keep up, Sarge.
These blasted pack-straps
are cutting my shoulders off.
Here. Lean on me.
My shoulders. Pack-straps.
My shoulders ache beneath my pack.
- Boy, listen to that gunnery.
- We're getting close to the war.
Sounds like the Fourth at Coney Island.
"My shoulders ache beneath my pack
"Lie easier, cross, upon his back"
I wish I hadn't thrown
my extra shoes away.
The squadron has a corn
of canned willy left.
- They can have it.
- It always makes me thirsty.
Gosh-darned rifle butt, my fingers is froze.
"My rifle hand is stiff and numb"
Boy, I hope it doesn't rain again tonight.
"From Thy pierced palms red rivers run"
Come on, you sons.
What's the matter with you?
Come on, come on, for the love of Mike!
Keep hiking, will you?
Don't die on your feet.
"Men shout at me who may not speak"
Pick 'em up. This ain't no excursion.
"They scourged thy back
and smote thy cheek"
What's that you're muttering?
It may turn out to be a prayer
or perhaps only a poem.
You know something?
A guy with your savvy
should never be no Sergeant.
You should join the candidate's school
and be an officer.
No. I'd have to leave the 69th.
This is it, gentlemen.
The old 69th again faces an enemy.
Major Donovan, you'll take over
the front line from the chasseurs.
- Yes, sir.
- McKenna, you'll be in support.
Major Moynihan with the third battalion
in reserve.
Any questions?
Don't worry, boys.
We'll all get a crack at 'em.
Kind of wish I wasn't a CO.
I'd like one good inning myself.
Well, I guess that's all.
Good luck, men.
Fall in. First company, right by twos.
March!
Put them on. Pull.
Here we go, boys.
All aboard for the roller coaster.
Do you feel like you're going down
in a fast elevator?
- I do.
- Say your prayers, Fritzy.
Your body may belong to the Kaiser,
but your soul belongs to Plunkett.
- Shut up!
- Dry up!
You got the loudest mouth
in the allied army.
- Plunkett this. What a you think...
- Plunkett.
- Listen to McManus show off.
- Shut up.
- Well, Padre, pray for us.
- I will, indeed.
- The reserve area's back there, Father.
- Yes, I saw it on the map.
But you've gotta go back there, Father.
It's regulations.
It's funny. With all the firing going on,
I seem to have lost my hearing.
- But you can't come up here.
- Yes, I know. I know all about it.
Now, suppose one of the boys met
with an accident.
It has been known
to happen up here, you know.
You wouldn't deny them the consolation
of my master's presence now, will you?
As the priest said to the bishop,
I only go to the races
in case one of the jockeys fall off.
That's near enough.
Hey.
You were told to keep your mitts off
that Very pistol.
What do you want the heinies to do?
Blow us all over France?
What's the matter, Sarge,
you're getting the wind up?
There's always an MP job waiting for you
back in Paris, you know.
Or maybe just those stripes
taking again, huh?
Maybe you ain't heard tell, soldier.
There's a war going on up here.
Yeah, I read about it in papers
but I ain't seen none of it yet.
If this is all there is to it,
I don't see
what those limeys and frogs are...
If I were you, I'd keep my big yap shut up
about the limeys and the frogs
until I earned a fighting man's right
to talk.
- And maybe you think I won't.
- Oh, hero stuff, huh?
Would you be satisfied with
the Distinguished Service Cross?
Well, if I don't get it,
it's because I got a wooden one.
And if you don't believe me, you got a bet.
Gee, that guy hates himself.
Yes, and that makes it unanimous.
Come on, you guys,
let's match to see who watches the baby
- and who goes to sleep, huh?
- Nothing doing. We all watch.
- Look at that dent, will you?
- Better there than in your skull.
I'll pay that son off.
Oh, still wanna play, huh? All right.
Better to see you with, Grandma.
- Hey, what're you doing?
- Hey, lay off!
Hey, what're you doing? Cut that out.
Phone headquarters at once.
No one was authorized to send up a flare.
- Yes, sir.
- Here's a kiss for you.
Those heinies seem to be sore
at someone.
Where's your duty roster?
- Corporal Sullivan.
- Yes, sir?
Have some coffee, gentlemen.
Duty roster.
Following men report to Sergeant Kilmer
for action detail at 4:00 a.m.
Pipe down, will you? Answer your names.
Take it easy now. Quiet.
Here you are, Corporal.
Laffy.
What a spot! What a spot!
Now, what's wrong?
I'm worried. You know what?
Those shells is talking to me.
Yeah? What are they saying?
You ain't never gonna
get back to the New York.
- Hey, stretcher-bearers.
- They're wrecking the whole line.
We'll be next!
The Sergeant warned you not to mess
with those flares.
All these guys are dead and you done it!
Jack!
O'Keefe!
A bull's-eye.
Hey, what are you doing here?
Get back up to your post!
Let me by! I don't want to stay up there
and get blown to pieces.
What do you think I am, crazy?
And you're the one
that's always popping off
about all the medals
you're gonna win, huh?
What kind of 69th man are you?
You yellow skunk!
- Now go on, get back up to that fire-step.
- I won't! I won't!
Steady, men! We'll get out!
Come on, step on it!
- Jerry! Jerry, are you hurt?
- No, Father. No.
What is it, then?
What were you doing in a dugout?
You're supposed to be
in the front line on duty!
- Who sent you back?
- Nobody. You see, Father...
Yes, I do see. Indeed I do.
I met Lieutenant Wynn down there,
and then the shell hit.
- Where are the rest of them?
- Down there, buried alive.
Let's go.
All right, you guys, now, all together, now.
One, two, heave!
Now, don't let this thing cave in
on my head.
All right, now give me your hand.
- I'm dying. My leg's off...
- Give me your hand.
- Here, take his head.
- It's Moran!
- He's out of his head.
- Shut up.
- Got a stretcher, somebody. Hurry up.
- Keep on working, there, you guys.
Have mercy on us. Have mercy.
They're buried alive, all of 'em. Buried.
Now, now, snap out of it, son.
- We'll get the others.
- No, you'll not.
You'll never get them out of there.
Lieutenant Norman's dead with a beam
that crushed his head like an egg.
They're all dead, except Eddie Kearney
and Lieutenant Wynn.
They can't get out.
They'll be dead in a minute.
Let me make a try at it, will you?
My brother is down there.
I'm sorry, soldier. But there ain't a chance.
- But...
- Steady, kid.
Dolan, I'm going down there.
Hold my ankles.
- Yes, Father.
- Sergeant, get your men to lift this beam.
You can't get down there, Father.
The whole place is gonna cave in
in a minute.
- Go on, do as he tells you.
- Yes, sir.
Go ahead, Father.
Ed. Ed Kearney!
John Wynn! It's Father Duffy, boys.
It's Father Duffy.
Can you hear me?
It's just like a tourist
kissing the Blarney Stone.
"...perhaps their brave young spirits hear
The bugle sing
"Go to sleep! Go to sleep!
"Slumber well
where the shell screamed and fell
"Let your rifles rest on the muddy floor
You will not need them any more
"Danger's past
Now at last
"Go to sleep!
"And up to Heaven's doorway floats
"From the wood called Rouge Bouquet,
"A delicate cloud of bugle notes
that softly say
"Farewell!
"Comrades true, born anew, peace to you!
"Your souls shall be where the heroes are
"And your memory shine
like the morning star
"Brave and dear
Shield us here
"Farewell!"
Sit down! Come on, get going.
Them French donkeys don't even
understand their own language.
Give me one of them vegetables!
I'll show you how to do it. Angelique!
Hey, look. Why don't we carry the donkey?
Does not one of you understand
the sensitive nature of the poor darling?
A donkey's not a gunnery mule.
A donkey's sensitive and high-strung,
like a thoroughbred.
Now watch me.
Beer. One. Compris?
There you are.
- American money?
- Keep the change.
Hey, you with the face,
ain't you supposed to be on guard duty?
Oh, yeah. Halt! Who's there?
Well, if it ain't old rattlesnake puss.
On your dogs!
Now, wait a minute, Sarge.
This beer is very important.
Take your hands off me,
you son of a banshee,
or I'll knock your teeth down your throat.
- You'll do what?
- You heard me.
Or are you gonna hide behind
those five and ten-cent stripes again?
Plunkett, you've been begging for this
for a long time,
and now you're gonna get it.
Give it to him.
Move over so he can fall down.
Not yet! Come here! Come on! Come on.
Come on.
You're bouncing around like a rubber ball.
Come on, get up.
Get him, Sarge!
Can't hit me, can you?
Never touched me.
Attention!
Sergeant, what's the meaning of this?
- Well, sir... That is, sir...
- All right, take the air. The party's over.
You know the penalty
for hitting a subordinate.
Yes, sir.
Report to your company commander.
You're under arrest.
- Yes, sir.
- You can prefer charges in the morning.
Charges? What charges?
There was no fight, sir.
- What do you mean, no fight?
- No, no. There, there was no fight.
I was just showing Mike...
I mean, the First Sergeant
how to roll away from a left hook.
Just a little exhibition for the boys,
that was all.
No, there was no fighting.
A real fight,
I'd mop up the joint with the big...
I mean, my friend, the First Sergeant.
No, it was just a gag,
we were only fooling.
He never laid a finger on me.
Yeah, so I see.
All right, Sergeant.
Forget that arrest order.
Yes, sir.
And the next time you two want to frolic,
don't play so rough.
Well, I guess I'm after owing you
something, soldier.
You don't owe me nothing.
I don't need
Donovan to do my fighting for me.
I can do my own, and I love it.
Yeah.
- Well, that settles it.
- Settles what?
Plunkett. Gonna get rid of him.
Transfer him out of the regiment.
- Why? Because of that little brush-up?
- Oh, that and everything else.
He's a bad egg, a troublemaker.
Unreliable in the line.
He's getting himself talked about
in a way that the 69th doesn't relish.
Bill, why don't you give the boy a chance?
I happen to know
he had a pretty bad shock up there.
Well, it's ruined his value as a soldier.
I've heard nothing but complaints
from his company commander on down.
Picking fights back of the lines
and dodging patrols when he's up there.
Reporting sick
when he's detailed to wiring parties.
Just one excuse after another,
whenever there's a man's job to be done.
I won't have a man like that
in the battalion.
Bill, I don't want
to interfere with discipline.
Don't you think it's possible
he has a good side?
I think he showed that.
Well, he can develop it someplace else.
My mind's made up.
Bill.
I think you'll agree that war has ruined
many a young fellow. Too many in fact.
Well, now here's an exceptional case,
one in a thousand,
where maybe the war will do a little good.
Why, Bill, I've heard you say yourself
a hundred times,
the 69th makes men.
Well, it makes men out of cowards
not cowards out of men.
Here's my chance to prove
that you're right.
You trust me and keep Plunkett on
and I'll assume full responsibility.
Oh, that blarneying tongue of yours.
I should have let them send you home to
collect funds for the Knights of Columbus.
Maybe you wanted to save me the trouble
of swimming back.
Come on, Bill. What do you say?
Shall we let Plunkett stay?
All right. All right, but from now on,
he's your guinea pig.
- All right. Oh, Bill, there's something else.
- What?
What if you give Captain Mangan
an okay to provide buses
to take the Jewish boys to Napier.
Sure. I'll take care of that.
You know, it's a good thing
there's no Mohammedans in the regiment.
I'd have no time for the war.
Well, it's a fortunate thing
you're not a crook.
You could sell the Brooklyn Bridge
to the police department.
- Yes?
- Private Plunkett reporting.
The Major sent for me, sir.
Will you see Captain Mangan
about those buses now?
Yes, sir.
Plunkett, you're a rotten soldier.
You have no loyalty,
no fighting spirit, nothing.
Stand up!
I've been getting more and more fed up
with you ever since Camp Mills.
But you jawed so much
about getting at the Germans,
I thought getting up to the front
might discover something in you.
Well, it didn't!
Beginning with our first night
in the trenches you...
- Oh, so Father Duffy talked, huh?
- He didn't have to.
I've got eyes
and so has every man in the regiment.
It was the same at Baccarat, Champagne.
In fact, every fight we've been in.
You're quite a scrapper, Plunkett,
behind the lines.
Pretty handy with your fists.
Trying to prove how tough you are
to a bunch of men
who no longer believe you.
Consequently, I've decided to boot you
out of the regiment,
- transfer you someplace else.
- Well, if the Major thinks that's best, sir.
I did, and so do you,
but Father Duffy didn't.
He believes in you.
That's why you're getting another chance.
But remember this,
the first sign of malingering
or sloppy soldiering,
Father Duffy nor the Archbishop of Meath
won't be able to save you,
and it won't be a transfer this time.
Yes, sir.
That's all, Plunkett.
Plunkett!
We're moving up to the attack
across the Ourcq River tonight.
It's your chance to redeem yourself
and prove that Father Duffy was right.
Now, get going.
Yes, sir.
Hold it! Hold it!
This is as far as we go tonight.
Man the fire-steps end detail outposts
and fix up these parapets.
- Yes, sir.
- We'll consolidate here.
- Wynn.
- Yes, sir.
Turn around. I want you to take a message
back to Regimental PC.
- Who's there?
- Relax now, Jerry.
It's only Father Duffy
making his parish rounds.
Is there anything I can do for you?
No. Just go away and let me alone,
will you, Father, please?
No, wait. Don't go. Stay a minute, huh?
You're like the old Irishman
who'd rather be quarreling than Ionesome.
A little jumpy, are you? Well, we all are.
The old 69th's been taking it
on the chin today,
but it's come back to stage a knockout.
- Yes, and you're part of it.
- Part of it?
Ducking into shell holes,
going ahead only when I had to,
seeing guys I knew torn to pieces
and figuring any minute
some heinie I can't get my hands on
is gonna crack a bullet into me.
Oh, it isn't the fight I mind, Father,
I love a fight and I've never been afraid
of anything in my whole life before,
but this stuff.
See what a bursting shell can do
to human flesh and blood.
It's made me yellow. Me, of all the guys
in this whole outfit. Yellow!
Scared is the word, Jerry. Not yellow.
- And you'll get over it.
- Get over it.
When everywhere I go,
and everything I do,
I see the faces of Casey and O'Keefe
and Lieutenant Wynn
and all those guys I killed up
in the dugout in Rouge Bouquet
staring at me and saying nothing,
just hoping I'll get mine.
I can't fight it anymore. I've tried.
Goes along for a while, everything's okay
and then suddenly it hits
until I feel as though if I don't get up
and run away I'll go nuts.
And I'd be out of this by now
if you hadn't stopped my transfer.
It's not for me to say, Jerry,
that's nonsense.
It isn't.
But Jerry,
there's only one way you can lick it.
- That's through faith and prayer.
- Faith.
Listen to those bullets.
Can faith stop them?
If a guy gets his pins blown off,
will prayer put them back on again,
or bring the dead back to life?
No, but faith and prayer can help you
defeat the fear that's possessing you.
Oh, Jerry, it's peace and courage
I'm offering you.
If you'd only open up your heart
and take it.
- Father Duffy, come quickly!
- All right.
Think it over now, Jerry.
Ask the Lord to help you.
- If there's anything I can do for you...
- No, there's nothing you can do.
Major Donovan.
It's from headquarters.
Air reconnaissance reports
an enemy patrol moving out
to occupy the far edge of the Colas woods.
We'll send out a patrol, intercept them
and bring in prisoners.
- Very good, sir.
- No, not you yet.
Lieutenant Ames and I will go forward
and size them up.
- You'll follow up with the patrol.
- Yes, sir.
I need 10 men to follow up
with Sergeant Kilmer.
It's a dangerous mission.
Who wants to volunteer?
- I'll go, sir.
- Good.
- Take me, sir.
- Okay, sir.
- Sure thing, sir.
- Count me in.
- Okay, with me, sir.
- Not without me, you won't.
Okay.
Thanks, Plunkett!
Give me five minutes' start.
Then arrange for a combat patrol to go
forward in charge of Sergeant Wynn.
Yes, sir. Watch yourself
- Listen, Sarge...
- Quiet.
Why don't we wait here with Big Mike
and the rest of them?
Pull yourself together.
The Major's up there.
We can't let him down.
Sarge, let me go back and see
if Big Mike and...
Shut up, you fool. If you start yelping now,
you'll get us all killed.
Well, then why don't we wait
for the rest of them?
Let go of me.
I want to get out of here!
I don't want to stay here and be killed!
Let go of me!
Wynn! McManus! Come here!
- Hey, come back here!
- Wait a minute! Come back here!
- What's the matter with you?
- They're all killed up there!
- Donovan, Ames, all of them!
- And you're the only survivor?
- Yeah.
- Where's your rifle?
- I... I...
- Why, you...
Look out!
Take care of these prisoners
and retire to cover!
Come on, sauerkraut, get up.
Get down!
Get them down! Get down! Get down!
Get them down.
Hold on, Major! We're on our way!
- Go ahead, step on it.
- Go ahead, sauerkraut. Hurry up.
- Mission accomplished, sir.
- Nice work.
We'll dig in here. Now that
we've got the wood, we'll hold them.
Run back and get B company up here.
My PC will be right here.
Yes, sir.
Who yelled back there
and upset the apple cart?
I wouldn't know, sir.
- It was Plunkett, sir.
- Plunkett?
- Is he killed?
- No, sir. I fumbled my chance, sir.
Never mind. I'll take care of him later.
Battalion attention!
Eyes right! Eyes right!
I don't know
what these guys are so cheerful about.
Believe me, in the next war,
there's gonna be three guys missing.
Me and the two guys that's chasing me.
This is the toughest spot
we've ever been in.
Is it true you're going to attack in
the Argonne without artillery preparation?
- It is.
- What's headquarters thinking of?
The element of surprise.
Regardless of the fact
that it'll probably cost us 60% casualties.
Well, orders are orders.
- Goodbye, Father.
- Goodbye, Major.
Well, I'll be seeing you up there
after you get underway.
Oh, by the way, Bill,
- were you able to do anything for...
- Plunkett?
No, nothing. Not even if I could.
But Bill, that's so unfair.
As I told the court-martial,
it was all my fault.
If I hadn't changed his transfer,
it never would have happened.
He shouldn't be executed for something
he couldn't help.
Now, look, Father,
let's don't go into this thing again.
I know what you're going to say.
There's a weakling in every outfit,
but never in history has a 69th man
disgraced his regiment like Plunkett.
Tomorrow morning at 7:00, he's going
to get exactly what's coming to him
and may God have mercy on his soul.
Is there anything I can do for you, Jerry?
What can you do for me?
This is curtains, ain't it?
Well, there's still time to make your peace.
Don't stand there talking like a sap.
Don't you understand,
they're gonna shoot me.
Tomorrow morning I get it.
If you're so hot to help me,
do something about that.
I've tried, Jerry. Believe me, I have.
I've gone to the Colonel,
to general headquarters.
Told them it was all my fault
and not yours.
Looks like there's no use.
There's nothing left for me to do.
Do you really believe it's because of you
I'm in this jam?
- I do indeed.
- It's not my fault I couldn't take it, is it?
Jerry, you're not the only one
in the regiment who ever knew fear.
It just happened you couldn't face it,
that's all.
Well, you can still do something.
Let me out of here. Help me to escape.
Look, you just said
they had no right to keep me here.
Let me out. I'll get home some way and
after the war they'll forget all about me.
Why not? You're a priest.
They can't do anything to you.
Jerry, you're forgetting
I'm a soldier as well as a priest.
Yeah. I see.
Jerry, ask me anything else.
I will. I'll ask you to beat it.
- But you don't...
- Oh, let me alone!
Please.
- Hello, Alec. How is it?
- For a mass suicide, the set-up's great.
A thick belt of uncut wire with strong
enemy machine gun positions behind it.
If they'd given us artillery preparation,
we could have blasted lanes
through that wire.
- What about tanks? Do we get them?
- Sure.
After we take the two villages beyond.
A sweet job that will be.
We'll be cut to pieces from that hill
before we get well started.
- Why the devil are they ordering...
- Ever read Tennyson, Alec?
"Ours not to reason why
Ours is but to do and..."
- You said it. Zero hour the same?
- Just before dawn, 4:45.
Reception committee is tuning up.
I'd better get back to my battalion.
Good luck.
- Well, Mike.
- Hello, Father.
How do you feel now?
Now, don't be like that.
It takes more than a.77 shell
to keep an Irishman down.
I'm on me way out, Father.
Could you maybe just
say a bit of a prayer?
Wouldn't you be wanting
one of your own faith?
No time.
- You mean you want me to help you pray?
- Yes, Father.
'Tis the only thing that's kept me going
for many a long day.
"O Lord God, I know that
my life and my death are in thy hands.
"May it be thy will to heal me.
"But if thou willest my death,
may it be atonement for all my sins.
"Into thy hands I entrust my spirit.
"Thou art my redeemer, Lord God of Truth.
"The Lord shall reign forever and ever.
Hear, O Israel.
"The Lord our God, the Lord is one."
Thank you, Father.
Don't tell me
they're starting to shell this place?
Let me out of here! Let me out of here!
Jerry!
- We're getting out of here!
- Where'll we go?
What are you gonna do with me?
Jerry, you've looked in the face of death
these past few hours.
Death by execution
and death from shellfire.
Now, you're still alive.
I can't let you stay here with this.
You're free, Jerry.
Free of everything but yourself.
Now, I can't tell you what to do.
I can only point out two roads to you.
One to safety for awhile. Perhaps to home.
The other... Do you hear that?
It's falling on your regiment, Jerry.
They're in a trap.
It's possible
not one of them will come out alive.
There are your two ways. Whichever
you choose, you'll have to walk alone.
What do you mean, whichever I choose?
Do you think I'm crazy enough
to try and go through that?
Goodbye, Father.
Jerry! Jerry!
Give me a hand here.
Don't go in there, Father!
That whole roof might cave in any minute!
Father Duffy!
Boys! Boys! Boys!
Everything's going to be all right.
This is Father Duffy.
Oh, aren't you ashamed?
Kicking up a row like this
over a few shells?
Timmy, lad, I'm surprised.
Do you want Almighty God to think
you've forgotten him?
Come on, now, Sean, buck up.
Buck up, all of you.
Believe me, I tell you,
everything is gonna be all right.
Get hold of yourself now, Timmy.
Come on, now.
We'll all say the Lord's Prayer.
Repeat after me.
- Our Father who art in heaven.
- Hallowed be thy name.
Thy kingdom come. Thy will be done
on earth as it is in heaven.
Give us this day our daily bread.
Forgive us our trespasses.
As we forgive those
who trespass against us.
- Lead us not into temptation.
- But deliver us from evil.
Amen.
Thank you, Father.
And if it so be that he find it,
yea men, I say to you,
he rejoiceth more for that
than for the ninety-nine
which went not astray.
Them things is getting on my nerves.
Give me a cigarette, will you, mac?
- What for? You can't smoke up here.
- I don't want to smoke it.
I want to chew it
to keep my teeth from chattering.
Hang on, men.
The tanks will be here soon.
Hey, Paddy, watch those big ears of yours.
They'll think you're a battleship.
How'd you boys like
a nice cold bottle of beer?
I'd settle for a hot one.
Hey, Brian, wait till the wife hears
you've been out all night.
Sorry, old-timer.
- It looks kind of mean, Alec.
- Kind of?
With all that around us, and
that wire out there, we're cooked, Bill,
- unless we get through.
- Well, we've got to get through.
Once we get into their trenches,
we can finish the thing off.
Well, here's a scrap that should satisfy
even the fighting Irish, eh, Sergeant?
Yes, sir, 'tis a fine bit of a scrimmage, sir.
We've got to knock out
those machine guns somehow,
cut a hole through that wire.
Are all those Stokes mortars
out of commission?
Yes, sir. And the crew's all killed, sir.
Maybe there's one we could fix up
somehow. That would do it.
Well, there's Scanlon's outfit
about 50 yards off the flank there,
- so maybe I could have a look, sir.
- Go ahead.
Come on, you men!
What're you doing up here
with fighting men?
Did you run the wrong way again?
I didn't come here to look
at your big, ugly puss. Now shut up!
- Show me how to use this stovepipe.
- What for?
So you can turn it on the 69th and kill off
a few more good men like Tim and Kilmer?
Listen, I know what you think of me
and I know what I think of you,
but never mind our own private scrap.
I'll give you a belly full of that later.
Now, shut your big Irish trap
and show me how to use this Stokes!
If you don't,
I'll shove this bayonet right through you!
You show me how to use it,
so I can't miss.
There's nothing to it. Here.
Put your hand on the fuse.
Pull the pin. Drop it in!
They don't look like much.
Enough TNT in them shells
to blow a lane in that wire
as wide as Central Park.
Here's a kiss for you, heinie!
- Are you all right?
- All right?
- I'll show them krauts. Can you walk?
- I guess so. Why?
Grab some men
and get this ammunition forward.
Hey! You 69th men!
Grab these shells and move up!
Put a sausage skin on this one, you krauts!
Here's one for the 69th!
- Who's firing that Stokes?
- Big Mike.
Here's one from Brooklyn!
If he can keep that up,
he'll blow a hole in that wire
big enough to sail the Leviathan through.
Here's one for Yonkers and the Bronx!
Divide it among you!
Here's one for you, pal!
And another one!
Look out, Mike!
Now, Alec.
Mike! Mike!
God bless you!
You've saved the day for us!
They're swarming up
and over and through.
- Man, what a fight you made.
- What a fight I made, Major?
- There's the man who made it. Not me.
- It's not Plunkett?
It is, sir.
I'm sorry, soldier.
Father Duffy.
Jerry, this is Father Duffy.
I just been talking to your boss.
- You're not afraid, are you, Jerry?
- No, Father.
Not anymore.
I been an awful lot of trouble to you,
haven't I, Father?
Father, who's that with you?
Major Donovan, Big Mike.
Mike?
I'm awful sorry about Tim.
I'm ready, Father.
I once thought this man was a coward.
A coward, sir?
From now on,
every time I hear the name of Plunkett,
I'll snap to attention and salute.
Pretty soft for you colonels.
- My feet are killing me.
- You see? You should be wounded.
Then they'd be cheering you, too.
Where was you wounded, buddy?
- Hoboken.
- Hoboken?
Yeah. I sprained me ankle
getting off the boat.
Say, this is fine.
O heavenly Father,
here I beseech you the prayer
of this, America's lost generation.
They loved life, too, O Lord.
It was as sweet to them
as to the living of today.
They accepted privation,
wounds and death,
that an ideal might live.
Don't let it be forgotten, Father.
Amid turmoil and angry passions, when
all worthwhile things seem swept away,
let the tired eyes of a troubled world
rise up and see the shining citadel
of which these young lives
formed the imperishable stones.
America,
the citadel of peace, peace forevermore.
This I beg of you through Christ, our Lord.
Amen.
English
Watch Movies, TV Series & Live Sports
www.admitme.app