Howdy.
- You lost?
- No.
Don't see folks
out this way much.
That's a lot
of dead prairie dogs.
It's just target practice.
You know, my grandfather
used to say,
"If you kill all
the prairie dogs,
there'd be no one left
to cry for the rain."
Prairie dogs don't
make it rain.
It's because they burrow,
and then that turns the earth.
They keep it from
getting too hard-packed.
And that way,
when it rains,
the water can get in
and make things grow.
Did I say something funny?
It's always funny
to listen to the white man
explain how the world works.
Still, hard to imagine
coming all this way
to see prairie dogs.
What can I say?
I dislike prairie dogs.
Can't find something you
dislike closer to home?
Y'all army or something?
Heard they was lettin'
was lettin' girls in.
Didn't realize they was letting
in little, pretty ones.
What...
I was handling it.
Psycho.
Target is
at seven o'clock.
The brunette.
I need confirmation.
No, no, Sam.
You're a fucking idiot.
Joe, the fate of humanity
rests on the line.
Oh, the fate of humanity?
The fate of your sperm anyway.
Dude, why don't you go
and pick her up?
Because he knows I'd
cut his balls off.
She would, she'll cut off my
balls, and I need my balls,
which is why I have to live
vicariously through your balls, Joe,
which frankly sucks.
Baby, tell Joe to hit
on the brunette, please.
- First, let's do some shots.
- Yes.
- How long ago did you break up with whatsherface?
- Who's "whatsherface?"
Can I get three shots
of tequila, please? Thank you.
- Janice.
- Janice, the girl you're still bent out of shape over.
That was six years ago. I'm not
bent out of shape over Janice.
If you don't date for six years
after your break-up with someone,
you're bent out of shape over
her whether you know it or not.
Hey, what are you doing
with my phone?
- I'm on Tinder.
- No, no, no, no, no.
Finding Joe a girl.
Why can't the three of us
just hang out, huh?
'Cause you're a third wheel, baby, and
we don't enjoy hanging out with you.
- What about Melanie?
- Give me my phone. I'm not kidding.
No, no. No, Mae.
Oh, no, never mind.
- You know what?
- Selfie with a baby tiger.
Even the kids
are worried about you, Joe.
Jude says to me the other night
when I put him to bed,
he looks up with me through his
sad little eyes, and he says,
"Daddy, I'm worried
that Uncle Joe is lonely."
You're such a shitter.
No, he didn't.
- No, he did.
- Liar.
He said it to me while
I was putting him to bed.
Yeah, right.
You haven't been home to put
the kids to bed in two years.
Hmm, thanks, Babe.
Just personalizing
the story for effect.
Being in a relationship
is like being in a cult.
When you're in one, you want every
one else to be in one with you.
Yeah, because it's
beautiful, Joe.
Okay, I'm gonna take
my sweet wife home.
I'm gonna make
tender love to her,
to my wife, to this woman
who I share a rich life with,
we share a family.
Show her my innermost secrets,
my hopes, my dreams.
You, on the other hand, you're gonna go
home in your shitty little apartment,
you're gonna eat cold pizza,
and jerk off into a pillow.
Dude, I don't have any pizza.
Okay, I just found your wife.
She's perfect for you.
- Let me see.
- And you're a match.
Let me see. Kathy H.?
- She's pretty.
- Let me see, let me see.
She's pretty.
Yeah.
Kathy H. is gonna
change your life.
Do you wanna have
a drink tomorrow?
No, no, no, no.
Don't send anything.
Did you send it?
Jesus. You sent it?
- To Kathy H.
Geez. To Kathy H.
Yeah.
Shut up.
Hey, Sam.
Hey, buddy,
pick up your pace.
You're not even running
an eight-minute mile.
Listen, I need you to come over
here and look at something for me.
No can do.
Your wife hacked
my dating life, remember?
Yeah, well, it's important.
I need your advice, Joe.
Okay, sure. I can be at your place
in an hour. Everything cool?
I actually need you
at the office.
You want me
to come to your office?
What I want is for you to take
those stairs up ahead on the left.
Sam, are you tracking my phone?
Not a good time
to stop, Pal.
Pick it up, Joe. Move.
Come on, buddy, two at a time.
Take a left to the top of the stairs.
What's going on, Sam?
Get in that van that's
right in front of you.
What van?
Let's go,
let's go, let's go.
Who are we gonna see?
Your Uncle Bob
and the Deputy Director.
Of the CIA?
- Of the CIA.
- Yeah?
Two years ago, you wrote a
program with Harold Floros
to help screen employees
at likely terrorist targets
in the Middle East and Europe
to assess the threat potential.
- Do you remember that?
- Yeah.
You know, I didn't think anyone
ever looked at that thing.
The program is operational?
It's operational, Joe,
and it works.
And you have a chance
to save a lot of lives today.
We flagged this guy,
Ammar Nazari.
Nazari is
a Saudi national.
Thirty-two years old.
Before your program
found this guy,
we'd never heard of him.
He's a fresh face
in the Sunni terror community.
Here we go.
Welcome to the big
leagues, Joe.
Let me show you something.
There it is.
This is everything
we've got on Nazari.
Now, we've been watching him
for the past six weeks.
He's clean, until noon today
when he goes to a PO box
that no one knew he had,
and picks up a package.
What's in the package?
That's the problem, Joe.
We have no fucking idea.
Yeah. We didn't have
time to do a sweep.
Sam, is that ComQuest Field?
Mmm-hmm. That's where Nazari's been working
as a janitor for the past six weeks
until your program flagged him.
The program I designed was
supposed to screen employees
with high profile targets
in the Middle East and Europe.
Joe.
Your uncle has been running
with this all by himself.
- Bob is running this?
- We had no idea.
If you have an issue with it, you take it up
with him, but you do it on your own time.
Nazari, right now,
is on his way
to a stadium filled
with people as we speak.
So, you have a state trooper
pull him over.
You search the car.
What if he detonates it?
- Detonates what?
- Exactly.
What is it?
Is it nuclear, biological, chemical?
We don't know what,
Why are we gonna give this guy
a chance to pull the trigger?
Okay.
Wait.
You're gonna kill him, aren't you?
That's what this is.
That's what this
room is, right?
That's why you're here.
Yeah, we wanna hear
every perspective...
- This is fucking crazy.
- ...before we act on it.
Subject is just over
one mile from the target.
Is it a target, Mr. Turner?
Joe, this is Mr. Abbott,
Deputy Director of the CIA.
Well, is it?
Uh...
The algorithm only looks at employees
of high profile targets, Mr. Abbott.
So the question isn't so much
if ComQuest Field is a target,
but more if Ammar Nazari
is a threat.
Your algorithm gave Mr. Nazari
a 12% threat probability.
Yes, but the algorithm wasn't
designed to be used in this country,
so there are variables
that will need to be adjusted
to make the program actionable.
The subject is
getting off I-495.
A Saudi-born American citizen
who is also a Muslim,
just visited a secret
safety deposit box,
and is on his way now
to a football stadium.
How many variables do we need?
But with all due respect,
uh, Mr. Abbott,
Muslim-Americans are allowed
to have PO boxes
and also work
in football stadiums.
- Sir?
- Excuse me.
What would you do
if this was your play?
I don't know.
How could I...
We don't have enough
time to not know.
Subject is pulling in
to the stadium parking lot.
Subject is parking.
Shadow 1 Bravo engaging. Over.
You're talking about killing a man
without any evidence against him,
except for an algorithm
that I wrote years ago
and subsequently forgot about.
Now forgive me for taking a second
to contemplate the 88% likelihood
that this man is guilty of nothing more
than coming from the wrong country
and applying for
the wrong fucking job.
You wrote the program, Joe.
Yeah, I did, so you guys
would know who to look at,
but not through the scope
of a fucking sniper rifle.
Enough dithering
with your nephew, Bob.
Let's get on with this.
He's the reason we're here.
His program found this man.
A man we suspect of being a terrorist
is about to walk a package,
whose contents
are unknown to us,
into a football stadium packed
with 80,000 American souls.
Subject's car door
is open.
Thank you for your valuable
service, Mr. Turner.
We should have more
young men like you.
We'll take it from here.
Thank you.
- Joe.
- Okay.
Let's go, Joe.
Sir, team leader wants to
know if we have a green light.
You know, the head coach and his offense coordinator...
You've reached Sam Barber.
Please leave a message.
Sam, it's me.
What the fuck was that?
I mean, are those
people safe or not?
I'm just standing here, watching the
fucking TV. Can you call me, please?
Bye.
And that part's been top-down.
Which is why we saw a change
coming into this season.
But you can't change the culture
of a football team overnight.
These things take time.
And right now,
you're looking at a group of young men
who are physically outmatching...
Oh, shit.
That takes a toll.
Big challenge for
the new coaching regime,
trying to ride this ship.
All right now,
first down in mid-field.
So, after the diagnosis, my aunt
started seeing this energy healer.
So, one day, I went with her,
and he shook my hand,
and said, "You have the gift.
You're a healer.
That's what you're meant
to do with your life."
He said that he could teach me how to
harness the power of my gift, and...
You know, use it
in a positive way.
So, uh, that's what you do?
You're a... A healer?
I'm a lawyer.
Uh-huh.
That's usually the part of the
story where people laugh.
You... Big football fan?
- Uh, no.
- Degenerate gambler?
- No, I have...
- 'Cause this is a new one for me.
Losing a guy's interest
to football in the first date.
I hate football. I couldn't
even tell you who's winning.
- Is that supposed to make me feel better?
- Yeah.
No, uh...
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
Uh...
What kind of law
do you practice?
- Intellectual property.
- Okay.
I have some semi-conductor
clients here in the US
whose US patents
are being knocked off
in, uh, China and Korea
and...
I'd rather not drink alone.
God.
Wait.
Wait, wait.
Look, I'm sorry.
I'm just glad something you're
interested in wasn't on.
I really am sorry.
Today...
Today was a bad...
It was a weird fucking day.
And the truth is,
I meant to cancel our date,
but I forgot.
Well, why didn't you
just start with that?
Yeah.
Yeah, in hindsight,
that was the obvious move.
Look, it's already late,
but I just live
a few blocks from here.
I mean if you wanna
walk me home.
Yeah.
All right.
Why was today a bad day?
Something happened. Work.
What?
I, uh... I can't really...
I can't really talk about it.
Yeah.
Everyone I know has
to sign NDAs now.
Yeah.
Wait, so what do you do?
You know what?
It doesn't matter.
'Cause I'm gonna quit tomorrow.
Do you go on
a lot of these?
Dates?
Uh, I text people.
And I fantasize they'd
be amazing.
Basically have an entire
imaginary relationship
that ends in a breakup before
they can even text you back.
You got it.
- I guess I'm not...
- As unique as you thought you were.
Me, neither.
How are you single?
That was a line.
Takes too long really
get to know someone.
- Mmm-hmm.
- That person is never as good as the one you imagined.
Sometimes you get hurt.
You know...
If we were a rational culture,
we would begin
every first date by saying,
"Here's what's wrong with me."
- Let's just get it out of the way, huh?
- Yup.
This is me.
Okay.
So fine...
- Tell me.
- What?
What's wrong with you?
Come on.
What? I'm a stranger.
You're never gonna
see me again.
You're not gonna see me again?
You think I'd go
on a second date with you?
Come on.
I know this cozy
little sports bar.
It's a few blocks from here.
You'd love it.
Okay.
Okay?
All right.
Hello.
I imagine you must
be pissed at me.
You don't have
to imagine too hard.
I can't be part of a program
whose mission I...
No longer believe in.
You're not the only one
who believes that spying
on American citizens
is wrong, Joe.
Yeah, but I am the only one
whose belief that it's wrong
stops him from doing it.
Sometimes, you have
to do the wrong thing.
Why is that?
So you don't have to do
the worse thing later.
See, you keep moving
the line, Bob.
That's your problem.
Or maybe it's your talent.
I don't know.
But I...
I can't do this anymore.
I out.
Sometimes a man's conflicted
only because it's in his nature
to be conflicted,
which is what makes him
so damn good at what he does.
It's the people
who don't have that
dissenting a voice inside them
that are truly dangerous.
That dissenting
voice doesn't mean much
if the dangerous people you work
for aren't willing to hear it.
We're in a crowded theater.
It's on fire.
All we can do is yell
as loud as we can.
I'm sorry, Bob.
You did a good thing, Joe.
Yeah, I don't know
what that means,
and I don't wanna know.
Turn on the TV. We'll
talk about it tomorrow.
I'm out, I mean it.
Any channel.
Did I wake you, sweetheart?
The airborne or pneumonic type of the
plague virus that was found on Nazari,
is the rarest and deadliest
form of the disease.
With a mortality rate of close
to 100% if left untreated.
Had Nazari been allowed to release
this bio-weapon undetected,
those 80,000 people might now be
back in their homes or offices
unwittingly infecting
thousands.
The FBI is calling
this an act of terrorism.
I mean the guy IPO'd at 24
and retired at 28.
Now he just sails around
on his boat, you know,
following the warm weather
like some kind of bird.
- Turner, Joseph. 8:22
- Oh, God.
Ellie, leave Harold alone.
He has work to do.
It's still
early right now.
The resolve
is melting, Joe.
Faster or slower the polar ice caps?
Good morning, Colonel.
See, I'm playing
a long game here, Joe.
I'm gonna win to the Christmas
party, and then I make my big move.
What happens
at the Christmas party?
I break out my secret weapon.
Colonel, do you see a, uh, secret
weapon anywhere on Harold?
No?
You need a calling card,
something to distinguish you.
I don't need a calling card.
What I'm saying is this is my home.
Joe, Joe, Joe, Joe, listen.
I'm a fantastic dancer, okay?
Women respond to this
on a primal level.
Do you get that? I mean,
they can't help themselves.
I lived with the Makalanga
for a year, all right?
They taught me how to dance.
Surely you want Ellie
to like you for your mind.
- Listen, attraction is instinctual.
- There you are.
In our base programming,
we're still primates.
And the big monkey gets
all the hugs. Great.
Only 'cause his algorithms saved a few
hundred thousand lives last night.
What's that now?
Comquest Field... That was...
Thanks for telling me. That's...
Our algorithm was used last night
to stop a terrorist attack.
Mmm-hmm.
Nice to know.
Probably saved all
of DC last night.
No big deal.
Right back to work.
Yup.
Not even so much
as a celebratory cigarette?
You're right.
I can't believe I have to go to
dinner with my folks tonight
and listen to my father bitch about
how he should have become a doctor.
Clark Kent will always be a
coward to his friends and family.
Not true.
Ma and Pa Kent
know he's Superman.
Ah, yeah.
Look, I know you won't get
any credit,
and you won't give
yourself any,
but you did some good, Joe.
I mean, that's what
this is all about, right?
You know, honestly,
until I saw
the news last night,
I was gonna quit.
- Shut up.
- No, I even told Bob.
You honestly wanna quit because a
terrorist's civil liberties are violated?
Not to mention
the civil liberties
of a whole lot of other people who
it turned out weren't terrorists.
Yeah, we collected data on
a bunch of innocent people
who are now safer for it.
- How's that bad?
- Okay, but what about the ones we watched?
Interviewed?
Held for a few hours?
Where's the line?
Eighty thousand people get infected
with the plague at a football game.
They don't show any signs
of being sick for days.
They go home.
They go to work.
And some get on airplanes,
and they go to other countries.
A couple of minutes ago,
it was just DC.
Now we save the world?
Come on.
What's he doing here?
What? I can't hear you.
It's thick glass.
Probably came to accept
your resignation in person.
Yesterday, countless
American lives were saved
because of this group.
And you deserve
congratulations.
But...
That's not what I'm here for.
Ammar Nazari got a job at
ComQuest Field with a plan
to infect Americans with the
plague during a football game.
We know very little else
about him.
Until six weeks ago,
he'd never been on our radar.
We don't know...
Who trained him,
who he's working for.
The device that was on him,
would have required a great deal of
engineering skill and manufacturing.
Which means Nazari was
most likely not working alone.
Someone out there could
still have weaponized plague,
and we have to assume
they're going to use it.
JTTF is working on the
encryptions on Nazari's laptop,
combing through his house,
interviewing his neighbors,
trying to trace the materials
on the device
back to a manufacturer.
But it wasn't the JTTF
who found this guy.
And I'm sure as hell not
gonna entrust this hunt
to conventional methods alone.
Now, I've rarely
ever given you anything
other an open-ended
mandate to innovate.
But today, I'm asking you...
To put whatever
you're doing on hold,
and make this
your only priority.
If the people Nazari was working
with are gearing for another attack,
we may only have a small
window to find and stop them.
You sure this is safe,
Nathan?
A hundred percent.
I got kids.
As one father to another
I guarantee you, you have
nothing to worry about.
Our man will pick it up
at the embassy tomorrow.
- Okay.
- Safe flight, Ambassador.
So that's it.
Let's do it.
Bob, about last night...
Let's talk about it later.
Walk us
through a scenario
where a weaponized
pneumonic plague
gets that kind of traction
in a major American city.
What kind of plans
does the CDC have in place?
Well, the plan
is mass prophylaxis.
So, the US has been stock piling
ciprofloxacin for decades.
So, in the event
of a health emergency,
PODs or Points
of Dispensing Sites
would be set up
in every major US city.
Stock transactions?
Every stock transaction in the pharmaceutical
sector going back three years.
Uh-huh. Why?
Uh, well, I was thinking about the
country's vaccine stockpiles.
- Oh.
- Ciprofloxacin.
Bingo.
Girl I used to date
called this morning
to ask if my father could
write her a prescription.
You're wondering if someone
made a move into Big Pharma
knowing vaccine stockpiles
would be depleted?
Like the terrorists shorting
airline stocks before 9/11.
You see, that's a fiction.
Yeah, well, Dick Tracy wore a
two-way wrist radio in the 40s,
and now people
wear Apple watches.
Not cool people.
The point is,
fiction can become real.
- Dick Tracy?
- He was an underrated detective.
So which transactions
stand out?
Uh, well...
I found these 12 companies,
and collectively, they bought over
a billion worth of Big Pharma.
What connects them?
See, that's just it.
They're all different sizes,
they're headquartered in
different countries.
It all looks completely random,
but that is exactly how you want it
to look if you're the one doing it.
Okay, so what you're saying is what
you found is that you found nothing.
Uh, no.
Humans don't do random well.
The minute we try to avoid
creating a pattern,
we just create a different
kind of pattern.
So your big idea
is to follow
the money back to the dick
turds who planned this thing.
Dick turds?
Yeah.
It's pretty flimsy there, bud.
Yeah, you're reaching.
I know, I know.
Now, the FBI is calling this
an act of terrorism,
but there's been no claim
of responsibility
from any known
terror organization.
Is there any indication that a...
Coming through.
Hello.
I have a new
assignment for you.
I need it expedited.
The target package
has been sent.
I'm looking at it now.
I'm gonna drop you
on your head.
Come here.
So how'd it go
with Kathy H?
Yeah, it was good. Maybe.
I don't know.
Thank you.
You're so good with him.
You'd be such a great dad if you
could ever get over your bullshit.
My bullshit?
They've heard worse.
Yeah.
You meet someone,
have an actual relationship.
Hard to do if you can't even tell
someone what you do for a living.
Yeah, that's the bullshit
I'm talking about.
Sammy, guys, bedtime.
Uh-uh.
Let me just finish this level.
What did I say?
She is a tyrant.
Yeah. No kidding.
Come on, Jude.
You've been working for the
CIA for a long time now, Joe.
How is this still
an issue for you?
I guess it's in
my nature to wanna...
Trust a few people.
You think Sam gets to tell me
what he does every day?
No.
But, at least you know
why he can't.
You know what your problem is?
What, I only have one?
Well, that's up for debate.
Unlike every other guy
in the universe,
you think with your heart,
instead of your dick.
Oh.
You can't start every first
date contemplating marriage.
Get laid. See where it goes.
Hey, babe,
sorry I'm late.
Whoa. Hey, hey, hey.
Do I know you?
Look, this creep's been
following me for six blocks.
Pretend you're
my boyfriend, okay?
Okay.
Is he there?
No.
No, I think you're good.
Thank you.
Anytime.
Thanks for meeting me, Sam.
What the fuck's
going on, Nathan?
I don't like being
exposed like this.
Gareth has been
doing some trades.
What kind of trades?
He bought stock
in pharmaceutical companies
that manufacture ciprofloxacin.
That greedy motherfucker.
It gets worse.
What?
Your friend, Joe Turner.
He found out about them.
And... You don't like
being exposed?
We're exposed.
- So this guy...
- You know, I thought you were gonna take advantage
of the situation and kiss me.
But you handled yourself
like a perfect gentleman.
Club soda and lime, please.
Can I... Can I buy
you a real drink?
I can't.
Big day at work tomorrow.
I need to keep a clear head.
What are you saying?
I already sent the
assignment to the assets.
You what?
You're mad because you
have a personal connection,
but once you get past that, you'll see
that this is really the only way forward.
Water.
What's that?
Sorry, I have a nasty habit of
taking my work home with me.
Isn't that usually a sign
of a fulfilling job?
What can I say?
I love what I do.
How about you?
Are you fulfilled?
I don't know.
Your accent,
where's it from?
Cleveland.
Oh.
If you're not gonna talk about
yourself, why should I talk about me?
Come on.
We don't know each other.
You don't even know my name.
How often do you get the chance to
be totally honest with someone?
All right.
I have to lie to people about
what I do for a living,
and it makes it hard for me
to get close to anyone.
You carry a lot of guilt.
That's good.
I don't feel guilty
about anything.
It's okay to be happy.
You're young, strong.
You got a long life
ahead of you.
I really like that.
You coming to bed anytime soon?
Ah.
I can't sleep.
You okay?
Sam, hey.
Sam, what's going on?
Nothing, nothing.
I think I'm coming
down with something.
Well, you should
definitely come to bed.
Okay, doc.
We have parent-teacher night
next Thursday for Jude.
I think we should both go
'cause his teacher's a bitch,
and I think I'm gonna lose my
shit if I'm in there by myself.
Hey.
Are you even listening to me?
Huh?
Did you hear
anything I just said?
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, I just...
Got a lot of stuff
on my mind, okay?
Whatever it is,
just let it go.
For once.
Come to bed with me.
I'll be there in
a minute, okay?
Sam?
Hi, Bob.
Are you at home?
There's too much
going on to be at home.
I'm at Nazari's.
I'm gonna head over.
I wanna run something by you.
Hi, Bob.
You seen Nazari's bed?
Yeah.
- Hospital corners.
- Yeah.
What compels a man
about to walk a plague
into a football stadium
to make his bed?
Well, I guess...
When you're in a combat zone, those
little routines are a big comfort.
Yeah.
I remember combat zones
being less comfortable.
Not much.
Did I ever tell you
I met your father once?
In Nha Trang.
I guess you saw a lot of shit.
I mean it's a hell of a
sacrifice to make for nothing.
We were born after all the
good wars were already over.
The world has changed.
These people used to
want a seat at the table.
Now they wanna blow
the table up.
How do you...
How do you fight
an enemy like that?
So what did you
wanna talk about?
You're right.
You can't fight an enemy
like that, not like that.
Hello?
Hey.
Power's out on the whole block.
Back-up generator's dead.
Huh.
Dr. Lappe...
Did you read my report
about the pharma stock trades?
Yes, I'm sending it up to Langley
as soon as the power comes on.
Morning, Colonel.
Arms up.
I'm gonna miss my flight.
Turner,
I may not have the most
glamorous job in the world,
but believe it or not,
I derive some satisfaction
in doing it well.
What time are you gonna
pick me up for dinner?
My job is to protect everyone
that works in this building.
You going on the fire escape
for your cigarette breaks
is a breach of security that puts you
and everyone who works here in danger.
I'm giving you
one last warning.
If I catch you again,
I'm writing you up.
There's one T in Turner.
You're an asshole.
Morning.
What's wrong?
- Hey.
- Hi.
Soy vanilla latte, right?
Harold, you didn't
have to do that.
I know, but I wanted to, so...
Also, hey, um,
so I was thinking
maybe, maybe...
Um, you and I could
do something some night.
Or something.
Harold, you seem
like a nice guy.
Well.
But you've been chatting me up every
day since you started working here,
and I've been very careful to
give you no indication whatsoever
that I might be at all interested
in seeing you outside the office,
precisely to avoid you asking me out
and having to hurt your feelings.
I know.
I just thought, you know, maybe the
drugs that I put in your coffee might
change your mind.
What?
Bitch.
Sharla called me a hypocrite.
Gave me a guilt trip
about how she'd work too hard
in recovery getting
to know herself to
waste time with someone who couldn't even
admit who they were to their own parents.
Get right in there.
You spent half a decade
behind that desk,
believing that you're
protecting all of us
just in case something
terrible happened.
Your life's purpose was
a pitiful delusion.
That flew right by my ear.
What the hell?
Look out!
Go! Get out! Go!
Go, go, go.
Go, go, go, go, go, go.
No, no, no.
Oh, Jesus.
He's in the basement.
Hey, it's me.
I'm in Saudi.
Package has landed.
I'll await the courier.
Pentagon.
Subtitles by explosiveskull