WOMAN:
♪ Those schoolgirl days ♪
♪ Of telling tales ♪
♪ And biting nails are gone ♪
♪ But in my mind ♪
♪ I know they will ♪
♪ Still live on and on ♪
♪ But how do you thank someone ♪
♪ Who's taken you from crayons ♪
♪ to perfume? ♪
♪ It isn't easy ♪
♪ But I'll try ♪
♪ If you wanted the sky ♪
♪ I would write across the sky ♪
♪ In letters ♪
♪ That would soar ♪
♪ a thousand feet high ♪
♪ To sir ♪
♪ With love ♪
♪ Those awkward years ♪
♪ Have hurried by ♪
♪ Why did they fly away? ♪
♪ Why is it, sir ♪
♪ Children grow up ♪
♪ To be people one day? ♪
♪ What takes the place ♪
♪ of climbing trees ♪
♪ And dirty knees in the world outside? ♪
♪ What is there for you ♪
♪ I can buy? ♪
♪ If you wanted the world ♪
♪ I'd surround it with a wall ♪
♪ I'd scrawl ♪
♪ These words ♪
♪ with letters 10 feet tall ♪
♪ To sir ♪
♪ With love ♪
Cor, my bleedin' feet.
Oh, hello,
Mrs. Joseph.
Oh, I like your hair. What do you
call that, strawberry blonde?
Go on. You're only jealous.
(LAUGHING)
Gert, whatcha got
for the old man's supper tonight?
Him, he'll be lucky to get
faggots and peas pud, he will.
He can't do much
on that, can he, eh?
(BOTH LAUGHING)
All I want him for
is to keep me feet warm.
MAN: Tickets, please.
Excuse me, dearie.
Thank you. Here, Gert. Wouldn't
mind having this little lot...
in my stocking for Christmas, eh?
(GERT LAUGHING)
You wouldn't know what to do with him.
You've been a widow too long.
You speak for yourself. It's like
riding a bicycle. You never forget how.
(WOMEN LAUGHING)
I tell you what I'll do.
I'll send my Alfie along to you.
He's not bad once he gets going.
Well, I hope he's well sprung.
(WOMEN LAUGHING)
(CHILDREN CHATTERING)
(TOILET FLUSHING)
Morning.
Looking for someone, mate?
Nope.
Nice day, isn't it?
(DISTANT CHATTER,
LAUGHTER)
(CHATTER, LAUGHTER
GROW LOUDER)
Oh! Sorry.
(DOOR CLOSES)
Hackman's
in the staff room.
Where he bleedin' well belongs.
Yeah.
(ALL SHOUTING)
(CHATTER, LAUGHTER
CONTINUE)
(DOOR CLOSES)
Good morning.
My name is Thackeray.
I'm a new teacher.
Yes. We were expecting you.
So you're the new lamb
for the slaughter.
Or should I say "black sheep"?
No, just a teacher,
Mr. Hackman.
I'm not Hackman.
Perish the thought.
He's departed.
God rest his soul.
He's probably pouring out his woes
to the divisional officer by now.
Oh.
Oh. Weston.
I'm Mrs. Evans.
Grace. Deputy head.
Mrs. Evans.
Have you seen
any of the children yet?
I looked in on Mr. Hackman's
class for a moment. Hmm.
I take them for domestic science.
(CHUCKLES)
Like a cup of tea?
No. No, thank you.
Not just now.
You been teaching long?
This is
my first appointment.
(CHUCKLES)
We call them jobs.
American, are you?
British.
From British Guiana. But I've
spent some years in the States.
Oh. Where?
In California.
Oh. Weather as good
as they say?
It's better.
(CHUCKLES)
Uh, what was your subject?
What did you major in?
Engineering.
Oh!
Well, uh, I must be off.
Make yourself at home.
Wander around if you like or stay here.
I'll introduce you to the others at lunch.
Thank you.
(SCHOOL BELL RINGING)
(RINGING STOPS)
(ALL CHATTERING)
This is Gillian, Mr. Thackeray.
(DOOR CLOSES)
Gillian Blanchard.
Hello.
How do you do?
She's new here too. Came the day
before yesterday. Tea, Gillian?
Thank you.
(DOOR OPENS)
(CHATTERING)
This is Mr. Mark Thackeray,
the new replacement.
How do you do? Josie
Dawes, Euphemia Phillips.
They teach the little ones.
Theo Weston you know. Yes,
I've had the pleasure.
He mistook me for Hackman.
I heard he's fled.
I can't say I blame him. That shower of
humanity is enough to destroy anybody.
He got what
he deserved.
I'm Clinty Clintridge.
How are you?
Clinty's a marvelous artist. Got one into
the Royal Academy a couple of years ago.
Teaching provides
the bread and butter.
That's all the staff, except for Mr.
Bell, our PT instructor.
Well, I do hope you're
going to stay with us.
I shouldn't if I were you, old man.
I should row home while you've a chance.
Don't discourage him, Weston.
Well, I must go.
I have to fix a bath for one of
the girls in Clinty's class. Why?
Oh, the kids are complaining again.
Won't sit near her.
THACKERAY: What's the matter?
Personal hygiene problems.
Fourteen and helpless.
You men are lucky.
The things we women
have to do for these kids.
Gillian dear,
encourage him to stay.
(WHISPERS) Why is it everyone
thinks I need encouraging?
(WHISPERS)
They said the same to me.
There's something frightening but at the
same time challenging about this school.
Do you know there's no form
of corporal punishment?
Or any punishment, for that matter?
None?
No. And I've no real teaching
experience, so I'm a little lost.
Well, I don't have
any experience either.
Oh. Oh, well, of course
it'll be much easier for you.
I'm a little afraid of them.
♪ (ROCK) ♪
Midday dance session.
During lunch break
the older kids use the hall.
I sometimes join them. Even the old
man shakes a leg on occasions.
Dancing is merely their way
of keeping fit...
for the more exciting pastime
of teacher baiting.
Couldn't you manage to be
a bit less discouraging?
It's the last thing
I want to do.
The music's louder
than usual.
They're probably celebrating
their victory over Hackman.
I'd better go
and see Mr. Florian.
I'll show you the way.
WOMAN:
♪ I gotta find out ♪
♪ I just wish I knew ♪
♪ Somebody help me
I just gotta know ♪
♪ What is the cause
that started this round? ♪
♪ I wish I knew who it could be ♪
♪ I've gotta find out
because it's torturin' me ♪
♪ I gotta find out ♪
♪ Uh-huh ♪
♪ I just wish I knew ♪
They're good, aren't they?
I suppose so.
♪ Who it could be ♪
♪ I've gotta find out ♪
The head's study is this way.
♪ Because it's torturin' me
I've gotta find out ♪
♪ I ♪
♪♪ (STOPS)
Um, do you two...
BOY: Don't know. Never had it.
(LAUGHTER)
Do you two shake?
Um, well, I'll, uh,
see you later, Mr. Thackeray.
GIRL:
Well?
I, uh... Thank you,
but I have to go and see the principal.
(STUDENTS LAUGHING)
♪ (RESUMES) ♪
♪ I just wish I knew ♪
MAN: You've excellent
qualifications, Mr. Thackeray.
Astonishing ones, in fact...
as a communications engineer.
Field experience in South American...
Why do you want to be a teacher?
Reasons.
You've already tried
to get an engineering post?
I've tried for 18 months now.
Mm-hmm.
We have no blueprint
in North Quay.
Most of our children
are rejects from other schools.
We have to help them
as best we can.
We have to teach them what we can
and as much as we can.
The local authorities
are not totally on our side.
And from the moment
you accept this position,
you'll be entirely
on your own.
Of course, I and the staff
will do everything we can to help you,
but success or failure
will depend entirely upon you.
Now, what's it to be?
I want the job, sir.
Good. Then it's settled.
Now, tomorrow you'll
take over Hackman's class.
THACKERAY: Sapiano. Yeah!
Wong.
Yes.
Osgood.
Yeah.
Tuffen.
Pegg.
Pegg?
Yeah.
Joseph.
Dare.
Yeah.
Potter. Potter!
Denham.
Hmm.
Buckley.
Yeah.
Purcell.
Hmm.
Fernman.
Yeah.
Jackson.
Strong.
Yeah.
Seales.
Seales!
Yeah.
Palmer.
PALMER: Yes, guv'nor.
Campbell.
Present.
I don't know how much you know,
so we'll start from scratch.
First, as I call your name,
will you please read anything you like
from one of your school books.
Fernman.
Right.
"Only those who..."
"Arrived."
"arrived on horseback...
or in a public coach..."
THACKERAY: Thank you.
Denham.
"If 14 hens lay an egg a day
for 30 days,
how much are the eggs a dozen,
and how many have you to sell?"
(LAUGHTER)
Moira Joseph.
"Pete Gilroy's weight
and the ever-tightening 'noosie'...
"about her neck..." BOY:
That's nice. Cor.
"About her neck
began slightly..."
to 'impeddie'
the wild mare's speed.
But Pete was only too fully aware
of what his fate would be,
"for he could not hope to escape death
from being battered and crushed."
Put that away, please.
(SQUEAKS)
(TOY SQUEAKS)
Thank you.
(SCATTERED CHUCKLING)
Is there anyone else
who would like to read?
Your name, please?
Pamela Dare.
"And he had learned to love.
I know not why."
For this in such as him
seems strange of mood.
But thus it was.
And though in solitude,
small power that nipped
affections have to grow.
"And in this glowed
when all beside had ceased to glow."
Well done!
(ALL CHEERING)
(CHEERING CONTINUES)
Thank you, Miss Dare.
Next: weights and measures.
What's "avoirdupois"?
"Avoirdu" what?
Avoirdupois.
Weights.
Oh, yeah.
Uh, heavyweight,
light-heavy, cruiser weight,
middle, light, bantam,
fly, featherweight.
BOY: Hey! Thank you very much.
(CHEERING, LAUGHING)
It's encouraging
that you have a sense of humor.
It seems you know so little
and are so easily amused,
I can look forward
to a very happy time.
Now, copy down
the following tables.
(MURMURING) Who does he think
he is, the cheeky devil.
(TAPPING)
Hello, Ducks.
Hello.
(CHUCKLES)
Thought you might need this.
Thank you.
How'd it go?
Well, let's just say
the battle was joined.
Ahh! I don't know what we'd do
without a cup of...
What's your name?
Thackeray.
I know that.
I mean your other name.
Mark.
A couple of things, Mark.
We all know the old man's views.
Basically, we agree with them.
But he's safe in an office.
Now, these kids come from homes where an
order is usually accompanied by a blow.
One rude word to their parents,
the roof'll hit 'em.
There's nothing like that
going on here, right?
So they've got us
at a great disadvantage.
Hackman tried to be popular.
He hung himself.
Weston couldn't care less about them.
Well, that's no good.
(SIGHS)
I can't guide you, but...
don't take any nonsense
from these little tykes.
They're good kids, Mark.
Most of them.
But if you don't solve them,
they'll break you, and damned quickly.
That's been tried...
by experts.
They're very expert.
Please, can I leave
the room, guv?
Yes. And it's "Thackeray."
Oh. Yes, guv.
(LAUGHTER)
Now, most of you girls help
your mothers with the shopping.
So sorry, Mr. Thackeray. Proper
drafty in these parts, isn't it?
(LAUGHTER)
About multiplying.
There are a few valuable
tricks to know.
Say that you're offered roast beef
at seven shillings per pound.
Potter! Must you do that?
I can't help it, sir.
It's me desk.
Aw, poor old Potts.
(ALL CHATTERING)
Blimey,
did it make a noise?
(CHATTERING CONTINUES)
(THACKERAY CLAPPING)
Sit down.
(MURMURING)
I'll speak with the caretaker
about it after school.
(ALL CHATTERING) Aw, isn't that nice?
Lovely.
I hope I didn't miss nothing.
Where was he, Pam, love?
Oh, yeah. About shopping or something,
wasn't it? That's enough, Denham.
Well, I was only asking,
Mr. Thackeray.
Don't wanna miss nothing,
now, do I?
Hey, Bert, he was just about to
show us a new, invaluable trick.
Oh, yeah. When you're
shopping, well, you see...
I said, that's enough.
Sit down.
Do exercise four, five and six.
(CHATTERING IN PROTEST)
Very quietly.
Don't worry.
The worst is still to come.
You're still getting what's known
as the "silent treatment."
What's the next phase?
Well, unless you can work up
a little black magic,
these little bastards
have a multitude of tricks.
Why did you take up teaching?
Oh, it's good to have
some kind of a job.
But I'm teaching them nothin'.
(CLUCKS TONGUE)
I'm not even getting to first base.
GILLIAN: Don't worry.
Your lot'll be leaving this term.
The next lot will be better.
They'll be just as bad.
Probably worse.
Then what's your answer?
What they need
is a bloody good hiding.
I feel rather sorry
for them, you know?
I mean, most of them
can hardly read.
You're so naive,
my dear old colleague.
They'll be earning twice as much as
us before you can shake a stick.
They'll happily be part of
the great London unwashed...
illiterate,
smelly and quite content.
An education's a disadvantage
in this day and age.
That is ridiculous.
WESTON: But still true.
So you had better start
brushing up on your voodoo...
if you wish
to remain sane.
Good morning.
(ALL CHATTERING)
All right.
Take your seats.
Ooh!
All right, sir?
I hope you didn't hurt yourself, sir.
Ooh, are you all right?
Gee, cheap stuff
they're sellin' nowadays.
Want me to help, sir?
(STUDENTS MURMURING)
(QUIETLY)
Sit down.
Take your proper places.
Here, we can move around here, you
know, sir. (CHATTERING IN AGREEMENT)
Take your proper places.
(DISAPPOINTED CHATTERING)
Here, don't go climbin'
all over the seats.
Don't behave
like a monkey.
(CHATTERING CONTINUES)
Lads, come on.
Sit down.
Keep quiet.
(YAWNS LOUDLY)
Beg your pardon.
(METAL CLATTERING)
Something the matter, Seales?
Seales,
is something wrong?
It's me mum.
She's awful sick.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Anything I can do?
No, nothing.
She's English.
I see.
You're like my old man,
excepting you're bigger and younger.
Rotten bastard. You shouldn't speak
like that about your father.
You know nothing. I hate him!
Hate him! Why not, eh?
I'll never forgive him
for what he did to me mum. Never!
Well, he married her,
didn't he? Didn't he?
(TRAIN PASSING)
THACKERAY: Today let's take
a look at South America.
Oh, I'm sorry,
Mr. "Fackery."
The bloody things just slipped.
The name is "Thackeray."
And they're not bloody things.
They were a pile of books.
(BOY LAUGHING)
That's a good one,
that is, squire.
Pam, love, it's not a bloody
pile, but it's a pile of books.
(ALL LAUGHING)
All right. Settle down.
I was only tryin' to help, Mr.
Thackeray, sir.
DENHAM: That's right, Mr.
Thackeray.
Old Curly was only tryin' to put
the little scrubber in her place.
Denham! I know what
Curly was trying to do!
Now, just settle down.
We are going to study
South America.
Now, turn to page 37
in your geography book.
(CHATTERING, LAUGHING)
"...from whence
the honey sprung."
They were alone
but not as alone as they...
who shut in chambers
think it loneliness.
The voiceless sand and the drooping
caves that lay around them...
made them to each other press as if
there were no life beneath the sky...
(CREAKING)
"Save theirs and that
their life could never-"
Sorry, love.
It's the bleedin' desk.
Do you use such words
when you're speaking to your father?
You're not my bleedin' father!
(SCHOOL BELL RINGING)
(BOOKS SLAMMING SHUT)
(ALL CHATTERING) GIRL: What I wanna
know is, who does he think he is?
(DOOR CLOSES)
♪ ♪
(TICKING)
(STUDENTS CHATTERING)
Shh!
BOY: Hey, shut up! Shut up!
(CHATTERING STOPS)
Morning.
Hello, Thackeray.
How goes it?
Fine, thank you, sir.
(STUDENTS CHATTERING)
(CHATTERING STOPS)
All you boys, out!
♪ ♪
And the girls
stay where they are!
What's the matter, Mr. Thackeray?
Out!
Out at once, before I...
♪ ♪
(DOOR SLAMS)
I am sick of your foul language,
your crude behavior
and your sluttish manner!
There are certain things
a decent woman keeps private.
And only a filthy slut
would have done this.
And those who stood by
and encouraged her are just as bad.
I don't care who's responsible!
You're all to blame!
Now, I'm going to leave this room
for five minutes, by which time...
that disgusting object
had better be removed...
and the windows opened
to clear away the stench!
If you must play these filthy games,
do them in your homes...
and not in my classroom.
♪ ♪
(DOOR SLAMS)
Whatever is the matter?
Man, oh, man.
(HANDS CLAP)
I lost my temper. The one thing I
swore I would never, never do.
God, did I lose my temper.
What happened?
I never would have thought after all
of the bull I've taken in my life...
In a few short weeks, those kids
have got me so steamed up...
so... so easy, so quickly.
I never would have thought it.
Look, perhaps you're
trying too hard.
Those kids
are devils incarnate, huh?
I've tried everything.
Everything! But nothing I try...
Kids.
What?
Kids. That's it.
Kids.
(DOOR OPENS, CLOSES)
Those are out.
They are useless to you.
I suddenly realized
that you are not children...
that you will be adults
in a few weeks,
with all the responsibilities
that implies.
So, from now on you will be treated
as such by me and by each other...
as adults, responsible adults.
Next, we are going to be
reasonable with each other.
We are just going to talk, you and I.
You are going to listen without
interruption, and when I am finished,
one of you may have your say
without interruptions.
Next... Oh, blimey, what
a morning I've had!
First of all, the bleeding
alarm didn't go off.
Then I had to wait hours
for a bus.
I must've stood there about three
hours waiting for a bus. Example.
There are two ways
to enter a room.
One is like an adult, a lady with dignity.
The other is like a brat.
Miss Dare has just shown us
the second way.
Perhaps you would care
to demonstrate the first.
(QUIETLY)
I'm sorry I'm late.
(MURMURING)
Next, we are all going to observe
certain courtesies in this classroom.
You will call me "sir"
or "Mr. Thackeray."
The young ladies
will be addressed as "miss,"
the boys by their surnames.
Here, why should we call 'em miss?
We know 'em.
I beg your pardon?
I said, "Why should we call them miss, sir?
We know 'em."
Is there anyone of these
young ladies you feel...
does not deserve to be addressed as miss?
(CHUCKLES)
No, sir.
Good.
Next, general deportment.
First, the young ladies.
They must prove that they
are worthy and appreciative...
of the courtesies
we are going to show them.
Soon boyfriends and marriage
will concern you.
No man likes a slut for long.
Only the worst type
will marry one.
And the competition for men
on the outside is rough.
Next, men.
I've seen garbage collectors
who are cleaner.
Toughness is a quality of the mind,
like bravery, honesty and ambition.
If you want to wear
your hair long, clean it,
else you will soon
get lice and smell.
Soon your principal interest
will be girls.
You will be much more attractive
to them with clean clothes,
clean shoes, hands, face,
teeth, et cetera.
Now, any...
any questions?
Miss Pegg.
What about Mr. Weston, sir?
He's never tidy,
and his shoes is never brushed.
And his hair's a mess, isn't it?
Yeah! It's filthy!
(STUDENTS CHATTERING IN AGREEMENT)
Mr. Weston is not your teacher.
We won't discuss him.
I'm the one to criticize if I fail to
maintain the standards I ask of you.
That's not fair.
Sir... or Mr. Thackeray.
Didn't you understand?
That's not fair,
sir.
I agree.
But that's just an example...
of the many things you'll have
to put up with when you're an adult.
You'll just have to take it.
Next, we are going to talk
about various...
Oh.
Good morning.
I just wanted to see how you were
getting on. Fine, thank you, sir.
Good.
Well, thank you.
(CHATTERING)
What is it?
Palmer.
What are we gonna
talk about, sir?
About life, survival,
love, death, sex,
marriage, rebellion,
anything you want.
(MURMURING)
(MAN ON RECORD PLAYER)
♪ No matter what you do ♪
♪ No matter what you say ♪
♪ I've had enough of you ♪
♪ No matter what you do ♪
I never did see one like him, Pam.
Even when he blew his stack,
no swearin' or nothin'.
Blimey.
Ain't natural, that's what.
Does he really mean
what he says?
I don't know. It'd be a
change, though, wouldn't it?
To see those creeps
acting like gents. Yeah.
Here, which one do you fancy?
I like Babs.
Yeah?
Watch this.
Come on, Pam, luv.
Aw, get lost Denham.
I don't like your
smelly tricks, do I?
And it's Miss Dare to you.
Get stuffed.
Come on, then, luv.
You heard what sir said,
Mr. Smarty Denham!
If you wanna dance with me,
you bleedin' well ask proper!
(LAUGHTER)
Uh, may I have the pleasure of this
dance, Miss Pegg? Blimey! Good old Potts!
Mmm, get you, Potter.
Shut up!
Who does he think he is,
bleedin' Fred Astaire?
Yeah! Come on, Miss Pegg.
(LAUGHTER)
♪ You took my love
for granted ♪
♪ And you pushed your love too far ♪
Oh, look at me.
I am a lady, I am.
(LAUGHTER)
♪ Just as far as I can go ♪
♪ I've had it up to here
and I want out ♪
♪ No matter what you do ♪
♪ No matter what you say ♪
♪ I've had enough of you ♪
Rotten tarts, all of them.
Bleedin' chimney sweep
was right about that.
Well, you won't catch me spending
me nicker on them, that's for sure.
♪ I've had it up to here
and I want out ♪
Hey, he said we could talk
about anything, didn't he?
You're so right,
Tich, me old mate.
He did say we could ask him anything.
(CHUCKLES)
Questions and answers, eh?
♪ You took my love for granted ♪♪
Yes, Denham.
Uh, last night on the telly,
Mr. Thackeray,
there was this, uh,
travelogue picture, you know?
A lot of black women
dancin' around with no tops on.
Don't they ever dress proper?
What's proper varies
throughout the world,
depending on customs and climate.
For their climate and according to their
customs, they were dressed properly.
Are you from South Africa, sir?
Of course not.
South Africans is white, isn't they?
(LAUGHTER)
A South African is a native of
South Africa, regardless of color.
I was born in British Guiana.
Yes, Ingham.
Uh, what did you mean the other
day about rebellion, sir?
Change. Take your hairstyles.
That's a form of rebellion, isn't it?
Aye? What, sir?
Don't you just do it to be different
from adults? Isn't that the reason?
Well, they've messed up
the world a bit, haven't they, sir?
You can say that again.
So you rebel.
Even the way you dress
is a form of rebellion, now, isn't it?
Oh, it's just
the new fashion, sir.
'Course, the adults
look proper stupid in our gear.
Do you think it's wrong to change,
to be different, to rebel, sir?
It is your duty
to change the world, if you can.
Not by violence...
peacefully, individually, not as a mob.
Take the Beatles.
They started a huge social revolution.
The fashions they set in dress and
hairstyles are worldwide now.
Every new fashion
is a form of rebellion.
Now, there's a fine exhibition of
costumes through the ages on...
at the Victoria and Albert Museum.
I think you
should go and see it.
Also, you should stop in and see the
Museum of Natural History. What?
Us lot go to a museum?
Yeah. Sure.
You're jokin'.
You'll discover that your hairstyles...
are 200 years old...
(CHATTERING, CHUCKLING)
And that your costumes or your
dress is, uh, right out of 1920.
(CHATTERING, CHUCKLING)
Shut up! Look, sir,
when can we go?
There's no time after school, and I've got
to look after the kids and flat and all.
Yeah, and I have to do
the housework and get
the supper for the
lodgers and all, sir.
Nor can I, sir. Me mum's expectin' a baby
any day, and I got to babysit the others.
Why don't you take us? We could
go in the morning. Oh, yes!
(CHATTERING IN AGREEMENT)
BARBARA: I'd love that. Smashing!
Who would like that?
(CHATTERING CONTINUES)
Oh, what a drag. What's the matter?
Don't you want a day off?
Put your hand up.
BARBARA: Come on, Potts!
Put both hands up.
Fat chance.
It wouldn't work. It's not the sort
of risk that we've ever dared...
to take at North Quay.
I would like to try, sir.
The best of pupils are
inclined to show off in public.
Your class?
You'd never be able
to supervise them.
When I took this job, you said...
that you wouldn't interfere as long
as I stayed within your framework.
Well, if you can persuade
another member of the staff...
to go with you,
I'll approach the council.
I see little hope of approval.
Thank you, sir.
(HEAVY VEHICLE APPROACHING)
Miss Blanchard.
Miss Blanchard, I-I think I can
arrange an outing for my class...
if I can get another
teacher to go along.
I was...
I'd love to. And it's Gillian.
When is the outing, Mark?
As soon as we can arrange
the travel warrants and permission.
Well, just let me know when.
(BELL DINGS)
Thanks, Gillian. Bye.
Bye.
(STUDENTS CHATTERING)
Good morning.
ALL: Good morning, sir.
What would you like
to talk about today?
Ladies first. Miss Joseph.
Marriage, sir. You know,
boyfriends and things.
How do you know
he's the right one?
What do you think
a girl should look for?
How to avoid divorce, sir.
Don't get married!
(CHATTERING, LAUGHING)
Where's Miss Purcell? She's to
look after the home today, sir.
Her mum had the baby
last night.
Oh. What hospital?
No hospital, sir.
The doctor came to her.
She all right?
Well, she just had a kid,
didn't she?
(CHUCKLES)
Yeah.
Well, now...
Marriage. First, let us lay
some ground rules.
I've never been married,
so what I say is as an outsider.
Now, what should a girl
look for in a man?
I think first we ought
to determine what is marriage.
Miss Joseph.
Holy wedlock.
Holy wedlock?
MOIRA: Potter, be serious.
You'll get your turn.
Miss Pegg?
It's life, isn't it, sir?
Everyone gets married.
I mean, sometime.
Why didn't you get married, sir?
POTTER: No one would have him.
I was very poor.
And there was something in me
that wanted an education,
so I put all of my energies into that.
And, well,
I got started later...
and just never met
the right girl.
Now, what should a girl
look for in a man?
Miss Clark.
What work did you do, sir?
I waited tables.
I cooked in a hamburger joint.
I washed dishes for a time. Cars.
For a year I was a janitor in an
apartment block. All sorts of jobs.
You washed dishes, sir?
I did.
Yeah, but you talk posh and all.
That wasn't easy.
MOIRA:
You didn't always talk like that, then?
When I was your age
I used a patois...
a kind of simple English.
(RATTLING OFF SLANG PHRASES)
(LAUGHTER)
Didn't understand a word, sir.
Well, I don't always
understand what you say either.
But the point is, if you're prepared to
work hard, you can do almost anything.
You can get any job you want.
You can even...
You can even, uh,
change your speech,
if you want to.
After I got my degree,
I went to work...
in South America
for an oil company.
The only women in that region...
were jungle Indians who carried
blow pipes and poison darts.
(LAUGHTER)
You could have broke my hands.
We were discussing marriage.
To my mind, marriage
is no way of life for the weak,
the selfish
or the insecure.
(GROANS)
What's the matter, Weston?
These damned fool Americans.
They bog up everything
they're connected with.
What a shower.
I'll never forgive the
president for not coming...
to dear old Churchill's funeral...
or at least sending
the vice president.
Rotten bad manners.
It was very naughty.
I quite agree.
A typically stupid, appalling
and unnecessary mistake.
Still, what can you expect?
Still beefing, Weston? Give
them a chance, Mr. Weston.
They have not been in the
business of leading the world...
as long as Britain was. You
continue to astonish me, old chum.
I should have thought if
anyone took a point of...
(KNOCKING)
Oh, now what?
Yes?
Excuse me, sir.
Miss Pegg wants to know
if the net ball is fixed.
Miss who? Barbara Pegg.
Miss Pegg, sir.
Here you are, Fernman.
Thank you, sir.
What's going on in this
classroom of yours, old chum?
Suburban formality? It's a bit foreign
in this neck of the woods, isn't it?
Some sort of experiment
in culture for the masses?
It's an elementary
experiment in courtesy.
And do we ignorant critters
have to follow suit?
Please yourself.
Well, thank goodness for that.
Do you object to being taught manners
by one of the boys, Mr. Weston?
I don't expect to be taught manners
by those morons.
So long as we learn, it doesn't
matter who teaches us, does it?
Afternoon, everybody.
WESTON:
Ah. Here's the man.
Now, Weston.
Now we're talking.
Thackeray.
Clinty.
Nothing like payday.
Oh, by the way. Your museum
visit has been approved.
But remember that if anything goes
wrong, the whole school will suffer.
Nothing will go wrong, sir.
Gillian.
Thank you.
Here you are, Miss Phillips.
Miss Dawes.
Here you are, Grace.
(BELLS CHIMING)
(SNIFFLES)
(LAUGHS) For a moment I thought
I was in the wrong classroom.
Where's Jackson?
We don't know, sir.
Old Tich wouldn't miss nothing like
this unless he was sick or something.
Well, we'll give him
a few minutes.
(CHATTERING)
It's me, sir, Jackson.
I've got to take the bag wash for me mum.
Can you wait a jiffy, please?
Sure. How long will it take?
Half a mo. It's just up the frog.
Lord love you, sir.
Here, hang on, Tich.
I'll give you a hand.
(CHEERING, LAUGHING)
All right, all right.
Back on the sidewalk.
What's a frog
got to do with it?
Oh, it's a rhyming slang, sir.
You know, old-fashioned cockney.
It's not used anymore, sir.
Just for the old people.
Oh, it's a drag, sir.
SEALES: Frog means road, sir.
Frog and toad, road.
Trouble and strife, wife.
Weeping willow, pillow. You
just use the first word, see?
Like the old currant bun, sir.
That's the sun.
Apples and pears, stairs.
Happy kill, skill.
(LAUGHING,
CHATTERING)
Ginger beer, queer.
(LAUGHTER)
All right, all right.
All aboard.
WOMAN:
♪ Those schoolgirl days ♪
♪ Of telling tales
and biting nails ♪
♪ Are gone ♪
♪ But in my mind ♪
♪ I know they will still ♪
♪ Live on and on ♪
♪ But how do you thank someone ♪
♪ Who's taken you
from crayons to perfume? ♪
♪ It isn't easy ♪
♪ But I'll try ♪
♪ If you wanted the sky ♪
♪ I would write across the sky ♪
♪ In letters ♪
♪ That would soar
a thousand feet high ♪
♪ To sir ♪
♪ With love ♪
♪ Those awkward years ♪
♪ Have hurried by ♪
♪ Why did they fly away? ♪
♪ Why is it, sir ♪
♪ Children grow ♪
♪ Up to be people one day? ♪
♪ What takes the place
of climbing trees ♪
♪ And dirty knees
in the world outside? ♪
♪ What is there for you I can buy? ♪
♪ If you wanted the world ♪
♪ I'd surround it with a wall ♪
♪ I'd scrawl ♪
♪ These words with letters 10 feet tall ♪
♪ To sir ♪
♪ With love ♪♪
(BOTH LAUGHING)
I think he fancies her.
I know you do.
Pamela Dare has quite a crush on you.
Women say the damnedest things.
I think he's nice.
So do I.
You've noticed, haven't you?
I don't treat her any
differently from the other girls.
I hope we can go out again, don't you?
I hope so. It was fun.
I hope we can go with him
because he's nice. I like him.
Don't make any mistake
about Pamela.
She's a woman
in every sense of the word.
I mean, not that I blame her.
(LAUGHS)
Bleeding rotten taste he's got.
(SCHOOL BELL RINGING)
(LAUGHING, CHATTERING)
Good night, sir.
Good night, sir. See you tomorrow, Mr.
Thackeray.
Good night.
Good night, sir.
Good night, Mr. Thackeray.
Good night. Good night.
Good night, sir.
Good night.
Sir...
(DOOR CLOSES)
Perhaps you'd like me
to tidy your desk.
Oh, well, no. That's all right.
No, it's all right.
It's no trouble. You know, you
ought to get a flat nearby.
Brentwood's much too far away.
Yes, well...
There are some nice ones around here.
I've thought of that.
I'll tell you what.
I'll keep my ears open for you.
That's very kind of you, Miss Dare,
but I'm fine for the moment.
I'll let you know. Thank you.
Don't worry
about your desk, sir.
I'll tidy it for you every day.
Thanks, but that...
that won't be necessary.
That's perfectly all right.
A woman's work is never done.
Night, sir.
(DOOR CLOSES)
(CHATTERING, LAUGHING)
Hi, fellas.
How are you?
(CHATTERING)
Good morning, sir.
Good morning.
Mr. Florian has given us
permission for more outings.
Oh, that's great!
Great!
I would like to hear suggestions
from you of what we might do.
Oh, the pictures, sir.
Wembley, sir.
Cup Final Day.
Here, the Chamber of Horrors.
Oh, that's a good one.
What about the Cavern?
Cavern?
You know, sir, Liverpool, The Beatles.
How's it going, Fernman?
Fine, thank you, sir.
Don't you worry about him, sir.
He'll come with me on my day.
You're under a supervision order too?
BARBARA: Around here that's nothing, sir.
Most of us have been up
in front of the law.
You know, breaking windows,
playing truant, raising hell...
and cussing the coppers.
Oh, you've cut yourself. Oh, you'd
better put something on that, sir.
You might get lockjaw
or something.
Blimey! Red blood!
What do you expect, pinhead, ink?
(CLATTERS)
I didn't mean no harm, sir. It was just
a joke. I didn't mean no crack, sir.
It's all right.
What's with you?
Are you addressing me, Denham?
Yeah.
Potts was only being funny. What'd you call
him pinhead for in front of chimney sweep?
Going after Potts
in front of him?
I was only having a little joke.
Sir didn't mind.
He said we could ask
him anything, didn't he?
You call those questions?
Always on about his color. You've got
nothing better to talk about, have you?
You're just wasting our time. And,
Seales, you ought to know better.
What have I done?
I didn't say nothing.
No, you never say nothing.
And you're half-colored too.
You sit on your fat ass
and keep your trap shut.
If they want to know,
why don't they ask you?
I'm not sir, that's why.
I only wish I was.
(SCOFFS)
I know what's eating you.
You fancy him, that's what.
Well, this is a fine how do you
do, isn't it, Potts, old mate?
You lay off, Denham, you son of...
(TRAIN PASSING)
Today I'm going to show you
how to make a salad.
You mean we've
to cook and all?
(CLAMORING)
Sure. Why not?
My old man never cooked
nothing in his whole life.
He says that's woman's work,
the kitchen and all.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
But suppose you're on your own,
as you certainly will be shortly,
then you'll have to do it for
yourselves sometimes, won't you?
(MURMURING)
Oh, not again, sir.
(LAUGHTER)
This is survival training.
Now. Hmm?
A normal English salad.
Not fit for human consumption,
even if you remove the usual slugs...
and add a dash of the extraordinary...
a bit of mayonnaise.
Now...
(DOOR OPENS)
BOY: Look at her.
(CHATTERING)
I'm sorry I'm late.
Mum had to go to the doctor and I
didn't want to miss the day, sir.
He won't be no trouble.
(FUSSING)
THACKERAY: It's all right.
Sit down.
Make room over there.
(CLAMORING)
Koochy-koochy-koochy.
All right, all right, Okay.
Come on. Now...
Never be afraid
to experiment.
And always remember that you can eat
well, even though you're broke.
See? You ever been broke, sir?
Real broke? Skint?
Yeah. Many, many, many times.
Oh, I don't
understand you a bit, sir.
I mean, you're a toff...
and you ain't.
Huh?
Sir?
What he means is...
Well, blimey.
I can't sort of put it into
words or anything, but...
Well, sir, you're like us,
but you ain't.
I mean, you're not.
It's kind of scary, but nice.
You know what I mean,
don't you?
Well, I... I don't know how
to answer you, except to say...
that I teach you truths...
my truths.
Yeah, it is kind of scary,
dealing with the truth.
Scary and dangerous.
Now, have you ever
had a salad with, uh,
with almonds and grapes
and tomatoes...
and lettuce
and pineapple?
(STUDENTS CLAMORING,
CHATTERING)
She's obviously
in love with you, Mark.
(LAUGHS) Oh, you shouldn't
be so surprised.
We have a lot of marvelous
schools now in the East End.
It's still difficult
to get quality teachers.
Take us...
the bottom of the pile.
Goodness knows we've
had a scruffy lot here.
Then along comes
Mr. Mark Thackeray...
big, broad, handsome,
clean, intelligent,
looking like he stepped
out of a bandbox.
What do you expect?
What do I do?
Nothing.
Just be patient.
Thanks.
Pamela's just finding out
she's a grown woman.
You're probably the only real
man she's ever met in her life.
Don't spend too much time
alone with her.
Why didn't you ask Gillian?
Oh, I thought you'd be wiser.
(SIGHS)
Well, thanks.
(DOOR CLOSES)
Well, hello, sir.
We can't have you
queuing up.
It's sir. He teaches our
Moira up at North Quay.
He's only got an hour for his
lunch, that's all he's got.
Now, what'll it be, sir?
Half a dozen oranges.
Oh, you'll like them.
They're lovely and juicy.
Here you are, guv.
Penny's wedding cake.
Jeanie's elder sister. She
went and got married,
so we thought we'd give you
a bit of cake for luck.
Jeanie Clark.
Oh! Yes. Miss Clark.
That was a lovely museum outing they
went on. We'll have to do it again.
The Museum? Oh, well,
we're trying to arrange
one a week.
Oh, that'll be lovely,
won't it, Horace?
The more education they learns, the better.
That's what I always say.
It's a proper bleeder, you know,
what with the bomb and all.
'Tain't the bombs. It's them
bleedin' foreigners, them Yanks.
Shut your gob.
My Gert's married to a Yank.
And a proper
nice gent he is, and all.
I'll thank you to keep
your opinions to yourself.
God Al-bloody-mighty.
Getting technical, eh?
Listen, first cast the mote
out of your own bleedin' eye...
before you cast the bomb out of mine.
Aw, shut up.
He's a proper faggot.
Here you are.
You'll like them, sir.
Thank you.
Thank you. Who's next?
Come on, girls.
Speak up.
Gillian?
Uh-huh?
I was wondering if you would also give
the girls some lessons in makeup.
I think quite a few
of them would be, uh,
very pretty
if they knew how to do it.
Well, certainly.
You really are getting
involved with your children,
aren't you?
No, I'm just trying to help.
That's the job, isn't it?
You want some of this?
No, thanks.
Is that all you're
having for lunch? Yep.
You on a diet? No. I'll
tell you... I'm a weak man.
At the moment, a little skint.
When I eat, (SLURPS)
do I love to eat.
(LAUGHS) And I love wine, but
I just can't have a glass.
I want to drink
the whole bottle.
So I avoid wine
and pastrami sandwiches...
and baked potatoes...
with butter and bacon...
and strawberry shortcake
and cheesecake.
(LAUGHING)
But I like to eat light,
uh, for lunch.
How is it
with the Dare girl?
No problems.
Are you going to stay on here, Mark?
Until I get sorted out.
No luck with the job?
But I'm plugging away.
Remember a few weeks ago, when you
thought you'd lost the battle?
I thought you had too. There's a good
angel looking after me somewhere.
Come on.
Sort yourselves out.
Go on. Hurry up.
All right, go.
Come on, Denham.
Hurry it up.
Land on your toes.
Do it again. Next.
Next!
Next! Buckley!
Come on, boy.
I'm not a boy.
I'm a man, and I don't want
to do it, sir.
It's too high.
You're a boy, and you're a fat boy too.
Come on. I'm waiting.
Get some of that jelly off of you.
Fats can't do it.
It's too high for him.
'Course he can't do it.
When I want your opinion,
I'll ask for it, boy.
I'm not a boy.
Shut up!
Buckley, do as you're told.
Come on.
(GROANS)
(MOANING)
Move out of the way, boy!
Shut up!
(BUCKLEY MOANING)
Is he all right, Bert?
(MOANING)
I don't know.
You bloody bastard.
Put that down, Potter! You
knew Fats couldn't do that.
You've always
had it in for him.
Potter, put that down.
Quick, sir! They're
fighting in the gym, sir!
Go on, Potts!
For the last time, put it down!
That weren't no accident!
Potter!
I'll take that.
Go and help Buckley.
Go on.
Potts should have done the
bastard like he did Fats.
You all right, boy?
Yes, thank you, sir.
Me stomach doesn't
half hurt though.
Jackson, Ingham,
help him up to Mrs. Evans.
All right.
What happened?
(SIGHS)
Hmm?
Buckley's all right.
More frightened
than anything else.
Why'd you make him
do that jump?
He just stood there
and refused to obey.
When he jumped, well, he sent the
buck flying and I couldn't catch him.
Oh.
Thanks for helping me out.
That Potter went berserk.
(SIGHS)
I understand
that Buckley is a...
pet whipping boy of yours.
Is that right?
I'd better report it to the head.
There's gonna be the devil to pay.
(CHATTERING)
Potter? I can't think of anything
that could excuse your behavior.
But it was him, sir!
He made Fats do it!
Fats said he couldn't do it! The bloody
bully has always had it in for him!
I'm not concerned with
Mr. Bell's behavior, but yours.
Suppose instead of a piece of wood, a
gun or a knife had been handy, eh?
What then? Potter was narked.
We was all narked.
That bleeder was in the wrong,
and you bloody well know it.
You're missing the point, Denham.
You all are.
In a few weeks you will
be going out into the world.
Are you going to use a weapon every
time someone makes you angry?
You're supposed to be learning
self-discipline here.
Potter, you owe Mr. Bell
an apology.
Huh? No (ALL SHOUTING)
Why should he apologize? Just 'cause
Bell's a bleedin' teacher, eh?
You'd better
answer that, Potter.
Do you think you behaved
like a... like an adult?
How about Bell apologizing
to Buckley, eh?
My business is with you,
not Mr. Bell.
It's easy for you
to talk.
No one pushes you around.
Well, Potter?
Are you a man or a hoodlum?
Do it, Potts. Do it? Denham!
(ALL TALKING)
Bell will put you up before the
law if you don't, won't he?
And you've got to have
recommends for a job, ain't you?
He's got to sign one,
hasn't he?
This has nothing to do
with what I sign or won't sign.
There's never been
a teacher you could trust.
We're only safe together... against them.
Like it's always been.
But sir's different! If he
says Potts is... That he is.
And he's wrong now.
You all know Bell's been
after old Fats for years.
Go on, Potts.
If you apologize
because you're afraid,
then you're a child, not a man.
(DOOR CLOSES)
When I leave, I've me own bearer,
so you can't touch me,
letters or no letters.
I'm sorry I'm late, sir.
But it's me mum, sir.
She's dead.
I've been helping
me dad with her things.
(VOICE BREAKING) I didn't... I didn't...
I didn't know where to go, sir.
It's all right.
(SOBBING)
Ingham, take over the class.
I understand that
the passing out class...
holds some kind of a celebration
at the end of term.
What happens?
Hmm?
We dance,
sir.
Did you apologize because
of what Denham said?
I believe one should fight
for what one believes,
provided one
is absolutely sure...
one is absolutely right.
Pass these out.
You have to fill those out.
For national health
insurance...
and so on.
(CHATTERING)
(COINS CLICKING)
What are you doing, Jackson?
It's for Seales, sir.
For flowers and a wreath.
That's-That's
wonderful of you.
May I be permitted
to contribute something?
No, thank you, Mr. Thackeray.
Here, Pam, luv.
You buy the wreath, eh?
The name's Dare.
Miss Dare.
Yeah, well,
you buy the wreath.
Send it round
when the time's right.
Send it?
Aren't you going to take it?
You don't think the girls
could take it, do you?
Well, why not?
MOIRA:
Well...
Well, it's what people
would say, sir.
What the family'd say...
if they saw us going
into a colored person's home, sir.
BARBARA: We've got
nothing against you, sir.
Honest.
But if one of us was...
Well, you can't imagine
the things that'd be said, sir.
Well.
(LAUGHS)
Well...
Thank you, Miss Pegg,
for making it clear.
Well, does that apply
to the men also?
You're dead right it does.
I'll take the flowers, sir.
Why should you do that,
Miss Dare?
Wouldn't that make you
subject to gossip?
Gossip don't worry me.
I've known Seales since
we were in kindergarten.
I'll take the flowers.
I wouldn't, if I were you.
Ah, Thackeray.
I've been looking for you.
There's a lady to see you...
Mrs. Dare.
By the way, I've canceled
all outings for your class.
Why?
I'm afraid the adult
approach hasn't worked.
It would have been better
to let things be.
You'd better take your boys for PT
until I get a replacement.
(DOOR OPENS)
Oh.
I-I'm sorry to disturb you, sir.
It's about Pam.
I'm Mrs. Dare.
What can I do for you,
Mrs. Dare?
Would you have a seat? W-Would
you talk to her, sir?
I'm sure she'd listen to you.
She's always talking about you.
What's the problem?
Well...
She always stays
out late at night, sir.
Often she doesn't get home
till past 11:00.
She never says where she's been.
She's a big girl, sir.
I'm worried about her.
She won't listen to me.
Well, I'm just a teacher, Mrs. Dare.
Oh, I know she'd
listen to you, sir.
When her friends are over, it's always,
"sir said this" or "sir said that."
See, she... she won't listen to me, sir.
She... She just won't.
Why doesn't her father
have a talk with her?
Oh. Oh, no.
No, we're divorced. H-He's uh...
He's up north somewhere.
He doesn't...
Well, it's not wrong to...
I mean, when your marriage breaks up,
your life doesn't end, does it?
Please talk to her, sir.
I'm frightened for her.
You never know what sort
of trouble she can get into.
Please.
All right. I will.
Thank you.
(DOOR OPENS, CLOSES)
Morning, sir.
(CROWD CHATTERING)
WOMAN: Hello, love.
MAN: Morning, Mr. Thackeray.
MAN 1: How are you. How's the kids?
Hello, guv.
Hello, sir.
It's a lovely day, ain't it?
Your kid ain't top of the class.
Who's got everything?
Mark! Hi! Hi!
Hi. You look as if
you'd won the pools.
Oh, better.
Whoop!
I got me a job... a real one...
when school ends.
Third assistant engineer
in a radio factory in the midlands.
They even sent me the fare.
Oh, that's marvelous.
Well, it's not that good,
but it's a start after so long.
Think she's gonna take
those flowers, Bert?
I don't know.
Hey, Pam!
Hey, sir wants you.
(DOOR OPENS)
Sit down, Miss Dare.
I'd like to talk to you.
Has my mum been in?
Yes.
The funeral
is Saturday, 10:30.
About my mum, sir? She's very
worried about you, Miss Dare.
Couldn't you
call me Pamela?
I think not, for the moment.
She says that you've
been staying out late.
Oh, I've just been
round to Gran's.
It's just round the corner.
It's not far.
Why haven't you told
your mother then?
Because she doesn't
care about me.
Well, now,
you know that's not true.
You're not in trouble, are you?
(SCOFFS)
Oh, no, sir.
Nowadays that's only
for fools, isn't it?
We're the luckiest bunch of kids,
the luckiest generation
that's ever been, aren't we?
We're the first to be really free...
to enjoy life, if we want,
without fear.
Well, what is the trouble?
Look, if you don't want to talk,
just say the word.
It doesn't bother me.
Well, it was all right
up until about a year ago.
Of course I miss Dad.
H-He was wonderful.
But... it's just one
of those things, isn't it?
Mum works up in a dress shop
up in the West End,
and we got on fine.
Then men friends
started calling on her.
Well, you know
what neighbors are like.
That's all, really.
There's nothing else to tell.
She doesn't like me.
I'm in the way.
Well, she's young and pretty,
isn't she?
I shall be glad when I can
leave school and be on my own.
Obviously, your mother loves you,
and you owe her much more
than any teacher.
I think you're wrong
about her.
Did she tell you that I found her
with one of her friends?
At home? At my home?
No, I bet she didn't,
but she was.
All families have problems.
I can't solve that for you.
But staying out late won't help.
Well, it helps me.
I can't stand the sight of her,
and if you were me,
you'd feel the same.
I'm in no position to judge.
I know that people make mistakes.
Are you saying it's my fault?
I'm saying that forgiveness
is the gift of God...
that people make mistakes... that it's up
to you to make peace with your mother.
Why should I? I haven't done anything.
Grow up, Miss Dare.
It's up to you to give her
another chance.
I told you what she did.
Why are you taking her side?
Because you're wrong
not to give her a second chance.
Everybody deserves that.
I thought you'd understand.
I thought you were different.
I thought I could trust you.
But you're just as Denham said.
Well, I'm not taking
the bloody flowers!
All right.
Let's line up here in the center.
Could we have boxing first
today, please, Mr. Thackeray?
(ALL SHOUTING AGREEMENT)
Why?
Well, it'd make a change.
Okay. Just sort yourselves
into pairs now.
Uh, do you mind having a go with me, Mr.
Thackeray?
Sapiano's hurt his wrist.
That's right, sir. Sprained it,
didn't I?
I think you, uh, ought to wait...
and have a go at Potter or one of
the others when they're finished.
Cor, he'll be done in, sir.
Go on. I don't mind having
a punch-up with you.
I think you'd better
forget that for today.
Let's go.
(SIGHS)
Okay.
Let's go.
(STUDENTS SHOUTING)
(ALL SHOUTING)
Come on!
(GROANING)
Stay where you are.
(GROANING CONTINUES)
Put your head down.
Potter, Gypsy, collect the gloves.
and put them back in the box.
The rest of you line up over here
for vaulting.
Put your head down.
(DENHAM GROANS)
Are you all right?
Yeah.
Come on over here for a minute.
I'm all right, sir.
Think I'll go wash up.
Sh...
You all right, mate?
Yes. Yes.
(CHATTERING)
(SCHOOL BELL RINGING)
(LAUGHING, CHATTERING)
Can I ask you something?
Sure.
How many times did you hit me?
Once.
I'm sorry about that.
I didn't mean to hurt you.
I just lost my temper.
I was meaning to hurt you.
Well, you did. You're pretty good.
Yeah, well, why didn't you
hit me again, eh?
Why didn't you fight, eh?
You had me easy.
I've been after you
since you got here.
Here. Are you afraid
or something?
Hitting you wouldn't have solved
very much, would it?
It's the truth. I don't
understand you at all.
Denham, what's a bearer?
A bearer?
With fruit on it and all.
A bearer!
You was wrong
about Potts.
Yes. From his point of view,
at his age, I was.
The girls was right
about the gossip and all.
From their point of view. What
other point is there, eh?
You're gonna have to figure
that one out for yourself, Denham.
How would you like
a part-time job next term,
teaching the youngsters
how to box?
Eh? If you'd like, I could
speak with Mr. Florian.
I'm sure there'll
be some fee... money for you.
Cor! Me?
A bleedin' teacher?
It's important for the youngsters
to know how to defend themselves,
isn't it? Here. Why are
you doing this, eh?
Good luck with your...
bearer, Denham.
MOIRA:
Hey, Pam.
♪ (WHISTLING) ♪
Here, what's the matter
with you?
You goin' to a bleedin'
wedding or something?
(SNIFFS) Whew! You don't
half pong, Potts.
(LAUGHING) What's
up with you, Fats?
Nothing, Bert.
Well, another week and we'll be
through with this place, what?
(MURMURING)
I ain't got a job yet.
(CHATTERING)
Here, Bert, I thought you
had the bleeder yesterday.
It was a lucky
punch, that's all.
Yeah? Well, you got eyes
in the back of your head, that's what.
Old chimney sweep could have done
me with one hand behind his back.
And none of your
"bleedin" ' here.
There's ladies present, that's what.
(MURMURING)
What sir said the other day
about the truth...
it's kind of scary, isn't it?
(FOOTSTEPS)
Good morning.
Good morning, sir.
About the party...
We've got a group and all, and the, uh...
the girls is fixin' the grub. You coming?
You inviting me?
Yeah. You're invited.
Thank you.
If I can, I certainly will.
Yeah, well, I guess
what you said's right...
about a man making up
his own mind and all.
(BELLS CHIMING)
Sir?
My goodness.
You certainly look lovely.
Thank you.
Sir, would you dance
with me tonight?
Of course.
But nothing too fast.
I am getting much too old
for that sort of thing, Miss Dare.
We'll make it something special.
Promise?
Promise.
Thank you.
Sir, would you
call me Pamela tonight?
Yes, Pamela.
Thank you.
♪ (ROCK AND ROLL) ♪
Oh, hi! Oh, excuse me
a minute, Bert.
It's Pam.
Oh! You look marvelous!
You look great too.
Where's the other earring?
Oh, it's the thing that's in.
Now, listen. I want to talk to the group.
You gonna come with me?
Yeah, but why?
Well, come on. I'll tell you.
♪ (CONTINUES) ♪
Good evening!
Good evening.
I hear you're leaving.
Yes.
It's a pity.
I'm sorry about that.
You're damn good, you know.
You've done wonders for this shower.
Well, thank you.
Thank you very much.
Anybody can be an engineer,
but teaching this mob, it's...
Well, I wish I had your gift.
Why so serious, Mark?
Good God!
It's Weston!
Oh, wrap up, Clinty.
Well, I'm damned.
He wasn't giving you
a hard time, was he?
On the contrary.
Sir, will you wave your magic wand
and make me sweet 16 again?
It has nothing to do with me.
Oh, you're a fine lad.
Your hand's in this, all right.
If you must leave, Mark,
go to another school.
You can't waste a marvelous
talent on rotten electronics.
Damn! I swore
I wouldn't interfere.
Would you like some more?
Yes, thanks.
Who made it?
I did.
It's Salad North Quay,
one of sir's special recipes.
Well, it's bloody marvelous,
Barbara...
I mean, Miss Pegg.
Oh, thank you,
Mr. Weston, I'm sure.
Actually, I don't like it.
I think it's terrible, don't you?
Blimey, I'm hot.
Thank you.
Excuse me, sir.
I got the job I wanted.
That's wonderful.
What is it?
Page boy at the London Hilton.
He can't wait to get his hands
on all that Yankee money.
(LAUGHING)
Cor, you're right there.
Still, I don't want
to be a page boy all me life.
I was wondering if you'd help me get
into night school or something.
I'd be glad to.
Ta, sir.
You don't half look dolly, miss.
(CHUCKLES)
Okay, now.
You ready, Pam?
Attention, everybody.
By special request,
it's a lady's choice.
(CHEERING, APPLAUSE)
♪ (MEDIUM-TEMPO ♪
♪ DANCE BEAT) ♪
Will you hold this,
please?
♪ (BEAT PICKS UP) ♪
♪ It's hard not to think
about you ♪
♪ To keep you off my mind ♪
♪ It's hard to live
in a world without you ♪
♪ And it's getting harder
It's getting harder ♪
♪ It's getting harder
all the time ♪
♪ It's so hard to walk
past a phone now ♪
♪ And not to try your line ♪
♪ It's hard to try
and make it alone now ♪
♪ And it's getting harder
It's getting harder ♪
♪ It's getting harder
all the time ♪
♪ Baby, I've got no more
foolish pride ♪
♪ Baby, I must have you
by my side ♪
♪ Can't stop wishing
for what I had ♪
♪ Need your kisses
and I need them bad ♪
♪ So hard to go on living ♪
♪ And know that you're
not mine ♪
♪ It's hard without all
the love you've given ♪
♪ And it's getting harder
It's getting harder ♪
♪ It's getting harder
all the time ♪
♪ (GUITAR SOLO) ♪
♪ Baby, I've got no more
foolish pride ♪
♪ Baby, I must have you
by my side ♪
♪ Can't stop wishing
for what I had ♪
♪ Need your kisses
and I need them bad ♪
♪ So hard to go on living ♪
♪ And know that you're
not mine ♪
♪ It's hard without all
the love you've given ♪
♪ And it's getting harder
Oh, it's getting harder ♪
♪ Ooh, it's getting harder
all the time ♪
♪ Oh ♪
Here, come on.
Everybody, come here.
Thank you.
Can I come
and see you sometimes?
You know, next term?
I won't be here.
Oh.
Everybody's got to move on.
I'm glad I met you though.
You've helped me a lot.
We were lucky to have you.
The whole world is waiting for you.
You're a smasher.
Thanks.
Bye.
Hold it. Listen a minute, everybody.
I've got an announcement to make.
It's about sir.
Well, sir,
we'd all like to thank you very much
for everything you've done for us.
And we'd like to give you
a little present to remember us by.
Come on, Babs.
You mean, Miss Pegg!
(LAUGHTER)
DENHAM: Babs!
(SCATTERED SHOUTING)
Come on, Babs!
(BARBARA SINGS)
♪ The time has come ♪
♪ For closing books ♪
♪ And long last looks must end ♪
♪ And as I leave ♪
♪ I know
that I am leaving ♪
♪ My best friend ♪
♪ A friend who taught me
right from wrong ♪
♪ And weak from strong ♪
♪ That's a lot to learn ♪
♪ What can I give you in return? ♪
♪ If you wanted the moon ♪
♪ I would try to make a start ♪
♪ But I ♪
♪ Would rather you let me
give my heart ♪
♪ To sir ♪
♪ With love ♪
(CHEERING)
Hooray! Speech!
(STUDENTS SHOUTING)
Speech! Speech!
(ALL SHOUTING)
Speech! Speech! Speech!
(APPLAUSE FADES, STOPS)
Well.
(SIGHS)
I think I'd better go and put it away.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Evening, guv.
Nice, isn't it?
I'm in your bleedin' class
next term.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
(DOOR SLAMS)
♪ (POP INTRO) ♪
BARBARA:
♪ The time has come ♪
♪ For closing books ♪
♪ And long last looks must end ♪
♪ And as I leave ♪
♪ I know that I am leaving ♪
♪ My best friend ♪
♪ A friend who taught me
right from wrong ♪
♪ And weak from strong ♪
♪ That's a lot to learn ♪
♪ What can I give you in return? ♪
♪ If you wanted the moon ♪
♪ I would try to make a start ♪
♪ But I ♪
♪ Would rather you let me give my heart ♪
♪ To sir ♪
♪ With love ♪♪
♪♪ (ENDS)♪♪