Captain Walker didn't come home.
His unborn child will never know him
We believe him missing with a number of men,
Don't expect to see him again
It's a boy, Mrs. Walker, it's a boy
A son! A son!
A son!
Hear the joyful celebrations in the street!
It's a boy born on this first day of peace!
We've won! A son! We've won!
I'm your friendly green coat,
And I welcome you to Bernie's Holiday Camp!
G'day, and you'll be happy,
And it's Bernie you will thank.
You must be little Tommy.
Well, call me Uncle Frank.
Welcome you too, Mrs. Walker,
Here you'll always find a helping hand!
The camp with the extras
If you come to Bernie's,
You might think you're in Heaven!
Here we have the winner, folks!
Have you ever seen a lovelier pair?
What a shapely ankle!
What a perfect shin!
If you could feel this silken thigh,
You'd know who has to win!
You'd know.
You don't know how much I've missed
To feel a man again,
To dance, to kiss.
Your eyes reveal: You're lonely.
This evening must pass slowly.
Until we're one, my heart won't rest.
Will Tommy share our happiness?
I'll be more than an uncle;
I'll be just like a Dad!
I will be a green coat too,
And when I'm big, I'll own a Holiday Camp!
A camp with a difference,
Always be good weather.
When you come to Tommy's,
The holiday's forever!
I'm glad you like your Uncle Frank.
He'll surely love you too, just like a Dad
He's very nice, I think.
Did he fight in the War?
Gotta feeling '51 is gonna be a good year,
Especially if you and me see it out together.
So you think that '51 is gonna be a good year.
We'll marry now and see it out together.
I have no reason to be over-optimistic,
But somehow when you smile
I can brave bad weather.
What about the boy?
What about the boy, he saw it all!
You didn't hear it, you didn't see it!
You won't say nothin' to no one,
Ever in your life. You never heard it.
How absurd it all seems, without any proof
You didn't hear it, you didn't see it!
You won't say nothin' to no one,
Ever in your life.
You never heard it.
How absurd it all seems, without any proof!
You won't say nothin' to no one,
Never tell a soul what you know is the truth!
Now he is deaf.
Now he is dumb
Now he is blind.
The guilty are safe,
But always accused by his empty eyes.
Nothing to say, Nothing
to hear, And nothing to see
Each sensation makes a note in his symphony.
Sickness will surely take the mind
Where minds can't usually go
Come on the amazing journey,
And learn all you should know.
A vague haze of delirium creeps up on him.
Soaring and flying images spin.
He is your leader, he is your guide.
On the amazing journey,
Sickness will surely take the mind
Where minds can't usually go.
Come on the amazing journey,
And learn all you should know
His eyes are the eyes that transmit all he knows,
The truth burns so bright it can melt winter snows.
A towering shadow, so black and so high,.
A white sun burning the earth and the sky.
Did you ever see the faces
Of the children, they get so excited
Waking up on Christmas morning
Hours before the winter sun's ignited
They believe in dreams and all they mean,
Including Heaven's generosity.
Peeping 'round the door to see what
Parcels are for free in curiosity.
He doesn't know who Jesus was,
Or what praying is.
How can he be saved
From the eternal grave?
Tommy, can you hear me?
See me, feel me, touch me, heal me.
Surrounded by his friends,
He sits so silently and
Unaware of anything.
Playing poxy pinball, picks his nose
He smiles, he cries,
He pokes his tongue at everything
I believe in love,
But how can men who've never seen light
Be enlightened?
Only if he's cured
Will his spirit's future level
Ever heighten.
And Tommy doesn't know what day it is.
He doesn't know who Jesus was,
Or what praying is.
How can he be saved
From the eternal grave?
You talk about your woman,
I wish you could see mine.
Everytime she starts to lovin',
She brings eyesight to the blind.
You know, her daddy gave her magic.
I can tell by the way she walks.
Everytime she starts to shake,
The dumb begin to talk,
She's got the power to heal you,
Never fear.
Just one word from her lips,
And the deaf can hear.
If your child ain't all he should be now,
This girl will put him right.
I'll show him what he could be now,
Just give me one night!
I'm the Gypsy, the Acid Queen,
Pay me before I start.
I'm the Gypsy, and I'm guaranteed
To mend his aching heart.
Give us a room, close the door.
Leave us for a while.
Your boy won't be a boy no more;
Young, but not a child!
'Cause I'm the Gypsy, the Acid Queen,
Pay me before I start.
The Gypsy, and I'm guaranteed
To tear your soul apart.
Gather your wits and hold on fast,
Your mind must learn to roam.
Just as the Gypsy Queen must do,
You're gonna hit the road!
My work is done, now look at him.
He's never been more alive.
His head it shakes, his fingers clutch.
Watch his body writhe!
Do you think it's alright
To leave the boy with Cousin Kevin?
There's something 'bout him I
Don't really like.
I think it's alright,
Yes, I think it's alright.
We're on our own, cousin.
All alone, cousin.
Let's think of a game to play
Now the grownups have all gone away
You won't be much fun,
Being blind, deaf and dumb,
But I've no one to play with today.
Do you know how to play Hide and Seek?
To find me, it would take you a week!
You won't go anywhere.
There's a lot I can do to a freak!
How would you feel if I turned on the bath,
Ducked your head under and started to laugh?
Maybe a cigarette burn on your arm
Will change your expression to one of alarm.
I'm the school bully,
The classroom cheat,
The nastiest play-friend
You ever could meet.
I'll put glass in your dinner,
and spikes in your seat.
I'll drag you around
By a lock of your hair,
And give you a push
At the top of the stair!
What would you do if I
Shut you outside
To stand in the rain and
Catch cold, so you'd die?
I'm the school bully,
The classroom cheat,
The nastiest play-friend
You ever could meet.
I'll stick pins in your fingers,
And tread on your feet.
We're on our own, cousin.
All alone, cousin.
We've thought of some nice games to play
While the grownups has all gone away.
You weren't too much fun,
'Cause you're blind, deaf and dumb,
But I'd no one to play with today.
Do you think it's alright
To leave the boy with Uncle Ernie?
Do you think it's alright?
He's had a few too many tonight
Yes, I think it's alright,
Yes, I think it's alright.
I'm your wicked Uncle Ernie;
I'm glad you won't see or hear me,
As I fiddle about, fiddle about, fiddle about.
Your mother left me here to mind you,
And I'm doing exactly what I bleedin' well want to,
Down with your bedclothes,
Up with your nightshirt.
Fiddle about, fiddle about, fiddle about.
You won't "shite"
As I fiddle "abite. "
Do you think it's alright
Leaving Tommy by the mirror?
You would think he had sight,
Been staring half the night.
Yes, I think it's alright,
Yes, I think it's alright
Extra, extra, pinball bonanza!
Deaf dumb and blind kid makes the big game!
Saturday, the final, he faces the champ!
Extra, extra, extra!
Pinball, the big time, a million in hand!
You can rule the world from a yacht in the bay!
Champagne flowing, you're popular, man!
Pinball, let's play!
Tommy keeps on winning,
He's a millionaire,
Momma's got a brand new Cadillac.
Hurry to the show,
We're nearly on the air!
Extra, extra!
Ever since I was a young boy,
I've played the silver ball.
From SoHo down to Brighton,
I must have played them all.
But I ain't seen nothin' like him
In any amusement hall.
That deaf, dumb and blind kid
Sure plays a mean pinball.
He stands like a statue,
Becomes part of the machine.
Feelin' all the bumpers,
Always playin' clean.
He plays by intuition.
The digit counters fall.
That deaf, dumb and blind kid
Sure plays a mean pinball.
He's a pinball wizard,
There has to be a twist.
A pinball wizard,
Got such a supple wrist!
How do you think he does it?
I don't know!
What makes him so good?
Well, he ain't got no distractions,
Can't hear no buzzers and bells.
Don't see lights a-flashing,
He plays by sense of smell.
Always has a replay,
Never tilts at all,
That deaf, dumb and blind kid
Sure plays a mean pinball.
He can't beat me now,
I've always been the champ!
I know it's a trick!
No freak's gonna beat my hand!
He can beat my favorite table,
He can beat the best.
His disciples lead him in,
And he just does the rest.
He's got crazy flipper fingers,
I've never seen them fall.
That deaf, dumb and blind kid
Sure plays a mean pinball.
He's a pinball wizard
There has to be a twist.
A pinball wizard,
Got such a supple wrist!
He's a pinball wizard
His score shoots even more
A pinball wizard,
The world's new pinball lord!
He's scoring more!
He's scoring more
thought I was the Bally table king,
But I just handed my pinball crown to him.
It rains champagne!
A son was born again!
A genius untamed!
A life of wealth and fame, wealth and fame!
Champagne flowing down just like rain,
Caviar breakfasts every day.
Merchant banks and yachts and...
Servants and cars and private sand.
See me, feel me, touch me, heal me.
They flock in, thousands strong.
We'll just play along.
A million in reserve.
For love, a just deserve, just deserve!
Birds and flowers and peacock's wings,
Sequined gowns and birds that sing!
Private planes and fishing lanes.
Bigger crowds and bigger, bigger, bigger takes.
But what's it all worth?
What's it all worth when my son is blind?
He can't hear the music nor enjoy what I'm buying.
His life is worthless, affecting mine.
I'd pay any price to drive his plight from my mind!
There's a man I've found
Could bring us all joy!
There's a doctor I've found can cure the boy!
A doctor I've found can cure the boy!
There's a man I've found could remove his sorrow,
He lives in this town, let's see him tomorrow,
He seems to be completely unreceptive.
The tests I gave him showed no sense at all.
His eyes react to light; the dials detect it.
He hears but cannot answer to your call.
There is no chance, no untried operation.
All hope lies with him and none with me.
Imagine though the shock from isolation,
When he suddenly can hear and speak and see.
His eyes can see,
His ears can hear, his lips speak.
All the time the needles flick and rock.
No machine can give the kind of stimulation,
Needed to remove his inner block.
I often wonder what it is he's feeling.
Has he ever heard a word I've said?
Look at him, now in the mirror dreaming.
What is happening in his head?
Oooooh, I wish I knew, I wish I knew.
Tommy, can you see me?
Can I help to cheer you?
Tommy, can you hear me?
Can you feel me near you?
Oooh, Tommy, Tommy, Tommy, Tommy.
You don't answer my call
With even a nod or a twitch
But you gaze at your own reflection!
You don't seem to see me
But I think you can see yourself.
How can the mirror affect you?
Can you hear me
Or do I surmise
That you fear me can you feel my temper
Rise, rise, rise, rise, rise,
Do you hear or fear or
Do I smash the mirror?
I'm free - I'm free,
And freedom tastes of reality!
And I'm waiting for you to follow me.
If I told you what it takes
To reach the highest high
You'd laugh and say "Nothing's that simple. "
But you've been told many times before
Messiahs pointed to the door
And no one had the guts to leave the temple!
I'm free - I'm free
And I'm waiting for you to follow me.
Tommy, can you hear me?
Mother, Father.
Touch me, feel me.
Who am I, where did I come from?
Have you known me, have you seen me?
You're a hero! You are famous!
You're a champion of the young!
You are rich, but it's so absurd to try
To explain all the things you've done.
You're a god, and you're loved;
Thousands watch you play
Pinball! It's a fever!
And you're the master of the game!
And now that you're whole,
You'll be champion of their very souls.
Yes, I'm healed!
Delivered from silent darkness.
No more locked doors
Or stifled screams.
Pinball! What I see now before me
Is far beyond the game,
Beyond your wildest dreams!
Those who love me
Have a higher path to follow now
And you, dear mother, too
Must be prepared!
Extra, extra, read all about it!
Pinball Wizard in a miracle cure!
Extra, Extra!
Right now, right now, story and pictures
Pinball bonanza, a mother's joy!
...to show times, lessons and actors.
Outside the house Mr. Simpson announced
That Sally couldn't go to the meeting.
He went on cleaning his black Rolls Royce
And she ran inside weeping.
She got to her room and tears splashed the picture
Of the new Messiah.
She picked up a book of her father's life
And threw it on the fire!
She knew from the start
Deep down in her heart
That she and Tommy were worlds apart,
But her mother said, "Never mind, your part...
Is to be what you'll be. "
The theme of the sermon was come unto me,
Love will find a way,
So Sally decided to ignore her dad,
And sneak out anyway!
She spent all afternoon getting ready,
Decided she'd try to touch him,
Maybe he'd see that she was free
And talk to her this Sunday.
She knew from the start
Deep down in her heart
That she and Tommy were worlds apart,
But her mother said, "Never mind, your part...
Is to be what you'll be. "
She arrived at six and the place was swinging
To gospel music by nine.
Group after group appeared on the stage
And Sally just sat there crying.
She bit her nails looking pretty as a picture
Right in the very front row
And then one of the people came on stage
And shouted, "Here we go!"
The crowd went crazy as Tommy hit the stage!
Little Sally got lost as the police bossed
The crowd back in a rage!
Your happy welcome is like a favor
I must now return.
The darkness of my childhood past
And flames of blood now burn.
The pinball game I play so well
Reflects a way of life.
This meeting is just another game;
Let's play to win, tonight!
She knew from the start
Deep down in her heart
That she and Tommy were worlds apart
But her mother said, "Never mind, your part...
Is to be what you'll be. "
Her cheek hit a chair and blood trickled down,
Mingling with her tears.
Try to walk the path I walked,
Never mind the pain and fear.
Each one of you has freedom
In your heart without my grace.
Let me see you raise your hands
See joy upon your face!
The crowd went crazy
As Tommy left the stage!
Little Sally was lost for the price of a touch
And a gash across her face,
her pretty face! Ooooh.
Sixteen stitches put her right and her Dad said,
"Don't say I didn't warn yer. "
Sally got married to a rock musician
She met in California.
Tommy always talks about the day
The disciples all went wild!
Sally still carries a scar on her cheek
To remind her of his smile.
While Tommy flies, the world is turning.
Life goes on for you and me
Our chief concern is money earning,
Why can't someone set us free?
Can't you feel him?
You'll feel me coming
A new vibration
From afar you'll see me
I'm a sensation.
I overwhelm as I approach you
Make your lungs hold breath inside!
Lovers break caresses for me
Love enhanced when I've gone by.
They worship me and all I touch
Hazy eyed they catch my glance,
Pleasant shudders shake their senses
My warm momentum throws their stance.
You'll feel me coming
A new vibration
From afar you'll see me
I'm a sensation.
Soon you'll see me can't you feel me
I'm coming...
Send your troubles dancing I know the answer
I'm a sensation.
I leave a trail of rooted people
Mesmerised by just the sight,
The few I touched now are disciples
Love as One I Am the Light...
Come to my house,
Be one of the comfortable people.
Come to this house, We're
drinking all night, Never sleeping.
Milkman come in!
And you, baker,
Little old lady, welcome,
And you, shoemaker.
Come to this house,
Into this house!
Be one of us.
Make this your house,
You can help
To collect some more in.
Young and old people,
Let's get them all in.
Ask along that man with a big red carnation
Bring every single person
From Victoria Station.
Go into that hospital,
And bring the nurses and patients.
Everybody go home and fetch their relations.
Come to this house,
Be one of the comfortable people.
Lovely bright home,
We're drinking all night never sleeping.
Hullo, Tommy, there's more at the door.
There's more at the door.
We need more room,
Build an extension.
A colorful palace,
Spare no expense, now!
Come to me now!
To raise your weary spirits high,
My son will teach your silent hearts
To talk!
Every home will have his picture.
Pilgrims all will touch his hand.
Pinball tables, gold and silver,
Altars to the Master's plan!
Rio, Paris, New York, London.
Moscow, Peking, Tokyo, the world
A Tommy Camp in every city,
Millions flocking in like sheep.
What they want ain't cheap, 's a pity.
But who am I to upset their dreams?
These pricy gips don't teach us!
Your freedom doesn't reach us!
Enlightenment escapes us!
Awareness doesn't shape us!
How can all this trvia
Take us to the goal you reached?
We came here to be like you,
To find the world you've reached
These pricy gips don't teach us!
Your freedom doesn't reach us!
How can all this trvia
Take us to the goal you reached?
We came here to be like you,
To find the world you've reached!
Welcome to the camp!
I guess you all know why we're here.
My name is Tommy, and I became aware this year.
If you want to follow me,
You've got to play pinball.
So put in your earplugs,
Put on your eyeshades,
You know where to put the cork!
Hey you, gettin' drunk,
So sorry, I've got you sussed.
Hey, you, smokin' mother nature,
You missed the bus.
Hey, hung up old Mister Normal,
Don't try to gain my trust.
'Cos you ain't gonna follow me
Any of those ways,
Although you think you must!
Now you can't hear me,
Your ears are truly sealed!
You can't speak either,
'Cos your mouth is filled
You can't see nothing,
And pinball completes the scene.
Here come willing helpers
To guide you to
Your very own machine!
We're not gonna take it.
We're not gonna take it,
Never did and never will,
We don't have to take it.
Gonna break it!
Gonna shake it!
Let's forget it better still!
Don't want no religion,
As far as we can tell!
We ain't gonna take you,
Never did and never will!
We forsake you,
Gonna rape you,
Let's forget you better still!
Listening to you I get the music.
Gazing at you I get the heat.
Following you I climb the mountain.
I get excitement at your feet!
Right behind you I see the millions.
On you I see the glory.
From you I get opinions.
From you I get the story.
Listening to you I get the music.
Gazing at you I get the heat.
Following you I climb the mountain.
I get excitement at your feet!
Right behind you I see the millions.
On you I see the glory.
From you I get opinions.
From you I get the story.
Right behind you I see the millions.
On you I see the glory.