Honey, I'm home.
Roger that.
Copy at the boat house.
Right on time.
Faisal, get your butt
in here. Harry's inside.
Yeah, yeah.
I'm coming. I'm coming.
Were you born in a barn?
Poor house.
You got your fur coat
razor blade there,
And a bunch of guys with guns.
I'm switching to subvocal now.
Check, check.
It's talk radio.
You're on the air.
That guard nearest to you
is moving away.
He's at the service door.
He's inside.
Have you seen khaled yet?
Yep. There he is.
How come billionaires
are always short?
Jamal...
Excuse me.
Colonel, how are you?
It's so good to see you again.
It's been a long time.
Terrific.
Who was that guy?
Could you hold this
for a second? Thanks.
You should be crossing
the main foyer
Heading for the stairs.
O.K., keep moving. Keep moving.
I'm in the library,
And I'm heading out
to the second floor balcony.
Modem in place.
Transmitting now.
Affirmatory.
It's a good hookup.
These are encrypted
files, guys.
It's going to take
just a few minutes.
I got your password.
Magnificent, isn't it?
Yes, quite.
I thought I knew
most of khaled's friends,
But I don't believe
I've met you before.
No, we haven't met because I
certainly would remember.
Renquist, harry renquist.
Juno skinner.
Come on. Come on.
Juno skinner, arts
and antiquities dealer,
Specializing in ancient persia.
This is persian,
if I'm not mistaken.
Very good.
6th century b.C., to be exact.
Do you like the period?
Oh, I adore it.
Alarm! Alarm!
Harry, we got a problem.
Guards are going
ape-shit down there.
Acquired most of these
pieces for jamal.
Do you tango?
Tango?
Harry? Harry?
You do not have time
to tango, buddy.
You copy?
Don't be stopping
to smell the roses now.
You got to get out of there.
Yes! Files are unlocked!
Fast faisal strikes again.
I'm in. I'm down, baby.
I got my hand up her
dress, and I am going for the gold...
Just copy
the goddamn files, o.K.?
And I thought this
was just going to be
Another bunch of boring bankers
And oil billionaires.
Harry, seconds count, buddy.
Ditch the bitch.
Unfortunately, I have to leave.
I have a plane to catch.
Well...
Call me sometime.
My offices are in rome.
I would like that.
He's with her two minutes,
And she's ready
to bear his children.
All right, twinkle toes,
what's your exit strategy?
I'm going to walk right out
of the front gate.
Ballsy.
Stupid but ballsy.
Sir?
May I see your
invitation, please?
Sure. Here's my invitation.
Aw, shit. Here we go.
Slight change in plans.
Halt!
Go!
Stay.
We're en route to the
roller rendezvous point.
I repeat...
backup rendezvous point.
Watch it! Watch it!
It's called ice,
And it gets a little slick.
Harry, do you copy?
I got it.
Shit!
Whoops!
Oh, my god.
I got it. I got it.
There he is!
Hi, guys.
Oh, yeah, that worked good.
Right out the old front gate.
Can you lean back a second?
Let's go.
We can still make our flight.
All right, that's it
for mr. Renquist.
O.K., go.
All right, we got harry
tasker billfold,
Harry tasker passport,
ticket stub,
Hotel bill, tasker.
I got two postcards
here from geneva.
Got some house keys
right there,
And I've got a souvenir
swiss snowing village.
What's that for?
It's for dana, stupe.
You know, bring your
kid home a gift.
Nice touch. Pick me up
tomorrow at 8:00.
Will do.
The debriefing is at 1000.
See you at 8:00.
O.K. Hey, harry.
Did you forget something?
What a team.
All right. Sleep fast, buddy.
Hi, honey.
How was your flight?
Oh, it was fine.
Good.
Brought you a little gift
from switzerland.
Snowy village.
Thanks, dad.
I've never had one of these.
You're welcome.
You're late for school.
You better get going.
Don't forget to feed gizmo.
O.K.
It's pretty lame.
I'm late.
Me, too. How'd it go
at the convention?
Did you make all the other
salesmen jealous?
Oh, it was fantastic.
You wouldn't believe it.
We were the big hit
of the show.
We did new model ordering system...
the 680 I told you about.
I can write up an order.
When the customer's name
comes up,
You see what
his credit line is,
What he's ordered in the
past, discounts given,
Every little detail.
Terrific.
It's fantastic. I love
the computer business.
Listen, the plumber called.
He says he has to dig
under the slab.
It's going to cost $600.
That's o.K.
Well, it's not o.K.
It's extortion.
So what did you tell him?
I slept with him, and he
said he'd knock off $100.
That's good thinking.
Bye, honey.
Hello.
Dana!
Boy, I remember the first time
I got shot out of a cannon.
Good morning. Go to school.
Thanks, dear.
Check these out.
Check 'em out.
Where's the image coming from?
Got a ccd camera
in a transmitter
In a pack of smokes.
Pretty cool?
What the hell.
Bye, dad!
What's she...
Dana! She's ripping
you off. Dana!
I knew it.
Dana!
Go!
Can't stop, I'm late! Bye, dad!
Shit.
Kids... 10 seconds of joy,
30 years of misery.
I got married three times.
I was never dumb enough
to have any.
She shouldn't be stealing.
I taught her better.
But you're not
her parents anymore.
Her parents are
axl rose and madonna.
The five minutes a day
you spend with her
Can't compete with that
constant bombardment.
You're outgunned.
It's not just because
you're a bad parent.
Kids today are 10 years
ahead of where we were.
Do you think she's
still a virgin?
Don't be ridiculous.
She's only...
She's 14.
She's only 14.
Her hormones are going
off like fire alarms.
Bet she lets that physicist
on the bike boink her.
Not dana.
Denial... it's not just
a river in egypt.
She's probably stealing the
money to pay for an abortion.
Why don't you open the door?
Or drugs.
20 here, 50 there.
I figured my wife's
boyfriend was taking it.
He takes everything else.
Never a beer in the fridge.
Thought you moved out.
Had to move back in.
It'll help me get the house
during property settlements.
You still owe me $200.
Good morning, janice.
Good morning.
Gentlemen, please identify
yourselves to the scanner.
Harry tasker, 10024.
Albert gibson, 34991.
All right, frances,
I don't believe we need you
any longer now. Thank you.
Sweet jesus, harry.
You surely screwed the pooch
last night, didn't you?
Please tell me
how I can see this
As anything
but a total disaster.
Well, total is a strong word.
Yeah. There are different
degrees of totality.
It's a scale, really, with a
perfect mission on one end
And a total pooch-screw
on the other.
You're new on harry's team,
aren't you?
Yes.
What makes you think
the slack I cut him
In any way translates to you?
Let me show you what we got.
We think he's dirty,
So we raid his private
financial files.
$100 million in wire transfers
From the commerce
bank international.
Which is a front for countries
to finance terrorist activities.
That's why we think
something big's going down.
A week ago, four warheads
were smuggled out
Of the former soviet
republic of kazakhstan.
We think khaled's group
bought the nukes
And is trying to bring
them to u.S. Soil.
So far, this is not
blowing my skirt up.
Don't you have anything
remotely substantial?
Harry,
Do you have any hard data?
Nothing you would
call rock-hard.
Actually, it's pretty limp.
Then perhaps
you'd better get some
Before somebody parks
an automobile
In front of the white house with
a nuclear weapon in the trunk.
It's not like
he's saving the world.
I mean, he's a sales rep.
Whenever I can't sleep,
I just ask him
to tell me about his day.
Six seconds and I'm out.
He acts like he's curing
cancer or something.
So you didn't get away
for the weekend?
No. Harry had
to go out of town.
I'm shocked.
Well, you know harry.
What's up?
Here. Check this out.
There's a $2 million
disbursement
From khaled to juno skinner.
That's right,
the babe at the party.
Well, that doesn't
mean anything.
She buys antiquities
for khaled.
No. He keeps his antique buys
On a separate ledger.
And this is a little
above market rate
For the horizontal bop,
even for a biscuit like her.
I want a complete
work-up on her.
Do we know where she is?
Right here in river city.
She lives in rome,
But she has a lot of
diplomatic connections,
So she has offices here.
So I guess it's time
To send in a specialist.
Care to tango?
Yes, I would.
Assholes.
It's all set up.
I got fax machine, ghost
phones, the usual stuff.
You have a suite
At the marquis hotel under the
name of renquist. Reality check.
My name is harry renquist.
I own the corporate
art consultant company
In san francisco and have an
appointment with miss skinner.
Harry.
Oh, hello.
I thought I'd see you again.
I just didn't know
it would be so soon.
What's the point of waiting?
I agree.
So your clients are looking
for something for the lobby
Of their new
corporate headquarters?
Yes. They would like to see
something very dramatic.
That's a nice piece.
I talked to many people,
And they all said
you're the one to see.
Really?
Checking on me.
So what did these people
say about me, exactly?
They say you can read
ancient sanskrit
Without having to
sound out the words.
Art dealers and archaeologists
Don't like you very much.
Those wimps.
It's because I use
my diplomatic contacts
To export cultural treasures
From countries which
tell them to take a hike.
See, most of our pieces
come from ancient persia.
Unfortunately, ancient persia
sits 20 feet under the sand
Of iran, iraq, and syria,
Not the most popular
places lately.
So I've had to become an expert
In international diplomacy.
Well, mr. Renquist...
Do you see anything you like?
Maybe.
Give me a break.
I don't think they'd
bug my tuna sandwich.
She's importing stuff
from all over the mideast.
She could be moving anything.
We've been getting calls
to the ghost numbers,
Checking out
the renquist front.
Step up surveillance.
Put on two more guys.
Maurizio, I said Saturday...
not Tuesday, Saturday.
Va béne. Ciao.
Ms. Skinner, may I have
a word with you please?
Stupid, undisciplined bitch!
It's a good thing you're
paying me a lot of money.
Do you realize there are
surveillance teams
Watching this place right now?
Your telephones are
almost certainly tapped.
And you were busy
laughing and flirting
Like a whore
with this renquist...
He checked out o.K.
We do not tolerate mistakes.
What would you like me to do?
Find out where
this renquist is.
Hello. Techtel systems.
Mr. Tasker's office.
Hi, charlene? Hi.
It's helen. Is he in?
Harry's in a sales meeting, mrs.
Tasker.
Let me try him in there.
Hold please.
Relay 10024.
It's a patch from techtel.
It's helen.
Hello, honey.
How are you? What's going on?
I'm sorry to bother you.
Dana and I want to make sure
You're going
to be home by 8:00.
We're going to a lot of
trouble for your birthday,
And we wanted to make sure...
Absolutely!
This time you can count on me.
Great.
Gotta go. Bye.
Bye.
That's disgusting, dana.
Calm down.
We've got a friend.
Three cars back
on the inside lane.
They've been on us
since we left the hotel.
In the station wagon?
Want me to lose them?
No. We need this lead.
Unit 7?
7 here.
We need you
At the georgetown mall
in three minutes.
Helen's going to be pissed.
Well, this is the problem
with terrorists.
They're really inconsiderate
When it comes
to people's schedules.
Pull over here. This is good.
O.K. Testing...
I got you. I got you.
O.K. They're right with us.
I make three of them
in the car.
Dickhead.
Blow me.
I got a couple
coming after you.
You think I'm blind?
Well, you do look
like ray charles.
So what's the plan?
Just getting a closer look
at beavis and butt-head.
There's a third one
still in the car.
O.K. Stay on him.
Hi, helen.
Yeah, it's gib.
Oh, not much.
Listen, harry forgot something
back at the office,
And you know harry, and...
Yeah, gib, I know harry.
Bye.
Bye. See you soon.
See?
Harry... Harry,
I lost the third guy.
Shit!
Hold it!
Oh, shit!
Hey!
Here. Cool off.
Move! Move!
Sorry about this.
Look out!
Hey! Freeze!
Oh, thank god.
Get into the car!
Here we go.
Federal officer
in pursuit of suspect.
Sorry.
Hey!
Harry, what's your 20?
Westbound through the park.
Suspect is on a motorcycle,
coming out on franklin.
Copy that.
I want you on 14th
in case he turns south
And 7 on the north
side to box him in.
And make it quick because
my horse is getting tired.
Your horse?
That's him!
Come on!
Go around to the back.
Copy that.
Out of my way!
Sorry.
Excuse me.
Out of my way!
Out of the way!
Move! Move! Move!
Get off there!
Down! Down!
Get down or die!
Hold still!
Come on!
Would you press the button
for the top floor, please?
Thank you.
No!
Shut up!
Say something.
That's a f-fine animal.
Eww!
Flat against the car!
O.K. Come on.
I'm so sorry.
Stay there!
Don't move!
Come on. Come on, fella.
O.K...
Back up.
You can do it.
Come on.
Good horse. Good.
Yeah, yeah.
Yeah. Go back now.
Come on.
Yeah. That's teamwork now.
Keep pulling.
Come on.
Good.
Now a little bit more.
Attaboy.
O.K.
Now, what the hell
were you thinking?
I had the guy,
And you let him get away.
Look at me when I'm talking.
What kind of a cop
are you anyway?
Hi, honey.
I know you're upset.
I'm sorry.
But I hurried home
as fast as I could.
It's o.K.
I'm sorry.
Thank you for the party.
Yeah. It was great.
Hey.
That's him.
O.K. Pause it right there.
Salim abu aziz.
This guy's really hard-core.
Highly fanatical,
a real psycho.
He's been linked to dozens
and dozens of car bombings.
You know that cafe bomb
in rome last year?
That was his.
And the 727 out of lisbon.
This guy's a major player.
He's formed his own splinter
faction... crimson jihad.
The other terrorist groups
were too warm and fuzzy.
They call him the sand spider.
Why?
Probably because
it sounds scary.
Well, this is impressive,
gentlemen.
It would be even
more impressive
If you actually
knew where he was.
We'll get him.
Why don't you pull over
right here.
What's up?
Oh, I really screwed up
with helen last night.
I'm just going to see if
she's available for lunch
To smooth things over.
You want me to hang?
Yeah. Just hang.
O.K., buddy, I'll
just... Be hanging.
Hold please.
Helen...
It's your mystery man on two.
Simon?
Oh, my god!
Hello? Simon?
Yes, I can talk.
You mean right now?
Yes... I can meet you.
O.K.
I can't wait.
Bye.
Can you cover me for an hour?
Just an hour?
Tell that stud
to take more time!
Would you shut up?
I should have never
told you about him.
Hee hee hee hee!
Have a good time!
Get a little bit for me
while you're at it!
Hey, hold it!
Fucker.
You sick or something?
Looks like you got gut-kicked.
It's helen... It's helen.
It's helen.
Helen. It has something to
do with helen, I'm guessing.
Helen...
Helen.
Is having an affair.
Welcome to the club, man.
Nobody thinks it can happen
to them the first time.
Same thing happened to
me with wife number 2.
I had no idea. Nothing's
going on, right?
I come home one day, and the
house is completely empty.
She even took the ice cube
trays from the freezer.
What kind of a sick bitch
Takes the ice cube trays
from the freezer?
But helen...
Hey, harry. Hey, listen,
helen still loves you.
She just wants to
bang this guy a while.
You'll get used to it...
Stop cheering me up!
What'd you expect, harry?
Helen's a flesh-and-blood woman,
and you're never there.
It was just a matter of time.
You know what? I say we
concentrate on work.
That's what I do whenever
my life turns to dogshit.
Work gets me by.
This is gonna be great. We're
gonna catch some terrorists,
We're gonna beat
the crap out of them,
You're gonna feel
a hell of a lot better.
Watch your head now.
Women... can't live with them,
Can't kill 'em.
Came by your office today.
I was in the area
and thought that
You might want to have lunch.
Real-really? Well, you
must've just missed me.
They said you had to run out
or something like that.
Oh, it was this rush job...
They needed these documents
At the district courthouse.
So of course, the big problem?
Our printer shut down.
I went to the third
floor to use theirs,
But they have the 1720,
And of course, the disk isn't
formatted for the 1720.
So I have to go back
upstairs and reformat,
Go back downstairs
and use the printer,
Then I couldn't get
my car to start.
Then traffic... Well,
I barely got there.
That's a little excitement
In an otherwise dull day.
Did it work out o.K.?
Yeah.
Great.
I'll check on dessert.
I'm done.
The great thing is,
They're practically giving
us a blank check on wiretap.
I've set them up on all of juno's
shipping agents and her clients.
Faisal's made a list of possible u.S.
Contacts of the crimson jihad.
Now we can just sit around...
Hey, this national
security stuff boring you?
Put a tap on her phone.
What do you mean?
I already did that.
I'm talking about helen's.
Put a tap on her office line
and my house. Do it now.
Just come over here.
Sounds great.
I have a question. I got two
words to describe that idea...
In-sane. An unauthorized
wiretap is a felony.
And we're doing it
20 times a day.
So don't give me
that crap. Do it.
Hello?
Helen, it's simon.
Is it safe to talk?
Yes. Go ahead.
I can't talk long.
Can you meet me
For lunch tomorrow?
I suppose so. Where?
Same place.
1:00.
I have to go now.
See you tomorrow.
Remember, I need you.
I thought that we might have
lunch together tomorrow.
You know, darn it,
I'm meeting allison.
We're going to go shopping.
Sorry.
No problem.
I think you're going
about this all wrong.
See, women like you
to talk to them.
And maybe you're not in touch
with your feminine side.
I was watching
sally jessy raphael...
All right. O.K.
I got the usual stuff here.
I got a telemetry-burst
transmitter, a gps tracker,
An audio transmitter,
a power supply,
I've got it
sewn into the lining here...
Hey, harry?
If you need to talk...
Speak into the purse.
O.K. Here she comes.
She'll pop out
right in front of us.
Watch. Bingo!
Looks like she's going
into chinatown.
O.K., she's parking.
O.K., give me audio.
You sure you weren't followed?
No. I kept looking behind
me like you taught me,
But I didn't see anyone.
Things are a bit hot now.
If I get a signal, I may
have to leave suddenly.
I understand.
Look, it's my job to take
risks, but not yours.
I feel bad about
bringing you into this,
But you're the only one
I can trust.
Were you out on a mission?
We say "op." covert operation,
And this one, well,
Got a little rough.
Worse than cairo?
Cairo.
Cairo was a day at the beach
next to this.
The guy's a spook.
But for whom?
Could be working her
to get to you.
Did you read
the papers yesterday?
Yes.
Sometimes the story's
a mask for covert operation.
See two men killed
in a restaurant
And two unidentified men in a
shoot-out at the marriott?
That was you?
You see? You're very good.
You recognize my style.
You're a natural at this.
He's taking credit
for our moves.
What happened?
Hardly worth talking about.
Two of them won't
bother me again.
Unbelievable!
You chased one?
I had to nail this guy
no matter what the risk.
Pretty hairy. I thought
he had me a couple times,
But I really can't take credit.
Why not?
It's the training.
It shapes you into
a lethal instrument.
You react in a microsecond
without thinking.
I'm starting to like this guy.
We've still got to kill him.
That's a given.
♪ More than a woman to me ♪
♪ more than a woman ♪
♪ more than a woman to me ♪
♪ more than a wo... ♪
The guy is a goddamn
used car salesman.
This keeps getting
better and better!
I'm sorry. I know
this has got to be painful.
But it's pretty damn funny.
If it was some idiot
and not you,
You'd be laughing your ass off.
One born every minute.
It wants you, too.
Feel it vibrate?
Say, how about a little spin?
Sure.
See, it's not just a car.
It's a total image.
An identity.
You have to go for it.
This isn't some
high-tech sports car.
It doesn't even
handle that great.
But what are we
talking about here?
Pussy, right?
Absolutely.
Let's face it, harry.
The 'vette gets 'em wet.
But it's not enough.
If you really want
to close escrow,
Well, you gotta have an angle.
I suppose you have an angle.
Oh, it's killer.
Look at me. I'm not
that much to look at.
No, no. I can be honest.
But I got 'em lining up.
And not just
the skanks, either.
Well, some are.
What's your angle?
Oh, oh, oh, oh, no.
Sorry. Trade secret.
O.K. Just ask yourself...
What do women really want?
You take these
bored housewives,
Married to the same
guy for years.
They're stuck in a rut.
They need some release!
The promise of adventure,
a hint of danger.
I create that for them.
So basically you're lying
your ass off the whole time.
See, I couldn't do that.
What are you, a boy scout?
Think of it as playing a role.
You gotta work on their dreams,
Get them out of their
suburban grind.
What about their husbands?
Dickless! Face it, if they
took care of business,
I'd be out of business,
you know what I mean?
Those idiots.
Hey, hey!
You mind keeping it under 90?
I'm still trying
to pay for this dental work.
Who are you working on now?
I always got a couple
on the hook.
There's this one, I got
her panting like a dog.
It's great.
What does she do?
Some sort of legal secretary.
You know, uptight
and conservative.
Oh! She could be so hot
if she wanted.
With you she gets
to be real hot.
Oh, red hot! Her thighs steam.
It's like a dying plant.
Just needs a little water.
Married to some boring jerk...
Married to some boring jerk?
Yeah. He doesn't
appreciate her.
She's like all these babes...
You get their pilot lit, they
can suck-start a leaf-blower.
She's got the most
incredible body
And a pair of titties
make you want to stand up
And beg for buttermilk.
Ass like a little boy...
So, then she must be really
good in bed then, eh?
Slow down.
You'll miss the turn.
See?
You and this car were
made for each other.
Why fight it?
I got some other
buyers on the line,
But I like your style.
What do you say?
Should we start up
the paperwork?
Let me think about it.
Hold it for me for a day, o.K.?
Hey. Because it's you.
I got today's transcripts.
Not much going on.
Nothing from simon?
No.
My turn to drive?
Give me the page.
What?
This jumped from
page 9 to page 11.
Where's page 10?
Give me the goddamn page!
O.K.
Seek help, harry.
Hello?
Helen, I need your help.
Can you meet me tonight?
What's happened?
It's serious.
Meet me on k street
Under the key bridge.
8:00 sharp.
Gotcha.
Shit. It's almost 8:00.
She's still at the house.
The purse is still
at the house.
Shit.
Unit 2, unit 7. Immediate roll.
Acquire subject at k
street and key bridge.
Vehicle is red and
white convertible.
You've got exactly six minutes.
Are you out of your mind?
You can't pull agents
off a priority surveillance
To follow your wife!
It's a misappropriation
of sector resources
And a breach
of national security.
You copy, harry?
You're losing it big-time, man.
I have to stop you.
Are you going to tell?
Both of our butts
are on the line.
So your life's in the crapper.
So you're wife's banging
a used car salesman.
It's humiliating, I know,
but take it like a man!
You tell on me, I tell on you.
I'm clean
as a preacher's sheets.
What about when you blew
a six-week operation
Because you were
getting a blowjob?
You knew about that?
Ha.
Let's take franklin.
It's quicker.
Quick, get in.
Hurry up. Let's go.
2 here.
Suspect, vehicle in sight.
One male, one female.
Don't be alarmed.
If I'm spotted, it'd be best
if they didn't see you.
You should keep your head down
Till we're out of the city.
Here. Let me help you.
That's better.
O.K., now the woman has her
head in the guy's lap,
Southbound on the key bridge.
2 in pursuit.
Roger, 2.
1 to condor, you got a visual?
Roger, 1. This is condor.
Subject is in sight.
Repeat. We have the ball.
We got a pretty good
lockup on infrared.
She's got her head
in his lap, all right.
Ya-hoo.
Maybe she's sleepy.
O.K., this is a safe house.
My place in the city
is too hot now.
So is the penthouse
in new york.
What is it exactly
you need me to do?
Helen, I want you
to be my wife.
But I'm married!
It's just for
the operation in paris.
I need to be married.
They'll be looking for
a man traveling alone.
Par-par... you want me
to go to paris?
Paris, with a quick
stopover in london.
Helen, there's a double
agent in my outfit.
I don't know who.
There's no one I can trust
Except you. Can you get away,
Just for a couple of days?
I just don't know.
Of course. I'm rushing you.
Forgive me. Sit down.
Make yourself comfortable.
Let me pour you some more wine.
O.K.
I'll do it.
You just saved my life.
You are incredibly brave.
I have to remind
myself of the fear
You must be feeling.
For me, fear is not an option.
In order to pull
this cover story off,
We have to look like two people
Who are completely
intimate with each other.
The enemy can spot
a fake easily.
You see what I mean?
Sorry.
That reaction could
get us both killed.
I'm sorry.
We can't afford that.
Try to relax.
It... it's just been a long time
Since anybody but harry's
touched me like that.
I know. It's awkward
for me, too.
I'm sorry.
That's all right.
Just sit back.
I'm o.K.
There. That's better.
Just let yourself...
Slip into the role.
That's it.
There we go.
Let yourself go.
Yeah. That's good.
That's great.
That's it.
No. I can't do this.
I can't do this.
What's wrong? It's o.K.
No. I cannot do this.
I cannot... Do this!
If not for me...
Do it for your country?
Shit!
God! Don't hurt me!
Don't hurt me!
I'll do whatever you want. Oh!
Please! I didn't do anything!
Oh, no!
Damn it!
Take her! Take her!
Oh, god, don't hurt me!
Son of a bitch!
Sit down.
I said sit down.
Who do you work for?
Stern, kessler,
goldstein & krumpnick.
I'm just a legal secretary.
Sure, mrs. Tasker.
What were you doing
With the international
terrorist
Carlos the jackal,
taking dictation?
How long have you been a
member of his faction?
I don't know anything
about a faction.
I just met simon...
Or whoever you say he is...
Just a couple weeks ago.
I barely know him.
That's not what it looked
like when we found you.
How did you meet him?
Well, ahem...
Keep this for me.
I can't afford to be
taken with it.
What?
It's a matter
of national security.
No.
Please, it's important.
I'll contact you.
Oh, shit.
Why did you continue
to see him?
He said he needed my help.
Not because you
were attracted to him?
No!
You were not attracted
to him at all?
No.
Well, maybe just a little.
So, is cheating
a common thing for you?
No. Never.
You're telling me
this was your first time?
I wasn't cheating!
Tell me about your husband, mrs.
Tasker.
Harry?
I... I... what can I say
about harry?
I mean, he's a sales rep
for a computer company.
So sex with him isn't exactly
waving your flag anymore.
That is none
of your goddamn business!
What kind of questions
are these?
You're in trouble. I
suggest you cooperate.
If we want to know intimate
details about your life,
You'd better tell us.
My husband is a good man.
But he's not exactly
ringing your bell...
Let me handle this part.
Do you mind?
Why did you go
to carlos' hideout?
He wanted me to go to paris
with him on a mission.
To... Pose as his wife.
And you agreed?
Why?
I don't know.
I guess I needed something.
What did you need?
I needed to feel alive.
I just wanted to do
something outrageous.
And it felt really good...
To be needed.
And to be trusted.
And to be special.
It's just that there's
So much I wanted to do
with this life,
And it's like I haven't
done any of it.
And the sand's running
out of the hourglass,
And I wanted to be able
to look back and say,
See? I did that!
I was reckless, and I was wild,
And I fucking did it!
Quite frankly,
I don't give a shit
Whether you understand
that or not.
This simon...
Did you sleep with him?
No.
She's lying.
You mean you did not have
sexual relations with him?
Listen, if you're going to
ask me every question twice,
This is going to take
a long time,
And I have to get back
to my family.
You're not going anywhere.
Just let me out of here!
Answer the question.
Answer the question!
No!
I did not...
Sleep...
With him!
Calm down, please.
You hear me,
you chickenshit bastard?
Calm down.
She could be telling the truth.
Calm down, mrs. Tasker.
Calm down, please.
I've only one more
question, mrs. Tasker.
What?
Do you...
Still love your husband?
Yes, I love him.
I've always loved him.
And I will always love him.
She loves you! Now what?
There's only one solution to
your problem, mrs. Tasker.
You must work for us.
What are you doing?
Just giving her
a little assignment.
You gotta be shitting me!
She wants a little adventure.
I'll give her one. I'm
offering you a choice.
If you work for us, we
will drop the charges.
You can resume
your normal life.
If not, you will go
to a federal prison,
And your husband and
daughter will be left
Humiliated and alone.
Your life will be destroyed.
Oh. Gee.
Let me think.
Yes or no?
Of course yes.
What's involved?
You will be contacted
with the assignment.
The code name of your
contact will be boris.
And your code name will be...
Natasha?
No.
Doris.
Pricks!
You son of a bitch.
Did you think you could
elude us forever, carlos?
You got the wrong guy.
My name's simon!
Just let me go. There's
no need to kill me.
I haven't seen your face...
No! Don't! Don't! I didn't see it!
I didn't see it!
Y-y-it's you!
Hey, you still interested
in that 'vette at all?
Hey, carlos.
The game's over.
Your career as an international
terrorist is well-documented.
Oh, no! I sell cars.
That's all!
Come on. I'm not a terrorist!
I'm actually a complete coward.
If I ever saw a gun... oh, god!
Oh, please, don't! Don't!
Don't! Don't kill me!
I'm not a spy.
I'm nothing!
I'm navel lint!
I have to lie to women
to get laid!
And I don't score much.
I got a little dick.
It's pathetic!
Oh, god.
Oh! Would a spy pee himself?
Oh, god!
Please, I'm not worth a bullet.
Have mercy, sir.
Get the fuck outta here?
Just beat it. Go on.
No! Soon as I turn,
you're gonna shoot me!
You're gonna shoot me!
Please, you can have
the car for free.
What do you say?
Get lost, dipshit.
So last night must've been
pretty exciting for you.
My flat tire?
Actually, it was a little scary
Because the tow truck driver
took such a long time.
I'll get it.
Hello?
Doris?
Yes?
Listen carefully.
In exactly one hour, go
to the hotel marquis.
Pick up an envelope marked
doris at the front desk,
And dress sexy.
What?
Hello?
No, no. Turn around.
Do it dulcimo.
Do it very slowly.
You've reached
a new all-time low.
You're really using the
suite at the marquis?
I can't afford
a suite on my salary.
Is jean-claude done yet?
Hang on.
Who wrote this shit... harry?
C'est la merde.
It's going great.
Hi.
Do you have an
envelope for doris?
This is doris.
Listen, you are a
prostitute named michelle.
Go to the room.
There will be a man there.
He is a suspected arms dealer.
Now, wait a minute. Wait.
You don't expect me to...
You know.
No.
He has particular tastes.
He likes to watch.
Tell him
That his regular girl carla
Is sick. If he likes you,
He will tell you what to do.
You must plant the bug
Near the telephone by the
bed before you leave.
If you do not
complete your mission,
The deal is off.
I'm gonna go to hell.
Hello?
Hello.
Have some champagne.
Come in here.
My name is michelle.
Carla thought you'd like me.
Let me do the talking.
You may start by
unzipping your dress.
No, no.
Turn around.
Do it dulcimo.
Do it very slowly.
Good.
Now slip the dress down slowly.
Now slide your nylons off,
One by one.
I'm not wearing any.
That's good.
Now, dance for me.
No, no, no.
Dance sexy.
Let your hands
be your lover's hands
On your own skin as you move.
♪ It's extreme self-pity ♪
♪ And frozen tears ♪
♪ 'Cause I want you with me ♪
♪ And you're not here ♪
♪ So I raise my nose
in the air ♪
♪ Till the roses
smell just like death ♪
♪ I'm all alone
in the dark, now, baby ♪
♪ I'm all alone ♪
♪ In the dark, now, baby ♪
♪ Darlin', it's hell ♪
♪ Alone in the dark ♪
♪ Since the day that you left ♪
♪ I just can't stand myself
anyway ♪
♪ I'm all alone
in the dark, now, baby ♪
♪ I'm all alone,
and darlin', it's hell ♪
♪ I'm all alone
in the dark, now, baby ♪
♪ I'm all alone ♪
Now lie on the bed
and close your eyes.
I thought you only
liked to watch.
Now lie on the bed
and close your eyes.
You pig!
Bastard!
Helen. Helen. Wait, wait, wait.
Harry?
Yes, it's harry.
I know it looks bad,
but I can explain.
Nobody move!
Don't move!
Helen, just don't do anything.
No, he isn't involved.
I'm the one you want!
Quiet, helen. Do what they say.
Guys, let the hooker go.
She's not important.
You don't need her.
Harry, please just
let me handle this.
Shut up!
What were you doing there?
You wouldn't believe
me if I told you.
Talk again, I'll kill you!
Harry.
I wish I could say
it's nice to see you again.
You know her?
You know, this shade's
totally wrong for you.
So who's your little friend?
I'm helen tasker.
Harry is my husband.
And you are...?
So now it's tasker,
not renquist.
She's just some wacko
hooker I met at the bar.
Harry, what's
the matter with you?
Just tell her the truth.
We are married,
and we have a daughter.
I don't know what's she's on,
But cut her loose and let's
get down to business.
Oh, yeah? Where did I
get this then?
Where did I get this?
Something before takeoff?
That hurt, you b...
She was telling the truth,
wasn't she, harry?
She really doesn't know.
How interesting.
Bring them.
Incredible, aren't they?
I call them the four horsemen.
They're warrior figures...
From the persian empire
of darius I,
Around 500 b.C.
They're absolutely priceless.
Pity.
Wait! Wait!
Open it.
Do you know what this is?
I know what this is.
This is an espresso machine.
No, no, no.
It's a sno-cone maker.
That's what it is.
Is it a water heater?
Do you know why you've
been brought here?
So that this man can
verify to the world
The crimson jihad is
now a nuclear power.
How can he do that?
He's just a salesman,
for christ's sake.
You're wrong about him.
Or the last thing you will see
Will be your blood
spraying across his face.
It's a soviet murph-6 from
an ss-22 air launch vehicle.
The warhead contains 14.5
kilograms of enriched uranium
With a plutonium trigger.
The nominal yield
is 30 kilotons.
What can I say?
I'm a spy.
You bastard!
You lying son of a bitch!
Sorry, honey.
Don't you call me honey!
You don't ever get to
call me honey again!
You understand me, you pig?
I can verify that
they have the arming box
And all the equipment necessary
To detonate all four warheads.
You have killed our women
and our children,
Bombed our cities from afar
like cowards,
And you dare
to call us terrorists?
Now the oppressed have
been given a mighty sword
With which to strike back
at their enemies.
Unless you, america,
Pulls all military forces
Out of the persian gulf area
immediately and forever,
The crimson jihad
will rain fire
On one major u.S. City
each week
Until our demands are met.
First, we will detonate
one weapon
On this uninhabited island
As a demonstration
of our power.
And the crimson jihad's
willingness
To be humanitarian.
However, if these demands
are not met,
The crimson jihad
will rain fire
On one major american city
each week...
Battery, aziz.
Get another one, you moron.
I think I have...
In the truck.
Jurias?
What?
Look at this.
That's not mine.
Nice transmitter.
Miami tower, jetstar
6479 delta on final.
We'll be on the ground
in 12 minutes.
Tell the d.E.A. To be ready
to fly in 12 minutes.
Signal's definitely
stopped moving.
It's an island in the keys
out past marathon.
We lost the signal.
Shit!
All right, everyone.
This is samir.
For 50 points, see if you
can guess his specialty.
Oral hygiene?
Not exactly.
Harry, what's going on?
Samir's going to ask harry
a few questions.
We're not even sure which
agency harry works for.
Now, samir's
absolutely first-class.
On the other hand,
we have harry here,
Who's managed
to lie convincingly
To the woman he loves
for 15 years.
So it'll be interesting
To see how long he can resist.
This will help.
You know, you should
swab that with alcohol.
I might get an infection.
I'll return when this
has taken effect.
Then we'll talk.
I'm looking forward to it.
Now, why are you helping
these raving psychotics?
Because they're very
well-funded raving psychotics,
And I'm getting a lot of money.
What, you think I care
about their cause?
Or yours?
Not at all.
You're damaged goods, lady.
Did you tell her
about us, harry?
There is no "us,"
you psychopathic bitch.
Oh, sure.
You say that now.
Thanks for everything, harry.
Wasn't bad while it lasted.
Let's go.
You two stay here.
There was nothing.
I swear.
What did they give you?
Sodium amytal,
or some other truth agent.
It makes you tell the truth?
Is it working?
Ask me a question that
I normally would lie to.
Are we going to die?
Yep.
I'd say it's working.
They'll shoot us in the head
Or they'll torture us to death
Or they'll
leave us here until...
Harry!
How long have you
been a spy, harry?
17 years.
Have you ever killed anyone?
Yeah, but they were all bad.
Is there anything
you want to tell me
Before we start?
Yeah.
I'm going to kill you
pretty soon.
I see.
How, exactly?
First, I'm going to use you
as a human shield,
Then I'm going to kill
this guard over there
With the patterson troika
on the table,
And then I was thinking
about breaking your neck.
And what makes you think
you can do all that?
You know my handcuffs?
I picked them.
Let's get out of here.
Come on!
Harry!
Drop the gun!
Honey...
Next time, duck.
Let's go.
I married rambo.
What are they doing?
It is done.
In 90 minutes...
A ball of holy fire...
Will light up the skies.
To show to the world...
That we speak the truth.
We are set on our course.
No force can stop us now.
Blah, blah, blah, blah.
If we're on an island,
Why are they using trucks?
We must be in the florida keys.
The overseas highway
Connects the islands
to the mainland.
There's no borders, no customs.
They can go anywhere
in the u.S.
There's nothing to stop them.
Just us.
Here.
Take this.
Oh, shit.
Shoot!
Shit!
Yes!
Let's go.
Oh. My condolences
to the widow.
We may need the hostage.
O.K., let's go, suzy homemaker.
Hurry up!
Just get her in the car.
Let's get going.
I thought this looked
like your work.
Let's go. I'll brief
you in the air.
You're welcome.
Let's go.
Let's get out of here!
Let's go. Come on!
You tell that son of a bitch
This is a bright boy alert.
I repeat. A bright boy alert.
This is not a drill.
Do you understand that?
All right. Hold on.
Put me through
to the white house.
No, see, the minimum safe
distance is 12 miles.
Get the marine patrol
in right away.
I want coast guard
and sheriff's department.
Anyone that cannot make that
distance, get 'em out by air.
You've got exactly 34 minutes.
I can get two marine corps
harriers here in 11 minutes.
Get them. I'll brief
them on the way in.
Send 'em in right away.
Would you like one?
I want state police driving
through the streets
On their damn loudspeakers.
Hey, here they come.
Lime 0-1's got a tally on three
trucks eastbound on the bridge.
Roger, lime 0-1.
You're clear to engage.
Break loose.
In hot with guns.
Let's get some.
O.K., marines,
time to kick ass.
Recommend using your mavericks
to take out the bridge.
Roger that. Lime flight,
switch mavericks.
Two.
Missiles won't set off
those nukes, will they?
Negative. That's a
negative, lime 0-1.
Fire.
Bingo!
Good shooting, marines.
I'll kill you!
It's out of control.
Somebody capped the driver.
Bitch!
Like one?
How about two?
Get down to the limo!
Come on. Take it down. Let's go!
Get down!
Take it down. All right.
Harry?
Harry!
The bridge is out!
What?
I can't hear you!
Oh, god!
The bridge is out!
Harry!
Harry, come on!
Come on!
Speed up a little bit.
Get down there.
Come on! Hurry!
Hurry, harry!
Grab my hand!
Come back! Harry!
To the right.
I can't reach! Get lower!
Lower! Harry!
Let's go! Hold on!
Hold on really tight.
Harry!
Oh, come back!
Pull up, pull up, pull up!
Grab my hand! Do it!
I can't reach!
Come down!
God, harry!
Harry!
Oh... Shit.
Come on, baby.
Ooooaaaaahhhh!
Hold on!
I got you!
Hold on tight!
Harry!
O.K., let's get
this thing on the ground.
All right, let's get these
aircraft on the ground, gentlemen.
We got a nuclear bomb
going off in about one minute.
Any minute now. Go, go, go.
Come here. Give me a bullhorn.
All right, everybody,
it's show time.
Do not look at the flash.
Do not look at the flash!
Get down over there.
We should be safe here.
Tch, tch.
This is the wrong finger.
Harry.
Hey, harry! Come here!
Go to work.
O.K.
Bye.
Listen, aziz's copter
landed about 20 minutes ago
Atop a high-rise
in downtown miami.
He rendezvoused with about
a dozen faction members,
And they're holed up
on the 20th floor.
I got s.W.A.T there. The
cops cordoned off the area.
Harry, they got a hostage.
It's dana.
What do you mean? My dana?
I'm real sorry, harry.
I guess he grabbed her in
the middle of the night.
We just found out.
But don't worry.
We'll get her back.
I've already got a guy inside.
Harry, listen.
We're going to get her back.
Here we go.
Excuse me, captain. I got
to borrow your plane.
Excuse me, sir?
You were cleared to give us
total cooperation, right?
Yes, sir, but...
That comes directly
from the president
Of these United States.
Bu-but, sir, you have to
sign for this aircraft.
I'll sign. You got a pen?
You take care of it.
It has been 10 years
Since you've been behind
the wheel of one of these?
I break it, they can
take it out of my pay.
Harry, listen, we got
a guy in the inside.
Got to move back,
everybody. Go!
All right, everybody,
it's going to be all right!
He's got hundreds of hours
in the harriers there.
He's a little rusty,
But that's a trademark
tasker takeoff.
It's like riding a bike.
You never forget, really.
We might want to seek shelter!
Sorry.
The streets are filled
with running people
As police try to
evacuate the buildings.
Appear to be shooting
wildly into the air.
These seem to be warning shots.
So far, they have not
fired at us or police.
This apparently
is the same group
Which just detonated a nuclear
bomb in the florida keys.
Crimson jihad will rain fire
On one major
u. S. City each week
Until our demands are met.
This tape was released
to the media
Just minutes
after the terrorists...
I have to go to the bathroom.
We'll repeat the tape
in just a few moments
Following this live
report from the scene.
Hold your fire. Hold your fire!
The video crew
you wanted is here!
Send them!
They're coming in.
They're unarmed.
Come on. Let's go.
Go.
This is a communique
from crimson jihad.
You have seen a
demonstration of our power.
Do not force us
to destroy this city,
And do not use
force against us.
I... we... are all prepared to die.
With one turn of that key...
2 million of your people
will die...
Instantly!
What key?
That key!
Who's taken the key?
Shoot her!
Holy shit!
Unit 1 to unit 7.
Give me a situation report.
1 to 7. Give me a sit rep.
Faisal, do you copy?
7 here. 21st floor secure.
About 12 faction members
on the 20th floor.
No hostages there.
Where's dana?
She's on the roof.
Give me that address again.
You shoot me, this'll fall!
Stay where you are!
Give me the key!
I'll drop it, I swear!
No!
Give me the key.
Come on, child.
You don't want to die, do you?
Give me the key...
And you won't get hurt.
I give you my word!
No way, you wacko!
Help me!
Please don't come any closer!
Help me! Help me!
Somebody!
Help me!
Help me, please!
Help me, somebody!
Help!
Dana, jump down!
Come on down. Jump down.
Dad?
Help me!
Daddy!
Daddy! Come back!
Daddy, get me down!
Daddy!
Dana, jump!
Jump! Daddy will catch you!
Jump!
I can't!
Hold on. Hold on!
Daddy, don't you
let me fall, please!
Daddy!
Dana, I got you!
I'm slipping!
No, dana!
Help me! I'm gonna fall!
Hold my hand!
Hold on tight, honey.
Yaah!
Daddy, he's behind you!
Take this plane down... now!
I'll kill her!
Take it down... now!
My god, do something!
You're fired.
It's o.K.
Dana.
Honey.
It's over.
Hi, pumpkin.
Just seconds after
the jet landed,
The unidentified pilot
was escorted from the scene
By federal agents.
Though it is unclear
which agency was responsible
For the operation which
ended the terrorist threat
So dramatically
early this morning,
We've learned
from miami police...
1...
No, wait. Stop.
Just begin. Now watch.
It's not just 1.
O.K., ready? Do it properly.
1...
1, 2, 3, 4, 1, 2, 3, 4,
I declare a thumb war.
5, 6, 7, 8, 5, 6, 7, 8,
Try to keep
your thumb straight.
Stop it!
You don't... wait!
I got you.
Just listen.
Listen to the rules.
1, 2...
No, just start over.
Hello?
We're on.
Yes? Go ahead.
Colonel, how nice
to see you again.
Good evening.
Who's that?
What's the scoop, team?
You see your contact yet?
Haven't seen him yet.
But I see somebody I'd
like to say hello to.
Let me pour you more champagne.
I got to keep up
the waiter bit.
These stakeouts can be tricky.
You never know when
things might explode
Into a life or death situation.
If it gets rough, stay
low until it's over,
And I'll contact you later.
Maybe you should...
So, we meet again, carlos.
Yuh!
Honey, I'm just going to
do him right here, o.K.?
Go for it.
Oh, god.
Fear is not an option.
Dance?
Tango. Oh, no.
Oh, shit. Here we go.
Harry, helen...
Guys?
Come on, now. Let's
not get distracted.
Get to work.
All right, guys. Come on.
Getting pretty
serious in there.
I'd be serious
if I was in there.
Don't ignore me, harry.
That's rude.
All right, guys. Come on.
National security,
guys. Come on.
Life or death.
Harry.
Helen?
Helen, I was always
on your side.
I was always there
for you, helen.
You know what? I'm sick
of being in the van.
You guys are going to be
in the van next time.
I been in the van
for 15 years, harry.
♪ It's getting near dawn ♪
♪ And the light
falls on tired eyes ♪
♪ I'll soon be with you,
my love ♪
♪ And give you my
dawn surprise ♪
♪ I'll stay with you,
darling, now ♪
♪ I'll stay with you ♪
♪ Till my seeds are dried up ♪
♪ Hey ♪
♪ I've been waiting so long ♪
♪ I've been waiting ♪
♪ So long ♪
♪ To be where I'm going ♪
♪ In the sunshine
of your love ♪
♪ Oh, yeah ♪