HEY, MOM!
WHAT IS IT, SON?
LISTEN. IF A FISH
WEIGHS 10 POUNDS
AND HIS BODY WEIGHS
TWICE AS MUCH AS HIS HEAD
AND HIS HEAD WEIGHS
TWICE AS MUCH AS HIS TAIL,
HOW MUCH WOULD
HIS TAIL WEIGH?
HOW DO I KNOW?
SAY, YOU GO ON WITH YOUR LESSONS
AND STOP ASKING ME RIDDLES.
IT AIN'T A RIDDLE.
THAT'S MY ALGEBRA.
AW, IT'S TOO HARD.
I CAN'T GET IT!
STOP TALKING LIKE THAT!
SAY, LISTEN.
IF YOU'RE GONNA GIVE UP AS EASY AS THAT,
YOU AIN'T NEVER GONNA AMOUNT TO NOTHING.
DON'T YOU WANT
TO BE A SUCCESS?
SURE, BUT... BUT CAN'T
A FELLA BE A SUCCESS
WITHOUT KNOWING HOW MUCH
A FISH'S TAIL WEIGHS?
HMM! CAN'T LEARN NOTHING
FROM A FISH'S TAIL.
HA! FISH'S TAIL.
HERE. GIVE ME
YOUR BOOK OF KNOWLEDGE.
ANNIE, CAN I HAVE
50 CENTS?
NO, YOU CAN'T
HAVE 50 CENTS.
NOW..."WHO WAS SOCRA-
CRITES-CRA-"
SOCRATES.
YEAH, SOCRATES.
"ANSWER: A GREEK
PHILOSOPHEER."
CAN I HAVE 25 CENTS?
NO, YOU CAN'T
HAVE 25 CENTS.
WHY CAN'T I HAVE
25 CENTS?
BECAUSE I AIN'T GOT
25 CENTS!
THAT'S WHY YOU CAN'T
HAVE 25 CENTS.
NOW..."WHAT WAS THE
FIRST WONDER OF THE WORLD?
ANSWER: THE PYR-I-MIDS
OF EGYPT."
CAN I HAVE 10 CENTS?
NO, YOU CAN'T
HAVE 10 CENTS.
THERE'S MORE WAYS TO KILL THE
CAT THAN KISSING IT TO DEATH.
AW, THAT'S
ENOUGH, MOM.
I DON'T WANT
TO LEARN ANY MORE.
LISTEN, SON, YOU GOT
TO KNOW WHAT'S GOING ON.
NOW, "WHAT DID
SAMSON SLAY THE-"
WHAT'S THIS WORD?
I CAN'T SEE IT
WITHOUT MY GLASSES.
"PHILISTINES."
OH, YEAH.
PHILISTINES.
LOOKED LIKE
PHILIPPINES TO ME-
"WHAT DID SAMSON SLAY
THE...THE STINES WITH?
ANSWER: THE JAWBONE
OF AN ASS."
NOW. NOW SEE IF YOU
KNOW THE ANSWERS.
"WHO WAS SO-CRAT-EES?"
SOCRATES?
OH, YES. SOCRATES.
YES. SOCRATES.
HE WAS
A GREEK PHILOSOPHER.
MM-HMM.
"WHAT WAS THE FIRST
WONDER OF THE WORLD?"
THE PYRAMIDS
OF EGYPT.
OH, I WISH YOUR FATHER
HAD YOUR BRAINS, SON.
NOW..."WHAT DID SAMSON SLAY THE STI
- THE STINES WITH?"
WELL? COME ON.
"WHAT DID SAMSON SLAY
THE SLILISTINES WITH?"
GEE, MOM,
I'VE FORGOTTEN.
WHAT'S THIS?
YOUR CHIN, MOM.
THAT'S THE JAWBONE
OF AN ASS.
THERE AIN'T ENOUGH OF THAT
HAWSER LEFT TO MAKE A NECKTIE.
AW, SHUT YOUR TRAP,
WILL YOU?
ANNIE WILL KILL YOU,
SURE AS ANYTHING.
WE DON'T USE IT
NO MORE,
AND ANNIE WON'T MISS IT,
UNLESS YOU TELL HER.
HERE. GET A HOLD
OF THAT.
GIVE US A HAND.
PEEL OFF ABOUT 25 FEET.
THIS 25 MAKES ABOUT 1,800 FEET
OF HAWSER YOU DRUNK UP, TERRY.
YOU WAIT TILL
ANNIE CATCHES YOU.
OH, SHUT YOUR MOUTH
AND GIVE ME THE DOUGH.
THIS IS FOR
THE SKIPPERS RELIEF FUND.
HA HA HA!
WHERE ARE YOU GOING,
HORSE FACE?
OUT AFTER
BUSINESS, ANNIE.
CAN I GIVE YOU A TOW?
ANYTIME THE FIREFLY SHOWS
HER HEELS TO THE NARCISSUS,
I'LL SWALLOW THE ANCHOR.
YOU'RE NOT GOING OUT AFTER
THAT SCHOONER, RED SEVERN!
ANYTIME YOU BUTT INTO MY BUSINESS,
I'LL JERK THE SKELETON OUT OF YOU.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN,
YOUR BUSINESS?
THE FELLA THAT GETS
THERE FIRST GETS THE JOB,
AND IT'S
GONNA BE ME!
NOT UNLESS YOU SPROUT
FINS AND A TAIL.
WHAT'S THE MATTER
WITH YOUR DAD, ALEC?
AW, HE'S SICK.
MY GOODNESS!
AGAIN?
AW, IT'S NONE OF YOUR BUSINESS, IS IT?
OK, SAM.
LET HER GO.
WE GOT A LOAD.
ALL RIGHT, PETE.
CAST OFF!
CAST OFF.
GEE, POP, WE'VE GOT
A GOOD HEAD START,
HAVEN'T WE?
AND WE'LL
KEEP HER THAT WAY.
GEE, MOM, DON'T LET SEVERN
GET THE LAUGH ON US, WILL YOU?
HUH! THE OLD NARCISSUS AIN'T
NEVER LET US DOWN YET, HAS SHE?
WOULD YOU LIKE
TO BORROW OUR ENGINES?
HA!
WOULD YOU LIKE TO BORROW
A SMACK IN THE POUT?
GEE, LOOK, MOM. WE'RE
CLOSING UP ON THEM.
SURE. WE'LL SHOW HIM HE
CAN'T SNEAK OUT ON US-
THE SNAKE IN THE BUSH!
BY GOLLY,
IT'S A RACE, MISTER.
THESE PUGET SOUND TUGBOATS
SURE GO AFTER THE BUSINESS.
WELL, MAY THE
BEST MAN WIN.
WE'RE BEATING YOU!
BLEAH!
LOOK AT THEM, MOM.
STILL COMING.
DON'T THEY KNOW THEY
MIGHT AS WELL GO HOME?
THEM AS LAUGHS FIRST SOMETIMES
CACKLES UP THE WRONG PANTS LEG.
HA HA HA!
YEE-HOO!
HEY, PETE,
TAKE THE WHEEL.
TERRY!
WHERE IS
THAT MISPLACED SWAB?
TERRY!
WAS THAT YOU
HOLLERING, ANNIE?
CAN'T YOU SEE WE'RE
COMING UP ON THE SCHOONER?
MAKE A SHOT LINE FAST
WITH THAT HAWSER
AND GET READY
TO HEAVE IT.
NO, NO,
NOT THAT ONE!
THE OLD ROPE HAWSER.
IT'S QUICKER TO HANDLE.
YES, BUT YOU DON'T
WANT TO USE THAT.
SAY, NOW, YOU GET READY TO
HEAVE IT, AND DON'T YOU MISS.
BUT, ANNIE, HOW DO YOU KNOW THE RATS
AIN'T BEEN GNAWING ON THIS HAWSER?
WHAT WOULD THE RATS
BE WANTING WITH A HAWSER
WITH A BIG PIECE OF CHEESE
LIKE YOU ABOARD?
HEAVE IT, STUPID!
HEAVE IT!
OK, ANNIE!
GOOD WORK, TERRY.
AH!
WHAT'S HAPPENED
TO THE HAWSER?
YOU...
OH!
HEY! SHE LOST
THE TOW.
GOT THAT SHOT LINE
READY?
ALL SET, RED.
NEVER MIND, MOM.
MIND? HMM!
WHY SHOULD
I MIND?
WASN'T SUCH A BIG-PAYING JOB NOHOW.
BABOON!
THAT'S THE THIRD JOB
WE'VE LOST THIS WEEK.
MOM, I'M NOT GOING BACK
TO SCHOOL NEXT YEAR.
WHAT ARE YOU
TALKING ABOUT?
OF COURSE YOU'RE GOING BACK TO SCHOOL.
HMM! YOU AIN'T
GONNA BE A QUITTER.
NO, BUT POP'S ALWAYS
DOING THINGS LIKE THAT,
AND IF HE WON'T LOOK
AFTER YOU, WELL-
NOW, WAIT A MINUTE.
YOUR POP LOOKS
AFTER ME ALL RIGHT.
WHY, HE'S THE FINEST, BIGGEST
HUSBAND A WOMAN EVER HAD,
CUSS HIM.
SAY-HA HA!
I ONLY HOPE YOU'RE HALF
AS GOOD A SAILOR AS HE IS
WHEN YOU GROW UP.
TOUGH LUCK, ANNIE.
OH, IT'S ALL
IN THE DAY.
ALL RIGHT, PETE.
MOM?
HMM?
WE GOT TO TALK
THIS THING OVER.
I'M NOT GOING
BACK TO SCHOOL.
OH, OF COURSE YOU'RE
GOING BACK TO SCHOOL.
YOU GOT TO GET
ED-I-CATED. HMM!
TUGBOAT'S NO PLACE FOR A BOY WHO
WANTS TO BE CAPTAIN OF A BIG LINER.
SAY, SUPPOSE YOU WAS
CAPTAIN OF A BIG LINER
AND SOME SWELL PEOPLE
WOULD COME ABOARD,
LIKE A PROFESSOR OR A BANK
PRESIDENT OR A CORONER,
AND THEY SHOULD TALK
TO YOU IN...IN LATIN,
AND YOU WOULDN'T KNOW WHAT
THEY WAS TALKING ABOUT.
WHY, THAT'D BE TERRIBLE.
THEY MIGHT
ASK YOU TO HAVE
SOME PATTY FOZE GRAZ (PÖTÉ DE
FOIE GRAS) OR CAVIOX (CAVIAR)
OR SOMETHING, AND YOU WOULDN'T
KNOW WHAT THEY WAS SAYING.
HMM! OH, NO. YOU GOT
TO GO BACK TO SCHOOL.
BUT, MOM,
DON'T YOU SEE-
YOU KNOW, YOUR PAPA AND ME IS
GONNA BUST WIDE-OPEN WITH PRIDE
THE DAY WE SEE YOU GO
KERSLOPPING PAST THE OLD NARCISSUS
ON THE BRIDGE
OF YOUR OWN LINER.
HA HA HA! OOH!
BET YOU EVEN TRY TO RUN
US DOWN, YOU BIG SMARTY.
HA HA HA! HMM.
ALEC BRENNAN,
MASTER MARINER.
THERE SHE IS!
WHERE?
OH, THERE SHE IS!
OW! OH!
WHAT'S THE MATTER
WITH YOU?
YOU'RE ON MY FOOT,
YOU BIG OX.
OH. OH, LOOK.
LOOK!
HA HA!
THIS IS A GREAT DAY FOR
US BRENNANS, AIN'T IT?
OH! OH, GO ON AWAY,
YOU BIG APE.
HA HA! KISS LIKE
A WET PAINTBRUSH.
SAY, KISSING ME
- PEOPLE WILL THINK YOU'VE BEEN DRINKING.
WHO, ME?
OHH! NOW, IS THAT
A NICE THING TO SAY
ABOUT A MAN WHO AIN'T
HAD A DRINK IN 5 WEEKS?
ALEC WILL BE THAT PROUD.
WAIT UNTIL HE HEARS THAT I AIN'T GONNA
TAKE ANOTHER DRINK AS LONG AS I LIVE.
YOU KNOW, IT TAKES A BIG MAN
TO STOP COLD JUST LIKE THAT.
AIN'T IT THE TRUTH?
GO ON, HUSTLE. PUT ON A CLEAN
SHIRT AND YOUR OTHER PANTS.
OH, NO, ANNIE. THIS IS
ALL RIGHT. I DON'T WANT-
GO ON, NOW.
DO AS I TELL YOU.
OH...
WHEN YOU'RE DRESSED UP, THERE
AIN'T NO HOOLIGAN ON THE WATERFRONT
LOOKS AS GRAND
AS YOU DO.
SAY, MANY'S THE TIME
I'VE HEARD ALEC SAY,
"WHEN POP'S
IN HIS SUNDAY BEST,
YOU COULD ALMOST
MISTAKE HIM FOR A GENT."
HE ALWAYS WAS A BOY
TO TAKE NOTICE. YEAH.
YEAH.
BUT WE GOT TO
DO HIM UP PROUD,
SHOW HIM WHERE HE GETS
HIS GOOD LOOKS FROM, HUH?
AND ME ON THE WATER WAGON. HOT DOGGIE!
GO ON. GO ON.
GET ALL SPROUSED UP,
AND DON'T TALK
SO MUCH ABOUT IT.
I WAS JUST WONDERING WHAT
YOUR FATHER'S GOING TO SAY.
AFTER ALL, YOU ARE
PATRICIA SEVERN AND-
AND MY FATHER WILL PROBABLY
THANK HIS LUCKY STARS
THAT IF HIS PRECIOUS
DAUGHTER HAD TO FALL IN LOVE,
SHE'D PICK
THE CRACK CAPTAIN
OF HIS WHOLE
DARN STEAMSHIP LINE.
THAT'S PROBABLY MOTHER.
SHE'S COMING UP
THE SOUND TO MEET ME.
DOESN'T SOUND MUCH LIKE
HER VOICE AS I REMEMBER IT.
HA HA! SILLY.
SHE'S A GRAND PERSON,
ISN'T SHE, ALEC?
THEY DON'T COME
ANY BETTER.
I WANT TO MAKE THINGS EASIER
FOR HER NOW THAT I CAN.
SHE DOESN'T KNOW IT YET, BUT DOCKING
MY SHIP TODAY IS HER LAST JOB.
COME ON OUT,
AND WE'LL WHISTLE HELLO.
ALL RIGHT.
ALEC BRENNAN,
MASTER MARINER.
STAND BY TO HEAVE THE LINE,
PETE, WHEN I BRING HER ABOUT.
NICE WORK, EH?
YOU BET.
WHAT A BOAT,
ANNIE!
TAKE THE WHEEL, SHIF'LESS.
I CAN'T WAIT TO SEE HIM!
AYE, AYE, SKIPPER.
I DON'T SEE MY FATHER.
HEY, TERRY,
ANNIE SAYS HURRY UP.
I'M LOOKING
FOR MY HAT.
LOST MY HAT.
TERRY!
TERRY?
WHERE ARE YOU?
HUH?
TERRY...YOU'RE DRUNK.
ANNIE, YOU'RE RIGHT.
AS MAYOR OF SECOMA
AND SPEAKING FOR THE THOUSANDS
OF APPRECIATIVE CITIZENS
OF OUR GREAT COMMONWEALTH,
I AM INDEED PROUD TO WELCOME
THE BEAUTIFUL GLACIER QUEEN,
FLAGSHIP OF
THE SEVERN LINE, TO...
NOW, THEN, STAND BACK!
NO SHOVING!
WELL, ANNIE!
WELL, IF THE BOY'S OWN
MOTHER AIN'T GOT THE RIGHT-
COME RIGHT THROUGH HERE.
STAND ASIDE THERE!
IT IS ALSO
OUR OPPORTUNITY TO DO HONOR
TO A BOY WHO GREW UP
FROM CHILDHOOD
RIGHT HERE
ON OUR WATERFRONT,
A HOMEGROWN
PRODUCT OF SECOMA
AND WHOM SECOMA
MAY BE WELL PROUD OF
AS THE YOUNGEST CAPTAIN THAT
EVER SAILED THESE WATERS-
CAPTAIN ALEC BRENNAN!
I, UH...
I DON'T KNOW
HOW TO THANK YOU.
IT...IT'S ALL SO UNEXPECTED
AND MOST EMBARRASSING.
OF COURSE, A SHIP'S MASTER
IS AN UNIMPORTANT COG-
COG! OH,
HE AIN'T NO COG!
MOM!
ALEC!
OH, ALEC!
OH, MOM!
YOU KNOW, HE ALWAYS
WAS BASHFUL.
THIS IS MY MOTHER
MRS. BRENNAN, SIR.
HOW DO YOU DO,
MA'AM?
YOUR HONOR?
YOU MUST BE VERY PROUD
OF YOUR SON.
AM I? HA!
THERE AIN'T A BETTER CAPTAIN
BETWEEN VANCOUVER AND SAN PEDRO!
BARRING HIS FATHER.
OH, HELLO, RED,
YOU OLD PINK-EYED
SNOOZER, YOU!
MOM!
OH, ME AND HIM'S
OLD FRIENDS.
ONLY SEEMS
LIKE YESTERDAY
WE'RE FIGHTING EACH
OTHER FOR BUSINESS,
HIM ON HIS TUG
AND ME ON MINE.
GLAD TO
SEE YOU, ANNIE.
THANK YOU, RED!
HA HA!
HOW DO YOU DO,
MRS. BRENNAN?
OH, MY, OH, MY!
IF YOU AIN'T GROWED UP
TO BE AS PRETTY
AS A PICTURE!
ENOUGH BEAUS, I BET,
TO MAKE A STANDING ARMY.
NO ARMY FOR ME,
MRS. BRENNAN.
I'M TERRIBLY PARTIAL
TO THE FLEET.
WHERE'S TERRY?
TER-UH...OH...
HA HA!
TERRY? OH, YOU KNOW HE WAS
SO FILLED FULL OF EN-THOO-SISM
THAT HE FORGOT THERE WAS A LADDER
FROM THE WHEELHOUSE TO THE DECK,
AND HE BRAVELY SUFFERED
THE SPRAIN OF A LEG,
BUT-BUT, UM,
HE SENT HIS REGARDS,
AND HE HOPES THAT
YOU AND YOUR HONOR
WILL COME DOWN TO THE TUG
AND HAVE MESS OF TEA SOMETIME.
THANK YOU
VERY MUCH, ANNIE.
I HOPE THAT INVITATION
INCLUDED ME, MRS. BRENNAN.
IT DID.
WHEN CAN I COME?
OH, AIN'T YOU
THE NICE GIRL!
WE THINK SO.
HOW ABOUT
TOMORROW NIGHT?
YOU CAN COME DOWN AND HAVE
SUPPER ON THE NARCISSUS.
SAY, I PROMISE YOU AS
FINE A MESS OF SAUERKRAUT
AS EVER YOU HEAVED
BELOW HATCHES.
WILL MR. BRENNAN BE
ALL RIGHT BY THEN?
OH, YEAH...
OH, YES, HE'LL BE ALL-
IT'S ONLY A TEMPORARY
CONCUSSION, YOU KNOW.
OH, OF COURSE,
FOR THE PRESENT,
HE'S CONFIDED
TO HIS CABIN.
BUT HE'LL
BE ALL RIGHT.
YOU KNOW, THE STRAIN
AND THE FALLING...
OF THE STRAIN...
PHEW!
CHOW?
YEAH?
WHERE'S THAT
RUM FLAVORING?
HERE,
MRS. BRENNAN.
WE'LL JUST PUT THAT AWAY SO MR. TERRY
WON'T MAKE ANY FOXY PAWS (FAUX PAS).
YOU KNOW, CHOW, SOMEDAY HE'S
GONNA TAKE A DRINK OF WATER
THINKING IT'S GIN, AND
HE'S GONNA DIE OF THE SHOCK.
HA HA HA!
OH, DEAR.
HUH! OH, MY.
TERRY!
TERRY?
WHOO-HOO!
SAY, WHAT'S WRONG
WITH YOU?
WHAT HAVE YOU
BEEN UP TO?
AW, I WAS JUST LOOKING TO SEE
IF THERE'S ANY WORMS IN THE NUTS.
HMM...THINK YOU'RE A
NUTPECKER, I SUPPOSE.
OH, I WAS JUST-
YOU WERE JUST UP TO
SOME OF YOUR OLD TRICKS!
COME ON-
UP WITH YOUR HANDS.
OH!
UP WITH YOUR HANDS!
SAW ANYTHING
LIKE YOU IN MY LIFE.
OH, HONEY,
DON'T DO THAT.
I AIN'T GOT NO BOTTLE.
YOU'RE ALWAYS FEELING MY-
WELL, ALL RIGHT,
ALL RIGHT.
WHERE'S YOUR COLLAR?
THIS AIN'T
NO FORMAL PARTY.
I SUPPOSE THAT'S THE REASON YOU
AIN'T WASHED YOUR HANDS NOR NOTHING.
PEOPLE WILL THINK
YOU GOT GLOVES ON!
GO ON-IN THE SINK.
DO I HAVE TO WASH?
IN THE SINK.
I HOPE TO GOODNESS YOU
DON'T STOP UP THE DRAINAGE.
GO ON!
AW, I DON'T WANT
TO WASH ANYMORE.
NO. YOU NEVER DO!
COME ON, NOW.
GET TO IT.
WON'T HURT YOU A BIT.
YOU KNOW, HONEY?
HMM?
SOAP'S A GREAT THING,
AIN'T IT?
YEAH, ESPECIALLY
FOR WHAT AILS YOU.
HA HA HA!
OH!
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
SAY, WILL YOU KEEP YOUR
DIRTY PAWS OUT OF THAT!
BUT I WANT TO-
CAN'T YOU WAIT FOR DINNER
LIKE THE REST OF US?
YEAH, BUT LISTEN,
HONEY, I-
MOM, WHERE ARE YOU?
HURRY UP! QUICK!
THERE THEY ARE.
YEAH, BUT LISTEN,
ANNIE, I GOT TO-
GET OUT OF HERE
AND GET YOURSELF DRESSED.
NOW, HURRY UP. YOUR NECK
LOOKS AS NAKED AS A TURKEY.
GO ON, NOW.
AND PUT YOUR COLLAR ON!
OH, MOM,
WHERE ARE YOU?
I'M HERE, KID.
HELLO, MOM.
HELLO!
HELLO, BOY.
WELL, IS SHE HERE
WITH YOU?
YES-OUT ON THE DECK.
OH, THAT'S GRAND.
SAY, CHOW, WE'LL EAT JUST AS
SOON AS CAPTAIN TERRY'S READY.
ALL RIGHT,
MRS. BRENNAN.
MOM, I WANT TO SPEAK
TO YOU ALONE A MINUTE.
YEAH?
POP ALL RIGHT?
AW, HE'S AS DRY
AS A SALT MACKEREL.
I HOPE SO.
WELL, I SAW
TO THAT PERSONALLY.
THERE AIN'T NOTHING STRONGER
THAN ROOSTERSHEER SAUCE
THAT HE CAN GET AT!
OH, MISS PAT!
HOW NICE OF YOU
TO COME DOWN WITH ALEC.
YOU MUST BE AWFULLY PROUD
OF YOUR SON, MRS. BRENNAN-
A SHIP'S CAPTAIN
AT HIS AGE!
OH, I KNEW
HE'D MAKE IT.
THE MINUTE HE SET
HIS MIND ON IT,
IT WAS
AS GOOD AS DID.
HELLO, ALEC.
HELLO, POP.
HELLO, MISS PAT.
HELLO.
IT'S NICE WEATHER
WE'RE HAVING,
EVEN IF I DO SAY SO,
AS PERHAPS SHOULDN'T.
YES, IT'S DELIGHTFUL
DOWN HERE.
I ALWAYS
LOVE THE WATER.
YEAH. SOME PEOPLE DO.
WELL, THE COMBUSTIBLES
WILL BE GETTING ALL COLD.
ANNIE, I WAS
JUST THINKING.
MAYBE IT WOULDN'T BE NICE TO
ENTERTAIN COMPANY ON A DIRTY OLD TUG.
BY ANY CHANCE, ARE YOU TALKING
ABOUT THE NARCISSUS, HUH?
OH, NO. SHE'S ALL RIGHT
AS FAR AS TUGS GO,
BUT I KNOW A SWELL
CHOP SUEY JOINT.
THEY'VE GOT
A MECHANICAL PIANO
AND THE SWELLEST
GUMBO SOUP.
OH, HO! GUMBO AIN'T A SOUP, YOU NINNY.
GUMBO'S A ELEPHANT.
WELL,
IT'S A SWELL PLACE.
THAT'S SWEET
OF YOU, CAPTAIN,
BUT I'M ALL SET
FOR THAT SAUERKRAUT.
THERE YOU ARE, NOW.
IF IT'S GOOD ENOUGH
FOR THE COMPANY,
I GUESS IT'S GOOD ENOUGH
FOR YOU TO EAT ON, AIN'T IT?
COME ON. LET'S GO.
ANNIE, ANNIE,
WAIT A-
DON'T SHOVE.
I WANT TO WHISPER
SOMETHING.
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
DON'T YOU THINK
I BETTER GO ASHORE
AND GET SOME ICE CREAM TO
KIND OF LIVEN UP THE PARTY?
MM-HMM... THE WIND IS
OFF THE BREWERY AGAIN.
OH, I JUST HAD
A LITTLE BIT, LIKE THAT.
OH...
YOU COULDN'T EVEN SMELL IT
IF YOU WASN'T EXPECTING IT.
COME ON, MOM!
YEAH, ALEC.
I'M COMING.
COME ON!
I'LL BE RIGHT THERE
IN A MINUTE.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
I GOT TO GO, ANNIE.
OH, WHY DO YOU LEAVE
EVERYTHING FOR THE LAST MINUTE?
HA HA!
I KNOW.
OH! OH, ALEX,
YOU SIT THERE,
AND PAT WILL SIT
RIGHT NEXT TO YOU.
YEAH.
THAT'S RIGHT.
THERE WE ARE.
AH!
THIS IS EVEN NICER
THAN I REMEMBERED.
NO WONDER YOU LOVE
THE NARCISSUS.
WELL, BARRING A SLIGHT WHEEZE
IN HER BOILER TUBES,
SHE'S AS GOOD AS THE DAY
I COME ABOARD.
THERE'S NOTHING LIKE
THE WATERFRONT.
THERE'S SO MUCH
ATMOSPHERE.
OH, THAT'S THE
TIDE FLATS YOU SMELL.
THAT'S THE SAUERKRAUT
YOU SMELL, YOU MEAN.
WAIT TILL
YOU TASTE IT.
OH, THIS LOOKS
TOO GOOD TO EAT.
I READ IN THE PAPER ONLY YESTERDAY ABOUT
A MAN WHO ATE SPARERIBS AND SAUERKRAUT
AND HE NEVER KNEW
WHAT HIT HIM.
WHY?
WHAT HAPPENED?
POMAINE (PTOMAINE)
POISON.
IT'S A FACT.
IT HAPPENS EVERY DAY.
THEY DIE OFF
JUST LIKE FLIES.
WELL, MR. BRENNAN,
ARE YOU GOING TO TAKE A
CHANCE WITH THE REST OF US?
FUNNY. I AIN'T HUNGRY,
SWEETHEART.
SAY, HAVE YOU BEEN SNEAKING
AROUND PINCHING GRUB AGAIN?
OH, NO.
HONEST, ANNIE.
I JUST AIN'T HUNGRY,
THAT'S ALL.
YOU AIN'T?
PAT, GO TO IT.
I'M JUST DYING TO SEE THE
EXPRESSION ON YOUR FACE
WHEN YOU TAKE
THE FIRST SWALLOW.
MM-HMM.
HOPE I DONE
MYSELF JUSTICE.
WELL, HOW IS IT?
I, UH...
I NEVER TASTED ANYTHING QUITE LIKE IT.
OH! TUCK IT
INTO YOU, KID.
TELL ME IF I DONE
MYSELF JUSTICE.
YOU KNOW, THIS IS
ALEX'S FAVORITE DISH.
FACT, I CAN HARDLY WAIT
TO GET AT IT MYSELF.
HA HA HA!
MOM, WHAT'S IN THIS?
IT'S AWFUL!
IT'S KIND OF SLIPPERY,
ISN'T IT?
GEE, I CAN'T
UNDERSTAND IT.
I NEVER LET MY FOOT SLIP
ON MY SAUERKRAUT BEFORE.
OH!
YOU GREAT BIG GALOOT!
THIS IS ALL YOUR DOING.
WELL, I WOULD HAVE TOLD YOU IF
YOU'D KEPT YOUR BIG BAZOO CLOSED.
TOLD ME WHAT?
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
DON'T YOU-
WHAT DID YOU DO?
POP!
DON'T YOU HIT, NOW.
HA! WELL, THE IDEA OF US BAWLING
EACH OTHER OUT IN FRONT OF MISS PAT.
YOU KNOW, IT'S A MISHAP THAT
MIGHT HAVE HAPPENED TO ANYBODY.
OF COURSE.
WHILE YOU WERE CARRYING
ON LIKE A SEA COW,
IT WOULD HAVE ALL
PASSED OFF AS PLEASANT-
YES! JUST AS
PLEASANT AS-
WELL, IT'S ALL RIGHT.
WE'LL SEND CHOW DOWN FOR A COUPLE
OF POUNDS OF PORK CHOPS, YOU KNOW?
THEY'RE MORE
DELICATE ANYHOW.
IT COULDN'T HAVE BEEN
ANYTHING I ATE, NO DOUBT.
WELL...I'LL TAKE PAT
TO A RESTAURANT.
LET'S ALL GO UPTOWN, BECAUSE
IT'S SO MUCH EASIER ANYWAY.
YEAH.
NO.
YOU AND PAT RUN ALONG.
YOU KNOW, I KIND OF LOST
MY APPETITE...SOMEHOW.
COME ON, PAT.
ALL RIGHT.
GOOD-BYE,
MRS. BRENNAN.
GOOD-BYE, PAT.
GOOD-BYE, MOM.
GOOD-BYE, KID.
GOOD-BYE! COME BACK
AGAIN SOON. HEH HEH!
GOOD-BYE, ALEC!
GOOD-BYE!
I CALL IT EXTRAVAGANT,
TAKING A BUS JUST
TO GO A HALF A MILE.
OH, IT'S ALL RIGHT. WE DON'T
GO OUT IN SOCIETY EVERY DAY.
THAT'S
ALL RIGHT, TOO.
HOW ARE YOU?
OH! OH, ANNIE,
MY SHOES.
HA! I TOLD YOU TO WEAR
THE BOX THEY COME IN.
OH, YEAH.
WHERE TO?
PIER 62.
GLACIER QUEEN.
THANK YOU TOO MUCH.
STOP THE BUS!
WAIT A MINUTE.
WHAT'S THE MATTER,
LADY?
MY HUSBAND'S CAR SICK.
WE'LL WALK THE REST
OF THE WAY.
PHEW!
WAIT!
WAIT A MINUTE.
WAIT A MINUTE!
GEE, MOM,
YOU LOOK SWELL.
DO I?
$25 MARKED DOWN
TO $9.98,
ON ACCOUNT OF IT
BEING A OFF-SIZE.
HA HA HA!
I DIDN'T WANT
TO SHAME YOU, ALEC.
OH, MOM.
I WOULDN'T BE ASHAMED OF YOU
IF YOU CAME IN A CANVAS BAG.
HA HA HA!
SAY, DON'T YOUR FATHER
LOOK GRAND?
HE SURE DOES.
HE'S THAT
GRATEFUL TO YOU
FOR NOT HOLDING THE
SAUERKRAUT AGAINST HIM.
YOU KNOW, HE AIN'T TOUCHED
A DROP TO DRINK SINCE.
LIABLE TO TAKE THE PLEDGE
AT ANY MINUTE NOW.
GOOD.
WILL YOU
HAVE SOME, MOM?
OH, THANK YOU.
YOU'RE WELCOME.
THANK YOU.
MMM.
THERE'S
SOMETHING IN IT.
WHERE'S YOUR FATHER?
WHAT DID YOU DO THEN?
WELL-AHEM-
I GRABBED MY KNIFE,
AND I JUMPED OVERBOARD,
AND I CAUGHT THAT SHARK
RIGHT IN THE GILLS.
AND SAVED
THE MAN'S LIFE?
BARRING HIM GETTING
HIS HEAD CHEWED OFF,
I GOT THERE JUST IN TIME.
JUST THINK OF YOU
BEING SUCH A HERO
AND TELLING US
NOTHING ABOUT IT!
OH, I DON'T LIKE
TO TALK ABOUT-HA!
AHH...
OH, TERRY!
OH, I'M THAT THIRSTY!
MMM!
TONGUE'S HANGING DOWN SO
LOW, ALMOST COULD STEP ON IT.
HEH HEH. THIS IS
MY LITTLE WIFE.
YEAH.
I'LL BET YOU'RE PROUD
OF YOUR HUSBAND.
HE'S SUCH A BRAVE MAN.
YEAH. BEEN TELLING YOU HOW HE
CAPTURED THEM PIRATES SINGLE-HANDED?
NO. HE WAS TELLING
US HOW HE RESCUED
THE MAN
FROM THE SHARK.
OH, THAT'S
A NEW ONE ON ME.
DO YOU MIND IF I BORROW
THE HERO A MINUTE?
NO.
OF COURSE NOT.
GOOD-BYE,
CAPTAIN BRENNAN.
GOOD-BYE.
NOW, TERRY, DON'T YOU
TOUCH A TASTE OF THIS.
WOULDN'T DO YOU
NO GOOD ANYHOW.
OH, ANNIE,
YOU DON'T TRUST ME-
A MAN OF HONOR
LIKE I AM?
WELL, HOW ARE YOU
ENJOYING THE PARTY?
OH, SAY,
YOU SURE DID
DO YOURSELF PROUD ON THIS THING, RED.
THANK YOU, TERRY.
ANNIE, YOU AND I SHOULD HAVE
A DANCE FOR OLD TIMES' SAKE.
OH, GO ON. YOU DON'T WANT TO
TOW AN OLD BARGE LIKE ME AROUND.
OH, SURE!
GO ON!
I AIN'T GOT A JEALOUS BONE IN MY HEAD.
GO ON.
WELL, I GUESS WE CAN'T NONE
OF US GET HURT VERY BAD.
COME ON, RED.
HEY, RED,
WHAT ARE YOU
TRYING TO DO-
THE RUMPLE
WITH ME? HUH!
I'LL BE BACK
IN A MINUTE.
THANK YOU,
TERRY, DEAR.
NONE FOR YOU,
TERRY?
OH, NO!
DIDN'T YOU KNOW?
TERRY ISN'T DRINKING
ANYTHING ANYMORE.
ARE YOU,
TERRY, DEAR?
UH, NO.
SAY, TERRY, COME ON.
LET'S HAVE A DANCE.
OH, ANNIE,
I CAN'T DANCE.
NOW, HEAR, YOU'VE JUST
BEEN HAVING TOO GOOD A TIME.
I WANT YOU
TO DANCE WITH ME.
OH, MY FEET HURT.
NOW, NEVER MIND
YOUR FEET.
YOU JUST...DANCE.
WE'RE GONNA-HA HA!
HOLD THAT FOR ME.
FUNNY-HA HA!
I'M DYING TO DANCE.
OH, ANNIE,
I CAN'T DANCE!
I KNOW, BUT I'M
JUST DYING TO DANCE.
WELL,
I DON'T DANCE.
YOU NEVER WANT TO DO
ANYTHING I WANT TO DO.
KEEP OFF MY BUNION,
WILL YOU?
YOU KNOW, ANNIE,
YOU SEEM TO HAVE
MORE FEET THAN MOST PEOPLE.
HA HA HA!
SAY, IF I WASN'T SURE
YOU WAS DANCING,
I'D PASTE YOU FOR WHAT
YOU'RE DOING TO ME.
OH, WHAT
DO YOU MEAN?
OH, YOU DANCE AS IF
YOU HAD SNOWSHOES ON.
I WISH I DID HAVE.
MY FEET'S KILLING ME.
LET'S STOP. COME ON.
MY FEET HURT. THEY BURN.
MY FEET HURT,
I TELL YOU.
OH, MY GOODNESS, THE MINUTE
I GO TO HAVE A GOOD TIME,
SOMETHING HAPPENS
TO YOU.
I WANT TO DANCE.
WELL, THEY BURN. THEY-
THANK YOU.
NO, YOU DON'T.
NO, YOU DON'T!
OH, PLEASE, ANNIE.
JUST ONE.
NO!
NOT ONE!
PARDON ME.
I HAVEN'T HAD THE
PLEASURE, MRS. BRENNAN,
BUT I'M YOUR SON'S SECOND OFFICER.
MAY I HAVE
THIS DANCE?
OH! YEAH, I'D...
BE DELIGHTED TO-
UH...
LET-LET'S TRY THAT
SWEDISH MOVEMENT AGAIN.
MY FAULT,
MRS. BRENNAN.
NO, NOT AT ALL.
NO, SON.
YOU DANCE LIKE
SAINT VITUS HIMSELF.
THANK YOU.
PHEW! IT'S GETTING
HOT IN HERE, ISN'T IT?
YES.
AHEM. THERE'S
A SEA COMING UP.
I DON'T THINK SO,
MRS. BRENNAN.
THERE'S A SEA
COMING UP.
I DISTINCTLY
FELT IT.
YOU DON'T SEE MY
HUSBAND ANYPLACE, DO YOU?
NO, I DON'T,
MRS. BRENNAN.
I'VE GOT TO GO AND SEE WHAT HE'S DOING
AND TELL
HIM NOT TO.
TERRY!
OH, I JUMPED ON AN ALLIGATOR,
THOUGHT IT WAS A HORSE
WITH A HOOPDAH DEE DAH
TERRY!
TERRY...
BREATHE.
I KNEW IT.
YOU'RE DRUNK.
WHAT IS IT? WHAT'S
THE MATTER? IS IT A FIRE?
NO, MOM.
HELLO, ALEC.
OH, HELLO, POP.
HELLO, PAT.
HELLO, MR. BRENNAN.
WON'T YOU COME
ABOARD, MISS PAT?
NO. WE'VE ONLY
GOT A MOMENT.
GO ON, ALEC. TELL THEM
THE GLAD NEWS.
HAVE YOU BEEN MADE
FLEET COMMODORE, MAYBE?
HA HA! NO, BUT I'VE
GOTTEN DAD A JOB.
A JOB?
FOR ME?
YES. MR. SEVERN NEEDS
A WHARF MANAGER-
YOU KNOW, SOMEONE WHO'LL
KEEP THINGS IN SHAPE
FOR THE ARRIVAL AND
DEPARTURE OF HIS SHIPS.
WOULD I BE A BOSS?
YOU'LL BE IN SOLE CHARGE
OF BOTH PIERS AND THEIR STAFFS.
OF COURSE,
IT MEANS HARD WORK,
BUT IT'LL BE A GREAT
CHANCE FOR YOU, DAD.
WILL I HAVE TO
WEAR A COLLAR?
SAY, I'LL GET YOU A HORSE
COLLAR IF YOU AIN'T CAREFUL.
MOM, YOU CAN SELL THE
NARCISSUS AND LIVE ASHORE.
I'LL GET YOU
A NICE APARTMENT.
YOU MEAN LEAVE
THE NARCISSUS?
OH, MOM, YOU WORK
TOO HARD.
I WANT TO MAKE THINGS
EASIER FOR YOU.
OH, GO ON.
YOU TALK AS IF YOU
THOUGHT I WAS A OLD WOMAN.
IF YOU WON'T DO IT FOR YOUR
OWN SAKE, DO IT FOR MINE.
WHAT'LL PEOPLE SAY-
WITH A JOB LIKE MINE
AND MY MOTHER SLAVING HER
LIFE OUT ON AN OLD TOWBOAT?
WELL, OF COURSE, I-
I WOULDN'T WANT THEM TO
MISJUDGE YOU ON ACCOUNT OF ME.
AND BESIDES, MOM, IT'LL
BE A GREAT CHANCE FOR DAD.
YOU CAN'T TELL. THE RESPONSIBILITY
MIGHT MAKE A NEW MAN OF HIM.
YEAH?
WELL, IT'S ALL
KIND OF SUDDEN.
OF COURSE, IF YOU THINK
IT WAS GOOD FOR YOUR DAD-
IT WILL BE.
UH-HUH.
IT'S ALL SET, PAT!
GOOD!
DAD, YOU GET DRESSED
AND GO UP AND SEE
SEVERN RIGHT AWAY.
HE'S EXPECTING YOU.
NOW, HURRY UP!
I'VE GOT TO GO
BACK UPTOWN.
AND, MOM, SEE THAT HE'S
CLEANED UP, WON'T YOU?
OH, I'LL SCRUB HIM WITH
SANDPAPER AND STEEL WOOL
TILL HE SHINES
LIKE A CRANKSHAFT.
FINE.
BYE, MOM.
GOOD-BYE!
BYE, POP.
BYE-BYE, ALEC.
YOU TELL SEVERN I'LL
BE UP THERE, ALL RIGHT.
ALL RIGHT.
GOOD-BYE.
BYE!
GOOD-BYE,
PAT!
GOOD-BYE!
SAY, YOU GO AND SWAB
YOUR CARCASS.
DON'T WASH YOUR FACE
WITH YOUR HAT ON!
OH, WELL.
23 YEARS IS TOO LONG TO
LIVE IN ANY ONE PLACE ANYHOW.
BE GLAD TO GET AWAY FROM
YOU, YOU DIRTY OLD...TUB.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING,
ANNIE-TALKING TO YOURSELF?
AW, LISTEN, HONEY.
ALEC IS RIGHT.
HIM BEING THE CAPTAIN OF A BIG LINER
AND ME THE MASTER
OF THE DOCKS-
WHY, WE GOT TO KIND
OF LIVE IN STYLE,
WHERE IT'S ALWAYS
HIGH TIDE.
YEAH, AND HIGH RENT.
AW, YOU-YOU AIN'T GONNA
BE MISSING THE NARCISSUS?
ME? MISSING
THIS PIECE OF SEAWEED?
COURSE I AIN'T.
ONE THING OUGHT
TO CHEER YOU UP.
WHAT?
WELL, YOU-YOU'LL
ALWAYS HAVE ME.
HUH! YEAH.
OH, YOU OLD FOOL, YOU.
AHOY THERE, PARTNER.
OH, HELLO,
TERRY.
I WAS
WONDERING WHEN-
WHY, YOU'VE BEEN
DRINKING.
OH, YOU GOT ME
ALL WRONG.
I JUST BEEN WETTING
ME NEW COMMISSION.
MR. SEVERN WANTED
TO SEE ME, MISS BLAKE.
WELL...YOUR FATHER'S IN WITH
HIM NOW, CAPTAIN BRENNAN.
MY FATHER?
OH, THAT'S FINE!
I GUESS I CAN
GO RIGHT IN, THEN.
IF YOUR OWN KINFOLKS
CAN'T SHARE WITH YOU
IN THE STEAMSHIP
BUSINESS,
I DON'T KNOW WHO CAN,
YOU OLD SEA MULE.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND YOU
MAKING THIS A FAMILY AFFAIR.
MY SON ALEX IS GOING
TO MARRY YOUR-
HEY, POP!
HELLO, ALEX. I WAS
JUST DISCUSSING WITH-
I'M SORRY ABOUT THIS,
MR. SEVERN.
WHEN YOUR FATHER LEAVES,
I'D LIKE TO TALK WITH YOU.
WHY, CERTAINLY, SIR.
I'LL SEE YOU
ON THE TUG IN AN HOUR.
ALL RIGHT, ALEC.
SO LONG, RED!
YOU NEED ME,
YOU SEND FOR ME,
AND I'LL BE
RIGHT THERE.
HEY, CHOW-HERE.
HERE. YOU CAN
HAVE THIS, TOO.
YEAH, AND ALL THESE.
NOW THAT CAPTAIN BRENNAN'S
GONNA GET A SWELL JOB ASHORE,
HE'S GONNA GET ME
A GRAND FLAT TO LIVE IN.
WILL HE KEEP SOBER?
WHY, HE HASN'T HAD
ANYTHING TO DRINK-
SAY, WHO ARE YOU TO
TALK LIKE THAT? THE IDEA!
HE AIN'T HAD A DROP
TO DRINK IN-
IMAGINE HIM
TRYING TO TELL ME
WHERE TO GET OFF AT!
ME! HA! HIM TO-
TELLING ME WHERE
TO GET OFF AT.
HIM!
ME-WHY, I WOULDN'T SPIT
ON HIM IF HE WAS ON FIRE.
SO...YOU LOST THE JOB.
AW, ANNIE, IT WAS WAY
BENEATH MY DIGNITY.
HMM.
AND YOU SHOULD HAVE SEE'D
THE WAY HE TREATED ME-
ME! JUST LIKE
I WAS DIRT.
HMM. YOU HAD
WORDS WITH HIM?
WELL, HE THOUGHT
HE KNOWED IT ALL,
AND I SHOWED HIM
HE DIDN'T.
I SAYS,
"RED SEVERN-
YEAH. HIM BEING
YOUR BOY'S BOSS
WASN'T ENOUGH TO MUZZLE
YOUR UGLY LIP, WAS IT?
WELL, I WASN'T GONNA LET
HIM MAKE A MONKEY OUT OF ME!
NO! YOU'RE THAT ALREADY!
STOP, ANNIE!
ANNIE!
OH!
MOM!
WHY, MOM,
WHAT'S HAPPENED?
MOM! ARE YOU HURT?
WHAT HAPPENED, MOM?
I- I-I WAS JUST REASONING
WITH YOUR FATHER.
YOU STRUCK HER!
OH, NO!
YOUR FATHER NEVER
STRUCK ME IN HIS LIFE-
EXCEPTING IN SELF-DEFENSE.
YOU GO AND PUT YOUR HEAD
UNDER THE PUMP.
MOM, LISTEN, I'VE BEEN
PATIENT FOR A LONG TIME,
BUT I'M NOT GOING TO LET YOU PUT
UP FOR ANOTHER MINUTE WITH THAT-
NOW, ALEC... IT'S YOUR
FATHER YOU'RE SPEAKING OF.
OH, I'M NOT
FORGETTING THAT, MOM.
BUT FATHER OR NO FATHER, I'VE
DONE EVERYTHING I CAN FOR HIM,
AND FOR YEARS NOW,
YOU'VE SLAVED AND WORRIED
AND MADE EXCUSES FOR HIM-
I KNOW, I KNOW. YOU'RE UPSET
BECAUSE HE LOST HIS JOB.
I DON'T BLAME YOU
A BIT, BUT-
NO "BUTS"
THIS TIME, MOM.
LISTEN, YOU'RE GOING
TO GET OUT OF HERE.
YOU MEAN...LEAVE HIM?
YES!
WHY, SON,
I'M MARRIED TO HIM.
OH, MOM, I'LL TAKE
THE BEST OF CARE OF YOU.
I'LL DO EVERYTHING
I CAN TO MAKE YOU HAPPY.
OH, I KNOW, BUT WHAT
WOULD HE DO WITHOUT ME?
WELL, COULD HE DO ANY
WORSE THAN HE DOES WITH YOU?
MOM, IT MIGHT BE THE BEST
THING IN THE WORLD FOR HIM.
IT MIGHT BE THE ONE THING
THAT WOULD STRAIGHTEN HIM OUT-
YOU KNOW,
A JOLT LIKE THAT.
YEAH. I'VE TRIED
EVERYTHING ELSE, HAVEN'T I?
HONEST, I DON'T SEE
HOW I COULD DO IT.
OH, MOM,
YOU'VE GOT TO.
ANNIE?
I WAS JUST-JUST THINKING
THAT MAYBE IF YOU'D GO OVER
AND KIND OF APOLOGIZE
TO RED SEVERN FOR MY-
THAT'LL BE ENOUGH
OUT OF YOU!
MOM'S LEAVING HERE
TONIGHT FOR GOOD.
SHE SHOULD HAVE
LEFT YOU YEARS AGO.
NOW THAT I CAN, I'M
GOING TO GIVE HER THE REST
AND COMFORT THAT SHE'S
NEVER HAD WITH YOU.
AW...
I - I KNOW I AIN'T BEEN SO GOOD AS A HUSBAND
AND A FATHER, BUT...
AND I DON'T
BLAME ANNIE,
BUT SHE WOULDN'T BE HAPPY ANYPLACE
ELSE BUT HERE ON THE NARCISSUS.
YOU KNOW THAT.
SO...I'LL GO.
TERRY!
WHERE WOULD YOU GO?
OH...
IT DON'T MAKE
NO DIFFERENCE-
AN OLD SOAK LIKE ME.
YOU'RE NOT AN OLD SOAK!
WHEN YOU'RE SOBER, THERE AIN'T A
FINER MAN ON THE WHOLE WATERFRONT.
MOM, DON'T YOU SEE? HE'S
JUST TRYING TO GET AROUND YOU.
THAT'S RIGHT.
GO ON AND ABUSE ME.
I WON'T HOLD IT
AGIN YOU.
I'LL GO.
I AIN'T GOT NO PLACE
TO GO TO, BUT I'LL GO.
AW, YOU CAN'T GO!
NOW, MOM-
ALEC, IT'S USELESS.
IT'S USELESS, I SAY!
TERRY, YOU'RE A GOOD-FOR-NOTHING
SEAGOING COCKROACH,
BUT YOUR PLACE
IS HERE WITH ME.
HE NEEDS ME, ALEC.
I'M NOT GOING TO PUT UP
WITH THIS FOR ANOTHER MINUTE.
HE'LL END UP IN THE GUTTER
AND DRAG YOU THERE WITH HIM.
NOW, MOM, LISTEN. HE'S MAKING
A FOOL OF YOU RIGHT NOW,
THE WAY HE HAS ALL YOUR
LIFE-PLAYED ON YOUR SYMPATHIES.
MOM,
MY MIND'S MADE UP.
DON'T SAY THAT, SON.
YOU CAN STAY HERE WITH
HIM OR COME WITH ME,
BUT YOU CAN'T
HAVE US BOTH.
OH! YOU DON'T MEAN THAT!
I NEVER MEANT ANYTHING
SO MUCH IN MY LIFE.
OHH!
ME OWN SON
AND ME OWN WIFE.
TURNED AGAINST ME, HUH?
ALL RIGHT.
HE CAN DO LOTS MORE
FOR YOU THAN I-
KEEP OUT OF THIS,
YOU RUM-
ALEC!
AW, LISTEN, ANNIE.
I'M GONNA BE
A CHANGED MAN.
YOU'LL BE PROUD
OF ME.
WHY, I AIN'T GONNA DRINK
ANOTHER DROP AS LONG AS I LIVE.
HONEST, I AIN'T.
ALEC...
CAN YOU SEE HIM, HONEY?
YEAH.
UH, GIVE ME A LOOK.
APPEARS TO ME HE'S GOT
THINNER IN THE LAST 3 MONTHS.
I BET HE AIN'T
EATING RIGHT.
HE DOES LOOK KIND
OF PEAKED, DON'T HE?
YEAH. I BET HE AIN'T
WEARING HIS THICK UNDERWEAR,
NOW THAT HE AIN'T
GOT ME TO NAG HIM.
SAY, HE'LL CATCH HIS DEATH
OF COLD IN THAT NORTHERN RUN,
SURE AS SHOOTING.
YOU KNOW, UH,
I- I KIND OF-
KIND OF THOUGHT
HE'D COME TO SEE US
WHEN HE WAS
IN THE HARBOR THIS TIME.
YEAH. WELL... NICE TO SEE
HIM COMING AND...GOING.
YEAH.
ANNIE!
HELLO, SAM!
GOT THEM
REPAIRS MADE?
BEST I CAN.
THERE AIN'T NO WAY TO REALLY REPAIR
THEM BOILERS EXCEPT TO GET NEW ONES.
WELL, TRY WHISTLING.
PERHAPS SOME NEW ONES
WILL COME DANCING ON BOARD.
AW, YOU NEEDN'T
GET SORE, ANNIE.
IT AIN'T MY FAULT THAT ANY TUGBOAT
IN THIS HARBOR CAN SHOW US ITS STERN
OR THAT WE'RE LOSING BUSINESS
RIGHT AND LEFT AND HINDWAYS!
WE GOT BAD BUSINESS
AND WE GOT
BAD BOILERS
BECAUSE WE GOT
BAD BUSINESS.
JUST LIKE A
MERRY-GO-ROUND, AIN'T IT?
YEAH. YEAH.
YOU KNOW, ANNIE?
WHAT?
IF I ONLY HAD
SOME MONEY SOMEWHERE,
I'D GO RIGHT OUT AND BUY
NEW BOILERS JUST LIKE THAT.
SURE YOU WOULD.
IT JUST SEEMS TO ME
LIVING ON THIS WATERFRONT
ALL THE YEARS WE HAVE,
THERE OUGHT TO BE
SOMEBODY ASHORE
LET US HAVE SOME MONEY FOR NEW BOILERS.
THEY SURE SHOULD.
YOU KNOW...
WHAT?
I'M GOING ASHORE,
AND I'M-
AH, NO.
NO, YOU'RE NOT.
HA HA! YOU'RE GONNA
STAY HERE.
I'LL GO ASHORE.
ALL RIGHT, ANNIE.
AND IF THERE'S A
TUGBOAT TOW COMES ALONG,
IT'LL HAVE TO WAIT
TILL I GET BACK.
ALL RIGHT, HONEY.
YOU GO ASHORE.
HEH HEH!
GO ON AWAY,
YOU BIG SLOB.
BUT, ANNIE, IT'D COST 2,000
OR 3,000 TO OVERHAUL HER.
AFTER ALL, THE NARCISSUS IS40 YEARS OLD.
THAT'S NOTHING.
I'M MORE THAN THAT MYSELF.
ANNIE, TERRY IS
A BAD RISK,
AND YOU-WELL, YOU'RE
NOT AS YOUNG AS YOU WERE.
I'M AS GOOD A TUGBOAT
MAN AS EVER I WERE!
YOUR BOY IS RIGHT.
YOU OUGHT TO RETIRE,
TAKE IT EASY.
I WANT YOU TO KNOW,
JOHN WILCOX,
THE NARCISSUS NOR ME AIN'T
READY FOR THE BONEYARD YET!
HUH! RETIRE, INDEED!
SAY, I AIN'T ASKING
YOU NO FAVORS-
JUST A PLAIN BUSINESS DEAL
WITH THE USUAL INTEREST.
HUH! SAY, IF YOU AIN'T WILLING TO
ACCOMMODATE ME, THERE'S OTHERS THAT IS.
I NEVER ASKED A FAVOR
FROM NOBODY IN MY LIFE.
I'M SORRY, MRS...
BRENNAN. TUGBOAT
ANNIE BRENNAN.
MRS. BRENNAN-
HMM.
TUGBOATS ARE ENTIRELY
OUT OF OUR LINE.
HMM.
HAVE YOU
ANY OTHER SECURITY?
NO. THE NARCISSUS IS THE
ONLY THING I GOT IN THE WORLD-
IN THE WAY
OF SECURITY.
WE CAN'T AFFORD
THE RISK.
SORRY.
WELL, I'M SORRY, TOO.
HELLO, ANNIE.
HOW ARE YOU?
OH, KIND OF
LA-DI-DA, MEYER.
HOW ARE THINGS
WITH YOU?
I CERTAINLY
CAN'T COMPLAIN!
HMM! THAT'S GOOD.
SAY, MIND IF...
I COME IN AWHILE?
NO. WISH
YOU WOULD.
THERE'S SOMETHING
I'D LIKE TO SAY TO YOU.
WELL, YOU TELL ME
ALL ABOUT IT.
YOU'RE NOT WORRIED
ABOUT ANYTHING?
ME, WORRIED? NO!
WELL, THAT'S GOOD.
CAPTAIN BRENNAN.
HUH?
AW, SURE.
WHERE?
RIGHT AWAY, RIGHT AWAY.
SURE.
COME ON, SHIF'LESS.
WE GOT TO PICK UP A LUMBER
BARGE DOWN AT THE POOL.
TELL SAM
TO CAST OFF.
BUT ANNIE AIN'T HERE!
WHAT OF IT? DON'T I DRAW AS MUCH
WATER ON THIS TUG AS ANNIE DOES?
LET'S GO. COME ON.
SHOVE OFF.
HMM! GEE...
THANK YOU, MEYER.
THAT'S MIGHTY FINE OF YOU.
DON'T THANK ME,
ANNIE.
LENDING MONEY TO THE BEST
TUGBOAT SKIPPER ON THE COAST
IS A GOOD
BUSINESS INVESTMENT.
OH, I KNOW, BUT-
GOOD LUCK.
JUST THE SAME, I...
I THANK YOU.
AND BLESS YOU.
YOU OLD RAT-WHISKERED
SON OF A GUN, YOU!
HA HA HA!
DROP IN ANYTIME, ANNIE.
OH, I JUMPED ON AN ALLIGATOR
THOUGHT IT WAS A HORSE
WITH A HOO-DA, HOO-DA-LA-DA
HEY, SHIF'LESS!
YEAH?
LOOK AT THAT BOX
OFF THE BOW, WILL YOU?
WHAT IS IT?
LOOKS LIKE A BOX OF HOOCH
SOME RUMRUNNER DROPPED.
GET THE POLE, AND I'LL
SWING HER ABOUT.
SURE!
TERRY, PULL HER
AROUND MORE, WILL YOU?
IT'S TERRY BRENNAN! WHAT'S
THE DRUNKEN FOOL TRYING TO DO?
HARD ASTERN!
HEY!
LOOK OUT THERE!
WHAT...
HEY!
LOOKS LIKE THE NARCISSUS
RAMMEDTHE FERRYBOAT!
IT'S TOO BAD,
ANNIE.
GENTLEMEN,
I ASSURE YOU,
YOU WOULD NEVER GET A CHANCE LIKE THIS
IF IT WEREN'T THAT THIS BEAUTIFUL TUGBOAT,
WITH YEARS OF HONEST WORK
AHEAD OF HER,
HAD TO BE SOLD TO SATISFY THE JUDGMENT
OF THE FERRY COMPANY AGAINST HER.
COME ON, NOW.
WHO'LL GIVE ME A REAL OFFER?
2,500.
AW, COME ON, FOLKS.
YOU KNOW SHE'S WORTH DOUBLE THAT
IN THE BONE PILE.
WHO'LL GIVE ME 3,000?
3,000.
$3,000 I'VE GOT!
NOW...NOW, WHO'LL
GIVE ME 3,200?
WHO'LL GIVE ME 3,200 FOR...
FOR THIS NOBLE VESSEL?
COME ON, FOLKS!
THAT'S ONLY A PALTRY $200 MORE.
COME ON! WHO'LL GIVE ME
THE 3,200?
3,200.
3,200 I GOT!
NOW, THEN, WHO'LL GIVE ME
THE 35? THE 35? 35?
GOT THE 32.
WHO'LL GIVE ME THE 35?
DO I HEAR THE 35?
NO? GOING AT 3,200.
GOING ONCE...
GOING TWICE...
THIRD AND LAST CALL!
ARE YOU ALL THROUGH?
SOLD TO THE GENTLEMAN
RIGHT HERE FOR 3,200.
STEP RIGHT UP
AND GET YOUR PAPERS.
GOSH, ANNIE, DO YOU KNOW
WHO BOUGHT THE NARCISSUS?
REYNOLDS, WHAT'S GOT THE
GARBAGE CONCESSION FOR THE CITY.
YOU DON'T SUPPOSE HE'D BE USING
THE NARCISSUS TO TOW THE SCOWS WITH?
TOWING GARBAGE.
HELLO, ANNIE.
I JUST BOUGHT
YOUR NARCISSUS.
YES, I KNOW.
WELL, WHAT ARE YOU GOING
TO DO NOW, ANNIE?
GET A JOB.
THERE AIN'T MANY JOBS ALONG THE WATERFRONT,
AND YOU AIN'T AS YOUNG AS YOU WAS.
WELL...I'LL GET SOMETHING.
BESIDES...
I GOT TERRY TO HELP ME.
SAY, HOW'D YOU LIKE TO STAY
ON AS SKIPPER OF THE NARCISSUS?
THAT'S NICE OF YOU.
YEAH. WHEN YOU GOT AN OLD,
BROKEN-DOWN TUG LIKE THAT,
IT'S GOOD BUSINESS TO HAVE SOMEBODY
AT THE WHEEL THAT KNOWS HER TRICKS.
COURSE, IT AIN'T MUCH MONEY,
BUT STILL, IT'S A JOB.
YEAH...
IT'S A JOB.
KIND OF SILLY TO GET A NEW
SKIPPER FOR THE NARCISSUS
AFTER SHE AND ME HAS...
BEEN RIDING THE WAVES
SO LONG TOGETHER.
GOOD.
THEN IT'S A DEAL.
MM-HMM.
IT'S A DEAL.
ALL RIGHT. I'LL SEE YOU
UP AT THE OFFICE.
WELL, TERRY, COME ON.
WE GOT A GOOD JOB...
YOU AND ME.
NARCISSUS! AHOY!
PATTY!
CAN I COME ABOARD?
WHY, SURE!
COME ON.
MY GOODNESS,
BUT THIS IS A PLEASANT SURPRISE.
WELL, PATTY!
OH!
NOW, DON'T YOU GET UP.
OH, DEAR.
COME ON.
SIT DOWN HERE.
NO, NO, NO. YOU SIT
THERE. I'LL SIT HERE.
OH, MY, BUT IT'S
GOOD TO SEE YOU.
I HOPE YOU DIDN'T MIND
MY COMING ABOARD.
MIND? WHY, YOU'RE AS WELCOME AS A
GRASSHOPPER IN A CRATE OF TURKEYS.
THANK YOU.
HOW'S YOUR HUSBAND?
OH, TERRY?
OH, WHY, HE-
HE'S IN BED WITH A BAD
CASE OF BROWN CRITTERS.
AW. THAT'S A SHAME.
AND HOW ARE YOU?
ME? OH, I'M ALL...
WELL, TO TELL YOU
THE TRUTH...
THE GARBAGE HAS GOT ME.
YOU KNOW, HALF THE TIME, I CAN'T
KEEP ANYTHING ON MY STOMACH-
EXCEPT MY HANDS.
HA HA HA!
OH, THAT'S A SHAME.
YOU KNOW, I'M AFRAID YOU'RE NEVER
GOING TO GET USED TO IT DOWN HERE.
NO, NO.
A SMELL'S A SMELL,
AND...HA HA!
AFTER 6 WEEKS,
A ONION IS A ONION.
MY! THAT'S A PRETTY DRESS YOU GOT ON.
LIKE IT?
YES. I'LL HAVE TO BE
GOING SHOPPING MYSELF
PRETTY SOON, I GUESS.
MY CLOTHES ARE...
KIND OF BAD.
HOW IS HE?
HE MISSES YOU DREADFULLY,
BUT YOU KNOW HOW STUBBORN HE IS.
OH, NO,
HE'S NOT STUBBORN.
HE'S JUST
STRONG-MINDED.
NOT STUBBORN.
WHATEVER IT IS, THE MINUTE
HE GETS BACK FROM THIS TRIP,
I'M GOING TO MAKE HIM
COME RIGHT DOWN HERE.
NO, NO. NO, I DON'T
WANT YOU TO DO THAT.
IF HE COMES DOWN HERE, I WANT
HIM TO COME OUT OF HIS OWN HEAD.
IT'S NICE
OF YOU, THOUGH,
TO WANT TO PATCH
THINGS UP FOR US.
YOU KNOW, EVEN WHEN
HE WAS A LITTLE SHAVER,
I USED TO WONDER WHAT KIND
OF A GIRL HE'D PICK ON.
I BET HE WAS
A CUTE ONE.
HE WAS THE COMELIEST LITTLE
THING THAT EVER WET HIS MAINSAILS.
I GOT HIS PICTURE
RIGHT HERE.
OH. CAN I SEE IT?
YEAH, SURE.
SEE THOSE DENTS?
THAT'S WHERE HE CUT
HIS EYETEETH.
THERE.
OH, WHAT A DOLL!
MM-HMM.
WELL, BARRING
SPROUTING WHISKERS
AND WEARING
MORE CLOTHES,
HE HASN'T CHANGED
A GREAT DEAL, HAS HE?
NO, NO, NOT A GREAT DEAL.
WOULD YOU LIKE
TO HAVE IT?
OH, I'D GIVE IT
TO YOU IN A MINUTE.
OH, I'D LOVE IT, IF
YOU'RE SURE YOU DON'T MIND.
I DON'T MIND.
I'VE CARRIED HIM FOR
NIGH ONTO 25 YEARS.
IT'S...
IT'S PAST TIME I WAS
GIVING HIM UP.
I'M GOING TO TRY
AND MAKE THE NEXT 25 YEARS
JUST AS FULL OF LOVE AND
DEVOTION AS YOU'VE MADE THE PAST.
MY ONE PRAYER...
IS FOR HIS HAPPINESS.
THE GLACIER QUEEN
OUGHT TO BE ALONG SOON.
SHE'LL BE DOCKING
IN ABOUT TWO HOURS.
YEAH,
PERHAPS IT HAS.
SAY...
BLOWING A GALE BEFORE
THE NIGHT'S OUT.
HOPE ALEC WILL
HAVE SENSE-
AW, DON'T WORRY ABOUT HIM.
SMART KID, THAT.
HMM.
I HOPE WE DUMP
THIS STUFF AND GET IN.
I'LL TELL YOU, IT DOESN'T
LOOK SO GOOD TO ME.
HEY, ANNIE.
WELL? WHAT'S
NIBBLING YOU, SAM?
IT'S THEM LEAKY
BOILER TUBES AGAIN, ANNIE.
THEY GET TO SPITTING LIKE
A LOT OF FIGHTING TOMCATS.
WE GOT TO DO
SOMETHING ABOUT THEM!
WELL, WE CAN'T DO
ANYTHING NOW.
IT'S AN AWFUL JOB TRYING TO
KEEP UP THAT STEAM PRESSURE.
IT WE RUN INTO HEAVY
WEATHER OUTSIDE THE CAPE-
OH, WE AIN'T GOING
OUTSIDE TONIGHT.
I'M GONNA DUMP THIS
STUFF AT POINT ADAMS.
IT DON'T LOOK GOOD, TERRY.
YOU GO AND TAKE THE WHEEL.
LET SHIF'LESS GO DOWN AND
HELP SAM WITH THE FIRE.
OH, ANNIE, I DON'T-
ON YOUR WAY, FISH EARS,
ON YOUR WAY.
COPPER REEF,
BEARING SOU' BY EAST.
ONE HALF SOUTH, SIR.
VERY GOOD.
WE'LL BRING HER BROAD ON
THE BEAM BEFORE WE SWING.
I'LL BE GLAD WHEN WE'RE
INSIDE, THE WAY IT'S BLOWING UP.
YOU'RE RIGHT, SIR.
AND THE WAY THAT
GLASS IS DROPPING.
WHAT'S THAT?
LOOKS LIKE WE DROPPED A
PROPELLER. GET THE MEN ON STANDBY!
YES, SIR!
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
WHAT'S HAPPENED?
NO CAUSE FOR ALARM.
BROKE A TAIL SHAFT.
AND THE WIND
AND TIDES SETTING UP...
CHIEF ENGINEER SAID
BROKEN TAIL SHAFT.
YES, I KNOW. TELL
SPARKS I WANT TO SEE HIM.
YES, SIR!
WE'LL BE BLOWN ON COPPER REEF
INSIDE OF AN HOUR.
IS THERE NOTHING
WE CAN DO, SIR?
TAKE OUT ALL HANDS AND GET
THE PASSENGERS INTO LIFE BELTS.
MAKE SURE
THERE'S NO PANIC.
DON'T HESITATE!
YES, SIR!
HERE'S SPARKS NOW.
SEND OUT AN S.O.S.
I'LL GIVE YOU THE DOPE ON OUR
POSITION, WIND AND TIDE, AND SO ON.
HURRY UP.
YES, SIR.
TELL THEM TO HURRY!
HAVEN'T SEEN ANYTHING OF THE
GLACIER QUEENYET, HAVEYOU?
WELL, I'M WORRIED.
THERE'S SOMETHING WRONG.
WELL, IF SHE DOESN'T
HEAVE IN SIGHT SOON,
I'M GONNA CUT
THEM SCOWS LOOSE
AND START OUT
TO HUNT HER.
BUT, ANNIE,
YOU CAN'T. I MEAN-
HE'S RIGHT, ANNIE.
IF WE GO OUTSIDE THERE,
WE'LL FOUNDER.
ALEC'S JUST IDLING ALONG.
OH, YEAH. JUST PICKING
DAISIES, I SUPPOSE.
TERRY!
IT'S A DISTRESS SIGNAL-
OFF COPPER REEF.
DO YOU SUPPOSE-
AW, YOU'RE CRAZY!
IT CAN'T BE.
IT IS! IT'S ALEC!
SOMETHING'S HAPPENED!
AW, NO.
CUT THE SCOWS LOOSE,
QUICK! QUICK!
SAM, IT'S TRUE!
GIVE HER ALL SHE'LL STAND,
IF YOU HAVE TO BUST
THE BOILER IN TWO!
SHE WON'T STAND MUCH.
THEM LEAKY TUBES, YOU KNOW.
IF OUR PRESSURE
GOES DOWN,
WE'RE GOING ASHORE
AS SURE AS JUDGMENT.
STOP TALKING
AND DO AS I TELL YOU!
THAT'S WHAT IT IS, SIR.
THAT VESSEL'S RUNNING LIGHT,
AND SHE'S COMING THIS WAY.
I HOPE YOU'RE RIGHT!
THAT VESSEL'S
GETTING CLOSER!
KEEP THE FLARES
BURNING!
YES, SIR!
IT'S THE NARCISSUS!
SHE'S TAKING
AN AWFUL CHANCE
OF GETTING
SMASHED UP, SIR.
THEY KNOW
WHAT THEY'RE DOING.
STAND BY TO
SHOOT THEM A LINE.
MAKE IT SNAPPY!
YES, SIR!
ANNIE, YOU CAN'T GET A
LINE ABOARD IN THIS WIND.
LEAVE IT TO ME.
GO ON AFT AND BEND THE HAULING
LINE TO THE TOWING WIRE.
I HOPE THAT LINE
DON'T BREAK.
ANNIE! ANNIE!
WE CAN'T STAND THIS.
WELL, WHAT-
THEM LEAKY TUBES HAVE RUN THE
STEAM PRESSURE DOWN TO 40 POUNDS,
AND THEY JUST WON'T
STAND THE STRAIN!
WE'LL BE ON THAT REEF OURSELVES IF
YOU DON'T CAST THAT LINER ADRIFT.
I'D CAST MY BACK TEETH
FIRST! WE'RE HOLDING ON!
BUT WE CAN'T!
IT'S SUICIDE!
YOU CAN SEE RIGHT NOW WE'RE IN A HOLE
OF OUR OWN WITH THE WIND AND TIDE.
YOU AIN'T GOT NO RIGHT
TO SACRIFICE US.
WELL, WHAT ARE
WE GOING TO DO?
THEM LEAKY TUBES HAS
GOT TO BE PLUGGED.
CAST OFF THAT LINE,
AND WE'LL RUN OUTSIDE.
WE'RE NOT GONNA
CAST OFF THE LINE!
TERRY! YOU GO
BELOW WITH SAM.
I'LL BE DOWN
IN A MINUTE.
WE'RE NOT CASTING OFF
THAT LINE.
ALL RIGHT, PUT ON
THAT WIRE, GUS!
TERRY, GO THROUGH THAT FIREBOX
TO THE BACK CONNECTIONS,
BACK OF THE BOILERS.
I'LL PASS THE STOPPER
ON THROUGH TO YOU.
YOU TAKE THOSE NUTS, SCREW THEM
TIGHT ON THE OTHER END OF THE ROD.
THAT'LL STOP THE STEAM
FROM LEAKING.
WE CAN GET
OUR PRESSURE UP AGAIN.
OK.
YOU'LL HAVE TO WORK FAST,
OR WE'LL ALL BE ON THE REEF.
THE TUG'S
NOT HOLDING US.
THAT WAS TOO MUCH
TO EXPECT, SIR.
HELLO, ANNIE.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
I'M GOING DOWN AND FIX UP
THEM TUBES THERE.
HEY, YOU CAN'T
GO IN THERE.
AW, IT'S GOT TO
BE DID, ANNIE.
WELL, ALL RIGHT. LET SHIF'LESS
OR GUS OR SOMEBODY ELSE DO IT.
AW, I CAN DO IT JUST
LIKE THAT. LET'S GO, SAM.
NO, YOU'RE NOT
GOING IN THERE.
LET ME GO, WILL YOU?
YOU WANT ME TO
PUSH YOU IN THE NOSE?
LISTEN. IT'S FOR
OUR KID, AIN'T IT?
WELL...
HERE...
YOU OLD SEA COW.
OH, NO, YOU CAN'T GO
IN THERE, TERRY!
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
LET'S GO.
GIVE ME
THAT HOSE.
GIVE ME THAT
HOSE, SAM.
OH, SAM!
HE'S BURNING!
AAH!
SAM, THROW THEM PLUGS!
GIVE ME THEM PLUGS!
SAM, START THEM RODS!
ALL RIGHT. HERE THEY
COME. ONE-TERRY, COMING!
AAH!
COMING THROUGH TO YOU.
HERE'S THE TOP ONE.
HERE'S ANOTHER ONE,
TERRY!.
AAH. AAH!
TERRY!
AAH!
UHH...
HE'S FINISHED,
ANNIE!
THE BIG LUMMOX!
OH! HE'S COMING OUT!
ANNIE!
SAM, GET DOWN!
ANNIE! ANNIE!
LET ME GO!
ANNIE...
OH!
TERRY!
TAKE CARE
OF HIM, ANNIE.
I GOT TO STIR
OUR FIRES AGAIN.
OK.
TERRY, SPEAK TO ME!
SHE'S HOLDING US!
YOU'RE RIGHT, SIR!
SHE IS HOLDING US.
TERRY?
TERRY.
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
WHAT ARE YOU SNIFFLING FOR,
YOU OLD PORPOISE?
SURE, I'M ALL RIGHT.
YOU SHOULDN'T HAVE
DONE IT.
GO ON.
IT WAS FOR OUR KID,
WASN'T IT?
YEAH.
TERRY...
I'M ALL RIGHT,
ANNIE.
STOP
YOUR WORRYING.
I'M ALL RIGHT.
IT WAS NICE OF YOU
TO COME, ALEC,
AND THE
YOUNG LADY, TOO.
WE BRENNANS KNOW HOW
TO PICK OUR WOMEN.
BUT WHAT
YOU WAITING FOR?
YOUR MOM AND ME
WAS MARRIED
TWO WEEKS
AFTER WE MET.
YOU ALWAYS WAS A
FASCINATING DEVIL, TERRY.
WE'LL HAVE
A GRAND WEDDING.
I'LL GIVE
THE BRIDE AWAY.
WHY, HE'LL BE
UP AND AROUND
AND OUT AT HIS OLD
TRICKS BEFORE ANYTIME.
SAY, TERRY,
YOU KNOW, THE STEAMSHIP COMPANY
IS GOING TO BUY THE NARCISSUS
AND FIX HER UP ALL BRAND-NEW
AND GIVE HER BACK TO US.
PRESENTING YOU
WITH THIS MEDAL
IS A GREAT
PLEASURE, TERRY.
BUT IT GIVES ME
GREATER PLEASURE,
ON BEHALF
OF MY COMPANY,
TO GIVE YOU BACK
THE NARCISSUS.
OH!
WHY, TERRY! OUR GARBAGE DAYS ARE OVER.
WELL, COME ON.
LET'S ALL GO IN THE MESS
ROOM AND HAVE SOME CHOW.
DAD, I'M PROUD
OF YOU.
YOU SHOULD BE.
HA HA HA!
WELL, POP, HOW DOES
IT FEEL TO BE A HERO?
OH, ALEC,
IT'S PERFECTLY NATURAL.
HA HA HA!
HA HA. HEAVEN HELP ME FROM NOW ON.
HMM. PRETTY,
AIN'T IT?
I OUGHT TO GET IT
FOR LIVING WITH YOU.
AW, ANNIE.
WELL, COME ALO-
WHO PUT THAT IN THERE?
Watch Movies, TV Series & Live Sports
www.admitme.app