You're human.
Please, just let me go.
Given the extent of their
physical degeneration,
we think that you'll
encounter minimal resistance.
That's my sister.
It's a
trap. We're under attack.
They must've cured themselves.
He's one of them.
I'm looking for someone.
Professor Bill Ward.
You've been
gone for months.
What did they do to you?
You have to kill him.
Mmm...
He's creating a virus
that will slaughter our people.
You will die with us.
You can stop it from happening.
How?
You have to kill him.
Em, what's wrong?
I can feel them.
What do you mean?
I feel their pain.
It's okay.
You're safe now.
None of us are safe.
How long
have you been sitting with him?
Most of the night.
Has he said anything?
I gave him the antibiotics.
The equations in his notepad.
I think they're important.
More important than
the lives of the people here?
Hmm?
Sophia?
This will terminate the
pregnancy in the first ten weeks.
Okay.
Have you told Nathan?
No. It's better
if he never knows.
If there's anything
else you need.
Thank you.
They'll never know
they were human.
It's better this way.
If they knew,
they'd grow up to hate us.
Like we grew up to hate them?
We lost some more of our people.
- How many?
- Six.
We cure ourselves so we
can die fighting them?
We have no choice.
We kill them, they kill us.
Sometimes I think
it will never end.
It's different this time.
Emily knows what
she's got to do.
What are you doing?
I... I was looking
for your mother.
Right.
Water.
Please.
Thank you.
The equations...
What are they?
They're formulas.
To measure the collapse
of the matter waves.
This matter wave...
Is it what we call
wave particle duality?
It's all around us.
It's...
It's only when we see them,
that we call them
objects or things.
Only then are they
part of space and time.
We know of these collapses.
We only partially
understand them.
It took us hundreds of years.
Even now,
transposing the matter
waves is dangerous.
You can control them?
Can you move objects
through space and time?
Yes.
We detected ripples
in interstellar space,
close to the edge
of our solar system.
Do you know what they were?
They are the echoes
of our transposition,
our journey to Earth.
But you came to Earth
more than six months ago.
Why are we only detecting
these ripples now?
The echoes travel
at the speed of light.
It took them longer to get here.
Longer than you?
Our journey took no time at all.
Hey.
You said you wanted
to change things?
It's not too late.
What do you mean?
How? How can you change it?
You walk along the river
and you join the other section here.
He regained consciousness.
Leave us.
Did he say anything?
He said their journey to
Earth took no time at all.
How is that possible?
In the quantum world, photons and
electrons can affect each other
even if they're
hundreds of miles apart.
It happens in an instant.
There's no travel, no
communication, no time passes.
Can they use this?
I think they can move objects
instantaneously across vast distances.
I think it's how they got here.
Catherine, how does it help us?
I don't know.
He said we could change things.
That it wasn't too late.
If you can manipulate the
world on a quantum level,
then maybe anything is possible.
Yeah, maybe.
I know I shouldn't have
given him the antibiotics.
All I could think about
was getting answers.
That was more important
to me than anything.
How can you love someone
who thinks like that?
It's not easy.
All I can tell you is that I do.
Em?
How're you doing?
I'm okay.
Mum has to stop herself from
crying every time she looks at me.
She was in pieces when
you didn't come back.
We thought you were dead.
Maybe you should
go and find Mum.
You're angry with me for
using the antibiotics.
When someone else needs them, you can
explain why you chose to save him.
And then you can watch them die.
There's someone out there.
I asked for volunteers to clear the
snow from around the service panels.
Oh, no.
Check the generator.
Stay away
from the windows!
What's happening?
Stay away
from the windows!
Theo!
-  Catherine, down!
- Theo?
-  Get down, Sophia!
Theo!
Sophia, get down!
- Theo!
Theo?
Sophia!
Emily, get down!
Theo?
- Theo?
No!
- No!
Theo!
Sophia, get up!
There's nothing you can do! Leave
him! You have to leave him! Let's go!
Quickly!
Nathan.
Nathan!
Let's go!
Catherine!
Got it!
The service tunnel! Go!
Come on, Sophia! Go!
Go, go, go!
Where's Theo?
He's dead.
Get out of here.
Get out!
Come on!
No!
Take them away.
Come on.
Micah?
Why did
you have to do this?
There has to be
another way.
There is no other way.
It's us or them.
It doesn't have to be like this.
Did you tell them
why you came here?
They should know that it
doesn't have to be like this.
Where is the notebook?
You cannot kill an idea.
They won't ever understand it.
Your ideas will die with you.
You can kill your own brother?
We cannot allow you to live.
Please...
Don't get old.
I think the chances of
that are extremely slim.
My boyfriend was
in the wine trade.
Yeah?
What happened to him?
He died.
In the attack?
After.
I tested Emily's DNA.
- She let you?
- I took a hair from her hairbrush.
She shares some of
the same mutations
as the aliens.
She... She's alien?
- It's incredible.
Her DNA is almost identical.
The chances of that are...
are billions to one.
How is that even possible?
I don't know.
It doesn't make any sense.
None of it makes any sense.
Well, you said that if
you had a live alien,
you could start
testing the virus.
Seems to me like you've got one.
You want me to test it on Emily?
Could you?
You're asking me to...
to deliberately infect her?
What would it do to her?
Well, I'm developing
RNA interferers
that shut down the genes
that cause insulin.
She would fall into a diabetic
coma and she would die.
Well, maybe that's a
price worth paying.
I'm not gonna do it.
How could I experiment
on a 17-year-old girl?
She's a child.
This is it.
This is what the end
of humanity looks like.
Drink up.
Hello, Tom.
- Hey.
Couldn't sleep.
Hmm.
Who can these days?
I
think they've gone.
You think it's weird
that they look like us?
What?
Nothing.
Pack up your things.
We're leaving.
Chloe?
You okay?
The tremor in Sacha's hand...
It's come back.
You can't be sure what it is. I
mean, maybe he's just tired...
No, no, no. It's the
muscular dystrophy.
And it's getting worse.
Like his father.
I can't bear it.
Come here.
Hey.
How are you feeling?
Everyone keeps asking
me that.
I'm not sure what
I'm supposed to say.
You can sit down.
Mmm, maybe don't
wanna get too close.
What do you mean?
Everyone thinks I'm one of them.
I don't think that.
So...
What's been going on with
you these last few months?
- Any good parties?
No.
- No good parties.
Met any nice girls?
You're seeing someone?
I thought you were dead.
I'm sorry.
Kariem, honestly, it's fine.
You're not jealous?
Well, is... Is she
prettier than me?
No, I...
You're joking.
What happened to
you on that ship?
I know something is wrong.
Whatever it is, you can tell me.
Please.
I want to help you.
Sometimes,
it feels like they're
inside my head.
I keep having these... thoughts.
I'm so scared.
Maybe you should talk to Bill.
No.
No, I don't think I should.
I'll check upstairs.
We just leave him up
there? We don't bury him?
It's too dangerous to go back.
If he was here he'd
tell us not to go.
I'm sorry.
I'll see if I can find
some wood for a fire.
I promised Theo I'd protect him.
I told him I'd keep him safe...
Sophia. Sophia.
It's not your fault, okay?
There's nothing you
could have done.
Get down! Get down!
Don't shoot! Don't
shoot! Don't shoot!
Check them.
Show me your wrists.
Your wrists, let me see 'em.
Take your bag off.
I'm looking
for my family.
Do you know them?
No. No way.
Tom and Emily's dad?
Are they still alive?
Yeah. Yeah, they're here.
They're here. They're inside.
Sarah?
Mate, she's with them.
Are... Are you sure?
You're sure... You're
sure that that's them?
Mate, I'm 100%. I've been
with them since the start.
Happy days.
Sarah.
Oh, my God.
You're alive.
Oh...
Hi.
Oh, Jesus.
It's so good to see you.
The kids?
They're here. They're fine.
We're okay.
Dad?
Tom.
Hey, buddy.
I thought you were dead.
No.
I never stopped looking for you.
- Same hair.
Em.
It's me. It's your dad.
I know.
I can see you.
You can
help me if you like?
What's going to happen now
Jonathan has his family?
What do you mean?
Will he get back with his wife?
I don't know.
Let's just be grateful
that he's found them.
Everything will change now.
Mom's
telling him about me.
It's okay.
I know you think
I'm one of them.
Are you?
No.
What is it?
It's Micah.
He's dead.
How?
He died fighting for our people.
I'm truly sorry.
Jokim will bring his
body here for burial.
Was Jokim there when Micah died?
Yes.
He did everything he could.
He couldn't save him.
Sarah.
Chloe?
This is, erm...
This is Chloe.
We, erm, travelled
through France together.
Hi.
This is Tom, Emily. My kids.
Your dad talked to me about you.
It's nice to finally meet you.
Thank you for
looking after him.
I'm glad he found you.
If you need anything,
anything at all...
Yeah, thank you.
Uh, this is my son, Sacha.
Hi.
We'll, uh,
let you settle in.
- I'll show you where we're sleeping.
- Yeah.
What?
I want the water,
and I'll take your bag, too.
Thank you.
Nothing.
We'll have to
squeeze in another mattress.
- Sarah...
- I don't want Emily sleeping on her own.
Not after everything
she's been through.
So she's in with us for now.
Sarah...
I'm with Chloe.
We didn't mean for it to happen.
I'm sorry.
Oh...
Oh, you thought
I was dead, so...
She's very pretty.
How old is she?
Sorry.
Everything was so
fucked up. I thought...
I thought I lost
you and the kids.
I was going under, I
was a mess. We just...
We needed each other.
- I'm sorry.
- Don't.
Things weren't exactly
great between us.
I've hated myself for
that, every single day.
Just go.
This
is the building.
Right, go ahead.
I'll keep watch.
How do we find
this Professor Bill Ward?
We have to assume
he's some kind of scientist.
We'll start there.
Look at the reference pages.
What are they?
At the back of the book, they list
all the sources used for research.
I miss the internet.
He's creating a
virus that will slaughter our people.
You have to kill him.
Emily?
I won't let you kill them.
Emily.
What's going on?
Jonathan's daughter, Emily.
She tried to kill someone.
Hello, Tom.
I heard what Emily did.
Oh, no. I'm fine.
She tried to kill you.
Yeah.
Everyone's saying
she's one of them.
Is she?
Yes.
How can she be?
She's my sister.
None of it makes any sense.
I'm sorry, Tom.
What are they gonna do to her?
I don't know.
We don't have a choice.
I'm sorry.
I didn't know what I was doing.
It's okay. It's okay.
Look, uh...
I'm gonna give you
something to, uh...
To help you sleep.
Okay?
Okay.
What is it?
It's, erm... It's
just a mild sedative.
Okay.
I'm sorry.
It's okay.
Just... Just get
some sleep, okay?