WEEK-END at the WALDORF
Here is the Waldorf Astoria.
Big place, isn't it?
But it's home to me,
because I happen to live there.
In fact, you might read
my newspaper column:
"Randy Morton's New York ",
Of course, it's rather
widely syndicated.
When this week-end
had started, Cassidy, the doorman
was on duty as usual,
and I must confess was rather nervously
strolling along with my Scotty Suzy.
Suzy was facing
a big crisis in her life.
She was about to be come a...
that is, she was expecting
Well, I'm sorry.
I don't know how this little character
ever landed in Park Avenue.
But anyway, it all started
with the arrival of
a young honeymoon couple
at the  hotel.
It was a Friday afternoon,
around tea time.
- Don't be nervous.
- I'm not nervous.
I just need my shore legs.
Look Johnny,
that is David Cugat.
That must be
the "Wedgewood Room."
Oh, Johnny!
Come on, honey,
we'll lose the bellboy.
I'm sorry, Mr. Morton, but there's
no listing for "Ackmy Cats and Dogs" Bideawee.
Are you sure you got
the name right - Ackmy?
That peculiar Lady Bush told me
she had three cats there.
Excuse me, where's
the Irene Malvern shindig?
- Please ask the receptioner.
- Thank you very much.
It was Bideawee, I'm sure she said.
Pardon me, where's
the reception for Irene Malvern?
39th 4 Towers.
Please check for the Towers.
I'm ready, sir.
- Ensign Wright and Mrs. Wright.
- Have you a reservation?
- I sent you a wire we arrive on Friday.
- Just a moment please.
She sneezed twice this morning.
I wonder if that means anything?
- In my experience, no.
- And she refused her biscuits at breakfast.
We have your telegram,
but unfortunately.
we have no accommodation
- You haven't?
- We telephoned around
and there is a room available...
...at a very nice little hotel...
- But we came to Waldorf.
- We'll only stay till Monday morning.
- I'm sorry..
We spent the whole night
on the day coach
not even in the same car.
I've always dreamt about
staying here..
About staying at Waldorf.
Just a minute.
They are full, dear.
Maybe that other place...
I know but...
A honeymoon couple.
See the rice?
Perhaps they've just had
a Chinese dinner.
Any important messages for me?
- I'll be at my place
in Connecticut till Monday.
- Yes, Mr. Jessup.
See those bride and groom
trying to get a room?
When he said it's a honeymoon couple,
I made a rather funny crack.
How was it I said...
Something or other...
I'm sorry, sir.
We've decided to wait
until you do have a room.
Don't think I can make any promises.
I'll do my best.
We just can't go anyplace.
We just can't.
- Excuse me.
- Yes, Mr. Jessup.
- They can have my apartment
over the weekend.
- Very good, Mr. Jessup.
- That's very nice of you, sir.
- Thank you very much.
How much is the apartment?
I mean, what's the rate?
Don't worry about that,
I keep it all the year round.
- That doesn't seem right somehow.
- That's all right.
You see, I lost a boy about your age
in the South Pacific.
Mr. Jessup.  Mr. Martin Edley
would like to speak to you
on the house phone, sir.
I'll take it.
Hello, Edley.
What's on your mind?
I got a wire
from the  Bey of Aribajan.
His Highness will be arriving here
any minute now.
Get to the point, Edley,
I haven't much time.
You know what a deal
with Aribajan would mean?
I thought you would like
to go in with me?
I wouldn't.
Would you like me to read
the wire I got from him?
Stevens, give me that wire
in that drawer there.
Hold on a moment, please.
Here it is.
Now listen...
Hello. Hello!
Hello, operator,
you cut me off.
Yes, Mr Edley,
I'll try to get Mr. Jessup back for you.
I'm sorry, Miss Malvern is not in.
Her secretary suggested
you send her scenario
to the studio.
I thought she was wonderful
in the 'Forgotten Angel'.
Yes, just a moment, please.
I'm sorry, Mr. Morton,
but the information has no listing
for the "Ackmy, Dogs
and Cats", Bideawee.
Are you sure you
have that name right?
What's that?
Try Ackny?
Very well, Mr. Morton.
Just a moment, please.
Beverly Hills, California,
calling Miss Malvern.
Sorry,  Mr. Jessup has just left
for the  week-end.
Gone for the week-end.
The President
of the Volcanic Oil Co
can't be bothered
with as little as
a 100 million dollar deal.
He's a New-Yorker for you!
No vision, no enterprise.
- Just a staff shirt.
- Wasn't interested?
I wouldn't touch him
with a ten foot pole.
- I'm going ahead anyway.
- With what?
We'll tell the Bey
that we've got Jessup with us,
- ...that Gideon Oil is a subsidiary.
- That's dangerous.
- Who's gonna know?
- We have to work fast.
Did you ever see me in action?
I am a self-made man.
How do you think I did it??
- I've been asked that question before.
- All right then, I'll tell you.
I've got vision, I've got enterprise.
Mr. Jessup has none.
But he's on his way out
and I am on my way in.
Eh? Speaking.
Fine, we'll be right down.
Someone else is on his way in.
His Highness the Bey.
Great! Come on!
- Who is that?
- The Bey of Aribajan.
His Highness will be glad
to see you on Monday week.
My Board of Directors
meets this Monday.
I've got to present
a closed deal.
His Highness
has chosen to reconsider.
If Mr Edley will dine with him tonight?
Oh, that's great!
I'm certainly glad
you are here, Your Highness.
It's too bad you don't speak English,
but we're in business.
Yes, sir.
Thank you. Go on.
The first thing to do
is to put the proposition on paper.
Hello.
Can I have the public
stenographer's office, please?
It's  Martin  Edley,  39-E.
I want a secretary.
Send me that little blond
who was here yesterday.
Yes, Bunny something or other.
This way, sir.
Well, angel face.
- Come into my parlor.
- Yes, Mr. Spider.
Hello, Edley.
Shades of peace
and prosperity.
If it isn't my old friend
Martin X. Edley!
Chip Collyer.
- What are you doing back in N. York?
- How is life..
...in a penitentiary?
You wrote a lot of lies about me.
You know very well I was acquitted.
Yes, because I was
off to war.
Oh, sorry!
Hi.
I want you to meet
my esteemed managing editor, Mr. Johns.
This is Martin Edley.
If you remember
we raised a little action
with Gideon Oil in the good old days.
I knew nothing about that deal.
I'm off to war again on Monday,
so whatever you are up to,
just relax.
By the way,
are you up to anything?
I should have you
thrown out of this hotel.
Thinks back to good old days.
If I weren't bent on sleeping,
I'd look into that gentleman's activity.
Oh yeah!
- Pretty nice foxhole!
- Yep.
Eat, sleep, read, relax.
All yours till Monday
and the paper pays for the works.
I will sleep is all I want.
Just sleep.
Wow!
I hope I don't walk in my sleep.
Who's that? You said
you wouldn't tell anyone
I was here.
- Now, I only want...
- Yes, I know you won't.
- Who is it?
- A waiter.
I thought you might
like something.
- Come in.
- Yes, sir.
- Mr. Collyer.
- Hello, Emile.
- How do you do, sir?
- Glad to see you.
- Thank you.
- I haven't seen you since you..
...put me to bed
at he Publishers' Convention.
That's right.
February 15,  1939.
-Welcome back to America, Mr Collyer.
- Thank you.
Why, you've been away a long time.
I read your dispatches
from all over the world,
Spain, London,
France, Africa.
- Did you really?
- Yes, sir.
- Are you going to stay with us
for a while? - Just until Monday.
- Off so soon?
- That's Simon's idea, not mine.
What about a little drink, Chip?
Suits me.
- Did you put that wine on ice?
- Yes sir, it's right here
in the pantry, sir.
I don't know...
...if I can wait for that wine or not.
Heads, I take my clothes off.
Tails, I sleep as is. Tails.
Attaboy, Chip. I want you fresh,
and raring to go.
Yep, I know.
Raring to go back there.
Hi.
Have you ever
seen man die...
...slowly..?
Now wait a minute.
Well, I have
wholesale.
Spain,
London, France,
Germany.
It ain't pretty.
Here we are, sir.
- I am tired.
- I know.
You know they send flyers back
after so many missions.
Well, you had a rest,
two weeks.
Twelve banquets...
Thank you very much.
Four lectures.
Newspaper publishers' conferences.
A cocktail party,
and one crap game in which I lost.
You'll feel all that better
after you have a little sleep.
You know, the man really needed it.
- Is there anything else, sir?
- No, I think that's all, Emile.
Thank you.
And don't bother coming back because
I'll be asleep in 5 minutes, or maybe less.
- Very well, sir.
- I'm gonna sleep for 48 hours.
I have to admit you're
getting a little stale.
That's why I brought you home
to give you a rest,
...to give you a fresh point of view.
Stale. I've gotten past the point
of being stale. I'm empty.
I don't see any more,
I don't feel.
Every word's an effort,
every word's tired.
You'll feel a lot different
once you get back to Europe again.
- Why don't you let me stay home?
- What for?
Look, you can get half a dozen
fresh kids..
...and get much more
out of any one of them.
- Have another drink.
- It won't do any good, I've tried it.
...but I'll have it.
You'll feel a whole lot better...
..after you have some sleep.
You want me to put out
a "Do not disturb" sign?
No, I'll take care of myself.
A carry my own.
I hope you have a good rest,
...and pleasant dreams.
And I'll settle for nightmares.
By the way, do you want me
to wake you up on Monday morning?
Don't you come here before.
- Well, bye, Chip.
- Bye, Hi.
Hello.
Chip Collyer? This is  Randy Morton,
we met once, I think.
Anyway, Irene Malvern, a movie star,
is having a cocktail party here
...for the press
and her press agent
came up with a grand idea:
If you drop by,
so we could get her picture.
You know, Miss Malvern between the man
from the war front, that's you,
...and the man on the home front,
I was on the Air-Raid Board.
How do we meet?
This is General Martínez
de Esperanza speaking.
I know no you,
and I know no Miss Malvern.
So I'm very chilly to your suggestion.
Definitely,
not a good neighbor.
- What do you mean?
- Somebody gave a bum steer, that's all.
I told you Collyer
was not at the hotel.
Sorry, Steve.
Well, it was an idea. Oh excuse me,
I've got to see Mr Burton.
I think she is mad about it.
All I asked was 15.000 dollars.
You are the luckiest producer
in the business, Burton.
I wish I had a star
like Irene.
No shenanigans, no nonsense,
no temper, no divorces.
- No relatives. Skilly.
- Yes, boss.
- Get around.
- Get around? Sure, boss.
I don't know, so if I don't
get there you'll understand.
Miss Malvern.
- I'm so glad
to get to New York.
- Thank you.
I shall read your book
first thing in the morning.
Did you inscribe it?
- Right there.
- How lovely.
I feel so stimulated.
New York really is so...
Excuse me.
This show is going on for 3 hours, she's got
to be fresh for tomorrow morning.
OK, boss.
Well, that's over.
You still got the opening of your picture
to go to tomorrow night.
Saturday. Then Sunday.
On Monday you leave.
Four days on the train,
rest.
You don't have to start "Farewell,
my Darling" until...
...a week from tomorrow.
A week from tomorrow.
Tired?
No.
- What are you doing tonight?
- Nothing.
You are not dated up?
How about dinner and a show?
I'll organize a small party
No.
- I thought you knew thousands of people in N.-Y.?
- I do.
- You don't want to see them?
- No.
Irene, I've never
seen you like this before.
I've never felt like this before.
Now, come on! What's the matter?
Feeling low?
Say, maybe you're anemic.
Maybe you need a doctor.
Do you take vitamins?
By the tons.
Holy mackerel!
You are not in love?
Yes.
Somebody I know?
- No.
- Some tramp?
- I resent that.
- I didn't mean that.
I'm sorry..
Naturally I thought it was a tramp
because you are so unhappy about it.
Well, he is not a tramp.
He's wonderful.
He's handsome,
...he's wise,
...strong, steady,
he's witty.
- He's charming, he's...
- Say, who is this guy?
He's as real as
everything else in my life.
He just doesn't exist.
And you got mad
because I called him a tramp.
Wouldn't you?
You're a funny girl.
Henry, would you like to see a present
from a fan?
The most appropriate present
I ever got.
The history of my life.
Put on one mask,
...take it off.
Put on another.
Till you realize
that I've never lived,
...and nothing has ever
happened to me.
School,  theater,
pictures.
Other people get married,
have adventures,
bear children, live.
And Henry, it's beginning to show
right up there, on that screen.
Ridiculous.
Your life has brought you 2 million three...
All right.
File and forget.
Pardon, Miss Malvern.
Dr. Campbell is on his way up.
- Will you tell him to come in here?
- You called a doctor?
Good, he'll give you
some vitamin B
and you'll be a different woman.
Say, did I ever tell you what happened
to my wife last summer?
She was feeling kind of low,
you know.
She went around saying
I bored her, can you imagine?
No.
Bobby.
Hello, Taffy.
- Henry Burton, Dr. Campbell.
- Very glad.
Take care, doc,
she's a valuable property.
Say, what do you say
about  vitamin B for her?
I'm not here professionally,
besides, I'm a surgeon.
- You're not gonna cut her up?
- Run along, Henry.
He's known me
since I was a kid.
Just the same, you look her over
while you're here.
Oh say, doctor, by the way.
I'm inclined to have
a little pain right over here.
I had my appendix out last year.
What do you think it could be?
- Henry.
- All right, all right.
I'm gonna find out.
I've been to 6 doctors
and they tell me
I'm imagining things.
I haven't got
that much imagination.
You really should examine him, Bobby.
You'll probably find
he's made of celluloid,
just like me.
May I express
a professional opinion?
- Fire away.
- Take a rest.
Thank you, doctor.
I'm going to take one.
4 days on the train.
A ride is not a rest.
Bobby.
Do you mind if I
don't go to your wedding tomorrow?
It's rather hard to explain,
it's just that...
I can't face people.
Of course,
if you don't want to come...
It isn't that, it's just that I...
It's when I...
I'm afraid,
I'll start crying and...
disgrace you.
I don't get this.
Neither do I.
It isn't that we were
ever in love.
After all those years at school
and you used to stick pins at me.
Because you had to
practice on somebody.
Now, listen, Taffy.
Bobby, I don't know
what's the matter with me.
I've never felt like this before.
You've been working too hard.
Look, I know how busy you always are.
But you just got to
come to this wedding.
You're the only glamour
I know.
If you just heard Cynthia's mother.
"My son-in-law, Dr Campbell,
is a very close friend of Irene Malvern.
As a matter of fact,
she came to the wedding.
She tells me
she cried real tears.
Doesn't use glycerin."
Never touched the filthy stuff.
- All right, I'll come.
- Good.
Oh glory be! Thanks a lot, Taffy.
See you tomorrow.
- Excuse me, Miss Malvern,
are you going out tonight?
- No, Anna.
- Is here something
I can do for you, Madam?
- No, thank you.
It's a beautiful evening, Madam.
Yes, it is.
Hello?
Miss Smith?
The public stenographer?
No, Miss Malvern
has changed her mind.
Thank you very much.
She changed her mind.
You know that's where
I'm going to be.
Sorry, I can't come to work today,
changed my mind.
Sorry, I can't pay
the rent today.
I've changed my mind.
Gee, what a life
she must lead!
She's got everything!
She can go anywhere,
do anything,
buy anything.
Stop drooling.
Well, I'd better take
these reports to Dr Campbell
before I start Mr. Edley's notes.
What did Mr. Edley have to say
this time?
He asked me if I knew
what a Park Avenue apartment cost.
- What did you say?
- I said, well, I wasn't a real estate agent.
- What did he say?
- He said "What are you doing tonight?"
Oh, I know the answer
to that one:
"I'm sorry, but
I'm working tonight."
- Say, Kate.
- Yes?
What does
a Park Avenue apartment cost?
Well, I just wanted to know.
Public stenographer's office.
Dr. Campbell?
She's on her way
up to you right now.
Thank you.
You can finish dressing now, Hollis,
I'll be back in a moment.
OK, doc.
- Here's your reports, doctor.
- Fine.
- And your book.
- Would you have time
to take a letter for me?
Yes, sir.
I want this to go air-mail
special delivery.
To Colonel Ralph Whitaker.
W- H-I-T-A-K-E-R.
Walter Reed Hospital,
Washington DC. Dear Ralph:
Pursuant to your request, I have
again examined Captain James Hollis
- Captain James...
- Captain James Hollis.
and his X-ray plates.
I am flattered you wanted me
to confirm your findings,
and I must say
that I agree with them entirely.
When I was still in the army
attached to Halloween,
we had a somewhat similar case,
and as you remember,
we barely pulled
that boy through.
This one is in even
more hazardous risk.
Nevertheless,
the operation that you plan for Tuesday
can be a success, if...
underline "if"...
the patient
has the will to live.
But actually, his present
state of mind
leaves much to be desired.
Excuse me.
Doctor Campbell.
Hello, Cynthia.
I'm dictating a letter, darling.
Is she pretty?
I haven't the faintest idea.
Yes, very.
Yes, Irene's coming.
I had quite a time persuading her.
I don't know why.
I'm a bit worried about it,
as a matter of fact.
Yes, darling.
Let's see, where were we?
Doc, I'm all ready.
Excuse me.
Put on the line, Doc,
what are my chances?
Well, I'm not going to pretend
that a shrapnel fragment
in your heart,
is a minor operation.
But you are in awfully good hands.
Colonel Whitaker is first rate,
one of the best.
He's had a lot of success
with the new technique,
but he just wanted me to check.
Well, I'd just like to know
if this is to be
my last week-end, because
Well, I'd just like to know.
You have no family, have you?
No.
Haven't you any close friends?
Yes, my navigator.
But he's dead.
He didn't have to go up with me,
he'd done all his missions.
But I asked him to.
Come on, Doc, let's have it.
Hollis, you got an even chance, but...
but doctors
can't give you the will to live.
Well, I've got me the will
to have one win of a week-end.
I've got me a room here at the Waldorf
I've got a lot of flying pay.
I'd take it easy
if I were you.
Won't you, Doc?
- Thanks, Doc.
- Good luck.
Excuse me, sir.
One moment, please,
I would like to go up again.
I forgot something.
- Would you mind?
- No, go ahead. I've got time.
Thank you.
Lots of time.
- Anna.
- Yes, Madam?
I thought you'd gone.
Forgot to leave the key.
Well, you could've left it at the desk.
Well, I wanted to leave it
with you here.
So clumsy of me!
Anna, what's the matter?
- I...
- Come here.
Yes, Madam.
- What's come on you, Anna?
- I've got something to tell you.
Well, I shouldn't be
worrying you with this.
- I should be going to the police.
- The police?
But I can't do this to him.
I love him.
And I know he's been
making love to me
to get to you.
To your jewels.
Anna, will you please stop sniveling
and make sense?
He wanted me
to meet him tonight
and give him the key
so he could get
in your apartment.
He must have money,
a great deal of money by Monday.
Of course, the only sensible thing
is to call the police.
Oh, no!
Oh please, Madam,
I would rather die.
I've been with you for 5 years.
If you have any feeling for me...
Of course, Anna,
you know I'm fond of you.
It isn't as if he was just a thief.
It's only the big idea
took hold of him.
The jewels.
I tried to reason with him,
but it's like an obsession.
But if you talked to him...
You want me to talk to him?
Please, Madam.
He worships you.
He says you are his
favourite actress.
And yet he wants
to steal my jewels.
I know it isn't logical.
But if you talked to him
he would see that.
You are so convincing,
so charming.
He respects you.
And Madam,
if he would give up this idea,
we could be happy.
I am not pleading
just for him.
I'm pleasing for my life.
- Anna.
- Yes, Madam.
During the 5 years
you've been with me
you've seen me handle
a good many people.
I haven't been too stupid.
I've always said,
Madam is not only talented,
but with a marvelous brain
and such a good heart.
- You trust my judgment?
- But of course, Madam.
Then give the key
to your young man.
- Let him come tonight.
- You will see him?
In 10 minutes I'll know
whether he's worth saving.
But I can't receive him in this.
I've got to wear something severe,
something black.
Madam, he's very
fond of blue.
In that case
I shall wear black. This.
- Shall I help you dress Madam?
- No, never mind, Anna.
- Good night...
- I understand, you are spending
the night with your aunt?
Yes, but I was supposed
to give my man the key first.
Go ahead, and give it to him.
Yes. He said he would meet me
a little while somewhere in the lobby.
- Good night, Madam.
- Good night, Anna.
- Anna.
- Yes, Madam.
- You forgot the key.
- Ah, yes, Madam.
- Good night.
Would you please give me
the hotel police?
Yes, Miss Malvern.
- Blake.
- Yes.
Get up to Miss Malvern's apartment,
she'll tell you what it's all about.
- She doesn't want to talk
over the telephone.- OK.
- And report back here.
- Yes, sir.
Yes, sir?
I'm Captain Hollis,
I'm up in 2318.
I know it sounds
kind of wacky to you,
but the fact is I've lost a song.
- You lost what?
- Song. Music.
I've lost it between
Dr. Campbell's apartment and my room.
Just a minute.
- Lost and found.
- Yes, sir.
Chief Jennings's talking.
There's a guest here
lost a song.
- A song?
- Yes, music.
Oh yes, the floor waiter found it
and he took it to Mr. Cugat.
- He did?
- Yes, sir.
Floor waiter found it.
Thought it was Xavier Cugat's.
He's always losing something.
We'll get it for you.
I wonder if Mr. Cugat will let me
try to get it myself?
- It's very important.
- OK.
- Thanks.
- The 11th floor, Room 1110.
All right.
- You're fired.
- Fired? I quit!
Excuse me.
And what do you want?
I'm sorry to barge in
this way Mr. Cugat.
but I was told
you have some music
that belongs to me.
- Music?
- Yes, the floor waiter brought it
here by mistake.
Music? Sure I have music!
I have them by the pounds,
by the tons, by the inch
by the yards, by the miles.
What kind of music?
I have tangos, boleros,
sambas, congas,
bossas, fox-trots,
concertos, cantatas,
overtures.
It was a ballad.
A ballad! Look,
I'm a very very busy man.
I have problems, I have responsibilities.
Why do you annoy me,
why do you confuse me?
Mr. Cugat.
I  had some music manuscript.
I lost it.
The floor waiter picked it up
he brought it here.
He thought it was yours.
Well, I don't know anything about it.
I have enough problems
keeping track of my musicians,
without bothering about floor waiters.
I'm not a Maître d'Hotel.
- Do you mind if I look for it?
- Certainly, I mind.
You're a flier, not a composer,
why are you doing with music, anyway?
It doesn't happen to be mine.
It was written by a buddy of mine.
He was shot down over Formosa.
I want to send it to his mother.
It was all that was left of him
except a couple of snapshots.
- Now, do you mind
if I look for it?
- Mind?
Certainly not!
I'll look for it myself.
I'll turn this place upside down.
Why didn't you say
you were looking for some music
instead of talking about...
floor waiters?
What's this?
- That's it, that's it! What a relief!
- That's it?
"And there you are".
Nice title.
Now, let's see.
Not bad, not bad.
You're never out
of my heart.
Yes, pretty nice.
We liked it.
Certainly, we would like
anything out there.
Well.
- Has she got a radio?
- Who?
- This man's mother.
- Oh, I guess so.
We'll broadcast from 9 to 10
tomorrow night. Tell her to listen.
- You mean you'll play it?
- On the "Starlight Roof".
- Tomorrow night.
- Tomorrow night?
I suppose you want me
to play it tonight?
We have to rehearse the new numbers,
you got to argue
with your musicians,
find them, humble them,
scream at them,
flatter them, curse them,
praise them, beat them.
If you think that you
put on a number
just like that
and seize it?
Did you see the girl
who just left here?
I've fired her!
Now I'm gonna take her back, she'll resign,
I'll accept, she'll refuse,
she'll come back, she'll go...
No, I can't play it tonight.
- What?
- Tomorrow night.
I'm sorry, Mr. Cugat.
I got time.
Lots of time.
- Mr. Collyer?
- No.
That's fine,
but this is your room,
you look like you.
- Are you a linguist?
- Yes, sir.
I took Spanish,
French, Italian in college.
How about English?
I speak English,
all my life.
How's your vision?
I just wear these to appear dignified.
I got 20/20 eyes.
Really?
Well, read those signs then.
Do not disturb.
Non disturbate.
- I don't seem
to know those languages.
- What the heck do you want?
My name is  Oliver Webson,
the boss sent me down here
to cover the Edley story.
He said it I ran in any trouble
you'll help me out.
- Ah, he did?
- Yes, sir.
- So you are a reporter.
Now I know what they mean
by the acute manpower shortage.
May I come in?
Yes, come on
and make it quick.
- Thank you.
- Now what is it?
The  Edley story, the boss said
you'd be interested.
What have you got so far?
You know, we got
a cable from Cairo
saying that the Bey of Aribajan
was going to lease out some oil.
The boss found out
that the Bey was staying
right here at the hotel.
Furthermore, the boss found out
that Edley is negotiating
with the Bey.
- He is?
- Yes.
Boss says
it's a very bad thing for the country,
see, because this contract
starts after the war.
And the boss has got an idea
with all that Nazi and jap money...
That...
Well, I haven't got it
quite straight but,
anyway the boss says
it's a bad thing for the country.
Anything that Edley is in
is a bad thing for the country.
So far you've told me
what the boss has found out.
What did you find out?
Nothing.
What did you do?
Well, I've found
the Bey's suite.
Say, do you know
he's got a goat?
He drinks goat's milk.
- Did you see him?
- Oh, sure.
- The goat or the Bey?
- The goat.
Did you go to the Bey?
Well, the Bey sent word
he was tired.
- Did you try Edley?
- Said he wasn't in.
I see.
Say, could I have a drink?
I've had a tough day.
Sure, that won't dull
that keen edge
to that razor-like mind of yours.
Oh, no!
Well, so far you have tried
the conventional legitimate ways
of approaching the victim.
Now you've got to try the illegitimate.
- How?
- Edley won't tell you anything.
Concentrate on the Bey,
you've gotta see him.
- But how?
- Figure out a way.
Listen,
the Bey's suite's
right next to yours, see?
Now if I could figure out some way
to sneak out on the face terrace
from here..
Of course, that's not for jump.
You see? First you have to enter
the Bey's room,
but to get to the Bey's room,
I don't need the terrace.
Boy, you're hotter than
a  firecracker on the 5th of July.
Who is it?
Maid.
- I beg your pardon.
I just wanted only...
- Don't bother now.
Very well, I'll go to the next one
and come back later.
- Just a minute.
You might as well go ahead.
- Thank you, sir.
-Where did you say
the Bey's rooms were?
- Next door, on the corner.
- The maid's heading there,
you heard her, didn't you?
- Yeah.
Suppose, you get in there.
- It's your chance
to sneak in that way.
- I can't do that.
- Why not?
- I'd feel silly.
Yes, of course you'd feel silly,
but you'll get there.
It isn't dignified.
Besides, I wouldn't fit.
Look, I'm bigger than you,
and I'd fit in there.
- I 'd like to see you try it.
- Well, I'll show you.
Then you pull them over like that.
You can't see me, can you?
- Good night, sir.
- Good night.
Good night.
- Wait a minute.
- Yes, sir?
Don't...
- Never mind.
- Yes, sir.
His Highness hasn't had time
to study the proposal,
- It's a very serious and important matter.
- Yes, but you see, on the other hand...
What's that?
Any trouble?
I'm the maid,
I was just trying to explain...
Ah, it's quite all right.
Thank you very much but....
His Highness is served entirely
by his own staff, you see.
- Oh! I'm sorry. Good night, sir.
- Good night.
Night maid,  Miss Malvern.
- What can I do? He wants
some time to think it over.
- I'd make a subcontract.
- I'll put it down in the morning.
- Maybe.
You just watch me.
It's very nice of you to come up.
- Sorry you wouldn't tell me
more about it, Miss Malvern.
- I'd rather not.
Anyhow, I'd see that these are going
in the safe in the main office.
- Thank you very much.
- And then I'll stay around.
- Good night.
- Good night, Miss Malvern.
- Good evening.
- Nice night, eh?
Well, now that you're here you...
you may as well come in.
I must say you
did it rather skillfully.
Well, well. Irene Malvern.
It's along way from Italy.
You know, you gave
a swell performance for me,
one night at Sovana.
Me and  5.000 GIs
The film broke a couple of times
but it was swell.
You'll never know
what you did to me that night.
What are you looking for?
- Cigarettes, but...
- There are some right there.
- Thank you.
I can explain this.
Anna has already explained
- Anna?
- Yes, Anna.
You took a mean advantage
of a poor devoted soul.
Did I?
Well...
Look.
I am a newspaper man,
and I wouldn't be
in this charming predicament
if I weren't half asleep.
Go on.
Well I was trying to...
show a silly cub
how to get a certain story.
The story I'd like
cut in incidentally.
Go on.
There it is. This, of course,
wasn't my destination.
When you came in,
I was
retreating
to shorten the line.
Go on.
It's been the communiqué.
You are not very clever now.
No,
I have my off moments,
and this is one.
Got a match?
- A lighter.
- Thank you.
Say, it's a handsome little piece.
- Now where were we?
- May I?
Oh, I'm sorry.
You just can't help
taking things, can you?
Look, Miss Malvern,
you've got me all wrong.
I know it's a bit complicated,
but if you pay attention
I'll diagram it for you.
Anna has already done that.
Well, back to Anna again.
Yes,
she told me everything.
- She did?
- Yes.
I can better understand her now.
You can?
I do well understand it.
Have you any love her at all?
Over...
You know how it is.
She was only a means to an end, eh?
- Did she say that?
- Oh, not in those words.
As a matter of fact, she
didn't make very much sense.
She was hysterical.
And I can understand that, too.
After all, you have been
using your wiles on her
for some time now.
And why?
To get my jewels.
Oh I see.
Let me assure you
my jewels are downstairs,
in the vault.
Ah, in that case...
And furthermore,
let me assure you
that there's a detective
standing outside that door.
Perry Mason, Peter Wimsy,
o Sherlock Holmes?
Do you want to go to prison?
That's an experience
I've  never really had.
So you are sensations eager.
Is that it?
That's it.
If I wanted jewelry,
would I be sitting here
with one of the loveliest women in America
watching her green-flecked eyes
change from fear to scorn,
to anger, to pity?
Oh yes, I saw
some pity in those eyes.
And while we are on the subject,
if you don't mind my saying so,
that's the nicest hank of hair
I've seen in many a lonesome month.
And the nose
isn't bad either.
But do you know
what gets me? The voice.
There's music in it.
Poor Anna.
She never had a chance,
did she?
Not a chance.
- Anything else, sir?
- No, thanks.
Say, waiter.
- Did you ever make out a will?
- Can't say I have.
But I had and aunt who did.
Lived in a big house
in Brooklyn, with 20 cats.
Every month
she changed her will,
and every month the whole family
had to go out and hear her reading.
And in the end,
you know who got the money?
The cats.
How do you start?
I mean, how do you go about it?
Search me.
But I'll tell you who can
put you right on that.
The public stenographer
right here in the hotel.
- She is supposed to know everything.
- Thanks.
And maybe she will
have it notarized,
you know?
- By a notary public.
- OK.
Thank you, sir.
Listen to this:
"14 rooms, 5 baths,
solarium, terrace,
one of New York's most exclusive
Park Avenue residences.
14.000 dollars annually."
- What? No bowling alley?
- No.
- Good night.
Excuse me.
I wonder if you could tell me where
I can find a Notary Public?
Well, I am one.
You are?
I thought you'd be sort of a
older gent with glasses
and false teeth that click
and a black string tie.
He forecloses mortgages.
Notary Public can be the male or female
over 21, must be bonded,
must have stamp,
stamp pad
and must never
have the license run out.
Now have you any identification?
- My dog tag any good?
- Well..
I see you got one, too.
Bunny
Bunny.
A silly name, isn't it?
I was christened ...
Bernaradine, but I never could pronounce
the darned thing, and still can't.
When I was a kid,
they'd always ask me
"What's your name",
I would say: "My name is Bunny."
Say that again.
My name..
Now have you any identification
with a signature already on it?
Well you see, I need that
for my own protection.
Oh, let me see.
Something with my
picture on it, maybe.
Ah, yeah.
That's me,
Captain James Hollis.
Right, Captain James...
- Captain James Hollis?
- Yes.
They forgot to make me a general.
Just an oversight.
Now what would you like
to have motorized?
My will.
- A will?
- Yes.
- Well...
- There it is.
Is that it?
Sure, isn't that legal?
Well, it's legal,
but it isn't legible.
Besides, wills don't
have to be notarized.
- They don't?
- No.
All you need are
two witnesses.
You see? They sign there and...
you sign here.
Suppose, I copy it first.
You're pretty business-like, aren't you?
One has to be in my business.
That'd break your heart.
Now, let's see.
"I leave my Air Medal to..."
- What's the name?
- Mrs. Hannah Slacken.
- Of...
- Jasmond, California.
- I see.
- Relation?
- My landlady.
- "I leave my..." what is this?
- Uniforms.
to...
Cadet John Mickels.
- Address.
- Kittle Center. San Antonio.
I see. Relation?
No. Just a fellow
I went to school with.
One guy that always wrote to me.
"I leave my..."
I leave my motorcycle
to Harry Clark of
Jasmond, California,
to be held in trust for him
until he reaches the age of
60.
It's in Joe Bonny's garage.
He always wanted that cheer-up.
You want me to put all that in?
Yes, I guess so. Yeah!
Do you really think
he can wait 50 years
for that motorcycle?
Oh I don't know
what I'm doing.
The trouble with me is that
I wanted to get home for a year.
I get home...
Well, I have no.
I see.
I sold my gas-station
before I went to the air-force.
That was home to me.
- It was a really good station, too.
- Really?
Yes.
A dog, and a cat,
and some bees.
-Everybody in  Jasmond has bees.
- Bees!
They don't bother you,
once they get to know you.
Like people, eh?
Where are you from?
- You won't tell?
- No, promise.
Well, I was born in New York,
on 10th Avenue.
We called it "double Fifth".
I think I know
that street.
Well, you haven't missed anything,
it's no Park Avenue.
Mamma would say we'd move
some day but we didn't.
You like Park Avenue?
Well, I like what it means.
What does it mean?
That I'm on my way.
Where are you heading for?
As far away from double 5th
as I can get.
Look.
I've got a whole week-end,
and I don't know a soul.
What are you doing tonight?
Nothing. I was supposed to work.
A conference, you know.
But it was postponed
until tomorrow.
Excuse me.
Public steno....
Yes, Mr. Edley.
Yes, I can come up.
At the Bey's apartment.
Very well.
I have this wrong,
the conference is on again.
What about tomorrow?
You don't have to work
on Saturday, too?
Not if I can help it.
Not on Saturday night.
I thought it was
a big night for me, too.
Even if I only went down
to the drug-store.
Look, you go about your schedule,
and I'll follow it.
- All right.
- It will be my last
Saturday night
in town.
The only thing is
we've got to be at the "Star Light Roof"
from 9 to 10.
- The "Star Light Roof"?
- Yeah, I've never been there.
Gee, neither have I.
- What about the will?
- Oh, we've got time for that.
Sure, lots of time.
- Then this is a date?
- Absolutely.
That's wonderful.
Do you like
crêpes Suzette?
What's that?
Sounds like a shirt.
That's French for pancakes.
We'll have them,
even if they are shirts.
- Well, see you tomorrow.
- OK.
- Hi, what's up?
- Routine.
But what made you a thief?
Oh, that's a long story.
Is it hereditary?
No, my father was a missionary.
- Oh, a good man!
- None better.
Eh...when did you
first...?
- Steal?
- Yes.
Well, let's not go into that.
Anyway, why are you taking
all this trouble over me?
You're a movie star.
You ought to be at El Morocco,
or some place,
getting yourself photographed,
danced with, engaged,
married, divorced.
Incidentally,
are you engaged,
married, divorced?
No, no, no.
How come?
I work.
That's something
I recommend to you - work.
The only thing in life.
Oh, I wouldn't say that.
Well, the only
satisfying thing.
I wouldn't say that either.
What else is there, then?
Well, there's... fishing.
You're a pretty lonely soul,
aren't you?
- What makes you say that?
- And frightened, too.
- Of you?
- Oh, no! Not of me.
Of life.
I'm not afraid
of anything or anybody.
I am.
Most people with any sense
are one time or other.
I don't understand you.
What is it
you're after anyway?
You've got looks, success,
a dizzy amount of it,
from what I can make out.
A hundred million women would
trample each other to pieces
to change places with you.
Yet, coming back to your eyes, which
certainly fascinate me,
there's something missing.
I am very happy.
What's more, we are not here
to discuss me.
I realize that's a subtle
form of flattery but ...
I assure you,
I'm on to it.
- I can't get around you, can I?
- Not very easily.
All right. Show down.
I'm the parasite.
Not a bad fellow.
Good manners, gentleman.
They call me the Baron.
- Who's they?
- The gang.
- You mean you work with a gang?
- Well, syndicate, if you prefer.
Then this whole thing
has been carefully organized.
Meticulously.
What are you going
to tell the syndicate?
If I should let you go.
That I couldn't pull the job.
Met my intended victim
she was beautiful, she was warm,
she was generous, sincere...
I still had a little
spark of decency left, so
I returned the necklace.
What necklace?
The  Grand Duke's.
"Grand Hotel".
That's straight out of the picture
That's right, I am the Baron,
you are the ballerina,
and we're off to see the wizard.
How very amusing!
Look.
Do you still believe
I'm a jewel thief?
But if you aren't
why did ask Anna for the key?
Can't you guess?
Why, that's the most
outrageous.
- I think you'd better go.
- Sorry?
Your necklace.
You were quite right about me.
But I'm not the same man
who came in here.
Won't you believe that?
Well..
Wait.
Do the police know you by sight?
There's not a cop in New York
who doesn't.
Wait here, then. I'll
get rid of the detective.
Lexington 20598.
Mr. Johns, please.
But I tell you,
you can go now.
I'm sorry, Miss Malvern,
but the chief left strict orders
I wasn't to move away from this floor.
- We are not taking any chances.
- I asked for you myself,
and now I'm asking
you to leave.
Well, Ma'am,
I 'm going off at midnight.
Ah, that's good!
But another man's relieving me,
and I will be back in the morning.
- Thank you.
- Not at all.
Don't tell me
I'm the only man who can...
Listen, I'm through,
I tell you.
Well. I was in \\\,
in the first place.
I don't care
what's at stake.
You can count me out, yes.
That was the gang.
Well, you're in.
And now, good night.
You can't go yet,
the detective won't budge an inch.
I'm going to call the chief.
Would you give me the chief
of protection service, please.
Sorry, I'm such a bother.
This is Miss Malvern.
Would you remove that detective?
Oh, no.
He is very nice.
It's just that
he's pacing up and down,
it makes me very nervous.
What did he say?
Even if he does stop
pacing up and down
it's just his being there.
But after all, I' don't need
anyone to guard me.
What's that?
He's not there just to guard me,
he's guarding the Bey?
What Bay?
"Bay" is a body of water
almost entirely
surrounded by land.
Oh, I see.
Thank you.
Well...
There's only one thing to do, ey?
- What's that?
- Stay here.
Here?
I hate to impose
upon you, I realize
that you hardly know me,
that you have no reason to trust me, however...
- And where do you
propose to sleep?
- Right here
In the living-room, of course.
All I need is
a blanket or something.
Wait just a moment!
Calm down, Miss Malvern!
You've done this before.
- I have?
- In one of your pictures.
- But that was acting.
- And this is real life, eh?
That'll be fine.
A little cold,
but that's all right.
- Do you mind?
- I certainly do.
Very well, then.
Call the police.
Wait.
All right, go ahead.
So, Miss Malvern,
good night.
You...
didn't lock the door?
There's no lock.
Good night.
What are you doing?
I once walked in the sleep.
Saturday morning the sun rose
in its accustomed place.
behind the Waldorf's towers.
It's really quite a sight,
if you are not too sleepy
to appreciate it.
Early morning in a big hotel
is quite a sight anyway.
People cleaning windows
just as they do in New-York
or Kansas-City,
except that the soap has a little
farther to fall.
I don't know what the people
behind these windows are thinking.
This Saturday morning
they aren't thinking anything at all,
most likely.
But before long
they will all be struggling
out of bed
peering out the seam of the day
is going to be like and
and going right back to bed again.
However some people
have to get up,
and  even the sidewalk
comes in for its morning shampoo
What appears to be a hockey team
ready for scrimmage is merely a crew
touching up the mosaic floor.
Waldorf's famous "Wheel of life".
As in these big lobbies a little later
there'll be the hum of guests and music
at this hour that hum is
from the dozens of cleaners,
waxing machines and vacuums.
The bell boys,
moving a bit faster
than I, I must admit,
are standing glove inspection.
Not rehearsing tip maneuvers,
as you might think.
Now one of the ledge filled out
the scheduled events for the day
and not one word about Suzy's
checking out for the  Bideawee.
Good morning, Waldorf Astoria.
It's 8:55.
- Waldorf Astoria.
- Astoria Center.
Room service? Just a moment, please.
Room service.
Mr. Edley would like
to have his breakfast
as soon as possible.
Good morning,  Mrs Drew.
Mr. Alex, maître d' hotel?
Just a minute please.
But we talked over the event
yesterday with  Dr. Campbell.
I know, Alex,
but doctor Campbell
is a doctor, you see.
I beg your pardon?
You want me to put something
medical on the wedding cake?
But Madam, the chef has already put
the flags of United Nations.
Four Cupids, two Psyches.
He's outdone himself.
Well, what have you in mind?
The Kansas City General Hospital?
I make her the Kansas City Hospital,
I'll go to the Kansas
City  Hospital!
Thank you.
I knew I could depend on you.
- Mother.
- Just a moment, dear.
Alex, will you meet me
in the "Jade Room" at 11 o'clock?
I want to go over
the floral arrangements with you.
Here's a wire from the singer
engaged for the wedding.
She's down with bronchitis
and can't sing.
Oh, what a nuisance!
- Cynthia, where are you going?
- Out.
What on earth for?
Please, Mother dear.
I'm just going for a walk in the park.
- Something I'd like to think about.
- Think?
What is there to think about
on your wedding day?
Time enough afterwards.
Afterwards may be too late.
What am I going to do
about a singer?
Hallo, will you get me
Mr. Randy Morton, please?
Yes, Mrs  Drew, just a moment,.
Miss Malvern? I'm afraid
I can't disturb her.
Who's calling?
Her maid? Very well.
Hello?
Madam, I'm sorry I troubled you
yesterday. It was so unnecessary.
He has reformed.
He's here with me now.
Madam, I was so happy
last night when he decided
not to go to your apartment.
Oh that's fine, Anna.
I'm very glad.
Good-bye, Anna.
What?
CHIP COLLYER.
WAR CORRESPONDENT.
Is there a Mr. Chip Collyer
registered here in the hotel?
Yes, there is, Miss Malvern.
Shall I ring him?
Did you say no?
Mr. Randy Morton?
Sorry, his line is busy.
I tell you, Mrs  Drew,
I think your best possibility
is  Mme. Jalaska.
After all, she was a great singer
and she's right here
at the hotel.
Not at all.
Very glad to help you.
Good-bye.
Time like this!
Bideawee.
How's Suzy?
I thought you were the Bideawee home.
I've been sitting up
the whole night waiting.
Yes, Mr. Morton, I know.
It's harder on the man
than it is on the dog.
Good morning, sir.
Good morning.
Yes, I'll send her right off.
Is there something I can do for you?
As a matter of fact
I was looking...
- Hello.
- I just wanted to be sure
about tonight.
- Tonight's all right.
Did you have fun last night?
Yes, I went to the airport
watched the planes come in.
Well, I just wanted
to be sure about tonight.
It's gonna be something special
and I kinda like
to have you share with me.
You know about that Cugat tonight?
Want to get you know.
He's gonna broadcast the song
a friend of mine wrote.
Really?
- 9 o'clock all right?
- Yes.
I'll take you up here or shall we meet
right at the Star Light Roof?
- Star Light Roof.
- Righto.
What happened to your grand plans?
The Park Avenue apartment.
Well you don't have to work
at it all the time.
Public stenographer's office.
Bunny?
Oh, Mr. Edley!
I think she just stepped out.
Stop protecting me.
Hang up.
Good morning, Mr. Edley.
Yes. Yes, I can come up.
All right.
Who said you don't have
to work at it all the time?
- Miss Smith.
- Yes?
You forgot your notebook.
Are you up and respectable?
Yes.
Good morning.
You didn't have to do that,
you know.
- Breakfast!
- Don't you think you ought to
put the furniture back?
What for? Breakfast?
Before breakfast.
Right.
Beautiful morning, isn't it?
Clear and crisp.
The kind of a morning that
sends a man on to his honest labors,
with a song on his lips,
and a purpose in his heart.
That is provided
he's had breakfast.
Why don't you go out
and get yourself some breakfast?
The detective. You forget
he's still there.
As big as life.
What's happened to your eyes?
They are cold.
Last night they were
filled with pity
and understanding.
That was last night.
This morning came...
what we in the Hollywood
call the dawn.
Frankly,
I'm terribly
disappointed in you.
Well, what have I done?
It's what you haven't done.
In Hollywood, Baron,
when a man says to a woman:
"Darling, I'm going strait",
when she wakes up,
he's off someplace
building a dam, or
running a railroad,
o plugging up a flood.
What have you done? I've slept.
Frankly, I'm terribly
disappointed in you.
- I'll reassure you just as soon
as I have my breakfast.
- I expected more, from the Baron.
Oh but wait till I've had my hot cakes.
So prosaic.
So un-heroic.
Hot cakes!
Irene.
Yes, Baron.
Sometimes a man gets himself
into a situation and
doesn't know how
to get out of it. Now...
Very funny.
I was..
going to suggest
that you might get out of it
by going through that door.
I don't think
the detective is still there,
day shift or night shift.
But if he is,
I have a feeling that he might
tip his head and say:
"Good morning, Mr. Collyer."
And that's my cue to say:
"Good-bye, Mr. Chip Collyer."
Look.
I apologize.
I tried to tell you, but
you wanted me to be the Baron.
Why not?
It was your way.
The fact is for 10 years
I've been looking for you
without even knowing it.
When I saw you, well...
I had to stay.
I...
think you'd better go
and get your hot cakes.
- Who is it?
- It's  Cynthia.
- Cynthia Drew. I must see you.
- Just a minute.
- I'm in a hurry. You go
through the door of my bedroom.
- But where am I going to see you again?
- What for?
- I can't leave like that.
Just a minute, Miss Drew.
Will you please, go.
Not until I've had my breakfast,
I'm too weak.
All right, help yourself.
And I hope.
Oh, hello.
- May I come in?
- Of course, please do.
I realize I should have
called first, but...
I haven't had my sleep.
No, it's quite all right.
So you are Cynthia?
- Bobby's told me so much about you.
- Has he?
Yes.
Come in.
- Sit down, won't you.
- No, thank you, I'd rather stand.
I really don't know
where to begin. I'm
afraid I'm being terribly impulsive.
And I've always been  impulsive.
You see, I asked Bob to marry me.
I didn't wait for him to ask me.
Why should you?
You mustn't mind me. I've...
been up all night,
all kinds of things racing through my mind.
A bride is supposed to be nervous
just before the ceremony.
At least, so I'm told.
I'm not a bit nervous,
I'm quite calm.
I've reason
just hoping I
Bob mustn't make a mistake -
it would ruin
his whole life.
What would?
Our marriage.
If he doesn't love me.
Calm now, sit down.
You're tired.
You haven't slept
and you're not yourself.
It isn't that. You see,
I know about you and Bobby.
- You know what?
- I know that he loves you.
- What?
- And I know that you love him,
I just know it.
Oh you're not serious,
you can't be!
Why.. it is so ridiculous.
What can I say to you?
How can I prove to you?
You didn't even want
to come to the wedding,
he had to persuade you.
Because deep down you felt
you were losing him forever.
But I have just  seen so many people.
- I couldn't face any more.
- It's not too late I...
- I can postpone the wedding.
- You can't. You mustn't.
I could say he'd been called away
for a very important operation.
I'm calling it off, I must.
The only fair thing...
- Wait.
- Yes?
Suppose...
- Suppose I told you...
- Yes?
Suppose I told you
that I was in love
with someone else.
I wouldn't believe you.
Suppose I told you
that I was married secretly.
I suppose now you'll
tell me he's overseas.
Really Miss Malvern,
I don't want to say you're lying,
You are not telling the truth.
Just a minute,
- Can you keep a secret?
- Why?
Come along.
Chip, darling.
Precious.
Cynthia, this is my husband.
Precious, this is Cynthia Drew,
she's marrying  Bobby Campbell
this afternoon.
You're Chip Collyer,
the war correspondent, aren't you?
- Yes.
- I've heard you lecture the college class.
and tell  them
the most fantastic stories,
some of them true.
Go ahead and
finish your breakfast, dear.
Sorry, we're out
of the hot cakes.
Bye, Mr. Collyer.
You can just dry those tears
and make up that face,
because you're going to be
a very very lovely bride,
in a very happy way.
And we'll just forget everything
that's just been said, shall we?
Of course.
I'm so happy.
Can you ever forgive me?
- I'm so glad I came. Good-bye.
- Good-bye
- See you at he wedding.
- Good-bye and good luck.
You may go now.
- What, precious?
- You came in rather handy.
She had some idiotic notion
that I was in love with Bobby.
She was going to call off the wedding
because of it.
- I couldn't have that.
- Certainly not.
When they return from their honeymoon
I'll explain. Do you mind it?
No, precious.
- I'm really not angry about last night.
- No?
In a way, I suppose,
I am to blame.
- I wouldn't say so.
- Good-bye.
- Look, what about...?
- Lunch? I'm sorry but I'll be
terribly busy.
- Then...
- I'm going to the wedding
later this afternoon.
And my picture has its premiere
tonight.
- I have a great many thing to do
before that.
- Yes, precious.
- Good-bye.
- Good-bye, precious.
Good morning, Mr. Collyer.
Good-bye, Mr. Chip Collyer.
- Come in.
- Thank you.
Confirming our verbal understanding
with His Highness the Bey,
Gideon Oil agrees to supply
equipment enumerated below:
geologists, engineers...
Take it away, take it away.
- Do you mind signing the check, Mr. Edley?
- Certainly, certainly.
Thank you, sir.
You're welcome.
Now let's see. Where were we?
Confirming our verbal understanding
with His Highness the Bey,
Gideon Oil agrees to supply
equipment enumerated below:
- geologists, engineers...
- You know, Bunny?
This deal we're working out
is one of the biggest deals
in the country,
- in the world.
- I know.
I want to transfer my headquarters
to New York.
- I'm going to get myself
a swell apartment.
- You are?
Of course I won't be here
all the time, just come and go,
you understand.
Bunny, I'll need someone
to take care of my private affairs:
you know, entertain my friends,
and business acquaintances.
Someone easy to look at.
Smart like you.
Know what I mean?
Yes, and no.
Like a confidential secretary.
Oh, I see.
What else would I have to do?
Nothing.
Absolutely nothing.
And you start tonight.
Tonight?
Yes, His Highness the Bey is entertaining me
at the Roof tonight.
And he's quite a fellow.
He has diamonds that big.
And he said to me,
it was translated:
"Bring that pretty little girl along.
That takes dictation."
You made quite a hit
with him tonight, yes.
Ah, did I?
Yes.
So I want you to dress up nice
and come along.
Well, I really haven't
anything to wear.
Oh, I can fix that.
en The hotel.
Well, the only thing is I...
have a date tonight.
Who with?
Oh let me see,
where was I?
- Gideon Oil...
- What does this date mean to you?
Are you sweet on that guy?
No.
- I'm not sweet on anybody.
- Well, I don't get you.
- Shall we go on?
- OK.
I am a business man.
I made you an offer
and you turned it down.
I didn't turn it down.
I just can't make it.
Tonight.
You  start tonight,
or you don't start at all.
What will you say?
Gideon Oil
agrees to supply equipment
enumerated below.
I think I need a shave.
Hello?
Put me in he barber-shop, please.
- That's the barber-shop.
- Yes, Mr. Edley.
- Thank you.
This way.
All right, Joe.
Make it quick, Joe.
Say, where were you last night?
A shave.
- Make out?
- And...
shine.
- Shine!
- You didn't see him?
And a massage.
-Did you get a story?
- And...
Let's have a manicure.
Manicure?
Please tell the fellow.
After all, I told the boss
you were taking over.
I'm going to a wedding,
that's why I'm getting the works.
What wedding?
The Drew wedding, you know?
That very rich dame.
You got an invitation to that one?
Sure, here it is.
Yes, this pretty special.
Certainly.
You're going back on the Edley story.
I'm coming to this wedding.
Wait a minute.
What do I tell the boss?
And hair.
You're wanted
on the telephone, Mr Collyer.
Hello, Mr. Collyer?
This is Cynthia Drew.
I've been trying
to get you everywhere.
I've done something rather awful,
I told Mother about you and
I was so happy,
I didn't stop to think
She told my uncle,
he's here for the wedding,
you know.
Did you tell anybody else?
Well, I told Bobby,
Dr. Campbell, you know.
Anybody else?
Joe, she is my best friend.
No, not a soul.
Except, of course
I had to tell  Mildred,
because Joe would have
told her anyway.
- The "Jade Room" please.
- Yes, Miss Malvern.
She is Irene Malvern.
Randy, find  a seat for her
in a prominent place.
I'm so glad she came!
- Irene.
- Hello, Randy, how's Suzy?
I have a good mind
never to speak to you again.
- Why didn't you tell me
you were married?
- What?
- And to Chip Collyer.
-Who told you that?
Never mind,
but I've got to write the story.
I can't explain now,
so just ignore it.
I can't ignore it,
somebody's got to print it.
- Is it true or isn't it?
-You want me yo deny it?
Yes, certainly, deny it, deny it.
- Right after the honeymoon.
What did you say?
I've saved your seat, dear.
- You..
- Here comes Mrs  Drew.
- You told Randy Morton.
- What?
- That we were married.
- No. Never laid eyes on the fellow.
Beautiful.
We must have
a proper ceremony too.
What?
- We are married under the law.
- What law?
- You introduced me as your husband.
- Well?
- That makes me your common law husband.
- That's silly!
- So you think yourself above the law?
- I never heard of such a thing.
Ignorance of the law is no excuse.
Let your attorney now consult mine.
- I don't want to talk about it.
- Here comes the bride.
Smile, precious.
Attagirl!
Let go my hand.
Ready?
Well.
Congratulations.
I know you two
will be very happy.
I won't forget it
as long as I live.
May I?
It's not every day one gets to kiss
a movie star.
That's right.
- I've had about enough.
- Just one more. A loving couple.
- I haven't come here to be openly pestered by you.
- Here's to bride and groom!
Both brides, both grooms!
Waldorf Tower entrance.
Yes, sir. OK.
Miss Malvern's car
to the  Park Avenue entrance.
is at the Avenue entrance
Tell her please,
she's in the "Circle Room".
I want to thank you
for the thunderous reception
you've given my picture
- You can't say thunderous, boss.
- Irene Malvern can say anything.
This is going to be the biggest open
this town ever seen.
How do you feel about "thunderous"?
-What?
- You weren't listening.
Are you looking for somebody?
No, no.
I beg you pardon.
Miss Malvern's car
is at the  Park Avenue entrance.
"Grandball Room",
the elevator's to your right, sir.
- Is there a special elevator
to the "Star Light Room"?
- Yes, sir. Right through there.
Thank you.
I...
a little early.
- I think I'd like
to order dinner in advance.
- Yes, sir.
Lobster cocktail, to begin with?
Sounds all right to me.
She'd like that.
Vichyssoise?
It's a cold soup,
very thick.
Cream.
Well, I guess you know your business.
Now...
something really elegant
for the main course.
- Have you got pheasant?
- Yes, sir.
Good.
Ah, yes! And she likes...
What did she call it?
Something like shirts - "crêpes suzettes".
Yes, sir.
And you might bring
some champagne now,
to get started.
- Any preferences?
- No, I leave that up to you.
Thank you, sir.
- What a place you've got here!
- Yes, sir.
What a place!
Her name is Miss Smith,
mine's Hollis.
In case she asks for me,
I don't want to get lost.
I will be careful.
- Captain Hollis.
- Yes.
- Here you are, sir.
- Thank you.
Thank you, sir.
Forgive me but I can't possibly
meet you tonight.
I'll explain tomorrow.
Bunny
Any answer, sir?
No.
No answer.
Here we are, sir.
Well chilled.
- Take the other plate away.
- Sir?
I'll be alone.
Yes, sir.
Might take away this with you, too.
Maybe your wife will like it.
Thank you, sir.
- Cigars?
- No, Thanks. I have some.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Ken Carpenter speaking.
from the famous "Star Light Roof"
in the Waldorf Astoria, New-York city
We bring you Xavier Cugat,
his orchestra, his fire Juanita,
who is back
with Cugat again.
The Mexican Rhapsody based on
Guadalajara.
Well, Cuggy.
It's a gay evening here
in the "Star Light Roof".
Here's a large card,
including many celebrities among the guests.
And right at this moment
His Highness the Bey of Aribajan
and his party are
being shown to a table
directly opposite the band stand.
And now on with our program
as Cuggy  tells you about his next number.
Thank you, Ken.
Signoras y signores, this is Xavier Cugat speaking.
Continuing our program we're playing
for the first time in the air
a new song entitled
"And there you are",
written by lieutenant
Joseph Goodman
of the Army Air forces.
It's a beautiful song
and I'm sure you will like the way
Bob Graham sings it.
Though we're oceans apart
You're never out of my heart
I simply close my eyes,
and there...
...you are.
There in the dawn...
...early light
and...
...in the still of the night,
I look behind the stars...
and there...
...you are.
Whenever there's
a storm,
I don't even hear the thunder
My heart with love
is so aflame,
I only hear each
little raindrop...
...repeating...
...your name.
And when the long...
...day is through,
I long for you,
only your.
And I pretend you're there...
and there...
...you are...
May I have the pleasure of this dance?
Will you give me your permission?
Of course.
Would you excuse me a moment, please?
Stevens, why don't you
dance with Bunny?
Shall we?
No, thank you,
I feel a little...
Did you get my note?
Oh, yeah.
I'm awfully sorry about tonight, but
Mr. Edley insisted.
I tried to phone you.
No, it's all right. I understand.
Well...
- Could I offer..
Wouldn't you like some wine?
- No.
Thank you.
Let's dance.
Yes, sure, sure.
You see, we have
Gideon Petroleum, we have Jessup...
- You have to explain the name\\\.
- Ah, yes.
Now if we take
Gideon Petroleum...
...20 million  dollars.
How about some fresh air?
That's a noble idea.
Gee, that's a lovely song.
It was sure nice of Mr Cugat
to play it.
You see, I wired Joe's mother
to listen in.
He used to be a  professional musician.
Ah, he was quite a guy.
It must have been awful
for you sitting there
listening to it alone.
Oh, no! No.
You see, I couldn't come tonight,
I meant to.
I wanted to very much.
But...
Yeah.
- Would you like to sit down?
- No, thank you,
...I have to get back in a minute.
Mr. Edley is mad,
but I'll explain it to him.
You see? He is very rich,
he is in oil.
And he likes me.
- Yeah.
- Yes.
He likes me very much.
Is he gonna marry you?
No.
I'm going to be
his  confidential secretary,
entertaining his friends
and business acquaintances.
And you want that?
Well, you know,
no matter what they tell you,
You don't get offers
like that every day.
I don't think it's so hot.
Don't you?
I do.
Oh, Bunny, I know...
I wish I had
a needle and a thread.
OK, OK,
I'll shut up.
Oh, no! That button's loose.
Can you cook, too?
No.
-  I can.
- Really?
If we were in Jasmond, I'd make
the best barbecue you ever had.
And we'd eat it under stars,
big big chunky stars,
not like these.
It gets pretty hot
back there n the sun.
Folks in Jasmond generally
do their cooking outdoors.
Kitchens get so hot.
No hotter in the kitchens
than in double 5th.
Only when it gets too hot
we go to delicatessen
and get some hot dogs,
and potato salad and a coke.
And the cops open the hydrants,
and kids splash around,
and the radios
go on all night,
and the firemen sit outside
the firehouse in their undershirts.
And then just when you think
you can grab some sleep,
somebody starts a fight.
And then you just
give up trying to sleep,
and wait for morning.
Some fun.
And Edley is gonna make it
all different.
Jasmond's different.
- Well, when you get back there..
- If I get back there.
Oh, but you will, Jimmy.
You will, must,
you've got a good chance on Tuesday.
Doctor Campbell wrote that
in his letter to Washington.
What do you know about it?
He dictated that letter to me.
You were in the nest room.
Jimmy, Jimmy,
promise me you'll try.
Bunny, I need you.
Jimmy, please, don't say that.
I've got to look after myself.
And you're making it
awfully difficult for me.
Oh, excuse me.
Mr. Edley was wondering
what happened to you.
I'll be back in a second.
OK.
That's  Mr. Edley's man Friday.
Well I...
Bunny, don't go back,
you don't know what
you're letting yourself in for.
Good night, Jimmy.
And good luck on...
Tuesday.
Oh Bunny!
I'd better go back.
Well, here we are.
Look, honey, now that we've got a hit,
don't you think we ought to
have a little celebration?
Come on over to the 21,
the whole gang's there.
- Come on.
-You two go ahead.
I am tired.
I'm going to take the war paint off
and go to bed.
Well, maybe you're right. Good night, Irene.
- Good night.
- Are you sure you'll sleep OK tonight?.
- May I have my key please?\
Your husband took the key
a few minutes ago, Miss Malvern.
What?
May I offer my congratulations?
Oh, yes!
Thank you.
Hello, dear.
How did the picture go?
Tell me all about it.
You have a room
in this hotel, haven't you?
One? I've got four.
From the hall
first turn on the right.
Can't miss it.
- Then you're not homeless.
- Oh hardly.
Just witless.
That's a matter of opinion.
I'd really like to know
what goes on
in that mighty brain of yours.
Ah, sweet mystery of life.
What would lead a man
to take a lady's key
and tell the clerk that
he's her husband.
and then plump himself down
in her living-room.
I'm just curious.
I'll probably never know but
if you're not out of here in two minutes
I'm going to call the authorities.
That's just variety.
"Dryden, Sims and  Corner".
I'm indebted to them for these.
Well, according to Blackstone,
and after all, he is the cornerstone
of our civilization,
there's no doubt that we are
really legally married
For right here... it says... in...
"Ravendew versus Clancy,
which engaged the attention
of  the Supreme Court
in September of 1896..."
I don't want to hear about it.
No, but this is one...
Excuse me.
One that I did want you to hear.
June 1904.
Rancon versus Hoover.
Plain had admitted
he had presented Miss Hoover
to various acquaintances
as his wife.
The result:
Rancon died
Miss Hoover collected a fortune
as his legal wife.
Will you please, get
yourself and those books
out of here?
I insist on my rights.
Your rights?
As...
your common law husband.
Will you please go back to your apartments?
Definitely, no.
Will you see what it is, dear.
I'm not in to anyone.
That's right.
We don't want  to be disturbed,
do we, precious?
Come over here
and sit down by me.
- For the last time, will you go?
- Sorry, no.
You still didn't have
to do that, you know.
- And there's one thing
I must tell you.
- What?
Mrs  Collyer,I will never
give you a divorce.
Early Sunday morning
in Park Avenue
is just about
like Sunday morning everywhere.
A New York policeman
can have just as little to do
as a village constable,
only a little more space
to do it in.
And a Waldorf cat can be just as philanderous
as a cat in a motel,
and just as hungry.
though he should have gone
to the  service entrance.
The service entrance, incidentally, is
where you'll find my column
being delivered in large bundles
entirely surrounded by funny papers.
Now comes the Waldorf
poodle parade,
in which this morning
poor little Suzy unfortunately
couldn't participate.
IRENE MALVERN MARRIED?
Mr. Collyer!
- Mr. Collyer!
- Yes, take it easy.
What do you think I've got?
- Mumps.
- No, look at this.
I see what appears to be
a table cloth.
- What do you think of that?
- Waldorf?
-From the Roof.
- With the spoons?
No, you don't get it.
Look at this.
Somebody doodled there.
The Bey gave a party last night.
So I thought:
"What would Mr. Collyer do?"
I sneaked up there
and there was Edley
writing on this table cloth.
And when they left
I thought:
"What would Mr. Collyer do
with that table cloth?"
So, I stole it.
Gideon. Jessup.
20 million,  worldwide petroleum.
That sounds like the setup.
Call up Jessup.
See if he is in it.
If he is you've got a big story,
if he isn't you've got a bigger story.
Don't stand there,
get some clothes on
and get down to the office
to write that yarn.
Just a minute,
you haven't got your clothes on.
- You want me to write the story?
- Of course, it's all yours.
I've just read in the paper
that you got married.
Congratulations.
- Thanks very much.
-  You are my idol.
No.
Eh! Your shirt is showing up.
I can't wait, I've got a big story to write.
I mean...
Where are the stairs?
I'll walk.
You are on the 39th floor.
I though I'd save time..
Jimmy.
Oh.
Did you want to see me?
I didn't know you are in.
I didn't think you worked on Sundays.
I was just finishing up. Come in.
Was it a good party? Did you have fun?
Sure.
I did a  rumba with the Bey,
a two-step with Mr. Edley
and a waltz with somebody else.
Cinderella was right back
on  10th avenue at midnight.
With a headache.
Did you want me to do something?
No, it's...
Just this is for you.
Just put it away.
"Not to be opened until Tuesday".
Why Tuesday?
It just won't mean anything
to you until Tuesday.
- That's my phone.
- If it's Mr. Edley...
Probably, as I 'm supposed
to have lunch with him.
No. No, don't answer it, please.
Until Tuesday.
But I'm a public stenographer here.
And it's part of my job to answer my phone.
I know, I know, but...
I'd rather you wouldn't.
I don't have to tell you this,
but...
I've been thinking about you.
Well, it's all there.
Very legal.
It's my army insurance.
But Jimmy!
Well, I haven't got anybody
to leave it to anyway.
If I don't come through on Tuesday,
you can have
Park Avenue without Edley.
You are...
You're beautiful,
and you're smart.
Why,  you can have your own agency
be your own boss, you know?
You can even go to college,
if you like, in style.
Without Edley and his kind
I don't have to say that,
but...
All I'm asking you to do is...
wait
until Tuesday.
Good-bye.
Jimmy!
Well, Mr. Collyer,
this seems to be all right,
but even though it's signed,
I wonder if you couldn't
change it just a little
as I suggested before?
- How?
- Like this.
Miss Malvern
and I are not married,
we're just pals.
No, she rides as she stands.
Miss Malvern and I are not married,
we're not even pals.
She obviously loathes me,
and that, gentlemen,
in my opinion, is not a solid basis
for a happy enduring marriage, so...
Miss Malvern and I
are not married,
we're not even pals.
All right, all right.
Gentlemen, I guess that's all.
- Well, bon voyage.
- Thank you.
There it is. Legal.
"We're not even pals."
- Was this his idea?
- He insisted on it.
I argued with him for hours.
- I guess he laughed.
- No.
- Oh, was he angry?
- What did he say?
- Nothing.
He just said "This is my statement.
We took it down,
we consulted each other,
recovered the important points,
and so we accepted it.
You know, he is a nice fellow.
What's nice about him?
What do you want?
A complete psychoanalysis?
He just struck me as being a nice fellow.
Thank you very much.
Sorry to have caused you
so much trouble.
- Now, if you'll excuse me...
- Sure, I know you're tired.
But you're leaving tomorrow.
Of course it's a good thing
we've got this in writing.
But he wouldn't have
given you any trouble.
Anyway he's going overseas
tomorrow morning.
- He is?
- Yes. He called from the airport
while we were there.
Your know...
You ought to send him
a going-away present,
like vitamin pills.
You know what conditions are.
They need vitamin pills.
Who knows?
He may never come back.
Why do you say that?
You shouldn't say a thing like that!
After all, he's
a war correspondent.
Irene.
- You're not stuck on this fellow?
- Certainly not.
- You're sure?
- Of course I'm sure.
That's great.
You had me worried there
for a minute.
- There's nothing for you
to worry about.
I assure you.
That's my Irene!
I wouldn't want you to be
like the others,
with husbands, with children,
with families, with complications.
You're alone.
You've got nobody to worry you,
nobody to worry about.
You go up to the studio in the morning,
you play your scene.
And you come back at night.
The house is quiet,
it's peaceful.
You have a nice dinner
and you go right to bed.
You're alone.
Perfect, isn't it?
Perfect? It's ideal.
You get up the next morning,
you go to the studio.
You come back.
You haven't got a husband to fight with,
no kids with measles,
no relatives.
- You're alone.
- That's wonderful.
If you feel like playing the radio,
you play it.
You haven't got to worry about him.
If you like reading, you read.
If you like sleeping, you sleep.
-Yes.
If you ever want kids,
you adopt a couple of them.
And you hire a nurse.
You don't even have to see them.
I tell you, if I knew then
what I know now,
my life would be different too.
And I'm not saying anything
against Mrs. Burton.
Good-bye, Henry
Believe me, Irene, there's nothing else
in life but work.
Oh yes, there is.
- What, for instance?
- Well, there's ... fishing.
Yes, sure.
Say, I didn't know
you like fishing.
I'm ringing Captain Hollis,
Miss Smith.
He's still out?
Please try again.
Are you sure
you're ringing the right room?
I'm calling
Captain James Hollis.
I'm still ringing
Captain Hollis's room.
Yes.
Excuse me, I believe
I left a pipe in the...
and some books.
- Yes, I was just going
to leave them for you.
They are right here.
Is there anything else, Madam?
- No, thank you, Anna. Good night.
- Good night.
This...
This is my lucky pipe,
I didn't want to leave it behind.
I understand
you're going away?
I tried.
I've started packing right now.
I wonder what I have to do with these.
They've 10 bucks pawn
in a little pawn shop\\
I thought you got them
from your lawyers.
You don't think any lawyer
in his right mind would
have me as a client?
Any more than any woman
in her right mind would
have me as a husband.
Oh, I wouldn't say that.
I'm sure many women would.
Name them.
- I can't say offhand.
-Think woman.
I'm in the market
for a wife. I told you that.
You won't have me,
you ought to know
a good second choice.
Someone
not as attractive as you are,
but, fairly attractive;
not as warm hearted, but,
fairly warm hearted;
Not as exciting, but
fairly exciting.
Think.
Well, I don't know many women,
except actresses.
Nice thing about picture actresses, though,
you can look them over on the screen
before you meet 'em.
Who did you have in mind?
Well, I have one or two stand-ins...
No.
No substitutes won't do.
It's you or nobody.
I can't have you,
so...
well, it was just a crazy notion anyhow.
Sort of a weekend mirage.
Imagine two people like us
getting together.
Ridiculous, isn't it?
Ridiculous.
Oil and water don't mix.
Law of physics.
Common sense.
East is East.
West is West.
Simple arithmetic.
It doesn't add up.
Doesn't...
..add up.
Good morning Waldorf.
No, sir, it's not Tuesday,
it's Monday. I'm sorry.
- Park Avenue entrance?
- Just a moment, please.
- Good morning, Mr. Morton.
- Good morning.
Good morning to these, too.
Look.
Triplet.
-Congratulations, Mr. Morton.
And a very happy day for all.
I think on occasions like this
it is customary
- to dispense regards.
- Thank you, sir.
For you, Harry? -Oh, thank you.
To you, boy. - Thank you.
Be very careful.
Don't ...
A nice weekend, Mr. Jessup?
- Morning paper, sir?
- No, thank you,
I've seen the morning paper.
Martin X. Edley involved.
Government officials
defraud suspected.
Let me see that again.
It's that fellow, Collyer.
I knew we would have
trouble with him.
I'll fix him.
but you're not leaving.
You can't.
You don't believe this, do you?.
There isn't a word of truth in it!
I tell you, Jessup
is behind me 100%.
Sorry but His Highness
is leaving very shortly.
But it's a pack of lies, lies.
- Where's His Highness? Where's the Bey?
- In the solarium.
Oh, Your Highness, I...
- Hello, Edley.
- Jessup!
That's the name.
But Mr. Jessup,  I can explain all this.
Explanations are not in order.
I'm afraid you little scheme
just didn't work.
His Highness is not signing with you.
You'll be sorry.
Go on, say that to him.
- I could have made him rich.
- To tell you the truth, Mr. Edley,
I am far too rich already.
It worried me at times.
He speaks English!
Yes, hey tell me,
I speak it quite well for a foreigner.
You see, Mr. Edley,
mine is a very sad life,
very dull.
You have brightened it considerably,
I am very grateful.
Thank you, Mr. Jessup.
- I'll see you in Washington.
- Your Highness.
He speaks English.
So does the  FBI.
- Here you are, sir.
Hope you enjoyed your weekend.
- Thank you.
Oh boy!.
- Could you get my bag, please? 2318.
- Yes, sir.
I'll be in the lobby.
- Good-bye, Chip, and good luck.
- Bye boss.
Thanks for everything.
I told you  all you needed
was a good old-fashioned rest.
Excuse me.
Pardon me. Did Captain Hollis come back?.
I called. His phone doesn't answer.
I think Captain Hollis
just this moment left.
- Jimmy, I want to talk to you.
- Yes.
I...
Come over here.
Jimmy, I can't make you do this.
I just can't.
But I told you,
there was really nobody.
I know.
That's why I'm going
to Washington with you.
- If you let me.
- To Washington?
Jimmy, you've got to pull through.
Then when you are all
well and ready,
we'll go to Jasmond together.
- If you want me.
- To Jasmond?
I'm not afraid of bees.
Pardon me, sir,
but the cab is waiting.
Come on, Bunny.
Hello, boss, it's Skilly.
The car's at the Park Avenue entrance.
Fine.
Skilly's got the car
on the Park Avenue side,
if you don't mind the mob.
Mind them? I love them.
I love everybody.
I love the world.
- That's OK.
- Madam, I don't seem to find
your cigarette lighter.
- Never mind that, Anna.
- I see.
Yeah?
Chip Collyer.
You don't want to talk to him.
Give it to me, of course I do.
Chip, darling.
Oh I thought you'd gone.
Oh, you are already at the airport?
You're about to take off?
All right.
Henry, wait for me,
I'll be back
in just a few minutes.
Henry, you've got to remind me
something very important.
When I get back
I want to enlarge my house
on  Beverly Hills.
He's got to have a study, no view.
He 's very easily diverted.
Oh Henry, couldn't I make
my next picture in London?
- I've got a date in London.
- Where are you going?
To the roof.
Chip!
So as you can see, the Baron
got his necklace after all.
That only goes to prove,
as I often say in my column:
anything can happen
on a week-end at the Waldorf.
Watch Movies, TV Series & Live Sports
www.admitme.app