Good morning.
I'm Dr. McRory.
Joseph McRory
of Fallbridge.
Have a chair, Doctor.
Why, thank you,
but I have no time to visit.
I have some business with...
Well, I'm sorry, Doctor,
but I can't just...
Oh, you may go in now.
Thank you.
It's a matter of
great importance.
Dr. McRory.
From Fallbridge.
How do you do, Doctor?
Sit down.
I believe we had
some correspondence.
Yes, of course we had.
Oh, yes,
physician to replace you.
Yeah, for two months,
during me vacation trip.
First in 30 years.
Now, I'd like a man of
substance, of experience,
a mature man.
That's been
taken care of, Doctor.
Fine, fine.
When can I see him?
As soon as you get
back to Fallbridge.
He's on his way now.
On his way?
Me dear sir, do you
suppose for a moment
that I'd place the health
of me town in the hands
of a person
I never set eyes on?
What'd you suppose
I came to Boston for?
To buy these
fishing things?
I assure you we've just
as good in Maine.
Yes, and cheaper, too.
Well, don't worry, Doctor.
We only send out
qualified physicians.
Besides, your letter was
a definite authorization.
Bindin', you mean?
Yes, but
there's no occasion
for concern, Doctor.
He's a good man.
Well, it's not my custom
to buy a pig in a poke,
but if it's binding...
What's his name,
this doctor?
Pearson. James Pearson.
Boston Times.
Get your paper before
the train leaves.
Paper.
Lower 10, sir?
Yeah. Take this with you, huh?
Yes, sir.
Hey, paper.
There you are.
Hey, fella!
What?
That's a quarter.
Well, tell 'em
where you got it.
Say, where's
the club car on here?
You can smoke in
the men's washroom, sir.
That's all the
club car we've got.
Your bag's in lower 10
and your trunks are
checked through.
Fine. Spread this
around, will you?
Yes, sir. Thank you, sir.
I always like a man
that whistles.
Well, I guess
there's room for one
more here, huh, fellas?
What's this?
Young man!
I'm sorry.
In the future,
you might look
where you're steppin'.
You're right. It's an
outstanding suggestion.
Board! All aboard!
Young man,
if you don't mind,
that's my paper.
What? This?
If you don't mind.
Well, you're welcome
to any part of it,
but it just happens that
I'm the legal owner of
this pillar of truth.
You're mistaken. I bought
that paper at the station.
What section of it
would you like?
I'm offering you
part of the paper.
You can have
the back part.
You may have
the front part.
I'm not thankin' you because
you're doin' me no favor.
It's my...
It's your newspaper.
Yes.
And I'm giving it to you.
Could that be
your newspaper?
You got a match?
Good morning, sir.
Good morning.
Right over here.
Thank you.
Oh, would you prefer to...
Oh, I'm not
sitting down just yet.
Tell me, would
it be possible to order me
breakfast while I'm shavin'?
You have a dish on this
train I'm very partial to.
Broiled brook trout
with butter and
lemon sauce.
Oh, a very nice dish.
It'll be right here
for you, sir.
10 minutes?
Thank you.
Oh, Clarence.
Yes?
Broiled brook trout...
I'm not sayin' that
all the young people in the
big cities are ill-mannered.
It's a matter of breedin'
and early trainin'.
Now, take that
young blatherskite
I was tellin' ye about.
The vulgar upstart.
He tramples on me package
and then he makes a great
to-do
about the ownership of
a three-cent newspaper.
Yes,
Good morning.
Mornin'.
He must've been hard up.
You mean he tried to
steal your paper?
Well, not exactly that.
Tell you later.
Breakfast is waitin'.
Say, can I use your plug?
Use me what?
I want to use your plug.
Smile
right back at the sun
And you'll have
a wonderful day
Smile right back at the sun
Gloom will get out
of your way
Just a cheerful expression
It's as easy as that
And you'll go walking
on a great big welcome mat
Why don't you try it?
Smile right back at the sun
The moment
he catches your eye
Waking up can be fun
Just depend on
your friend in the sky
If you start
your daydreams early
You're gonna get
a lot more done
So get up and get out
and smile right back
at the sun
Thank you.
Young man.
Huh?
This is a washroom,
not a cabaret.
No! I never knew.
What did you do,
cut yourself?
Let me see it.
No, thank you.
Oh, say, Steward.
Steward, do you
have a single that...
Broiled brook trout
for you, sir?
Hmm?
That's very attractive.
What, are you pushing
trout today?
Oh, no, sir. This
is the very last order.
Well, drop it yonder. Mmm.
Yes, sir.
Good morning, sir.
Me order's been taken.
Broiled brook trout
with lemon and
butter sauce.
Oh, I'm sorry, sir.
They told me table
number five.
This gentleman...
I don't...
I'm afraid this
is your trout, sir.
I'll thank you
not to talk to me.
Bring me another order.
I'm sorry, there's
no more trout, sir.
No more trout?
No, sir.
Well, if you don't mind
finishing this,
I've only made
a small dent in it.
You may bring me
some oatmeal.
Oatmeal. Yes, sir.
I'm sorry, sir.
I don't think we
have any more oat...
Maybe we have some
more oatmeal. Maybe.
I'll be pullin' for you.
Want some of mine?
Here's your change, sir.
Waiter, bring me
some pipe tobacco.
Any 15 cent
brand will do.
We have no
pipe tobacco, sir.
What? No pipe tobacco?
No, sir. How about
cigarettes or cigars?
No, no. Thanks.
Thank you, sir.
You bet.
Oh, that's perfectly
all right. Go right...
Yeah,
I thought it was me own pouch.
Oh, of course.
They do look so
similar, don't they?
They do not.
Won't you help yourself?
No, thank you.
Oh, now you broke it, huh?
Blatherskite!
Hey, here's your hat, sir.
Hillboro,
Carson Junction, Lankato,
Tanner City, Bentonville,
Fallbridge and Callensburg.
I thought you were
going on a vacation.
I'm leavin' Tuesday, Ben.
Lot of things to
tend to back home.
Uh-huh. Well, get right in
and we'll take off here
right now.
Always room
for one more.
Thank you.
Okay.
Stand away from the door.
Move back in the bus,
everybody.
Move back a little, friend.
Move back?
Where am I going?
Sardines have
taken over back there.
You all right?
Oh, me bunion!
Oh, I'm sorry.
Service, hey, Joe?
Right up to your
front door.
Thank you, Ben.
Here's your coffee, Unc.
Thank you, Jackie.
Is this the main
thoroughfare here?
Always has been.
Hi. Where do
I find a taxi here?
Down by the Weekly.
Thank you.
Say, could you take me
to Dr. McRory's house?
Yup. Cost you half a dollar.
Fine.
Oh, is it?
Sure. What's the matter?
Well, when
the customer
likes the price,
sometimes I don't.
Oh, you mean
you could have
asked for more?
Don't put words
in my mouth. Get in.
Say, you want
to re-negotiate?
Nope. Bargain's a bargain.
I could've said a dollar.
Not to me, you couldn't.
I couldn't?
No, sir.
That's what I figured.
Man in my business
gets to know human nature.
I sized you up
as a half-dollar fare.
You the new doc?
Yeah, while McRory's away.
Say, has he been
here quite awhile?
Thirty-five years.
Oh, he's an elderly man, huh?
He'll do for awhile.
Is there much work
here for a doctor?
Population of 2,400.
Well!
That get-up
you're wearin',
is it from Boston?
No, no, this is
California treatment.
You no like?
Well...
We're almost there.
Mrs. Gilley.
Mrs. Gilley!
Yes, Doctor?
What is it, Doctor?
Now, are you quite sure
there's been no message
of any kind
from this Dr. Pearson?
Dr. McRory,
for goodness sake.
I see, I see. No message.
Have I ever
failed to tell you
when someone called?
Yes.
I...
The door. The door,
Mrs. Gilley. The door.
Here's your coat.
Oh, no.
Keep the change.
Charged a half dollar,
keep a half dollar.
No extras.
May I tell you something?
What?
You'd be a big hit
in New York.
How do you do?
I'm Dr. Pearson.
Come in.
Thank you.
Take the bag to the
back room, Mr. Dorkas.
I know.
Put your coat down.
Are you Mrs. McRory?
Heaven forbid!
It's enough that I do
his cooking and tidying up.
I'll tell him.
He's here, Doctor.
What's that?
I say he's here.
Dr. Pearson?
Yes.
Fine, fine,
bring him in.
Come in, Doctor.
Welcome, Doc...
Yup.
No. It's not possible.
Well, it's me.
I can't believe it.
Me, neither.
180,000 physicians
in the country and...
You got me.
You know, Doctor, actually,
it was my newspaper,
you know.
Young man,
do you try to
be objectionable?
I'm not trying.
I can tell you this.
If I'd seen you in Boston,
I wouldn't be seein' you now.
What's this you're wearin'?
What are you dressed up for?
Oh, you like my outfit.
Not too loud?
Let me look at
your credentials.
Got 'em right here.
I know of no Drake
Hospital in Boston.
Oh, the Drake isn't
a hospital, Doctor.
It's a hotel.
You worked in a hotel?
Hmm-mmm. I wasn't
hopping bells, either.
I was house physician.
Three months.
Were you fired?
No, I took a job
as ship's doctor on the
New York to Bermuda run.
Five voyages.
What's this here
about Valpar...
What's that name?
Oh, it's Valparaiso.
That's down in Chile.
I did a little
hospital work
down there.
Yeah, you were there
three months, huh?
Hmm-mmm.
I see you did a little
better in Goose Liver,
Wyoming.
No, that's Goose River,
Doctor.
Ah, yeah,
you were there
almost four months.
Just about. I was
personal physician
to a wealthy rancher,
till he died.
Died, huh?
Well, that couldn't
have surprised the
poor man.
Pearson, as a doctor
who has been working
in the one community
for 35 years,
I find this
extremely painful.
I was hoping
to get a good man.
A man of substance, a man
who might perhaps stay on
and assist me in
the new hospital, but...
Oh, I couldn't
handle that, Doctor.
I'm leaving
in a couple of
months for Guatemala.
Got my passage booked.
Well, fine.
You wouldn't think of
going even sooner, huh?
Right now?
No.
You have nothing to
worry about, Doctor.
I'm really
an able physician.
To be honest, I wouldn't
trust you with me dog.
I find nothing
to recommend you.
Even your accent,
the way you speak, it's...
It's disturbin'
to New England ears.
Where did you acquire
your Yankee accent?
Don't change the subject.
I suppose you
have the agreement,
the letter I signed?
Yeah, sure.
And you regard it
as bindin'?
Of course.
Oh.
Well, Mrs. Gilley will
show you to your room.
Mrs. Gilley.
Yes, Doctor.
Pay no mind
to the old fellow.
He can be as ornery
as a hawk in a henhouse.
But he's a good man.
Well, he'll be leaving soon.
Yoo-hoo!
Oh.
Come in.
Oh, Trudy.
Well, it's finished, Doctor.
Me sweater?
Hmm-mmm. For the trip.
One fitting and we can
put the front and
back together.
Take your coat off
and turn around.
I see the new
doctor's here.
Yes.
Trudy, you're a person
I can talk to.
Hmm?
I want to tell you
about that young man.
All right.
Who?
Oh, she came in there
a minute ago.
Don't put that satchel
on my clean quilt.
Oh, I'm sorry.
She had sort of a checkered
ribbon in her hair.
Oh, that's Trudy Mason.
She's the schoolteacher.
Schoolteacher!
I never had schoolteachers
look like that when I went
to school.
I may go back and
brush up on my spelling.
Well, are you sure
he's incompetent?
I know he's incompetent.
The man's not a doctor,
he's a hobo.
He's never
been in one place for
more than three months.
And he's arrogant about it.
Oh! He sounds dreadful.
He is dreadful.
Well, then
get somebody else.
No, I made
an agreement.
I'm bound in honor.
Besides,
he has it in writing.
Oh, dear.
What's wrong?
I'm afraid it isn't
a very good fit.
Oh, I'm sure it's grand.
No, I did the thing
too fast.
Why don't you
pay him off, Doctor?
Well, that's me intention.
But if I do, I can't
get away for a vacation.
Oh, well, that's
out of the question.
You need a vacation
and you're going
to have one.
Oh, it's awful!
Oh, it isn't awful.
No, no, that's grand.
It's roomy. You know,
I like a sweater roomy.
Come in.
Say, Doctor,
did I leave my...
Well?
Well, I was going to pretend
that I came in here on
business, but...
But what?
Oh, that's nice.
That's very attractive.
Hmm.
What is it?
Secret?
It's very obviously
a sweater.
Just one?
I'm afraid
it does look more
like a woolen nightgown.
Well, woolen nightgowns are
here to stay, don't you think?
I don't think I've met
Miss Mason, Doctor.
No, I don't believe
you have.
Miss Mason,
Dr. Pearson.
Delighted to meet you.
How do you do?
You're the teacher
here, huh?
I'll talk to you
later, Doctor.
I'm being dismissed.
Doctor...
No, you are right.
I have been a bad boy.
I sang
in the washroom and
I ate Dr. McRory's fish.
Really?
Now, that'll be just
about enough, young man.
I'm gone.
See? That's what they
call doctors nowadays.
Dr. Pearson.
Yeah, huh?
I may have
seemed rude.
No.
Well, I didn't
intend to be.
Let's sit down
some place, shall we?
Nothing I'd like better.
In the parlor?
Good idea.
The sofa?
Uh, no,
this chair is fine.
I'm sort of
partial to sofas.
We didn't have any
in the Army, you know.
Fortunately,
we won the war, anyway.
So we did.
I understand you've
done a lot of traveling.
Quite a lot.
Don't you think, Doctor,
after all the things
you've done,
Fallbridge is going to be
very dull?
You don't like me,
do you?
I hadn't thought
much about it.
Do most people?
Like me?
Oh, a fair percentage.
I don't cheat at cards,
pay my bills and
I never kicked a big
dog in my entire life.
It's very quiet
in Fallbridge.
Very restful, too.
And it's going to
be awfully cold soon.
It's a little chilly
here right now.
What I mean, Doctor,
is you're obviously
a big city man,
and this is
a small place
and I honestly think
Dr. McRory would
release you,
if you wanted to leave.
Oh, you do, huh?
Yes.
Look, Teacher,
school is out.
I'm on my own now.
And I think it would be nice
if I went around making
my own decisions.
Of course.
Thanks, Teach.
A little
hot coffee, Doctor?
Yes, please.
Dr. Pearson?
No, thanks.
Come in.
Hiya.
Oh, Doc.
What's it, Nat?
Oh, good evenin'.
Morton Elkins
over at his barn,
up in the haymow,
fell and hurt his leg.
Bad?
Not good.
Want me to run
over there, Doctor?
No, thank you.
I can manage.
I'll get me bag.
Say, Mrs. Gilley.
Yes?
They have a movie
in this town?
Yes, they do.
Good.
But not tonight.
Picture show's on Tuesday.
What's showing Tuesday?
Some picture
with Bob Hope in lt.
I'll wait
till a week
from Tuesday.
Doctor.
Yeah.
You come along
with me tonight.
With you?
You'll have
a real nice time.
What are we going to do,
hit the hot spots?
Just as soon as I get
the dishes finished up.
Let me help you. Give me
a towel there and we'll
get goin'.
How could a grown man
fall from a hayloft?
He slipped.
Mort Elkins,
you clumsy fool.
Where are you?
There's no one here.
What did you expect,
a brass band?
A brass band.
Now, what kind
of a ridiculous...
Say, what's all this?
Is Morton hurt?
He's over there, Doc.
Oh, sure. Sure.
Over here, Doc.
Here I am.
Oh, it hurts
bad, too, Doc.
See, can't hardly
do this anymore.
Mort, you old
scalawag, ya!
Here, you can set his leg.
Wait till I get this
through me head.
Come on, Doctor.
Have some punch
or cider.
Great to see you, Doc.
Have a good time, Doc.
This is very
embarrassing,
Trudy.
Embarrassing?
A farewell party
and I'm not going away.
Oh, but you are
going away.
But I can't.
Well, why not?
Attention, everybody,
attention. Up here, Doc.
And Trudy.
Oh, of course.
You, too, Trudy.
We've got
to have Maine's prettiest
schoolmarm on the platform.
Well, here we are.
Sit down, everybody.
Sit down.
Let's have it
quiet, please.
We have here in Fallbridge
the biggest little chamber
of commerce in Maine.
And I'm going
to call on its president,
your friend and pharmacist,
and my son,
Mr. Roy Chesley.
Thank you,
Mr. Chesley.
Ladies and gentlemen,
I dare say that when
more than half of you
first came into the world,
and first
opened your eyes,
the first man you saw
was our guest of honor.
A man who has served this
community and served it well.
You're looking very nice
this evening, Mrs. Gilley.
Thanks.
Place we're going
ain't no hot spot.
It ain't?
You shouldn't
say "ain't," Doctor.
You say it.
I live here.
When you say it, it sounds
like you're making fun of us.
Oh, I wouldn't do that.
Not for the world,
'cause I like you.
Well,
you won't be
so bad yourself
once you learn not
to talk all the time.
Now, a word
from Trudy Mason.
Oh, Trudy.
Dr. McRory,
your friends,
and that means
all of us here
in Fallbridge,
want you to have
this for your trip,
with all our love.
Well, uh, thanks.
Open the bag.
Look inside, Doc.
Look inside.
Go ahead.
What in the world is this?
It's your new
hospital, Doctor.
That's right.
Ain't that
a neat little model?
Mort did a good
job of it.
The excavating
starts next week.
That's right. And we've
got every dime raised, Doc.
Well, well.
You're good people,
all of you.
Uh, and...
As on this date,
all outstandin' bills
due to me are cancelled.
Every penny.
I don't think
I've felt like this
since I was a little kid
on Christmas mornin'.
Good evening, Mrs. Gilley.
Good evening.
That's all.
Who's he?
Evening, Mrs. Gilley.
Good evening.
Good evening, Abbie.
Hello.
Good evening.
Dr. Pearson,
this is Roy Chesley.
How do you do?
Glad to meet you.
Well, thank you.
And his father,
Mr. C.J. Chesley.
How do you do, sir?
Pearson, Trudy and
I were discussing you.
Why, that's
very flattering.
I'm president
of the Fallbridge
Chamber of Commerce...
Oh, really?
Say, would you
hold this a minute?
Miss Mason and I
have this dance.
Oh, uh... Well...
Uh-huh.
Doc, Trudy told me about
your problem with that fellow.
Let me handle him.
No, no.
There's a friend of mine
in Augusta. Dr. Jenks.
He's a fine MD.
He can be here Friday.
Well, looks
good enough
to eat.
Really heartwarming, this
New England hospitality,
isn't it?
All these nice,
friendly faces.
Fella down at the board of
education was telling me of
a new ruling they have there.
Guess he must
have been wrong.
What ruling?
They told me it was okay now
for schoolteachers to smile.
Oh, yes, he must
have been wrong.
Well, I heard that...
Well, I must
have been wrong, too.
Could be.
What have you heard?
Oh, the impression I had
that doctors always had
good manners.
May I?
Of course.
Dr. Pearson.
Hmm.
I'm Bill Walters.
Yeah?
Editor, reporter, copy boy
of the town's leading and
only newspaper.
So?
I'm drunk.
That was my diagnosis.
I wanna give you
a little advice.
Get drunk.
The town's more
charming that way.
Well, I'll sleep on it.
Folks. Attention.
Attention, please.
I've got some
disappointing news.
No square dances tonight.
I'm sorry, but Jeff Hawkins
just phoned from Bentonville.
He has to work tonight
and he can't be here
to do the call.
It's my big chance.
Oh, Mr. Chesley.
Yes?
I learned a little bit
about these barn dances
when I was out in Wyoming.
Do you mind if I try?
Get your partners
for a square dance, huh?
Say, do you fellas
know Country Style?
Yeah, we do, but...
Young man, we are
perfectly capable of
managing our own affairs.
And we don't have any
square dances without
Jeff Hawkins.
Well, it's a shame
he isn't here.
Then we could have
done a very nice duet.
Contact.
All set?
Well,
you pull up your pants
You tighten your traces
You all join hands
You're off to the races
Break your holds
and you backtrack back
Promenade, single file
Ladies in the lead
that Indian style
And swing that gal
behind you
Cut across and swing Grandpa
He ain't been swung
since last fall
Ladies start a-center
Gents on a little side bet
Meet your partner
You ain't through yet
It's four hands 'round
with the couple you met
Four hands up
and around you go
And when you get straight
it's a do-see-do
Chicken in the bread pan
picking out the dough
Grab your partners
A- home you go
Ladies to the center
Back to the bar
Gents to the center
You form a star
Pick your partner, promenade
Around the track
Don't stay in the shade
Gents swing out
and the ladies swing in
They cross their hands
and you're off again
Ladies swing out
and you all eight swing
Now you're back home
in the same old ring
First and third,
you balance and swing
Down the center
Divide the ring
Ladies go east
and the gents go west
Meet in line
Four abreast
Forward eight
and fall back eight
Forward again with
a right and a left
Cross the hall
and you pass them all
And take that
very pretty gal with you
Meet your partner
Promenade eight
Round the old track
till you come out straight
First and third
You balance and swing
You lead right out
to the right of the ring
You right and left through
and a right and left back
Promenade all around
the track
When it comes
to fancy dancin'
Or to music with a smile
Or to nice romancin'
Make mine country style
When it comes
to hands that hold ya
Eyes that shine about a mile
Like I just now told ya
Make mine country style
Hear that fiddle
I could listen all night
Hear that banjo
Ain't that somethin'?
Darn right
Dance and share
a lovin' cup
With different partners
for a while
But for hitchin' up with
Make mine country style
When it comes
to fancy dancin'
Or to music with a smile
Or to nice romancin'
Make mine country style
When it comes
to hands that hold ya
Eyes that shine about a mile
Like I just now told ya
Make mine country style
Catch that couple
Cosh all hemlock
Gee whiz
Ain't that snappy?
Ain't that steppin'?
Sure is
Dance and share a lovin' cup
With different partners
for a while
But for hitchin' up with
Make mine country style
Country style
How about
a nice waltz?
Okay.
Number four, fellas.
Pardon me.
Huh?
No, Trudy,
it's Pearson I want.
Well, no, I think
I prefer to dance
with Miss Mason.
She's prettier.
Hello, Trudy.
You'll pardon me?
Yeah.
Pearson, you're not going to
win any popularity contests
in Fallbridge.
I haven't entered any.
You know, I learned
how to handle fellows
like you in the Army.
I was a captain.
Well, I learned how
to handle captains.
I was a major.
Let me give you some advice.
Are you a lawyer?
No, I'm a pharmacist.
Well,
I might send you some of
my prescription business.
Oh, say, some day
I wish you'd show me
how to make
a good banana split.
I do love banana splits.
Pardon me.
Cutting in seems to be
your specialty, Doctor.
Oh, no,
I'm a general practitioner.
Do you
generally go around
making friends this way?
I'd rather concentrate
on just making one friend.
I like blue eyes.
Am I supposed
to say, "Thank you, Doctor.
I'm glad you like blue eyes"?
Well, you could
say that.
But I'd just
as soon you looked up
and gave me a nice smile.
I like your smile, too.
Is that
the shipboard approach
or the bedside manner?
Teacher.
You know, I can't
really figure out
which of
the Chesleys
I dislike more.
Roy or his father.
Oh?
I guess Roy, though.
I guess he's a little more
obnoxious, don't you think?
Dr. Pearson.
What?
Roy and I are
going to be married.
Thanks for the dance.
Seems downright stubborn,
you goin' away so
sudden-like.
I did plan to
stay a little longer.
You haven't
told the Doctor?
I haven't seen him,
but he'll be delighted.
Old fool!
I'm driving you
to the bus.
You are?
In Andy Weaver's
pickup truck.
And we can take
this with us, too.
There's no sense in your
wasting your money on
that Dorkas.
I'll appreciate that,
Mrs. Gilley.
I'll take
your horse blanket.
Just about the shortest
engagement I ever had.
Make mine city style
Oh, my achin' back.
Aren't we going the
wrong way?
No.
Before leaving,
you'll want to
see the Doctor.
Oh.
There he is.
Why, that old phony.
Didn't he tell you
he had an urgent
pneumonia case?
He did.
How'd you know
he was here, then?
Fishing poles and boots
don't cure pneumonia.
Take your time, Doctor.
The bus don't
leave till 4:00.
I'll be back.
Hey! How's Mrs. Hickey
comin' along?
Huh?
How's Mrs. Hickey doin'?
Oh, her pneumonia
is better. Much better.
Oh, glad to hear that.
Young man,
are you spying on me?
No, I've just come to
tell you I was leaving.
Are you now? Well...
Ah, yes.
You'll not be leaving
for a couple of weeks?
Next bus.
Pearson,
I'm an honest man.
I'll not pretend
I'm going to miss you.
But I'd be
greatly obliged
if you'd stay on
for a fortnight when
I have a good doctor coming.
Oh, that is, this man Jenks
is most highly recommended.
Roy Chesley says he...
I thought you told me
you wouldn't hire
a man again
without seeing him first.
Well, yes, I did.
But this
could be nothin'
but an improvement.
Improvement?
Why don't we start
the improvement
right now, then.
Goodbye, Doctor.
Pearson!
What?
Be reasonable.
I want to start
me trip on Friday.
No.
Now, I'm not asking you to
handle any difficult cases.
If anything serious
comes up before
Jenks arrives,
Wheaton will come over
from Bentonville.
No. Next bus. Goodbye.
I'll give you
a cash bonus
if you stay.
Say $10... Say $5.
You said $10.
Did I?
Yeah.
All right, Doctor, $10.
No, Doctor.
The town doesn't like me
and I don't like the town.
I better get out today.
You'll never
catch anything with
that routine, either.
I've been fishin' here
for 35 years.
Have you now?
Then maybe it's time
you had a few suggestions.
Do you mind?
So you're
a fisherman, too?
Well, I ought to be
a standout in this league.
Let me see this
equipment you got here.
What are you doing
with this big buoy on?
My heavens!
I like to get the hook
down into the fish's
living room.
Down deep.
Down where the money is.
Let's see.
Get it way out there, deep.
There we are.
Stand by for action.
Well, that's interesting.
Very interesting.
You'll stay for
a couple of weeks, eh?
No.
My heart is a hobo
Loves to roam through
fields of clover
Are you
deliberately trying
to scare away the fish?
On the contrary.
Best audience I ever had
was an eight pound trout.
How he loved
boogie-woogie.
My heart is a hobo
Loves to roam through
fields of clover
Hates to have
to think things over
And though it's wrong
I string along
My heart is a hobo
Loves to go out
berry-picking
Hates to hear
alarm clocks ticking
It isn't smart
But that's my heart
When hopes are out
at the elbows
And dreams are run down
at the heels
My heart refuses to worry
Except about
rods and reels
My heart is a hobo
Loves to quote
from Omar Khayyam
Hates the stodgy guy
that I am
And though it's strange
I just can't change
my heart
Doc! Bill Walters
is in bad shape.
I just took him home.
What's it?
Whiskey?
No. One of his
bustin' headaches.
Tell him to take two of
the capsules I gave him.
Well...
Is that the
newspaper fellow?
Yeah.
What causes
the headaches?
Wish I knew.
Don't you think he ought
to be seen? Be examined?
Examination
shows nothing.
I've had him in me
office a dozen times.
I think
I'll run over and
take a look at him. Here.
You?
Yeah. Doctor.
I don't think I could stay
for a fortnight, but I'll
tell you what I'll do.
What?
I'll stay a couple of weeks.
Coming
right with you, Nat.
Used up about 20 cents
worth of gas gettin'
out here.
Well, I'll take your
temperature sometime.
On the house.
My heart is a hobo
Loves to roam through
fields of clover
Doctor, Nat's still
waiting for you.
Well, tell him to go ahead.
I'll walk home.
Come on in, Emily.
Did you find out what's
wrong with him, Doctor?
No, I'm afraid not.
I'd like to have been
here during the attack.
Blood pressure's a little
high, but that shouldn't
do it.
A dozen doctors
have told me that.
Pretty interesting
case, huh?
I'd like to speak to
your father alone,
Emily, huh?
Yes, sir.
Want a drink?
No, thanks.
Would you guess, Doctor,
that the present editor
of the Fallbridge Weekly
once won a Pulitzer Prize?
Well, I did,
back in Boston.
Were you drinking
better whiskey then?
I wasn't drinking then.
Whiskey isn't why I'm here.
The reason I'm here is
because you can't work
on a daily paper
and have your head
splitting wide open
half the time.
I might be able
to find out something
about those headaches
if I could examine you
some day when you're
not drinking.
Why don't
you lay off for,
well, till Friday?
I could say I would,
but a drunk's promise
isn't worth very much.
That's a mighty sweet kid
you have there.
Yeah.
Pretty busy girl, huh?
Mmm-hmm.
Oh, Doctor.
Yes.
Do you think
you can help him?
Well, I'm going
to try, Emily.
Oh, please do.
I'm not sure,
but I have a hunch
your father isn't
going to drink
for awhile.
Well, I don't know.
Don't you go
to school, Emily?
When Papa's well, I do.
Doctor,
we won't be able
to pay you for a while.
Well, that's all right.
You can pay me
when you've married some
big billionaire lumberman.
With 4% interest.
I'm going to marry
a newspaper man.
We'll waive
the interest.
Emily!
Oh.
I'll have to put off
making any resolutions
till tomorrow, Doctor.
I just found
another bottle.
I'd better...
I'd better fix his supper.
And your ticket,
you haven't forgotten
your ticket?
You asked me
that twice, Mrs. Gilley.
It's in me wallet. I think.
And your woolen muffler?
Yes, in me wallet.
Where the blue blazes
is Pearson?
No occasion for
profanity, Doctor.
All right,
all right,
all right.
Now, bear in mind,
anything important,
telephone Dr. Wheaton
in Bentonville.
Yes, you told that
to Dr. Pearson.
Oh, that Pearson!
Now, he knows I'm leaving.
Oh, it's you, Nat.
Will you take these out,
Mr. Dorkas?
Nice bag.
Makes the others
look terrible.
You didn't see Pearson?
No.
And don't forget
these, Mr. Dorkas.
I only got two hands,
Mrs. Gilley.
Well, I'll wait
two minutes longer.
Doctor!
Huh?
Emily!
Good afternoon.
What's your hurry?
Well, I just saw you and
I thought I'd get home
before it started raining.
I see.
How's your dad?
He's fine.
He hasn't been...
Good.
He has confidence
in you, Doctor.
I have, too.
Oh, I'm glad about that.
Doctor.
Huh?
I must have
sounded awfully vain
when I told
you I was going to
marry a newspaperman.
But still, men do marry
girls who aren't pretty,
don't they?
Well, you have
nothing to worry about.
A gal with your good looks.
Doctor.
Hmm?
If I asked you a question,
I mean casually, not like
a visit,
well, would there be a fee?
Well, it depends upon
how casually you ask
the question.
You see,
I was wondering...
I saw in
a newspaper
advertisement
that if you send in a dollar,
well, they send you back
something for freckles.
Freckles?
Do you think
you need any more?
Oh, I mean
to get rid of 'em.
Oh, you must be kidding.
But I'm not.
Well, it's a good thing
you came to me then,
because I want to
straighten you out
on something.
Don't you know that in
New York, Paris and
Hollywood, too,
women are not considered
smart unless they have
freckles.
Those glamour girls,
they sit around in
the sun all day
just trying to pick up a few.
They do?
You've read about
Cleopatra, haven't you?
Yes.
And her freckles?
Did she have freckles?
Why, they used
to call her Speck.
Thank you, Doctor.
I don't believe a word
you said, but thank you.
So long, Cleo.
Well, Nat,
what's the latest
scuttle on the weather?
See it bankin' up
over there?
Yeah, got it.
Be comin' down soon.
That's your
considered opinion, huh?
Yeah.
The young blatherskite.
He knows I'm leavin'.
Now, now, now.
Don't get yourself
overheated.
Here's your umbrella.
You haven't been
feelin' too well.
And how could
I feel well?
Haven't you left yet,
Doctor?
And how could I leave
without giving you
instructions?
I thought I had
my instructions.
If anybody gets sick,
I'm to call Dr. Wheaton.
Young man, I can do
without the sarcasm.
Now, Wheaton will come
over for serious cases.
Okay.
You stay here
till Jenks arrives.
Right.
See that Mrs. Sims takes
calcium tablets for
her chilblains.
Calcium tablets.
Yeah.
And give Miss Lennek
some sugar pills.
Sugar pills?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
She thinks she's ill.
Oh, I get it.
Yeah, and Mat Tewson's
carbuncle's about ready
for lancing.
All right.
Yes.
And you might
drop in on Mrs. Krelly.
Her baby is about due.
Doctor, do you think
I'm quite capable
of delivering a baby?
Frankly, no. But I'm not
worrying about Mrs. Krelly.
She's had 10.
She'll tell you what to do.
It's starting to rain.
Oh, all right.
I have me umbrella.
Well, goodbye, Mrs. Gilley.
Well, I'm...
Nat's gonna drop me off
at the Ladies' Aide.
So long, Doctor.
Hope you have good fishing.
Goodbye.
Now, remember, no surgeries.
No surgeries.
Miss Lennek's sugar pills.
Mrs. Sims gets
some calcium tablets.
Mat Tewson's carbuncle's
about ready to pluck.
Oh, Doctor, I'll run back
and get you a little
baking soda.
You will not.
Get in there.
Everyone thinks
he's a doctor
around here.
Drive on at once!
My heart is a hobo
Loves to roam through
fields of clover
Hates to have
to think things over
And though it's wrong
I string along
My heart is a hobo
Loves to go out
berry-picking
Hates to hear
alarm clocks...
Hello.
Oh, hello.
I've missed him,
haven't I?
Dr. McRory? Yeah,
a few minutes ago.
My car wouldn't start.
You couldn't lend me
an umbrella, could you?
Well, ordinarily,
there's a small charge
for that service,
but in your case,
we'll waive it.
Help yourself.
Thank you.
Don't let it
get around, huh?
No, I won't.
Oh, say, Teach, I have
some good news for you.
You have?
Mmm-hmm.
I'll be leaving soon.
Well, I'm sorry
there won't be time
for a civic celebration,
but I'm sure
the town is grateful.
Oh, you know, those
are the first kind words
I've heard in Fallbridge.
My heart is a hobo
Loves to quote
from Omar Khayyam
Hates the stodgy guy
that I am
And though it's strange
I just can't
change my heart
Dr. Pearson!
Open up! Open up!
What's the matter?
What happened?
Well, we get to the bus
and he seemed to be fine.
Pain in me stomach.
Let's get this
wet coat off.
We no more
than shake hands,
he keeled over, like
he was kicked by a mule.
Help me carry him
in the office.
No, no.
I can walk.
I'll help you.
What is it?
I don't know.
Will you wait here?
Pearson,
call Dr. Wheaton.
He's sick. Mighty sick.
What's wrong?
I ain't no doctor
and I don't think
Pearson is neither.
Well, call me
if you need me.
Call Dr. Wheaton.
We will, Doctor.
Oh, me appendix.
Probably have to come out.
Trudy!
Pearson, I wish
you'd let me alone.
Take it easy, Doctor.
Now, you've had your
finger jabbed before.
Certainly.
I don't mind a little thing
like that.
You don't have
to jab me so deep.
One, two, three, four, five.
What's
the blood count?
Wait a minute.
Nine lymps, two monocytes,
16,000 whites, 89% polys.
Oh, Trudy,
call Dr. Wheaton.
Bentonville 1-4-8.
1-4 what?
Bentonville 1-4...
Look, please
get off the line.
This is an emergency call.
Dr. McRory's office.
It's that chatterbox,
Mrs. Higgins, I suppose.
Thank you.
Operator?
Bentonville 1-4-8.
Was it Mrs. Higgins?
Mrs. Sims.
That one is just as bad.
I don't think I'd put
off the operation, Doctor.
Nice vacation!
Hello.
Is Dr. Wheaton there?
Oh.
He's gone to Elktown
on a confinement case.
He won't be back until 10:00.
We can't wait, Doctor.
Can't? We must wait.
I'd take you to
the Bentonville
hospital myself.
But it's a long trip
in the rain and
the roads are rough.
I'd better
operate here.
You?
Pearson, I may be
a very sick man but me
mind is perfectly clear.
I'd as soon call in
Sweeney The Butcher.
Let's be sensible,
Doctor.
I know
that you don't have
any confidence in me,
but there isn't
any other choice.
Your pulse is 108.
Trudy, call Dr. Blodgett
of Millbrook.
Is this Millbrook
near here?
Over 90 miles.
Look, Doctor...
No.
You speak to him,
Miss Mason.
You know what
a perforated appendix can do.
The danger
of peritonitis.
Dr. McRory, please.
It has to
be done, Doctor,
and immediately.
Pearson, I warn you, if
you operate against me will,
you'll go to prison
for manslaughter.
Doctor, you've had a lot
more experience than I have.
Now, what would you do with
a patient as ornery, as cranky
and as downright
disagreeable as you are?
Now, that's not
a fair question.
Come on, Doctor,
we'll get you ready
for the operation.
No, no.
Pearson,
have you operated before?
Certainly.
Well...
Miss Mason,
you're going to help me.
What?
Mmm-hmm.
Well, all right.
Come on, Doctor.
Well, I've had a good life.
Me fishin' tackle
goes to Mort Elkins,
a true friend.
Andy Weaver is
to have me pipes.
Doctor.
No, no,
write it down
as I tell you, Trudy.
Mrs. Gilley...
I'm sorry, Doctor,
but Miss Mason will have
to give up her legal work.
I need a nurse.
Me house goes
to Mrs. Gilley
and me war bonds and
savings go to you,
Trudy,
and to little
Emily Walters.
Pearson, you're a witness.
Come on, you'll be up
playing football in
three weeks.
No. I know.
Even with a good surgeon,
10% of peritonitis cases
are lost.
Well, then
you needn't worry.
I've already lost my 10%.
What are you doin' there?
Put that away!
I'll take no ether.
I want a local
anesthetic, Pearson.
Now, be reasonable,
Doctor.
I'd like to
give you a spinal
if I had somebody to
watch your blood pressure.
And who said anything
about a spinal?
I said a local.
Oh, Doctor!
Believe me, Pearson,
you'll be grateful
for my supervision.
I've had a lot
of experience.
Well, I've told you this
isn't my first operation.
A local, please.
All right.
Trudy, you see that
over there?
Get it.
What?
The mirror.
The mirror?
Yes, the mirror.
Yes.
Here?
Do you know how to
locate the appendix?
Yes, I do.
What kind of incision
are you planning?
A McBurney.
No, no.
Make a lateral.
Give you more exposure.
And the sutures,
you're using catgut?
Silk.
Oh, no,
I don't hold with silk.
Use catgut.
Doctor, maybe you
better do it yourself.
And how can
I do it meself?
If you can't, then let me.
Your instructions clear?
I... I think so.
Well, Doctor,
remember, no movement.
Trudy,
move your head a little.
I can't see
into the mirror.
Maybe it's as well
we didn't wait.
Is it over?
It's over.
Is he all right?
He's asleep.
Oh, thank heavens.
You did a fine job,
Miss Mason.
Thank you.
Doctor! Doctor!
Mrs. Gilley!
Hello, Doctor.
Good morning.
Hi, Doc.
Howdy, Dr. Pearson.
Hello, boys.
How's the old doc?
Oh, he looks better
than I do.
Say, I hear
you saved his life.
He sure did.
I had to.
He owed me
a week's salary.
He's a joker.
Did a good job, eh?
Oh, Dr. Pearson!
Hello, Miss Lennek.
Going on the sleigh
ride this evening?
It's our annual.
Oh, I wish I could.
Dr. Pearson!
Nurse Mason.
Hello, Chesley.
Hello. What will it be?
I'd like
a couple of dozen
phenobarbital tablets.
Half gram.
Jed Conway's account.
Well...
That's a hypertension case.
Yes, that's right.
We have some
potassium thiocyanate.
I believe it's
considered more modern.
Would you
be terribly offended if
I insisted upon phenobarbital?
No, just as you say.
Thanks.
Say, Nurse,
I'm taking out
some tonsils tomorrow.
Would you like to join me?
Are you doing it with mirrors?
That was quite
the experience, wasn't it?
I had one disappointment.
What's the matter?
I had the impression
you always sang
during surgery.
Well, it was
sort of unexpected.
Forgot my music.
But, you know,
I don't think you realize
just how wonderful you were.
I've had
experienced nurses who
weren't nearly so helpful.
Well, you were a help, Doctor.
Really?
I don't think I could
have saved Dr. McRory alone.
Oh, you...
Of course,
Dr. Pearson knows
that an appendectomy is
probably the simplest
of all operations.
Roy!
No, he's right.
Oh, I don't
mean to belittle
Dr. Pearson, Trudy.
But you do know that
appendix operations
are often performed
even by pharmacists.
Still?
Well, on shipboard.
In the movies, too.
Well, thank you.
Oh, Doctor...
Yeah.
I don't suppose you'd care
to go along on the
sleigh ride.
I imagine
Dr. Pearson
is too busy.
Well, I am, yes. But
you'll have a lot of
fun, I know.
Bye, Nurse.
Goodbye, Doctor.
Hello.
Hello, Emily.
Oh, hello, Doctor.
Ronnie!
It's Ronnie Jenks.
Why, certainly
I'll pick you up.
In person.
You wait for me at
the Elktown station.
The new doctor?
Yes, he's
Butch Jenks' brother.
I've told you
about Butch Jenks.
Well, this kid
is just like him.
Well, if you're
going to Elktown,
won't we miss
the sleigh ride?
No, you go right ahead.
I'll meet the
sleigh in Bentonville.
At the church supper.
And we'll have the
ride back together.
How's your father?
Fine.
He's only had one attack
and he's still drinking tea.
Good.
I'll examine him
again before I leave.
But, Doctor...
Yeah.
Is it unethical for
a doctor to take
a girl with him
on his calls?
No. I wouldn't think so.
Come along.
Thank you.
I'd love to.
Of course I don't
blame you for going away.
You are, huh?
Mmm-hmm.
As soon as
Dr. Jenks gets here.
I guess
for people like us,
Fallbridge is awful slow.
Awfully.
Doctor.
Yeah.
If I asked you
a very frank question,
well, would you give me
a frank answer?
I'll try, Emily.
Well, did you
really mean it
when you said that
you thought I was pretty?
Indeed I did.
Thank you.
You're quite welcome.
And, Doctor.
Mmm?
Has it ever occurred to you
that in five years, I'll be
practically 18?
No, no, it hadn't,
but five years and
practically 13 is
practically 18.
That's simple arithmetic.
And besides, in
some parts of the world,
not that I approve
of it, of course,
but girls often get
married when they're 10.
Emily Walters.
You're an old maid.
Well?
Looks like it froze up.
Must be out of alcohol.
Do you have any?
Well, I got to
thaw it out first.
I'll have it
over at Doc's house
first thing in the morning.
Well, how are we
going to get home?
Well, if
Molly wasn't sick,
she could drive you in.
Well, Mr. Pinkett,
your wife's going
to be all right.
But you've been
letting her work
a little too hard.
Here's my prescription.
One hired girl.
Mmm-hmm,
that's what she needs.
A couple of days rest in bed.
That'll be $2.
Doc McRory would rather have
Mrs. Pinkett's pickles
than cash.
Well, there's
this to be considered.
A man with some
pickles laid by
ain't likely
to lose them on
the horses, is he?
You'll enjoy them, Doc.
Look, Doctor!
Hello!
Howdy, Nat.
How about giving us a lift?
Howdy, Doc!
Sure.
If you're heading
for Bentonville.
Sleigh ride's a dollar.
Church supper is extra.
Come on along.
Yes, why don't you?
If you haven't
any calls to make.
Come on, Doc!
Sure, come on!
Well, calls are all finished.
What do you say, Emily?
Gee, yes!
You've got a date.
Get aboard.
Come on then.
Say, Mr. Pinkett,
would you call
Mrs. Gilley and tell her
that I can be
reached through the
Bentonville operator?
And tell
Bill Walters
that Emily's with me.
Say, Doc.
Huh?
Fixing cars is
a business with me.
That'll cost you $2.
Certainly.
Are you done?
Hey, Trudy,
have an apple.
Keep the doctor away.
Save the apple for Roy.
Nice going, fellas.
They are very rude,
but she is engaged.
I know.
Where is Roy?
He's meeting the new
doctor, Ronnie Jenks.
Oh.
Sorry you're leaving.
Me, too.
I imagine a girl
who isn't engaged
is even sorrier
when someone
is leaving.
Don't you think so,
Miss Mason?
Yes, I do.
Are you warm enough, Emily?
Uh-huh, except
for a little draft.
Oh, well,
let's fix it.
There we are. There.
Thank you.
Better?
Uh-huh.
Are you all right?
Oh, fine, thank you.
How is Roy, Miss Mason?
He's fine.
Say, all this kidding
and everything,
Roy isn't
apt to take it
seriously, is he?
Roy? Oh, no.
Hmm-mmm.
You don't really
know Roy, Doctor.
He's very understanding.
He knows that
you and I are...
Yes, we are.
Here we are.
Mind you, Ronnie,
he's not young.
And I won't say
his methods are
very modern.
It's precisely why
I'm here.
The more old-fashioned he is,
the sooner I'll get to be
number one boy.
Oh, Mr. Chesley,
come in.
Thank you.
How are you feeling,
Mrs. Gilley?
Oh, well enough,
I guess.
This is
a quaint
old place.
Mrs. Gilley,
will you please
tell Dr. McRory
that Dr. Jenks is here?
Dr. Jenks?
Yes.
This way.
Doctor!
Will the
masked rider get there
in time
to save Annie from
Black Horse Baskin?
Listen in tomorrow,
same time, same station...
... when crispy,
crackly, creamy
crusties presents another...
Doctor...
Hello.
Hello, Dr. McRory.
Glad to see you, Roy.
This is my very
good friend,
Dr. Jenks.
Jenks?
How are you, Doctor?
I'm satisfactory,
thank you.
Everything is set.
Jenks is moving
into that little cottage
Dad owns across the street.
And he's ready to take over.
Take over?
Take over what?
Well, your practice, Doctor,
as I understand it,
until you...
Young man, I hope you
haven't traveled
very far
because I have
no opening for you.
Huh?
But, Dr. McRory,
you asked him
to come here.
Oh, no, Roy,
you asked him.
I'm very sorry,
but I have the most
excellent man with me now.
And I see no reason
for a change. Thank you.
Now, wait a minute,
Doctor.
You made it quite clear that
you consider Pearson just
as I do.
An incompetent, arrogant,
vaudeville singer,
not a doctor.
Now, you needn't
distort the facts, Roy.
Dr. Pearson's
a man of great ability.
Which I...
Yes, I was the
very first to recognize.
And he's a fine surgeon.
And as for objection
to a doctor singing,
well, now, what sort of
narrow-minded nonsense
is that?
I'm surprised at you, Roy.
Well, I guess there's
nothing more to say.
Yes, there's
one thing more.
I'll thank you
not to use me to get
your friends employment.
And now,
if you don't mind,
I'll be taking me rest.
I don't want
to be disturbed.
Yes, you should.
I won't forget this, Doctor.
See that you don't.
Goodbye.
Is Dr. Pearson
really staying on?
Why wouldn't
he be staying on?
The position of
assistant director
and chief surgeon
in the most
modern hospital
in all of Maine...
Did he... Did he
say he was staying?
Mrs. Gilley,
I'm not a well man.
All this chitter, chitter,
chatter is most disturbing.
Turn on me radio, please.
It's funny, Roy's
not showing up, hmm?
Yes.
Lovely night.
Beautiful.
As long as I'm dreaming
How nice it can be
How nice to have you
In love with me
Did you know
that you just kissed me?
What a thrill I got
As long as I'm dreaming
My love
If I were just wishing
What good would it do
What chance would I have
To wish for you
If you never know
I love you
Still it works out fine
As long as I'm dreaming
You're mine
The doctor is as good
as Frank Sinatra.
Yes, and I can take
your blood pressure
at the same time.
Oh! Oh, well.
Don't worry about
Emily, Doctor.
I'll get her home.
Thank you,
Miss Lennek.
Good night, everybody.
Good night.
Good night, Miss Mason.
Good night, Doctor.
Trudy, Trudy.
Yes?
Roy Chesley has been
telephoning.
He wants you to
call him right away.
All right,
I'll take it from here.
Good night, Nat.
Hello, Doctor.
Back in bed again, huh?
Did you get a little tired?
Ah, no, I'm all right.
Well, I hear you were on
the sleigh ride.
Yeah.
Had a good time?
Oh, wonderful.
Trudy was there?
Yeah.
Without Roy?
Mmm-hmm.
Well, what do you
think of that?
Ah, there's
a fine girl, Trudy.
Great pity she's throwing
herself away on that rag,
Roy Chesley.
Don't you think?
He's
a pretty stuffy fellow.
Pulse is good.
Yeah, Trudy, Trudy...
She tells me that
Dr. Jenks has arrived, huh?
Oh, that blatherskite.
Most incompetent young man.
And so rude. He went away.
Huh?
Wait a minute, here.
I'm leaving, you know,
as soon as you're well.
Oh, I have another
doctor coming.
Yes, yes.
Who?
A Dr. Gilrooney.
What's his first name?
What's that?
First name?
Oh, Peter.
A very nice young man.
But far from
your acumen, boy.
Well, naturally.
Yes, of course.
If you change
your mind...
No. Anyway you'll be up
and around in a week or so.
You'll be back on the job
all by yourself.
All by myself.
How those words
describe me whole life.
I'd like you to see
something, Doctor.
Lovely young lady,
isn't she?
Oh, she's lovely, yeah.
I was very fond of her,
very fond.
And she of me.
What happened?
Oh, you know,
just a young doctor
just starting,
not too bright. Yeah.
While I was
making up me mind,
she married.
And now,
I'm a lonely old man.
Don't make the
mistake I made, me son,
or you'll be lonely, too.
Trudy has a very
high opinion of you.
Doctor, I'm leaving
at the end of the week.
Oh, don't think
for a moment that
I intended to say that...
Close, please.
I was...
Close. Please.
Oh, listen to me.
We waited for you there.
I know. I know. I saw
you waiting, both of you.
I drive all the way
to Bentonville and...
Oh, I'm sorry you're upset.
Honestly, I am.
Well, where can
I see you later?
Oh, at my place
in half an hour.
At the boarding house
Goodbye.
Right on the line.
Could have told you that
before you took it.
Hello, Doctor.
How's our patient?
Oh, he's himself again.
Health, fine.
Disposition, terrible.
Dr. Pearson, telephone.
Yeah?
Excuse me.
Anybody I know?
I doubt it.
Trudy, sit down.
Yes, Doctor?
Oh, it'll be a sad day for
Fallbridge when that
young man leaves.
Great ability.
It's too bad that...
What's too bad?
Oh, no. It's not for me
to violate a confidence.
Still...
No, no, no.
You know you're going
to tell me, Doctor, so...
All right. Then,
perhaps I should.
Dr. Pearson
is most unhappy.
What about?
About your
engagement to Roy.
Did he say so?
More.
He says you're engaged
to a stuffy young man.
Oh?
And that's why
he's going away.
He's not happy, Trudy.
He doesn't show it,
you know, but...
Well, population
of East Fallbridge
is about to increase.
Mrs. Chanock.
Edie Chanock? Oh, a fine,
healthy girl. Her first.
Say, how do I get there?
Oh, if you go...
Oh, well, no, you'd
never find your
way there.
Not on these
roads at night.
Oh, I'd better
drive you there myself.
If you'd just
hand me my gown...
No, you can't do that.
I know
the house, Doctor.
I'll take you there.
Now, isn't that
very generous of her?
It's very sweet of you.
Come on.
I brought your hot milk.
A lovely pair
they'd make, huh?
What on earth
are you doing with
my cousin Hattie's picture?
And my album?
Oh, well, they...
When they...
You see, it's...
Old pictures, old wine.
Old buttinsky.
Well, another
couple of weeks,
I'll be on a boat.
Going where?
There's only
one place to go
this time of the year.
Go south.
Doesn't having a home
mean anything to you?
Well, you bet it does.
That's why I have so many.
What did I do?
Say something funny?
No, not you. Dr. McRory.
He said you were
going away heartbroken.
Heartbroken? Over what?
Me. He'd do anything
to have you stay.
Oh.
He told me you were
a pretty fine fellow.
Cupid McRory, yeah?
Well, he couldn't have
set a more attractive trap.
Thank you.
Come in, Doctor.
We've been waiting for you.
Give me a lift
with this bag, man.
Oh, sure.
I'll run along in.
All right.
Everything all right?
Oh. Where's the doctor?
He'll be in
in a minute.
Well, tell him to come
right in the bedroom.
And sit down, won't you?
In there.
Her ma's with her.
Here. Let me have that.
Is he any good?
Dr. Pearson? Very good.
Gee, I hope so.
Dr. McRory
couldn't come, huh?
No, but you...
Trudy, this is gonna
take a little time.
You better run along.
I can get home all right.
Oh, I'll wait.
Is she all right, Doc?
She's fine.
Anything I can do?
No.
Well, yes. Do you
have a checkerboard?
Checkerboard?
Makes the time go faster.
Doctor.
Yes?
You better come in now.
I'll be right with you.
You take care
of the father,
huh, Trudy?
I will.
Gosh!
It's my first one.
There's my grandson.
A boy? My son.
Ed, she wants to see you.
He's so little.
And so...
Well, here we are.
I was asleep.
Not much of
a night's rest
for a gal who
has to be at school
at 9:00 in the morning.
You're frostbitten?
Just cold.
Let me see.
Well?
Roy?
You were gonna
meet me in a half hour.
Some half hour.
Oh, I'm terribly sorry, Roy.
I meant to phone you.
But a woman in
East Fallbridge
had a baby, and...
Of course,
you had to be there.
Without your help,
women in East Fallbridge
couldn't have babies.
Well, Chesley,
it's really my fault.
I didn't know the roads
and she...
I'd like you to
keep out of this.
I'd like to
keep out of it, too, Roy.
I'm sorry I've upset you.
I tried to explain
and I'm very tired.
Good night.
Good night, Doctor.
I think with
all your equipment,
you better take my car.
You can drop it off later.
Thank you, Trudy.
Oh, so it's Trudy now?
Isn't that my name?
You seem to forget that
it's also gonna be Chesley.
Roy, people are sleeping.
Maybe you'd
like to forget
that we're engaged.
When you talk that way,
yes, I would.
That's what I thought.
Well, it's fine with me!
I'll give you two minutes
to take that back.
She didn't mean that.
She'll be right back.
Then you better wait.
I ought to
punch your nose.
Maybe I better wait.
Yes, there's
a couple of things
I'd like to settle with you.
Certainly.
Now, don't think
I'm worried.
Miss Mason is far too smart
to throw herself away on
a hobo doctor.
A guy who gets paid
in jellies and
sauerkraut.
Not always. I had a very
big day yesterday.
I got pickles.
I'm not thinking
of myself.
If I thought
she'd be happy with you
living in
a freight car,
I'd say, "Fine!"
That's very noble of you.
I can be noble.
What's wrong with that?
Nothing.
I'm impressed.
I'm thinking of her
own good. Are you?
Well, no.
I don't think I am.
Are your intentions marriage?
Now, that's a notion
I've always tried
to avoid.
Listen to me, Pearson...
Wait a minute.
Quiet. We seem to have
picked up quite an audience.
Let's keep it bright, huh?
Boys, people
are trying to sleep.
I tried to sleep, too.
In a chair, all night!
Oh, Trudy, I'm sorry.
I know you didn't mean
what you said.
But if you'd just keep away
from this quack.
Roy!
He isn't interested in
marriage, he just told
me that.
Trudy, I...
I don't like to come
between engaged people.
He's upset.
It's a natural
misunderstanding.
Out so late
and everything.
You needn't be
alarmed, Doctor.
Your freedom
isn't in any danger,
whether I'm engaged or not.
And, Roy, I'm not.
Good night, both of you.
I wasn't of very
much help, was I?
I ought to punch you...
Oh, here, let me see.
There's no fracture,
just put an icepack on it.
Next time, don't
telegraph your punches.
You can
wind up with
no knuckles at all.
Good morning.
Well, what happened?
Six pound boy.
Boy, boy.
Yeah. Just left
Trudy, huh?
Yes, and Roy.
They've just broken
their engagement.
Have they now?
Well, I hope you seized
the opportunity, huh?
All right,
Doctor, don't you think
you've done enough meddling?
Meddling?
A man tries to squeeze
a little brains into that
narrow, pig-headed skull
of yours and you call
it meddling?
In my opinion, the girl's
too good for you.
If you'll pardon me,
I'd like to wash my face.
A girl
with brains, a personality,
an education
and a good figure...
Oh, you've gotten
rude again.
I was right about you
the first time.
Breakfast, Doctor.
All right, all right.
Uh...
Doctor...
Mrs. Gilley, you might
inform Dr. Pearson
that I'm not interested
in what he has to say.
Well, if I offended you...
Yes, and
that I'd much rather
he didn't speak to me.
Mrs. Gilley, would
you remind Dr. McRory
that he and I
are grown men?
What's gotten
into you two?
You have your
instructions,
Mrs. Gilley.
Well, you heard
each other.
Mrs. Gilley, you might
inform Dr. Pearson
that he needn't
bother to remain on here.
Tell him
I'd strongly recommend that
he takes the 4:15 bus today.
Mrs. Gilley,
would you be good
enough to tell Dr. McRory
that I agreed to remain here
until he was able to resume
his practice?
And I'll keep my word.
Inform Dr. Pearson that he'll
not get one penny salary
after today.
I'm busy frying eggs.
You mind passing
the sugar?
Dr. McRory, Dr. Pearson
would like the sugar.
If you get
a little time on your hands,
thank him for me, will you?
Good morning.
Good morning,
Mrs. Gilley.
Good morning, Al.
I see you got a new
neighbor, Dr. Jenks.
Jenks?
Who? Who did you say?
Dr. Jenks,
across the street.
Just moved in
that little Chesley
property last night.
Oh, they're just
visiting, no doubt.
No, staying.
Just ordered a whole
lot of groceries.
Well, see you tomorrow.
The man's an idiot.
Oh, he'll never last, Doctor.
Nobody's gonna take your
place in this town.
Well, other doctors have
come in here and lasted
a month,
at the longest.
This fellow
won't last three weeks.
Three weeks?
Three weeks.
You still mad at me?
No. Whatever
made you think
I was mad at you?
Sit down there.
Finish your breakfast.
Smile right back at the sun
At the sun
The moment
he catches your eye
Your eye
Oh, waking up
can be fun
Just depend on your
friend in the sky
In the sky
If you start your
daydreams early
You can get
a lot more done
Oh!
So, get up, get out, and
smile right back at the sun
Let's start again with
a little...
With what?
Remember
on the train when you
cut yourself shaving?
Yes, yes.
Yeah. Jim.
Huh?
I don't think I'll go
to the station with you.
I don't like farewells.
Well, I won't be leaving
till 4:10, Doctor.
What I think of it,
my good friends
call me Joe.
Joe?
I've liked working
with you, Joe.
Well, I wish
I could say that
I found you objectionable.
Yeah?
Yeah, then your
going away would be
a very happy occasion.
Thank you, Joe.
I'll pick you up after
I see about my trunk.
Hello, Doc.
Hello, Harry.
Gee, Pop, those
are fighting words.
Yeah.
Hello, Emily.
Hello, Dr. Pearson.
Hi, Bill.
Hiya, Doc.
Well, let's have
a drink, huh?
What?
You mean you want
me to have a drink?
Mmm-hmm.
Kept this for
a special occasion.
You were right.
It wasn't the drinking
that was causing those
headaches, Bill.
Just got this letter
from Dr. Sachs.
Who's he?
He's my
old professor
at medical school.
He's an authority
on pheochromocytoma.
Pheochromo...
Of the adrenal gland.
Confirms my diagnosis.
Do you mean
I need a drink
before I find out
what happens to me?
Oh, no.
It's to celebrate.
Oh, you mean,
he can be cured?
Mmm-hmm.
There's the man
that'll cure him.
He's gonna perform
the operation.
Oh, an operation?
Yeah.
Oh, well,
if it'll cure you, Pop.
Why don't you operate?
Oh, no,
I'm leaving
by the next bus.
Say, could you meet me
in Boston tomorrow?
I can't get out of
this town quick enough.
Haven't you heard
what's happened
to Dr. McRory?
No, what?
Get a load
of this poison.
And now,
we come to a subject...
What I want to say is
and I'm speaking for
the entire board.
We'll always appreciate
your great service
to Fallbridge.
Yes. Thank you,
thank you.
Hello, Jim.
Doctor.
Gentlemen.
We will proceed.
We know the hospital is
pretty close to your heart.
Well, yes, it is.
Well, it's close
to our hearts, too.
And we sort of feel that
a doctor with
more modern methods,
with newer ideas...
What's that?
Well, to get down
to brass tacks, Doc,
times have changed and...
You mean,
you don't want me
to run the hospital?
We feel
we need a younger man.
A man like Dr. Jenks.
If you'll excuse me.
Just a minute, Joe.
That was a very touching
little speech, Mr. Chesley.
Are you a member
of this board, Pearson?
If I was, I'd be
ashamed to admit it.
There's some pretty
short memories here.
I was present
when this town
paid a tribute,
a fine tribute it was,
to Dr. McRory and
his 35 years of service.
I didn't
realize then how much
he deserved the tribute,
but I do now.
I just want to add that
in taking care of you people
and your parents
and your children,
Dr. McRory has learned
more about medicine
than Dr. Jenks or I
will ever
get out of books.
Listen, Pearson,
you'll have to admit
there are new methods,
new discoveries in medicine.
Oh, yes,
very important
discoveries, too.
But no one
has discovered
a substitute for skill,
or wisdom,
or practical experience,
or for goodness of heart.
It isn't that
we don't think highly of Doc.
And he canceled
all 'em debts, too.
Now, wait a minute.
Yeah, when
we gave the party...
Now, wait, wait,
wait a minute.
If Dr. McRory
is the better man,
there's a way to find out.
A written examination.
Conducted by
the medical society.
That seems fair.
Yeah, I don't see
how the Doc could object
to a written examination.
Oh, you don't, eh?
I shouldn't have to
remind you two fellows
that Dr. McRory hasn't
written an examination
paper in almost 40 years.
And Mr. Cartwright,
before McRory
saved your son's life,
did you ask him to sit down
like a school boy and
write an examination paper?
Oh, nobody's knocking
the old Doc.
But we want to do
the progressive thing.
And I think the examination
is progressive.
All in favor, say, "Aye."
Aye.
No.
Six to two.
It's carried.
Let's go, Jim.
Corresponding
secretary will read
his report.
Joe, that examination,
don't you think...
No, no, I don't. No.
I wouldn't.
Ah, I've been
here too long.
A man's a fool
to bury himself
in one little corner
of the world.
Yeah, but, Joe,
you wouldn't have
too much trouble
with that
examination, really.
Let's pretend
that I wouldn't.
At my age...
Jim, would you believe it,
I'm past 60?
Really?
Gee, I never
would've guessed it.
You wouldn't, huh?
No, never.
Well,
what do you think of that?
Joe?
Would you like
me to stay here awhile?
Just sort of hang around, hmm?
No, me boy.
I'll be gone soon meself.
Ah, you've got
the right idea.
Travel around,
have a good time.
You know,
I might do that meself.
Get me a job on
one of those boats.
Well, I don't think
that you...
Yes, I imagine
I could fix it
for you.
Well, it's about
time for the bus.
Where's your grip?
It's inside here
in the hotel.
You wouldn't like
to wait around,
would you?
See me off?
No. No, I don't think so.
I think I'll walk home.
It's a fine day.
Well...
Dr. Pearson, it's been
a pleasure knowing you.
Has been for me, Joe.
Bye.
Well, he...
You see, I do a lot
of business with Chesley.
Yes, I understand.
I'll see you again sometime.
Leaving, Doctor?
Hmm?
Oh, hello, Miss Mason.
Yes, finally.
I called to
say goodbye...
But goodbyes
aren't pleasant.
No, they're not.
You generally manage
to avoid things that
aren't pleasant.
Yeah, if I can.
Mmm-hmm.
It's wonderful
having a little world all
your own, isn't it, Doctor?
Your friends have problems,
that's their misfortune.
You just get on a little boat
and your whole world is snug
and cozy again.
Say, wait a minute now,
Teacher.
Have you any idea
what that hospital
meant to Dr. McRory?
Have you the vaguest notion
what losing it will do to him?
Aren't you confusing me
with the Chesleys?
I didn't
take that job
from Joe McRory.
And my staying here
wouldn't give it
back to him.
You could stay
and help him prepare
for the examination.
Oh, he'd never take it.
Not with his pride.
Pride?
That hospital is
the dream of his life
and you talk about pride?
If you urged him to take
the examination, he'd take it.
If you coached him,
he'd pass.
But no, it's much more
pleasant in Guatemala.
And here's your bus.
Have fun, Doctor.
It's been nice
knowing you.
What do you mean,
you're gonna
work on a boat?
A man of your age.
Will you be good enough
to pack, Mrs. Gilley?
Oh, you're
an impossible old fool.
What will I pack?
Everything.
Everything? You mean...
I wouldn't know
where to begin.
Neither would I.
Jim?
Did you miss the bus?
No, took me
back to the house.
Joe, get your coat off.
Me coat?
Hang it up right there. Hmm?
But what happened?
Here's your glasses.
Come on, you and I
are going to work.
To work?
But... Yeah, but...
All right.
List the possible
complications of pertussis.
Go ahead, come on.
Pertussis. Can't you
just say whooping cough?
Is a man a better doctor
because he knows that
measles is rubeola?
Or that hordeolum
is a sty in the eye?
Or that tinea sycosis
is the barber's itch?
Ah, I'm not a school boy.
I'm tired,
I'm going to bed.
Joe, you want that
hospital, don't you?
What conditions
develop in advanced
hypertrophic emphysema?
Don't tell me,
don't tell me.
I won't.
Polycythemia.
Lowered vital capacity.
Pulmonary vascular
hypertension.
Eberthella typhosa.
It's getting
a little late, Joe.
You better get to bed.
What?
You better go to bed.
No, no,
tomorrow's
the examination.
Eberthella typhosa.
Salmonella paratyphi.
Salmonella paratyphi...
Name the tests
of liver function?
How do you treat
thyrotoxicosis?
You can do it, Doc.
Lots of luck to you, Doc.
Yeah, Jenks
ain't got a prayer.
Thanks.
I'll do my best.
Our man's in great shape.
He'll win without taking
a long breath.
Say, Mort,
if you get over
to the barber shop,
will you
put this sawbuck
on McRory's nose?
Okay.
Oh, you shouldn't
have done that.
Oh, you'll gallop.
You'll breeze. Come on.
You know, Jim,
once when I was a little boy,
just before an arithmetic
examination,
I started sneezing
and they sent me home.
I wish I was
sneezing now.
Oh, you're gonna win,
all right. You gotta win.
Get in there.
Hello, Doctor.
How do you do?
Mr. Dorkas,
I understand
there's quite a lot
of gambling going on
over at the
barber shop?
Some, yeah.
Would you bet that
dollar for me?
Why, Mrs. Gilley.
Warm, isn't it?
All finished, Doctor.
Dr. Jenks.
Yes?
Mr. Chesley wants you
over at the school
house right away.
School house?
Some kids are sick.
What's that?
What's the matter?
Don't know, Doc.
I'll be right with you.
Well, thank you, sir.
You'd better finish.
You only have
25 minutes to catch
the bus, Dr. Morton.
I know.
Doctor, hurry up, please.
We've got a terrible
situation.
Yes, I'm coming.
Open your mouth.
Open up. That's it.
Here's the basin, Trudy.
Where do you want it?
Over there?
Ah, throat's red.
Is it anything serious?
Eddie's my nephew.
He's Lucy's boy.
Well, four boys
sick at one time,
food poisoning's
ruled out.
And I don't like
these dizzy headaches.
These youngsters been
out of school lately?
George was
absent yesterday,
but he wasn't sick.
He was emotionally upset.
His horse died.
Horse died?
What from?
They didn't know.
What are those marks
on that boy's arm?
Uh-huh.
Mosquito bites.
Yeah.
Mosquito?
Yes, looks like it.
What's it?
What's the matter, huh?
Oh, hello,
Miss Mason, Chesley.
These your pupils?
Yes, Doctor.
Maybe you can help.
That won't be necessary.
It's a fairly obvious case.
Is it? What is it?
It's not a common
disease, Doctor.
I don't believe
you'd know about it.
I might.
Well, if I'm not mistaken,
this is equine encephalitis.
Mosquitoes
carry the virus,
chickens harbor it.
The disease is more
common among horses.
Aren't you being
a little hasty, Jenks?
If not wasting time
is being hasty, yes.
Doctor, is it fatal?
There was an epidemic
in Massachusetts in 1938.
More than 50%
of the children died.
Equine...
What did you call it?
Oh, call it
virus brain fever.
Brain fever?
Brain fever!
What?
Brain fever?
Stay here.
Roy, call Bentonville.
Tell them to get an
ambulance here at once.
Hello, Operator.
Get me Bentonville,
the hospital. Hurry, please.
I said,
Bentonville,
the hospital.
Such telephone service.
Yes, the Bentonville
Hospital. Hurry, please.
Psst.
This is Roy Chesley,
let me speak to
Dr. Wheaton.
Hello, Dr. Wheaton,
we need an ambulance
for the Fallbridge
Public School.
The Fallbridge
Public School!
Why don't you
listen to me?
At the school.
S-C-H-O-O-L!
Virus brain fever,
four boys have got it.
Hurry, please.
Line to Bentonville is busy.
Some kids at school
got brain fever.
Must be an epidemic.
We were right. Take a look.
It's a virus, all right.
That's nice work, Joe.
Come on.
Long distance.
Get me back that Washington
number I was talking to.
I was cut off.
Doctor, if I may
make a suggestion...
Not now, if you don't mind.
We're getting a vaccine
from Washington.
Yeah, but...
Dr. Jenk's case, Joe.
Customary ethics.
Give me
Congressman Beeker.
He'll know who it is.
Mr. Chesley,
I can't allow you to...
Please. Please.
Hello. Give me
Congressman Beeker.
Oh, is that you, Congressman?
This is Charlie Chesley,
in Fallbridge.
Charlie, who?
Chesley! C-H-E...
Well, you remembered me
before the election.
Oh, yes, yes.
Well, what can I
do for you, Chesley?
Yeah, well,
that's better.
Now, listen, Congressman,
my nephew's got equine...
Equine what?
Encephalitis.
Yeah, my nephew's
in a coma.
He got it from a horse.
Where did the horse get it?
From chickens.
Chickens?
Now, listen, Congressman,
the War Department has
got that vaccine
and I want
some of it flown up
here and I want it quick.
It's for equine encephalitis.
Do you
plan to vaccinate
everybody in town?
Uh, naturally. Roy.
Dad, get 2,400 doses.
We need 2,400 doses.
Twenty four...
What? For one horse?
This is
not for a horse,
it's for chickens.
What chickens?
Uh, for my nephew.
Say, look here, Chesley,
I'm a busy man.
Congressman?
Operator? Operator?
All right. It's all right.
You've got nothing to
worry about.
The vaccine will keep
the disease from spreading.
Well, if it isn't being
too unethical, I suggest
you forget the vaccine.
Dr. McRory here
has a simpler cure.
Yeah. Me own
prescription is
a hairbrush.
A hairbrush?
What?
Yeah, a hairbrush.
Vigorously applied
across the seat
of the pants.
Huh? What are you
talking about?
Well, it's the best cure
I know for 12-years-olds
who've been
smoking cigars.
What?
I feel better already, Doc.
Me, too.
Boys!
You won't tell Pop,
will you?
Swell job, Doc!
Oh, Mr. Cartwright,
let's get rid of this.
You'll start
another epidemic.
Good work, Doc.
Mr. Chesley,
if you'll only let me
explain, I am certain...
Get away from me,
you horse doctor, you!
Everything's all right.
You can go home now.
Oh, Miss... Teach!
Yes?
I'm surprised at you.
You shouldn't permit
your kids to smoke cigars.
Oh, I guess I shouldn't...
Well, you're just gonna have
to be a little more careful
with our kids.
Oh, don't be so smart.
No, wait. Come here.
Listen, Joe,
the hospital,
it's yours.
But I don't want
the hospital.
But, Joe...
For 35 years, I've been
thinking of Fallbridge,
now I'm thinking
of meself.
Oh, Joe.
It's a big job
for a man of my age.
Unless, of course,
Dr. Pearson stays
on to assist me.
Oh, I'm sorry, Doctor,
my plans are already made.
Unless, of course,
Miss Mason...
I think
it could be arranged.
Watch Movies, TV Series & Live Sports
www.admitme.app