Good morning, beauty.
Let's go, or we'll never
leave on time.
I'm totally ready.
Come on. I'll make you some waffles.
- Mother....
- Caitlin.
Blueberries!
Hey, Cooper.
You want some breakfast too?
You want some waffles?
Good boy.
Look. They're at it again.
Christ, that's twice in....
When did they move in?
Three weeks. What's their name?
Feur, I think. Psych department.
Figures, they're all nuts.
She's awake.
We'll be quiet.
Quick and quiet.
I don't want to be either.
- When's she out of here?
- Norman Spencer!
All right, I can't stand
the rejection. I'm going for a run.
Hey, you okay?
Yeah.
Come on, Pooper. Let's go.
We'll have to leave by 11
if we want to beat the traffic.
Eleven o'clock.
You know, you can call me...
...whenever you want.
Sweetheart...
...I've known this day was coming
for a long time.
I have Norman, and the garden
and the new house.
You really don't have to worry.
- I'm just saying--
- Really.
Okay.
Mom?
Mother?
I have to go.
Honey, if I don't get you out of here
quick, they'll make you enroll.
- I'll call you.
- Okay.
- Bye.
Come home often.
Call your mom.
- Beatrice, it's nice to meet you.
- Bye.
- You take care of each other.
- I won't go to a bar without her.
I'm just kidding.
Bye.
Well, I almost made it.
What are you reading?
"Genetic Repair Mechanisms
in Eukaryotic Organisms."
Eukaryotic. How is it?
Excellent.
Oh, a couple of...
...Swedish sailor cells just gang-
divided a virginal cheerleader cell.
Almost there.
- If you have to work....
- No, no. Just let me get this.
Okay, almost.
There.
How's it going?
Great. I think we cracked it.
The prenatal thing?
Yeah, I targeted repair.
You are so brilliant.
Yep.
Madame Curie, Jonas Salk...
...Norman Spencer.
Yes!
How are you?
- I'm fine.
- Yeah?
I am. Yeah, really.
It's okay if you're not, you know.
To tell you the truth, I'm...
...excited.
Really?
Yeah, I'm gonna get my life back.
Get some time for myself.
Some time for us.
Did a great job.
She's a good kid.
We did.
Just us now.
I know.
Tired?
Nope.
Want to fool around?
Yep.
Jesus.
What is he doing to her?
- I guess they're making up.
- Wait.
Leave it open.
Think we can take 'em?
It's worth a try.
Do the brilliant Norman stuff
some more.
And speak up.
Oh.
Hello?
Ouch! Ow!
Mrs. Feur?
Hello?
Are you all right?
He's so....
It's too much...
...and I can't....
I can't breathe.
And I'm afraid.
What? What are you afraid of?
That one day I'll just...
...disappear.
Is there something I can do?
Can I...?
I've never even met you.
I know. I'm sorry.
I've been consumed.
This fence...
...it's so....
I'm sorry. Listen, would you like
to come over for coffee, or--?
Oh, God, he's back.
I'm sorry. Please forget what I said.
I don't even know you!
Please!
She sounded...
- ...terrified.
- Of what?
Of him, I think.
Did she say that?
More or less.
I want to go over there.
Let's go and--
- Why?
- To see if she's all right--
Honey, we're not going to march over
to our new neighbors and accuse them--
- That's not what I'm suggesting.
- Especially since they'll keep us up...
...with their sexual olympics.
What if something happened to her?
- Nothing will happen.
- I'd never forgive....
Honey, people argue.
People fight.
It's not our business.
- I've got to work tonight.
- I know.
This conference is the first
big preview of my paper.
I've just got to stay focused
a little while longer.
This is what I've been working for.
I just wish you could have heard her.
I'll tell you what I'll do.
I'll call Harvey Tomes tomorrow
in the psych department...
...and I'll see what I can
find out about him.
Promise?
Yeah, I promise.
Hey, lady!
What are you doing?
Looking for you.
Just trying to drop off this
welcome thing for the new neighbors.
Not home?
Guess not.
- You are so good at this.
- If I were, I'd have done it weeks ago.
I gave my neighbors wine
that someone left at my house.
- Are you staying?
- Just came by to see how you're doing.
Good. I'm good.
Are you?
Why does everyone
find that so surprising?
Because your only daughter
just left for college...
...who you're extremely close with.
I'd be tripping.
Oh, right.
You had a hell of a year too.
The move, the new house...
...the garden.
The car.
A minor setback.
Was that a year ago?
This week.
Wow. Now Caitlin.
Big stress stuff.
Okay.
I'm a little tender.
Good. You're human.
And so far this week, my big task
is to take pictures of my roses...
...for the garden club.
Got here just in time, didn't I?
Brought you something.
It's Kambucha mushroom tea.
It soothes heartache
and promotes psychic wellness.
- Floriana suggested it.
- So you discuss me with your psychic?
No, and she's not really a psychic.
Just an enlightened spirit.
Like me.
That's worse.
You're gossiping about me.
Notice anything different?
Oh, my God. You bought it!
Yep.
Nice.
It's a beautiful thing, alimony.
You lose a husband...
...get a car.
- Think it'll help me pick up dudes?
- Absolutely.
Cool.
I have to run. You take care.
Thanks for the tea.
Norman.
- Norman!
- What?
Come here. You have to see this.
- What's the matter?
- Look.
What, Claire?
I thought I saw....
- I--
- What?
- I thought I saw something.
- Jesus Christ!
Ow.
Hi, is Caitlin there?
Any idea when she'll be back?
You be sure to tell her I called?
Thanks, Beatrice.
Well, that's a first.
Cooper, come on.
Get your ball.
What's the matter?
Cooper, it's your favorite ball.
- Hello?
- Hi.
I'm stuck here for another
couple of hours. Sorry.
Unless you want me to come home?
No. No, it's fine.
You sure?
Claire?
Huh?
Oh, absolutely. Take your time.
See you soon. Love you.
Love you. Bye.
Cooper!
Fine. Have it your way.
We use different kinds.
Now we're using halothane.
Halothane? Is that a sedative?
It's a dissociative.
It paralyzes motor function
but leaves her conscious.
She can't move
but knows what's going on.
- Hi, Mrs. Spencer.
- Hi, Teddy.
- How long does that last?
- Five minutes.
- Sometimes three.
- Can it be used on all mammals?
Yeah, any procedure where you want
to get the patient immobile, pain-free.
- Hey.
- Hi.
Hi. What are you doing here?
- Are you okay?
- I....
I heard noises.
- What kind of noises? Where?
- At the house. I was scared.
- Did you call the police?
- No.
I'll have the police
check on the house while I'm gone.
Oh, great.
"Could you check in on my wife?
She's hearing voices."
Wait till that gets around.
I'll be in New Haven for the
conference. I want you to feel safe.
I do.
I'm sure it was just...
...nothing.
Did you call about the Feurs?
Oh, yeah.
Harvey says the guy's harmless.
Wouldn't hurt a flea.
Warren. Warren Feur.
What about her?
I know he told me....
Oh.
I met Schumway today.
Who wrote that book you love.
They were doing some spiel
for the chemistry department...
...so Bob Shine introduces us.
You'll love this.
He looks right at me...
...and congratulates me
on Spencer's Theorem.
He didn't know your father was dead?
He knew.
Oh, Norman.
What?
You're so sensitive about that.
- No, I'm not.
- You are.
You always overreact.
I'll have to watch that, won't I?
Was it Mary?
Mrs. Feur.
Warren and Mary?
Yeah.
Mary. That's it.
I'm gonna do some work.
Hello?
Mrs. Feur?
Can I help you?
Oh, yes.
Hi.
I'm Claire Spencer, from next door.
Nice to meet you.
I wanted to stop by and welcome you
to the neighborhood.
Thank you, but this really isn't
a good time. I'm running late.
Is your wife home?
No, she isn't.
When will she be back?
I have to go.
I'm sorry. It was nice to meet you.
What's he doing?
Eating dinner.
Alone.
TV dinner.
That's bad.
That's my shiatsu guy.
Listen, call me back if he starts in
on some serial-killer dessert...
...like ladyfingers.
- You got it.
- Bye.
Where did you go?
Shit!
Jesus, Claire.
- What the hell are you doing?
- I was looking--
- Spying.
- Spying on Mr. Feur.
- How come you're not dressed?
- Dressed?
Dinner with Stan.
- Tonight?
- Tonight.
- We're going to be--
- Fashionably five minutes late.
Are you saying he murdered his wife?
Is that so ridiculous?
She was terrified...
...and now she doesn't answer
the door, but her car's in the garage.
Maybe she was out,
or in bed with the flu.
- Or maybe she was abducted by aliens.
- Who are you calling?
- Restaurant.
- We're not at the center of the bridge.
You can't get service
until the center.
I know we're not at the center.
There. See?
Well, that's a relief.
Hi, Stan.
Hey, Claire. Norman.
- Sorry we're late.
- It's my fault.
We just got here.
- Where's the new squeeze?
- Here I am.
- This is--
- Elena?
Oh, my God. Claire!
I don't believe it!
- This is--
- We know each other.
- Norman.
- Hello, Norman. How do you do?
Claire, look at you!
You look beautiful.
Here was this brilliant conductor
in purple bikini briefs...
...with no bangs...
...cursing his ass off in Finnish.
Oh, Claire.
I made an honest woman of her.
How long have you been in Vermont?
Oh, well, Norman grew up here.
Remember Beau Flynn, head of cardio
at the hospital? He was just sacked.
I just dropped her off at college.
He was involved in some stalking
incident. An intern, some girl.
We're getting so old!
They don't screw around
with that anymore.
- When did we last get together?
- New York.
- Of course. Right after--
- Right after Michael died.
- Michael who?
- Marlov.
Claire's first husband.
- Oh, the musician.
- Yeah.
You know, we all toured together.
Have you heard her play?
No.
No, I....
I would sit on-stage...
...during Claire's solo...
...and I mean, truly, I had tears
streaming down my face.
I mean, she's fabulous.
So why did you stop?
Oh....
Well, one night, after a concert...
...I met a dashing, handsome...
...genius scientist...
...and three months later,
I was married.
Is that when you guys
moved up to Vermont?
No, we were living in Boston...
...when Norman was offered a position.
A position.
The DuPont Chair in genetics.
I see. So now you're teaching
at your father's school here.
I actually don't...
...do much teaching anymore.
I run a research project.
Oh.
Norman's father had this old stuffy--
--stately place on a lake.
- Which we're renovating.
- Practically gutted.
- No, we didn't.
- Yes, we did.
"Gutted."
- Wait till you see it. It's beautiful.
- It is beautiful. You'll see it.
It's haunted.
No.
Is it really?
Claire's hearing things.
What? What are you hearing?
I, um....
I don't know. I heard...
...voices, whispering....
A picture fell.
You know, I completely believe
in all that.
You do?
I do.
Wait a minute.
Who do you think it is?
I know exactly who it is.
It's my old man.
He's pissed about us
dicking around with the house.
Ow.
Claire.
Jesus....
It's all right.
Calm down, Claire.
It's okay.
Whose idea was it?
Mine. His.
We both thought....
I didn't want to come here.
- Then why did you?
- He was worried about me.
- Your husband?
- Yes.
I'm sure he's hoping you'll pack me
full of Prozac or lithium...
...so he can live out his life
in peace.
- Do you really think so?
- No.
Are you on medication?
No. Well, Valium.
For sleeping.
Having trouble sleeping?
Sometimes.
When I get anxious.
Do you get anxious only at night?
No, I only take Valium at night.
For sleeping.
Why do you get anxious?
I don't know.
Why do you think
your husband's worried?
Because....
I don't know.
Because ever since Caitlin left--
Ever since my daughter left
for school...
...there have been....
I've been....
Why is this so hard?
Here. Have a fireball.
Thank you.
It's hard because I'm
a complete stranger...
...and you're talking about
incredibly personal things.
Besides, most people, when they
come the first time, are wondering...
...if I think they're crazy.
Don't worry. I'm required...
...to have three sessions
before I can commit.
That was a joke.
These are good. They're hot.
There's a ghost in my house.
I saw her in the water, beside me...
...in the bathtub.
What does she look like?
She looked like...
...me.
Oh.
Only she had green eyes.
Any idea who she is?
Maybe. But I'd rather not say
just yet.
Fine.
What do you think I should do?
Try to contact her.
Communicate with her somehow.
Find out what she wants.
What do you want me to do?
Go buy a Ouija board?
Ah.
Are we hoping the ghost
will have to use the potty?
This is where she was.
This is where I...
...saw her.
That makes sense.
- Where did you finally find one?
- Kmart.
I think we're supposed to sit
in a protective circle, aren't we?
What's that for?
- Where did you get it?
- Never mind.
You stole her shoe.
You have to have something
of the dead woman's.
Says who?
Is that blood on it?
I don't know. Just place your fingers
on the message indicator.
Okay.
We wish to commune...
...with the spirit--
What?
"Wish to commune."
- Forget it.
- What?
No, this whole thing is insane.
I'm sorry.
What's her first name?
Mary.
Feur.
Mary Feur, Mary Feur....
Mary Feur....
We wish to communicate...
...with the spirit of Mary Feur.
- Not much happening.
- Shh.
What was that?
It's flickering.
Yeah.
- Did you see that?
- Yeah.
Cooper!
Listen...
...about our little séance.
Norman doesn't need to know.
- I won't tell if you won't.
- It's just that...
...ever since the accident...
...he treats me like I'm this...
...fragile, loopy....
Well, I am seeing ghosts
in the bathtub, aren't I?
You did wrap your car around a tree
doing, like, 80.
He was pretty shaken up.
- We all were.
- It was an accident. A year ago.
I'm fine.
Right?
Of course you are.
You're just not much of a medium,
however.
I'll call you tomorrow.
Get some rest.
Did you pick up any dudes yet?
I have one in the trunk.
Bye.
What do you want?
She's dead.
- Who's dead?
- You know damn well who's dead.
The Feur thing.
Listen to me.
He killed her and I'm not crazy.
Jody and I had a séance in the
bathroom, and nothing happened...
...but when I went back there
she was there. She was.
Wait a minute.
You had a séance?
- Are you angry with me?
- What?
- Maybe you resent how busy I've been.
- No.
You know what I've got at stake for
this paper. How important it is to me.
I can't help feeling that you're
trying to sabotage me, to hurt me.
Norman, this isn't about you.
Something is happening to me.
And it's not to get even, and it's
not some warped bid for attention.
Something is happening in our house,
whether you like it or not.
Claire.
Claire, stop.
You're overreacting.
Don't tell me how to react.
- Will you keep your voice down?
- I will not!
Maybe you're right.
Maybe I am losing my mind.
But what if I'm not?
What if she died...
...some horrible death?
Can we please not do this here?
Oh, wow.
You.
You think you're smart, don't you?
You think you got away with it.
Well, I know you killed her,
you murdering son of a bitch!
Who?
Don't give me that shit.
Your wife.
She's very upset. Forgive us, please.
Honey.
I didn't kill my wife.
Are you all right?
Come on, honey.
Come on. Let's go.
I'm sorry.
You all right?
Oh. Yeah.
I'm fine.
What happened? Just now?
I just saw Norman's face.
He was so frightened for me.
How's your marriage?
Good. Really good.
We've had our moments, I guess...
...but he's a wonderful husband
and father.
I mean, sure, he can be obsessed
with his work...
...and sometimes it's like...
...that he doesn't see me.
Or, you know...
...like I'm....
That there's something wrong...
...with me.
That can't feel good.
No.
Okay.
I see where you're going with this...
...but my marriage is fine. No.
I have had some kind of
empty-nest episode...
...where I saw...
...some things that weren't there.
Let's deal with that.
I'm willing to deal with that.
"Thought you might need this.
Love, Jody."
Uh-oh.
Mrs. Spencer.
I wanted to apologize
for scaring you like I did.
When I thought about
how it must have seemed--
Please. Let's just....
Claire Spencer.
Mary Feur.
- Would you like a cup of coffee?
- Very much.
That day at the fence...
...you seemed terrified.
I don't think I imagined that.
No.
What were you so afraid of?
Have you ever felt so completely
consumed by a feeling for someone...
...that you couldn't breathe?
Thought that your time together
was so...
...passionate and consuming that you
felt physical pain when they'd leave?
Um....
Sure.
I couldn't catch my breath...
...and I panicked.
I never dreamed anyone would hear me.
I tried to leave him.
I went to my mother's in Providence...
...but he brought my things up...
...in the middle of the night...
...during the rainstorm.
He pleaded with me to come home.
You must think I'm pathetic.
No.
I don't.
I'll be quick. I've got to get Sidon
to okay my budget before his trip.
What's Templeton's wife's name again?
Lois. Phil and Lois Templeton.
Don't let her corner you,
she'll chew your ear off.
- Evening, Phil.
- Here they are.
How do you do? Hi.
Hi. Nice to see you again, Lois.
White wine, please.
How are you holding up?
Just fine. It's a lovely party.
Norman was telling me the house
is finished.
- Almost.
- Wonderful.
It's good to see you doing so well.
Thank you.
Well, I was worried.
I don't think I've seen you since
Norman's reception here last year.
You were worried?
I swear, I've become that nosy old lady
I used to run away from at Amherst.
No, I'm just not sure what you mean.
You got so upset.
Oh, at the party.
For the DuPont Chair.
You remember?
Well, I remember the party, but....
Oh, God!
I had completely forgotten.
I broke your crystal.
Oh, my dear.
A cheap wine glass from the caterers.
But you went completely pale.
You couldn't catch your breath.
It was as if you had seen a ghost.
"Missing girl."
Madison Elizabeth.
M-E.
Frank.
Madison Elizabeth...
...Frank.
M-E-F.
Claire?
Hey, good morning.
Up all night?
Mm-hm.
You okay?
Do you remember this?
It's the girl that disappeared
last year.
Did you know her?
No.
Claire, I'm afraid to ask.
Where's all this going?
It's her.
The woman I saw in the bathtub.
- The ghost?
- Yes, the ghost.
I thought it was Mrs. Feur,
but it's not.
I'm positive this time.
Claire, stop it!
Stop it.
I know you're going through something
I don't understand.
I have tried to be here for you,
but this is enough, Claire.
Enough.
Do you want to go see somebody
together?
I'll call Dr. Drayton.
Then what, Claire? What?
Tell me what to do.
It's her.
So let me ask you this....
Mr. McCain?
- McCann.
Nothing was ever found?
No car, or...?
Listen....
This girl's a real live wire.
She drives around in a souped-up
Mustang convertible.
Most people think she's...
...off around Mexico or somewhere
with her friends.
The police downgraded it to a runaway.
Her mother lives out here
in Addison County.
- Mrs. Frank?
- Yeah?
I'm Claire.
I wanted to talk to you about Madison.
Just plain coffee.
- None of that mocha nonsense.
- Fine.
You look a little old for a student.
I'm not a student. We met at a party.
Well, that sounds about right.
I never understood how a girl
that wild got all A's.
She liked to read a lot, though.
Sometimes she'd lock herself up
in her room for days, just reading.
They wanted to put her in a school
for the gifted when she was young.
Maddie wouldn't hear about it.
I don't know where she got it.
She didn't get it from me.
She probably got it
from her father's side of the family.
She never really mentioned her father.
Yeah, well, she wouldn't.
She was 12 when he left.
Never spoke about him after that.
You don't even need the sound.
You can pretty much tell
what's happening by the faces.
I turn it up sometimes, though.
Feels like there's someone here.
Why are you here?
I don't know.
You want to see her room?
Full scholarship.
Princeton too.
She wanted to stay on the East Coast.
You must be so proud.
These are the last pictures
taken of her.
The police used this one.
Let me get that. Excuse me.
Claire?
- Hello, Dr. Spencer.
- Mrs. Spencer.
Forbidden fruit.
You got a problem with that?
Guess this means you're not
mad at me anymore, huh?
I wouldn't go that far.
Ow.
Take it easy, huh?
What's got into you?
- Ow!
- What's the matter?
It's too rough.
Since when?
This is a brand-new--
Shh.
- Okay, Claire, that's--
- Why don't you shut up, professor?
Why don't you just...
...shut up?
I think she's starting
to suspect something.
Who?
Your wife.
Stop it!
You know.
What the hell are you doing?
I know.
I was there.
Just before the accident.
I remember now.
What?
I came to the door.
There was whispering.
I saw you in the mirror...
...lying there with her...
...in our house.
Claire, listen to me.
She was at the DuPont party...
...staring at me. It was her.
That's why I couldn't breathe.
That's why I dropped the glass.
Honey, that was last year.
We were having troubles.
So you slept with a fucking student?
- That's not what I'm saying.
- Don't touch me.
Get away from me.
Get out!
I said, get out!
Fine.
Claire, please, please.
I gave up everything.
Claire, please don't....
- My life, my music.
- I never asked you to quit.
There was never any other choice!
You had to topple perfect daddy.
That meant perfect wife.
- Perfect family.
- That's not fair.
You were touring with a baby...
...and you were happy to give it up.
When you did, you hated me for it,
so you gave it all to her.
- Who?
- Caitlin!
Leave her out of this.
And then some bright
young woman finds me attractive.
- Stop it!
- And I slipped!
- God help me, I slipped!
- I'm not gonna listen.
- Claire, I tried to break it off.
- You should've tried harder.
I was in Adamant.
In Adamant?
You know, that artsy little hippie
village a couple hours away down on 7.
I stopped at this café to get coffee,
and I see Norman sitting in the back.
But he wasn't alone.
It was a young blond woman.
I didn't see her face.
I didn't think anything of it
at first.
And I was walking over to say hello.
And they started arguing
in such a way...
...that it stopped me.
Then a few days later,
you were in the accident.
And I get a bizarre call from Stan
working at the hospital...
...asking me, was I with you that day?
If you were upset about anything.
He made it sound
like you had deliberately...
...driven your car into a tree.
And I thought, "Oh, my God.
Claire's found out."
And when I went to the hospital,
I see Norman.
And he was so desperate
at the thought...
...of losing you.
I couldn't say anything.
Please...
...don't hate me, Claire.
I don't hate you.
Hello, this is Miss Jody.
Can't get to the phone. Leave your
name and I'll call you back.
Jody, it's Norman.
I'm looking for Claire.
Will you please...
...ask her to call home, please?
I can't talk to him.
Will you call and tell him
I'll be home in the morning?
I have to ask him something.
Norman?
Norman!
Oh, God!
- How's his blood pressure?
- 140/80.
- How about his rhythm?
- Rhythm is normal. Normal sinus.
- No sign of arrhythmia.
- Good.
Pulse/ox is normal.
His pupils were equal.
I'd still like to take you down.
I'm fine, really.
Dr. Powell, I'd recommend
a cardiac workup.
- I'll take care of that.
- He needs to sign the release form.
Thanks, guys.
They can take you for a CAT scan
tomorrow if you start feeling dizzy.
I'm not going to the hospital...
...unless they have
a miracle drug for clumsiness.
Honey, I'm so sorry.
Thank God you came home.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
You know, if that breaker
hadn't popped, he....
I know.
Yeah, don't worry, Claire.
You just keep him quiet tonight, okay?
You might want to think twice
about keeping anything electrical...
- ...next to the tub.
- Oh, thank you.
Goodbye. Call me, okay?
I called you last night.
I left a message on Jody's machine.
I want you to answer one question.
Did you have anything to do
with her disappearance?
Yes.
I had an affair with her.
And when I tried to break it off...
...she became unstable.
She came out here to the house.
She threatened to kill herself...
...or you.
I didn't think she'd
go through with any of it.
But then she....
She disappeared.
It was her, Norman.
She tried to kill you.
- Claire.
- You said it yourself.
She wanted you dead.
Are you saying I was attacked
by a ghost?
You had an affair with a girl...
...who threatened to kill herself, and
now there's a presence in our house.
A young, blond girl.
Don't you get it?
She did it, Norman.
She's dead...
...and now she's trying to hurt you
or both of us.
- You don't know that she's dead.
- Of course we do!
It's the only thing that makes--
Oh, God.
It's my fault. I....
I opened the door.
- Madison. I stole her hair.
- From where?
- And it gave her power.
- Claire.
Nothing attacked me.
There are no ghosts.
It was an accident. I'm fine.
It's not your fault.
Are you listening to me?
- Yes.
- Claire, say it.
Say it:
"It was an accident.
It's not my fault."
Say it, Claire.
I need to go lie down.
I didn't sleep last night,
and I need to lie down.
I want to be alone for a while.
Hey, Teddy, it's me.
Right, yeah.
What's the name of that friend of
yours? That who-you-gonna-call guy?
The guy that does the paranormal
psych stuff?
Holodnik.
Could you contact him and ask him
to give me a call here?
I'd really like to talk to him today.
Hello.
Yes, this is he.
Thanks for calling back.
No, sir. That was my father.
Yeah, he passed away
a couple of years ago.
Yes, he was. Thank you.
Look, the reason I'm calling is....
I'm a little out of my depth here.
Someone who is very close to me...
...believes herself to be
or seems to be...
...in contact with some kind of...
...entity or spirit, and--
No, there's no...
...no history of delusional behavior.
Well, I guess what I'm asking is,
is it possible that she could be...
...causing these manifestations...
...through some kind of unconscious
or telekinetic--?
Uh-huh.
Is there anything else
that it could be?
And this has been documented?
Really?
I'm sorry,
but could I call you back...
...or have you call me back?
Please, yes, that'll be great.
Thank you, sir.
Claire!
You all right, Claire?
The braid!
Where's the braid?
What are you talking about?
This?
Is this what you're talking about?
- Where'd you get this?
- I took it from Madison's house.
This is hers?
This is Madison Frank's hair?
What do you think?
I really don't know.
Norman.
Yes...
...I believe you.
You're playing.
She's gone.
How do you know?
I can feel it.
I picked up the book you ordered
at the bookstore.
Claire, I don't know how to apologize
to you for what I've done.
But if you give me another chance...
...I promise I'll spend the rest of my
life making you glad that you did.
Please.
Last sail of the year.
Beautiful, isn't it?
We ought to take a drive
before the leaves all disappear.
- Stay at a little bed-and-breakfast.
- Look for antiques.
Yeah, we haven't
done that for a while.
Adamant.
- Adamant?
- An artsy little village down 7.
Supposed to be charming.
- Do you know it?
- No.
Maybe we'll stop there for lunch.
What's that for?
Nothing.
God, oh, God....
You don't understand what that is.
Don't I, Norman?
That's Madison's necklace.
You killed her, didn't you?
I did not.
I didn't kill anyone.
Jesus, Claire.
Listen to me.
When I got here...
...she was already dead. She killed
herself in our house to destroy me.
Do you think I'm stupid?
She left that for you in the garden,
with a letter.
I burned the letter
and threw the box in the lake.
A week before...
...she showed up at the DuPont party.
I was terrified.
She insisted, so I agreed
to meet her here.
When I got here...
...she had taken pills.
I tried to revive her, but...
...she was gone.
There was nothing I could do.
So I put her in her car...
...and I drove to the boat ramp...
...and I rolled it out into the lake.
I made a terrible mistake.
I know that.
But tell me, Claire.
What should I have done?
Should I sacrifice everything?
Our marriage?
My work,
which I spent my whole life on?
Tell me, Claire.
Tell me, please. Because we can
put this behind us.
Our life can go on.
It's not too late.
What are you asking me to do?
I'm asking you to forgive me.
That girl must be brought up.
Hello. This is Dr. Norman Spencer.
I have some information...
...about a missing person.
Madison Frank, yes.
Could you send an officer
out to the house, please?
15 Willoughby Lane.
It's about a mile from the bridge.
Okay.
Thank you.
I'm gonna go get dressed.
Information. What city?
Don't!
Stop it!
I begged you, Claire.
I pleaded with you.
But you wouldn't let it go.
Oh, Claire.
I never wanted any of this to happen.
All I ever wanted...
...was for you to love me.
Be proud of me.
To be happy.
She was going to go to the dean.
She would have ruined us.
Did she think I was just
gonna sit there...
...and watch it happen?
You have no idea what it was like.
Hold her underwater...
...watch her life slip away.
But she gave me no choice.
And neither have you.
I can't figure out
how you put it all together.
At first I thought you knew.
Thought you created the whole
ghost thing as an elaborate trap.
Then I realized you believed it.
It was a passive-aggressive
masterpiece.
The first time I met you...
...all I ever wanted was to spend
the rest of my life with you.
It's not gonna happen now.
Too cold.
I almost froze to death laying here...
...wet, naked, pretending to be
electrocuted.
Hey, Coop.
How you doing? How you doing, boy?
Let's go get your ball. Come on.
Come on.
Jody, it's Norman.
If you're there, pick up, please.
It's Norman.
Listen, Claire and I...
...had a terrible blowout.
Could you do me a favor?
I'm sleeping at the lab. Could
you check on her in the morning?
I'm worried about her.
Thanks.
The halothane's starting to wear off.
I'm sure in some...
...tragic way,
your suicide is gonna...
...help bring Caitlin and I
closer together.
And every time I look at her...
...I'll see you.
Oh, God.
What's this?
Oh, shit.
I'm on the bridge!
Somebody help me!
No!
I beg you...
...think of Caitlin.
Please, don't. Please.